<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-19T12:43:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 29</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/19/OOCY29.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 29" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/19/OOCY29</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/19/OOCY29.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/02RCq2W.png" alt="&quot;It's not because I like boo- breasts! I'm groping you because I like you, Subaru! It's not for any perverted reason whatsoever!!" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>For the LIGHTEST bit of context, this is very consensual.</p>

<p>source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 42 - Night Manor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-42.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 42 - Night Manor" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#42</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-42.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OktYVCe.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While UFO Soft has toyed with scary, isolating, spooky, and macabre conecpts before, with games like in Divers, or Fist Hell, or hell even Waldorf’s Journey, this game goes far, far beyond that. The only game with a WARNING, this is a straight up horror game. And it makes sense. It’s the first, and only game (unless you count UFO 50 itself) that was lead by longtime developer Greg-Milk. Milk, despite being a massive scaredy cat, is very into horror, and wanted to share his love with a video game. How did he do?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/THWFrxq.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You play as an unnamed woman driving home from a party. The party is said to be thrown by “Amy”, so we can consider this yet another game in the Partyverse! That ends up having some dark connotations for what’s happening just outside town, but then again this town DID have a zombie uprising, so it’s kind of in character. On your drive home, you crash your car into a figure in the road, and blackout. You wake up an unknown time later in a dilapidated house, in what looks like a cell of some kind. This is where your game begins.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N2JbIRe.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Night Manor is a very loving tribute to the Macventure games, three extremely influential and beloved point and click adventure games of the 80s. You’ve PROBABLY heard of Shadowgate, but there’s also Uninvited and Deja Vu. This is very Uninvited energy, personally, but also has a lot of Clocktower and contemporary horror energy. You have to solve puzzles, collect items, and explore this horrorfying house. As you explore, you are also being hunted by the Monster, a scary man in some kind of mask with a knife who chases you if you make too much noise. So like, don’t flush the toilet over and over, he hates that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Q3Wp42t.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I really like point and click adventure games, and this is a good one! But I have a few complaints. Some of the puzzles and items are a LITTLE obscure, not nearly as bad as 80s games could get, but y’know, a little obscure. And there’s the problem of the horror guy. The first time he shows up, it’s genuinely effective. There’s a loud noise, a scary monster, a knife, and your cursor is suddenly shaking and hard to control. You need to try and run for it, while struggling to control your own panic, and it’s a great and fun idea! And you dive into hiding spots throughout the house, and have to do a quick time event mini game to hold your breath as he hunts for you. It’s hard, but rewarding once you survive. And as you explore, these hiding spots get destroyed, and become less numerous, so it becomes more harrowing the further in you get. This all SOUNDS good, and it is good! The first few times! But you HAVE to make noise to proceed, and every time you do, he shows up, and you gotta run away from the puzzle you’re solving to hide in a bush, and do a mini game, and if you fail the mini game, he’ll just kill you and then you wake up in your cell, with all your items, and nothing has changed. There’s NO penalty for dying, at all. Which is good, cause it’s easy to die. But then why even have this mechanic? It’s not BAD, it really just destroys the pacing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/opSV666.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Milkdud clearly loves his horror. The game has a warning, and it means it. There’s some fucked up imagery and concepts in here. My favorite is the screaming corpse you find in the bathtub. This place is NOT a happy place. Lots of people died here, including dogs and children, so uh, warning. Anyways, Night Manor is a really solid point and click adventure game with great atmosphere, great graphics and style, and fun puzzles that can keep you scratching your head for a while. One of the best games in the collection for sure.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 41 - Lords of Diskonia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-41.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 41 - Lords of Diskonia" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#41</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-41.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KqUQbQS.png" alt="Diskonia" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Inspired by the Indian game of Carrom, Diskonia is a board-game esque strategy game. Pretty unique and cool, I liked it at first glance, but I hear a lot of people don’t like it very much and find it tedious. We’ll see what you think as I explain it, though!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KarpGh1.png" alt="Diskonia" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Lords of Diskonia, you have a campaign of ten levels. Each level has a map, which is just paths, and you and your opponent take turns drawing out a path on these lines. They start very simple, like this, and then get more complex in the later levels. You cannot go backwards on your own line, and if the opponent reaches you or your line, combat happens. There’s powerups and resources to grab on the map, and taverns where you can recruit units for battle.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PEwBIhi.png" alt="Diskonia" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Once your troops meet, battle begins. You two take turns flicking disks at each other, deciding angle and strength of the flick. Units have unique stats and abilities, as well. A knight has good health but bad offense, but is cheap. An archer can only attack traditionally once, but uses a crystal to shoot a tiny powerup arrow. The Ogre hits hard and stuns, but can only attack once, and can’t go very far cause it’s so big. Things like that. There’s also sand mechanics, water traps which will instantly kill any unit, the health wells from Valbrace return, healing and overhealing your units. If you bounce an enemy into your units, like by pincering them, you can deal more damage. Or you can make them bounce into each OTHER, which hurts them both. The game boils down to good aiming, power management, and being able to get good trick shots. It’s a lot like Pool, in that way.</p>

<p>But a lot like computer simulations of Pool, the AI is, of course, infallible. A good AI can make perfect shots every time to hit your units a bunch. So it seems like, in this game, they kind of just roll before going if they’ll Fuck Up and throw a unit into the water, or just miss a shot. But as you go on, the AI gets NASTY with it. It never really understands the dangers of water though, so that’s a good strategy to play around.</p>

<p>While the concept is super cool and I ended up liking it quite a bit, I cannot deny the game is very slow paced, and maybe overstays its welcome. The strategy element of the world map falls a bit flat, and while the combat is fun, it’s a bit samey. Still, a very fun game.</p>

<p>…Okay, lore time. Inside the game is a hidden message that you can find… “HOW FAR IN THE FUTURE ARE YOU READING THIS?”. Huh, that’s ominous. I wonder what that’s all about? Well, during this time at UFOSoft, there were some rumors around the office. Rumors that these games they were making weren’t actually being sold. They weren’t being released, but instead were being shipped off and sealed somewhere. But for what purpose? We shall see, in time.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 40 - Grimstone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-40.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 40 - Grimstone" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-40.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dVafPbK.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Oh man, we’re finally here. This is my #3 favorite game in the pack. We’ve got #1, Magic Garden, and #2, Divers, and now finally it’s #3. This is Grimstone, which takes place in the same universe as early 1987’s Rail Heist, but it actually started development before Rail Heist did. I mean, it makes sense. Grimstone is, by far, the biggest game UFOSoft EVER made. While some games are longer than others, the 2nd longest is probably around 7 hours. This, the longest, is a 15 hour JRPG.</p>

<p>Grimstone takes place in the state of Lonestar, which is literally Texas that has sunk into the Earth and fallen into Hell. There’s a war here between angels and demons, and the Humans are stuck inbetween. Angels don’t have enough power in Hell to save the Humans, and the Demons are just killing willy nilly. The game is a wild west themed story, with all the trappings and energy that includes. Your characters are cowboys and bandits and the like, and the game starts with them all being called to a meeting by a woman, Lily O’Mule. Lily O’Mule is rumored to worship Satan, but she’s offering drinks, so why not? However, during the meeting, the bar is lit on fire, and everyone dies…</p>

<p>…except an Angel comes by JUST at the perfect moment to save those who were called to the meeting. But the Angel doesn’t have enough power to save all eight. You start the game as this Angel, in the burning building, and you wander to each of the characters, it gives you a brief description, and then you decide if they live or die. You can only choose 4, and you get nothing beyond their descriptions. Things like “a tough looking cowpoke with a sad look behind his eyes”, or “a one armed man with a doctor’s bag”. Using this VERY limited knowledge, you have to build your team.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t0MPbfG.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game I can most compare this to is Final Fantasy 1. You build your team at the start of certain classes, and stick with them the entire time. The game does not hold your hand. You can build a shit-ass team of all thiefs and suffer. Hell, you can start the game with only a single character, and play the whole game like that as a one-class challenge! These aren’t classes like Final Fantasy though, these are full on characters. They have their own personalities, skills, stat spreads, and story beats, each character having one or two story moments you can run into while exploring Lonestar.</p>

<p>You’ve got eight characters:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FJn20gF.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Anne, the independant dancer, who’s a support with skills to buff and heal the posse. She’s a fragile jack of all trades, and can dual wield pistols.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A02fZgi.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Bull, the cowboy, who has no MP or skills to speak of, but can use any gun and is a fucking wall of meat that hits like a truck. I used Bull.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JxiUlcv.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Doc, the one armed sharply dressed doctor. He doesn’t hit well and has terrible defense and stats, and shockingly doesn’t get good healing magic very quickly… he makes up for it with his ability that makes healing items heal MUCH more and get double uses. Healing items are practically useless without him, but AMAZING with him. I used Doc, too.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uQzhWp0.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Lee, the handsome scholar, who is the Blue Mage of the game. He can study enemies to learn their attacks. Be careful though, there’s a maximum he can learn, so don’t choose abilities you’ll never want to use! Very versatile.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5tzaPQq.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Maria, the notorious outlaw with a deadly aim. She’s one of the main protagonists from Rail Heist! Which is sad that you can just let her fucking die in the tavern, like I did, not even knowing it was her. I love Rail Heist ): Oh well, more excuse to play the game again!! Maria is a bit of a rogue who deals deceptive amounts of damage.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/03NIp10.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Pearl, a tall elegant amazon rich girl. She’s a tank who hits like a truck. Very similar to Bull in that wy, but she has some more magic abilities and is well equipped for using heavy gatling gun weapons.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SAV4HkA.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Rufus, the one eyed dog. Lily O’Mule’s dog, Rufus has the unique skill of Dog, which says: “Is a dog. Cannot be controlled.” IS A DOG, CANNOT BE CONTROLLED was a MASSIVE meme of my run, and of course I used Rufus. Rufus is a barkserker, he attacks on his own, and while his accuracy is kinda shit, he hits like a mother fucker. Very glass cannon, but he has very good evade.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sDXbmaN.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Umbra, the mystic. Umbra is special in that she directly learns magic abilities from wild animals, who give her two options to choose from. This means she’s very versatile, and can either be your white mage, red mage, or straight up black mage. Her spells are VERY useful and she is, IMO, the best character hands down. She was the last member of my team.</p>

<p>Huge thanks to Llamakazi for these gifs, which they made for their Steam guide. You can see it here: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3337445448</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w02SBYG.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While this is a turn based JRPG, very similar to Final Fantasy 1, it’s a BIT more than that. The combat has a meter system. If you time your hits correctly, you hit. So you have to be constantly paying attention, no just spamming attack over and over and falling asleep like a lot of classic JRPGs. This is a hardcore NES style RPG, with all the grinding and lack of explanations that implies, but even more intense cause you can’t just use speedup and zone out. If you hit the red, too, you get a critical hit! I missed these, A LOT, which is why Umbra’s magic attacks were so damn useful. I don’t have good timing. It’s also worth noting that while it’s a very FF1 JRPG, it does NOT have random encounters. Enemies appear on the world map, and move as you do. You can kite and outsmart them, if you play your cards right, but if ANY of your four units are hit by an enemy, it’s battle time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BZhwmNC.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I seriously cannot suggest Grimstone enough. While it’s that NES style RPG, it is much more accessible than the other RPG of the pack, Divers, and easier to grasp. The story is actually really nice, with good little story moments for your characters. The setting is REALLY cool and exciting, I LOVE wild west hell. The aesthetics are all fantastic. It’s long, exciting the entire way through, has a lot of potential for replaying, and especially challenge runs. I’ve already heard of a lot of solo dog runs being done. There’s even a code to play a team of FOUR DOGS! Sadly no way to save, which is suffering in a 15 hour RPG. I will eventually do this run, I promise.</p>

<p>10/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 39 - Star Waspir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-39.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 39 - Star Waspir" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-39.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MISQch2.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another Shmup, it’s been a little bit! And this one is a VERY classic top down shmup. Humans have been living immortal thanks to the Blue Flower, a magic flower they found on a planet that is inspired by a painting they have hanging in the UFOSoft Offices. Things were good, until a horde of bugs came out of nowhere and started destroying everything. Now, you have to fight back! Choose one of three ships, each with a different attack pattern and option pattern, and go on a bug hunt!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0UmWblQ.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Star Waspir is a little unfortunate. I think most people don’t like it very much. And uh, I’m sorry to say, I’m kind of most people. I like shmups, I do, I really like shmups. But uh, this one has some issues. It’s JUST a top down shmup with no actual stage gimmicks, think something like 1942. This is fine for the early 80s, but in 1988, it’s very disappointing, especially compared to Caramel Caramel, which had interesting stage gimmicks and concepts, and game out YEARS prior. The most interesting thing is the stage where there are enemies that are like long walls, and you gotta blow up the correct part of the wall before it reaches you from the top. But the rest of the stage gimmicks aren’t anything too special, though they DID try to make the levels unique, with new enemies and hazards. But they failed in some ways. We’ll get to it. There’s also a mechanic where you’ve got two bullet types, one where you tap A, and one where you hold A. Usually holding A does more damage, though you move faster if you just tap, so you need to jump between them for when you’re focusing between bullets or trying to get away fast.</p>

<p>Other than just being a shmup, this game has one gimmick. As you blast away enemies, they drop the letters “E” and “G”, in the pattern of “EGG”. You can spell a few things with this. EEE and GGG give you options, which block shots as well as shoot. This actually fucking sucks ass, My options blocking shots just throws me off, and ends up destroying the fucking options, which is another thing I need to focus on. In game iwth a shit ton of bullets, like this, I am weaving in and out of bullet fire all the time, and I can’t ALSO be careful that my mother fucking options aren’t getting hit too. You can spell “GEE” for a bomb, though honestly this isn’t too helpful from my experience, and you can, of course, spell EGG. Ahh, Petter. EGG will increase your multiplier, and is going to be your #1 goal in this game. Weave through bullet fire, and spell EGG. That’s the game. I actually kinda like the idea?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MuZl7aM.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The concept of a shmup where you’re constantly spelling EGG is one I really like on paper. It adds a nice challenge, more to focus on without like, being too much or annoying, like the options thing is. Its not constant, you don’t HAVE to spell EGG. But it gives you score! And score gives oyu lives! So you want to do it, because you will die, a lot. Star Waspir is, in my personal opinion, the hardest game of the entire 50, and that’s saying a lot, some games are very hard. Rakshasa and Fisthell are no cakewalk, but this beats them both by a wide margin, I think.</p>

<p>The speed is just way, way too much. This game moves too fast. If it was 70-50% slower, I think it’d actually be REALLY interesting? But unless you are a bullet hell genius, you are going to struggle really hard to spell EGG and also dodge bullets and also hit enemies and also keep your options alive and also spell GGG when your options die because they will, all while the game moves at a million miles per hour. And that’s not even mentioning stage 3. Stage 3’s grave sin is a really bad gimmick. This stage is filled with asteroids that you break up as you shoot them. Okay, that’s fine? No big deal? Except the asteroids are a dark purple. On a black background. They look SO MUCH like background scenery that I, and literally everyone I have EVER seen get to them, just fucking runs right into them as they’re trying to dodge the onslaught of bullets. It’s really bad design.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vXF1G8M.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And like I said, I like shmups. I’m not very good at them though, especially not bullet hells. This isn’t a bullet hell, but it’s actually worse, IMO. Cause it’s a LOT of bullets, a WHOLE lot of them, and bullet hells throw out a million bullets, but they are in patterns. You need to be able to read the pattern and quickly dodge them, it’s hard sure, but there’s a pattern. In this game, there’s like, 20% less bullets than a bullet hell, but there’s no real pattern. They fly all over the fucking place and you’ve gotta weave on the fly and it’s way, way too much at the speed the game moves.</p>

<p>So yeah. That’s a LOT to say I think Star Waspir is a really good idea, on paper, but is executed pretty poorly. Actually fun fact, if this game IS too fast for you, you can easily test my theory that it’d be better at 60% speed by changing the FPS of the game. Many modern games tie the speed to the framerate, and this game is no exception. At 30 FPS, the game will move half as fast. While I didn’t rely on this playing it, cause it felt like cheating, if you don’t have those qualms, or just want to see if my theory is correct, you can try it. I HAVE looked to see if it’s better, and yeah, I still think it is. If this game was like 60% as fast, it’d be a 7/10 maybe, cause it looks cool, has a cool concept, and has great music. But the speed and difficulty, on top of the few bad design choices, make this just kinda unfun.</p>

<p>4/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 38 - Rakshasa</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-38.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 38 - Rakshasa" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#38</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-38.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Np50uZ1.png" alt="Rakshasa" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>We are now entering into what I call UFOSoft’s “India Period”. This game takes place in India. The following game has a character who I’m PRETTY sure is supposed to be Indian. Game #41 is directly inspired by an Indian board game. I imagine someone on staff went to India and came back EXTREMELY inspired, which is such a fucking game dev thing, that shit happens ALL THE TIME, I kinda love it being represented here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n3mxrWG.png" alt="Rakshasa" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>God I feel this, buddy. This is me most days.</p>

<p>In Rakshasa you play as Jangi, this Karnov-ass mother fucker, a village chief who’s entire village is slaughtered by demons. Jangi fights back, but is brutally killed as well. However, he finds himself re-awakening as a spirit, clinging to life. He can regain control of his body and fight on, in revenge for his people.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Q6x5Lnr.png" alt="Rakshasa" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Y’all like Ghosts n’ Goblins? Cause that’s EXTREMELY what this game is. No other game is more inspired by something, I think. It’s got the same slow stiff movement, lack of air control, and hard as fuck difficulty. This game is BONKERS hard, top 5 hardest games in the pack, for sure. You can walk and jump, and aim your attack at an angle. You’ll WISH you can aim straight up and down, as things come from those angles and they will fuck your day up. You cAN aim down by jumping, but again, you don’t have much mobility in the air. You can get powerups for your attack, three different weapons: spread shot, a short shotgun burst. Homing, long range but slow homing rings. And fireball, long range, fast, and very damaging. It’s the best, IMO. Charged, it has really good range and width, and missing an enemy with an attack is DEVESTATING, so making sure things land with a charged fireball will save your life a LOT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iuyPtik.png" alt="Rakshasa" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game’s major gimmick is its unique life system. You don’t have lives. Instead, each time you die, you have a chance to return to the land of the living. Rings will spawn, and you float around the screen as a spirit. Grab all the rings, and you’re back! But with each death, more rings will spawn, and more nemies will too, flying around to hit you. And they get faster and more violent with each death. You only need to get hit once for game over. You start the game doing this actually, and it’s very funny that you can start the game and IMMEDIATELY game over if you fucking suck at dodging this purple blob, though you probably won’t.</p>

<p>Rakshasa’s music is sparse, it’s most ambiance and animal sounds. It’s art is good, but a you looking like Karnov is very distracting. Those purple fly enemies are appearing a LOT in recent games. A LOT of bug imagery has been appearing in recent games actually. Huh, I wonder what that’s about. But yeah I really love the Indian flavor here, but I’ve always really liked Indian culture, I had a lot of Indian friends as a kid. The game is hard as fucking nails, but it IS learnable, like any GNG game, and it’s very rewarding once you do.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 37 - Valbrace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-37.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 37 - Valbrace" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#37</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-37.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BkrRevH.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One of the more immediately interesting games at first glance, Valbrace draws players in as soon as they see it exists. How could it not? Valbrace is a hardcore dungeon crawler, a classic 80s design that some people are really REALLY into. I’m pretty into them, myself. Grimrock is wicked, and I love a good blobby. As I played more of this though, parts of it started to kinda fade away and I realized I didn’t like it NEARLY as much as I’d hoped from the outset.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OiI4lHJ.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The lore is EXTREMELY simplistic. Some high fantasy world, you’re a knight who’s going to an evil castle to stop an evil dude, you’re caught by him, stripped of your equipment, and thrown in the depths of the tower. Climb down, fighting enemies and getting equipment, to proceed. The game is a hardcore first person dungeon crawler, akin to something like Wizardry. You’ve got equipment, stats, magic spells, traps, hidden secrets, switches, all the goodies. The game is the same every time though, like those classic 80s crawlers, it is NOT some modern roguelike-esque crawler. It is hand crafted, which means if you get REALLY lost and stuck, a map will work, though honestly it’s not needed.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8FDIeD0.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Perhaps the most interesting thing about this game is its magic system. See, you don’t learn the spells. YOU learn the spells. That make sense? Of course it doesn’t, I needn’t elaborate, though I will anyway, because I love hearing myself talk. You can cast any spell at any time, as long as you have the MP. But YOU, the player, must first learn the glyph for it. By pressing B and then moving around, you draw out a glyph, a mirrored character, and if you correctly put in a spell, boom, you cast it. As you explore, you find glyphs written in walls, hidden in spots, and it makes for some classic, utterly fantastic excuses to pull out pen and paper and write notes, alongside the notes you’ll be taking for maps and things.</p>

<p>On top of that, you’ve got a few other mechanics, like the chairs you’ll find on each floor, which you can use to increase your stats at the cost of essence, basically EXP. And of course there’s the combat, which is over the shoulder and live, kind of like a punchout almost. You can block, weave, dodge, and hit back. This is maybe my biggest gripe with the game. The combat is fine. But the enemies are numerous, and keep spawning, and it gets to be a MASSIVE slog by the end, especially as it spawns groups of like 6 god damn enemies, that are all blocking constantly, hit you through block, and bounce between the front and back row, while also throwing projectiles. It’s fucking annoying, and slows the pace to a crawl. This along the fact that all the late game weapons kinda suck ass, and are slow and awkward to use. I was using the same fucking rapier from floor 1 until I HAD to get rid of it because it was barely doing anything anymore.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Gq9gglx.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Valbrace is super interesting, and I do like it, but it really cooled on me as I was beating it, and I don’t think I ever have reason to go back to it, unlike so many other games here.</p>

<p>Also, from this point on, I probably won’t be elaborating on new members of staff. Why? Well, it’s now 1988, and over the next year, we will see eight total testers appear and disappear, and most of them are not very important, except for maaaybe two of them. One will become a full time tester, Delia Pace, and one will become the receptionist, Faiz Hanek. I’ll also talk about one of them, Sten Murzbach, MUCH later, but for now, no staff changes are particularly important…. except for one.</p>

<p>Valbrace is the final game made by long-time UFO Soft alumni Chiffon Bola. Was she fired? No. On February 29th, a month after her last game, Valbrace, was released, Chiffon Bola went missing. She is never found, and is presumed dead. I will go more into this later, as well, but it’s a pretty dark day for UFOsoft, which must continue on. But dark clouds are on the horizon, and the writing is starting to be seen on the wall by some of the people working there, who are getting uncomfortable with management, and a few… other things, which will become apparent soon.</p>

<p>7/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 36 - Hyper Contender</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-36.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 36 - Hyper Contender" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-36.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ouX6AOu.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Every company needs their fighting game, right? Taking place in the same universe as their other hits, Hyper Contender brings back the Pits of Phogon from Overbold, prolly worked on around the same time tbh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ix2cdCV.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a platformer fighter, less a “traditional” 2D fighter and more something a little unique. And thus better. I’m sorry, I hate the traditional 2D format. Street Fighter 2 was a blight on the creativity of the genre. Thankfully in this universe, that doesn’t seem to have corrupted the industry so every single 2D fighting game doesn’t HAVE to just be a shitty clone of Street Fighter. Instead we get this, and it’s got a lot of creative ideas! Originally it was supposed to have a more traditional health system, actually, which is still in the game as a secret code, but the ring system works very well.</p>

<p>It’s simple. You choose your character, who has a movement ability and an attack ability, as well as a melee atack. Rings spawn throughout the arena every ten seconds or so, and your goal is to get five rings to win. You can beat the rings out of your opponents, and they go flying, bouncing around. It can get EXTREMELY hectic. You can also block, which helps dodge the ranged attacks and stun melee attackers.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2nHZxQO.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The characters are all nicely varied. I’m a big fan of Donkus, myself, because of fucking course I am, but the wolf angel is damn good too. I dunno if it’s BALANCED per-se, I struggled to win with some characters, but thankfully to cherry it you only need to win with half the cast. :3 And that’s it! While I really enjoyed Hyper Contender when I first played it, it seriously dimmed on me with subsequent plays and time away from it. It’s prolly really fun with friends though.</p>

<p>Also every character gets an ending! Here’s an ending from the 2P recolor of Donkus.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/is2qr1U.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Huh that’s some fun world building and certainly not commentary on anything else in particular :)</p>

<p>By the way, I haven’t brought him up yet, but there’s a new staff member at UFO Soft! His name is Winston Nemuru, and while his exact relation to new CEO Tao Nemuru isn’t stated, my guess is he’s his son. I’m sure he was hired for his skills and abilities and certianly not cause of his relation to the new CEO. He’s been sprinkled into the credits of other games, and is in the credits as this one, listed for having the idea for it, alongside KC Levin. Actually, above KC Levin. I’m sure he just came up with more of the concept :)</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 35 - Campanella 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-35.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 35 - Campanella 2" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#35</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-35.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fw3FFUE.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I have a theory I call “8-Bit 2nd Game Syndrome”. It’s that games from the 8-bit era that evolved into series would try something completely different and weird in the 2nd game, which would be completely ignored in future installations. Mario 2 USA. Zelda 2. Metroid 2. All the black sheep of the franchise. Does Campanella 2, UFO Soft’s flagship franchise, suffer the same fate? Well right off the bat, we don’t have Pilot! At Joy Akebi’s suggestion, he has been deplaced by Isabell, his sister, as the main character, because Pilot has been kidnapped and is being kept in a space station, and Isabell the bounty hunter has to go rescue him!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JwecRIO.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game uses the same engine as Campanella, the same fluid smooth UFO movement you know and love, but with a few twists. You can land your UFO and step out of it, very blaster-master style, and enter doors where you travel on foot. Either getting help from people (in rooms that REALLY remind me of Rygar), or a cave with items at the end. Because this isn’t your regular level-based game like Campanella 1, or even an adventure game where you explore. Campanella 2 is a roguelike.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SAnUeMn.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Look at this handsome man</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WgqKuii.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All of the levels are randomly generated. At the end of caves, one in each area, you get one of three powerups to choose from, stuff for your blaster, ship, or health/fuel. There are shops that also sell these upgrades. After two levels in the same world, you go through a cave, fight a boss, and move onto the next world. Each area has a bunch of stars floating in it, and once you get 10, the doors close and the exit opens, and you also summon The Bile Of Old. Stay too long, and more will spawn and fucking destroy you in one hit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wxuFHcS.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, in the 2nd area of every world, you have a Sage who will give you a scroll and tell you which world to go to next. Get to all three of them to get the good ending. This isn’t too hard, though exploring the big open areas in your UFO can be a little intimidating, because fuel is in VERY short supply. Stars replenish it, yes, but if you get too many of them, you can kiss seeing that sage goodbye. If you DO run out of fuel, you can burn coins, but only for a short time. It’s interesting.</p>

<p>When I first played this game, I thought it was the best of the three Campanella games. The most unique, the most creative, the best music. I still think that last bit, but it’s cooled on me a bit, and now it’s my least favorite. It’s still very good, I just like the other two more. It’s maybe not different enough in some ways, and sometimes it feels a little rude, like I’m fucked no matter what. But it’s still a good fun romp, just not as replayable as the other two, despite its roguelike roots.</p>

<p>8.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 28</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/18/OOCY28.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 28" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/18/OOCY28</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/18/OOCY28.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Eta5xbv.png" alt="&quot;Also, there's just one more thing I feel disappointed about. This magic refuses to give me any big doggos.&quot; BIG DOGGOS." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>BIG DOGGOS.</p>

<p>source: laundry cat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="laundry cat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>