<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-20T16:26:11-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 30</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/20/OOCY30.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 30" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/20/OOCY30</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/20/OOCY30.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bUlcT1L.png" alt="A page from a manga that shows a woman stripping to reveal character print underwear and her partner calls her out on her lack of sex appeal. Don't be rude to the big-eared seal!" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Nobody but You</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nobody but You" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 46 - Combatants</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-46.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 46 - Combatants" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50#46</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-46.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pr3rR0q.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Ahhh, this is one of the big ones, and a perfect game to usher us into the End Times. Often times when people play this game on a stream or something, conversations happen about the quality. What’s your favorite game? Your least favorite? There’s a lot of answers for favorite, but for least favorite, there’s usually only three. This one is the most common of those. Combatants is almost universally considered the worst game in the entire pack. And there’s GOOD reason to assume it’s bad on purpose. Let’s talk about it.</p>

<p>It is 1989, the final year, and while up until this point, Tao Nemuru has been funding the games as producer and not much else, this time he’s taking a more direct approach. Mr. Nemuru had a vision for a game, and he wanted it realized, and using his little army of game devs, his little army of ants, he had it created.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pevx3mJ.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Combatants is a top down strategy war simulation game with some RTS elements. You play as the blue ants, who are fighting back against the red ant menace. Red ants are more dangerous, stronger, more numerous. So the odds are not with you. AT ALL. But you have to fight back! You control a little soldier ant, and you can issue commands to nearby ants. You can tell them to stay, follow, or follow their instincts (let the AI take over). You can also order the queen to make workers or soldiers. Soldiers can shoot bullets, but take 2x the food. The AI will always go and collect food, unless it sees an enemy ant, then it will go and attack that ant. When there’s no more food they’ll just beeline straight for the enemy queen to kill it. Once all enemy ants are down, that’s level done, onto the next level.</p>

<p>There’s a few problems. Well #1, the game is slow as shit. It’s awkward, and all the ants move in a weird stilty way. This is bad, but also good, as I’ll explain later. #2 problem: The AI is dumb as shit, and the game is weighted in a way to take advantage of that, against you. Look at that level up there. The blocks are aligned in such a way that often, your workers, if they’re set to going by themselves, will just get stuck on the rocks and not get to the food, because the AI is fucking dumb as shit. And then there’s problem #3: The game is weighted against you in every other possible way. Again, look at the image. Notice the rocks block you, but not the enemy. Notice the enemy has more food on their side. Notice they start with more units. And if that’s not enough, a red ant is literally 2x as strong as a blue ant. For every red ant death, you need to sacrifice 2 blue ants. When an ant meets another, they will scrum like it’s For the Frog the Bell Tolls, and then come out of it weakened or dead.</p>

<p>This game is intentionally unfair. It is built in a way to be frustratingly unfair. There are hard games in this pack, sure, but none weighted this heavily against you. But the problem is, it has to be. Because the AI is so fucking stupid, that if it WEREN’T weighted against you, you’d win instantly, cause you’re not the AI.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jq2AHYH.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If you try and play this game as intended, it is an exercise in frustration. You don’t want to play this game how it wants you to play it. Instead, you need to make your own rules, your own strategies. You need to cheese the fuck out of it.</p>

<p>There are a few cheese strategies that work. You can set up soldiers behind your queen and use her as a meat shield, dragging enemy workers who are holding food to her, where the soldiers hiding in her folds can then snipe them, and boom, free food for more soldiers. You can cheese enemy soldiers, because their AI is terrible, and once they start shooting at something in their range, as long as it stays in their range, they will never turn. You can dodge a shot to the side, then just walk around them and shoot them in the ass, they won’t stop you. You can get enough soldiers to make a Murder Ball and have them clump up and follow you, creating a machine gun of ant murder. And of course there’s the spiders.</p>

<p>I did not find this game very fun, EXCEPT for the spider. The most fun I had in this game was domesticating these things for Ant Murder. You can go to a spider, and it’ll slowly (very VERY slowly, cause everything in this game is slow as fuck) follow you. You can then lead it to the enemy encampment and let it go to town, devouring every enemy spider in its wake. It can eventually be killed, but it can do a LOT of damage as you go off to work on other projects, like other enemy queens, cause very often this game has 2 or 3 enemy queens to your 1.</p>

<p>Is Combatants intentionally bad? I don’t think so. I do know it was very smartly created, they didn’t accidentally make it this way. If the AI was good and it moves fast it’d be impossible to play. So they made it like this, cause it’s the easiest way to handle it. Combatants is problably the worst game in the collection based on quality, but it is certainly not my least favorite. But I’m scoring based on actual quality, so sadly…</p>

<p>3/10</p>

<p>Also work noting, the credits do something weird here. No one is credited by their actual job. Nemuru is the head, Spinzer is the thorax, everyone else is the body. Y’know, the people who actually did the work. Hmm.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ac9bIZY.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Tao Nemuru loves his bugs :)</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 45 - Mini &amp;amp; Max</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-45.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 45 - Mini &amp;amp; Max" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50#45</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-45.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MdFA1qY.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Here it is. One of the big ones. When people talk about this game, it’s usually listed as their favorite. It WAS my favorite, but it’s fallen a bit. Still top 10 for sure. I’ll talk about my reasons why later. But yeah, this is a very VERY beloved game. Let’s find out why.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pmqsCrM.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Taking place in the Partyverse, Amy the Party Girl is throwing yet another party, but she has to watch her kid sister. So she just locks her in the closet instead, alongside her talking pet dog, Max. The two sit there bored for a while, after Mini throws a mirror at the door in frustration. They just need SOMETHING to entertain them. Max suggests that they just become small. Mini is like “We can do that?” and Max is like “well I’ve never tried, but we could explore this whole room as small for a new perspective. Lemme try!” and then he becomes smol. Mini follows suit, and the adventure begins.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tdlzdhV.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mini and Max is a platforming game, kind of like a Mario 2 in some ways. You can run around, picking up and throwing objects and enemies as your primary attack. you hold down to shrink, and up to regrow. There’s not much to do in the room, but it can be used as a kind of level select, as you can grow big and stand near where you wanna go, then shrink again. There’s a BIG WIDE room to explore while tiny, and you are QUITE tiny. But that’s not all… early in the game, you meet someone who can teach you how to get EVEN SMALLER. This is where I slapped my forhead and went “Holy shit HOW BIG IS THIS GAME?!”</p>

<p>It’s big.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jx3Cbr4.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got the upper room, a big wide room while small, all one big level, and then microscopic worlds you can explore. These worlds are a lot more procedurally generated, though apparently it’s the same every time, it’s less polished and specific than the other areas, though there are PLENTY of things to find. Villages of chlorophyte people, little mushroom men called Mol Dolks (another reference to Night Manor, neat!), lamp people who worship the lamp. And like I said, the middle level ain’t no slouch either. It’s filled with bugs waging war on each other and a bunch of toys and things.</p>

<p>The main conceit of the game is that, a while ago, shinies fell to the mini’s world. Little shards shaped like stars, they’re so pretty and shiny, and now capitalism has infested the entire tiny world. Wars are fought and people die for these shinies, and it’s all shown as a Pretty Bad Thing. I wonder what was going on in the dev’s minds as they made this, huh. Money corrupts, don’t it? :) Anyways, that’s all fun and good, but the goal of the game is literally to get shinies. You can explore and find power ups and find fun settings, but the #1 thing you’re doing is getting shinies. There’s no real dungeons, per-se, no major powerups you need to complete major areas. They can HELP, for sure, but you can beat the game kinda bare bones, actually. Just… get the shinies, give them to the king, and he’ll open the door for you. Boom, that’s the game.</p>

<p>Some might view that as reductive, and it kinda is. There’s a LOT to discover and explore, and that’s the main fun of the game. There’s a bunch of things to do to GET those shinies. But once I realized it was JUST shiny hunting I ended up having a “is that it” moment. I feel this concept could have been refined to something really cool, and while what’s here is cool, I can’t help but have that “what could have been” moment. But I seriously am just splitting hairs. Mini and Max is a FANTASTIC game, and honestly worth the 25 dollar admission all by itself. It’s my #6 favorite game, after all. There’s a reason people love it. It’s creative, cute, filled with a bunch of references to earlier games, and the PERFECT late era UFOSoft game to show they weren’t losing their touch yet!</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I view this as the beginning of the end for UFOSoft. Things are starting to get… bleak around the office, and the golden days are over. With one last beautiful swan song, we now enter the Closing Era of UFOSoft. The final five games.</p>

<p>9.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 44 - Pilot’s Quest</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-44.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 44 - Pilot’s Quest" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50#44</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-44.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FvCjTCL.png" alt="PQ" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>AGES ago when I was talking about Party House, I mentioned that it was one of two games that feels less of its time and more like a modern game backdated, cause it’s a genre that didn’t exist until the 2000s. That is, deck builders. This is the other one of those, and this genre is even newer. Y’all like clicker games? Because wowee zowee, this is one of those.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EGRsM3n.png" alt="PQ" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>At some point, it’s never actually stated when, the LX2 was updated to the LX3. The new LX3 had some new features, but key of those was an internal clock. Now you could make games that are ALWAYS running in real time! How to take advantage of that, though? Well, in Pilot Quest, Pilot once again crashes on Zoldath, and must get the pieces of his ship together and gather resources to escape. He has to do this by building up resources slowly, by hitting the Moon Crystal.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lzVfG1R.png" alt="PQ" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You trade Moon Crystals in to the Gumma Tree, who plants seeds and those seeds naturally give you moon crystals. You can also turn those crystals into ingots, and as you play any other game in UFO 50, the plants will generate crystals. You can build houses for villagers, who can use work benches you make to craft ingots naturally. You can befriend a spider who makes silk, you can assign villagers to a research station. All of this will generate resources over time.</p>

<p>This game is half cookie clicker, but the other half is an updated take on Zoldath. I didn’t like Zoldath, and way back when I reviewed it, I said that its ideas would be done much better later. Uh, this is later. The other half of this game is a Zelda-like. You can buy meat from a trader, and that meat will add time to your timer as you enter The Wild Zone. You then have a big open area to explore in the alloted time. It’s prolly a good idea to try and get at least like, 10-15 meat before you explore, so you have like 15 minutes. Damage takes off time, and if you die, you lose everything you find in the wild zone. The wild zone has semi-randomized features, like some paths are open in some playthroughs but not in others. Cave entrances are all randomized. Some caves contain dungeons, others contain NPCs and things.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ab4hYAq.png" alt="PQ" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The music is charming, the graphics re-use old Zoldath assets but I don’t mind, and the idea is super creative. But while it’s really cool, and I enjoyed my first playthrough immensely, it tries to kind of make it a replayable thing by having a mechanic to boost production with subsequent playthroughs. Also if you beat the game without getting the cherry requirement you have to play it ALL again. Luckily I was warned beforehand, most are blindsided. And the game IS fun, but I don’t feel it’s multiple playthroughs fun. Absolutely worth cracking into early in your UFO Quest though, so you can rake in all those moon crystals!</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 43 - Elfazar’s Hat</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-43.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 43 - Elfazar’s Hat" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50#43</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-43.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9TVSEgv.png" alt="Elfazar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>My fifth favorite game, Elfazar’s Hat fills a niche that is sadly ignored. Y’all know Pocky and Rocky? It’s a REALLY cool game pretty beloved. It’s also really, REALLY fucked up. That game is bonkers hard. It is for sickos, and it is mean as a mother fucker. But it’s so cool and charming! What if we took that game and made it… playable?</p>

<p>Insert Elfazar’s Hat. You’re the adorable little animals being used by a cruel magician for his magic tricks. You escape your captivity, and make your way to his evil castle to save your other captive friends! You have two playable characters, a cute bunny girl, and a grumpy looking pidgeon who looks very much like a duck. You’ve got a shoot button, which locks your direction, and a dash button for dodging attacks. You walk through levels that are linear and filled with enemies and traps, blowing everything away, and fight a boss at the end. After 5 levels, you’re done! Simple, short, and very very sweet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Pe3g5p6.png" alt="Elfazar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game, like a lot of shmups, as this IS a shmup IMO, has a power up system. You have cards that drop from enemies and destructibles, and if you get three of a kind, it gives you a power up. You get a weaker version of that with 2 of a kind and another random card, which usually isn’t too useful, but is VERY useful when it comes to life ups.</p>

<p>You’ve got a few different power ups. Purple gives you health and max health. Green improves your shots. Orange gives you a cute little option. Red has you drop bombs as you charge, and blue gives you a shield. These aren’t really as useful, IMO. The shield blocks hits and then breaks, and that can be nice sure, but it feels distracting to me, in the same way the options are in Star Waspir, though not NEARLY as bad. And the bombs are nice I guess, but honestly you don’t wanna get that close to anything.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aPKhKiz.png" alt="Elfazar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The graphics, style, and music, are all FANTASTIC. I especially love level 3’s music, which is a REMIX OF MAGIC GARDEN. THEY DIDN’T FORGET ABOUT MAGIC GARDEN!!! God bless Joy Akebi. Also god bless Joy Akebi, because of course SHE came up with this concept! If there’s a cutesy girly thing, it’s prolly Joy. And it’s also hilarious, because the big bad turns into a spooky eldritch horror in the end. I wonder if Joy had any input in that or if that was someone else.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4l2ecfP.png" alt="Elfazar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I should also mention the bonus levels, where you bounce an option around collecting coins. It’s legit harder than the game. I took me two tries to 1CC this game, I got NO bonus lives from these bonus levels, because it took me <strong>six tries</strong> before I got any. You can get NINE lives from these if you play them well, so it’s useful to do em if you wanna 1CC the game. This stage is also notable because it’s the attract screen, and the bonus stages are well hidden, leading people to go “wtf is this game in the attract screen???”</p>

<p>10/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 42 - Night Manor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-42.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 42 - Night Manor" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#42</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-42.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OktYVCe.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While UFO Soft has toyed with scary, isolating, spooky, and macabre conecpts before, with games like in Divers, or Fist Hell, or hell even Waldorf’s Journey, this game goes far, far beyond that. The only game with a WARNING, this is a straight up horror game. And it makes sense. It’s the first, and only game (unless you count UFO 50 itself) that was lead by longtime developer Greg-Milk. Milk, despite being a massive scaredy cat, is very into horror, and wanted to share his love with a video game. How did he do?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/THWFrxq.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You play as an unnamed woman driving home from a party. The party is said to be thrown by “Amy”, so we can consider this yet another game in the Partyverse! That ends up having some dark connotations for what’s happening just outside town, but then again this town DID have a zombie uprising, so it’s kind of in character. On your drive home, you crash your car into a figure in the road, and blackout. You wake up an unknown time later in a dilapidated house, in what looks like a cell of some kind. This is where your game begins.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N2JbIRe.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Night Manor is a very loving tribute to the Macventure games, three extremely influential and beloved point and click adventure games of the 80s. You’ve PROBABLY heard of Shadowgate, but there’s also Uninvited and Deja Vu. This is very Uninvited energy, personally, but also has a lot of Clocktower and contemporary horror energy. You have to solve puzzles, collect items, and explore this horrorfying house. As you explore, you are also being hunted by the Monster, a scary man in some kind of mask with a knife who chases you if you make too much noise. So like, don’t flush the toilet over and over, he hates that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Q3Wp42t.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I really like point and click adventure games, and this is a good one! But I have a few complaints. Some of the puzzles and items are a LITTLE obscure, not nearly as bad as 80s games could get, but y’know, a little obscure. And there’s the problem of the horror guy. The first time he shows up, it’s genuinely effective. There’s a loud noise, a scary monster, a knife, and your cursor is suddenly shaking and hard to control. You need to try and run for it, while struggling to control your own panic, and it’s a great and fun idea! And you dive into hiding spots throughout the house, and have to do a quick time event mini game to hold your breath as he hunts for you. It’s hard, but rewarding once you survive. And as you explore, these hiding spots get destroyed, and become less numerous, so it becomes more harrowing the further in you get. This all SOUNDS good, and it is good! The first few times! But you HAVE to make noise to proceed, and every time you do, he shows up, and you gotta run away from the puzzle you’re solving to hide in a bush, and do a mini game, and if you fail the mini game, he’ll just kill you and then you wake up in your cell, with all your items, and nothing has changed. There’s NO penalty for dying, at all. Which is good, cause it’s easy to die. But then why even have this mechanic? It’s not BAD, it really just destroys the pacing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/opSV666.png" alt="NightManor" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Milkdud clearly loves his horror. The game has a warning, and it means it. There’s some fucked up imagery and concepts in here. My favorite is the screaming corpse you find in the bathtub. This place is NOT a happy place. Lots of people died here, including dogs and children, so uh, warning. Anyways, Night Manor is a really solid point and click adventure game with great atmosphere, great graphics and style, and fun puzzles that can keep you scratching your head for a while. One of the best games in the collection for sure.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 41 - Lords of Diskonia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-41.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 41 - Lords of Diskonia" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#41</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-41.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KqUQbQS.png" alt="Diskonia" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Inspired by the Indian game of Carrom, Diskonia is a board-game esque strategy game. Pretty unique and cool, I liked it at first glance, but I hear a lot of people don’t like it very much and find it tedious. We’ll see what you think as I explain it, though!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KarpGh1.png" alt="Diskonia" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Lords of Diskonia, you have a campaign of ten levels. Each level has a map, which is just paths, and you and your opponent take turns drawing out a path on these lines. They start very simple, like this, and then get more complex in the later levels. You cannot go backwards on your own line, and if the opponent reaches you or your line, combat happens. There’s powerups and resources to grab on the map, and taverns where you can recruit units for battle.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PEwBIhi.png" alt="Diskonia" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Once your troops meet, battle begins. You two take turns flicking disks at each other, deciding angle and strength of the flick. Units have unique stats and abilities, as well. A knight has good health but bad offense, but is cheap. An archer can only attack traditionally once, but uses a crystal to shoot a tiny powerup arrow. The Ogre hits hard and stuns, but can only attack once, and can’t go very far cause it’s so big. Things like that. There’s also sand mechanics, water traps which will instantly kill any unit, the health wells from Valbrace return, healing and overhealing your units. If you bounce an enemy into your units, like by pincering them, you can deal more damage. Or you can make them bounce into each OTHER, which hurts them both. The game boils down to good aiming, power management, and being able to get good trick shots. It’s a lot like Pool, in that way.</p>

<p>But a lot like computer simulations of Pool, the AI is, of course, infallible. A good AI can make perfect shots every time to hit your units a bunch. So it seems like, in this game, they kind of just roll before going if they’ll Fuck Up and throw a unit into the water, or just miss a shot. But as you go on, the AI gets NASTY with it. It never really understands the dangers of water though, so that’s a good strategy to play around.</p>

<p>While the concept is super cool and I ended up liking it quite a bit, I cannot deny the game is very slow paced, and maybe overstays its welcome. The strategy element of the world map falls a bit flat, and while the combat is fun, it’s a bit samey. Still, a very fun game.</p>

<p>…Okay, lore time. Inside the game is a hidden message that you can find… “HOW FAR IN THE FUTURE ARE YOU READING THIS?”. Huh, that’s ominous. I wonder what that’s all about? Well, during this time at UFOSoft, there were some rumors around the office. Rumors that these games they were making weren’t actually being sold. They weren’t being released, but instead were being shipped off and sealed somewhere. But for what purpose? We shall see, in time.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 40 - Grimstone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-40.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 40 - Grimstone" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-40.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dVafPbK.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Oh man, we’re finally here. This is my #3 favorite game in the pack. We’ve got #1, Magic Garden, and #2, Divers, and now finally it’s #3. This is Grimstone, which takes place in the same universe as early 1987’s Rail Heist, but it actually started development before Rail Heist did. I mean, it makes sense. Grimstone is, by far, the biggest game UFOSoft EVER made. While some games are longer than others, the 2nd longest is probably around 7 hours. This, the longest, is a 15 hour JRPG.</p>

<p>Grimstone takes place in the state of Lonestar, which is literally Texas that has sunk into the Earth and fallen into Hell. There’s a war here between angels and demons, and the Humans are stuck inbetween. Angels don’t have enough power in Hell to save the Humans, and the Demons are just killing willy nilly. The game is a wild west themed story, with all the trappings and energy that includes. Your characters are cowboys and bandits and the like, and the game starts with them all being called to a meeting by a woman, Lily O’Mule. Lily O’Mule is rumored to worship Satan, but she’s offering drinks, so why not? However, during the meeting, the bar is lit on fire, and everyone dies…</p>

<p>…except an Angel comes by JUST at the perfect moment to save those who were called to the meeting. But the Angel doesn’t have enough power to save all eight. You start the game as this Angel, in the burning building, and you wander to each of the characters, it gives you a brief description, and then you decide if they live or die. You can only choose 4, and you get nothing beyond their descriptions. Things like “a tough looking cowpoke with a sad look behind his eyes”, or “a one armed man with a doctor’s bag”. Using this VERY limited knowledge, you have to build your team.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t0MPbfG.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game I can most compare this to is Final Fantasy 1. You build your team at the start of certain classes, and stick with them the entire time. The game does not hold your hand. You can build a shit-ass team of all thiefs and suffer. Hell, you can start the game with only a single character, and play the whole game like that as a one-class challenge! These aren’t classes like Final Fantasy though, these are full on characters. They have their own personalities, skills, stat spreads, and story beats, each character having one or two story moments you can run into while exploring Lonestar.</p>

<p>You’ve got eight characters:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FJn20gF.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Anne, the independant dancer, who’s a support with skills to buff and heal the posse. She’s a fragile jack of all trades, and can dual wield pistols.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A02fZgi.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Bull, the cowboy, who has no MP or skills to speak of, but can use any gun and is a fucking wall of meat that hits like a truck. I used Bull.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JxiUlcv.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Doc, the one armed sharply dressed doctor. He doesn’t hit well and has terrible defense and stats, and shockingly doesn’t get good healing magic very quickly… he makes up for it with his ability that makes healing items heal MUCH more and get double uses. Healing items are practically useless without him, but AMAZING with him. I used Doc, too.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uQzhWp0.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Lee, the handsome scholar, who is the Blue Mage of the game. He can study enemies to learn their attacks. Be careful though, there’s a maximum he can learn, so don’t choose abilities you’ll never want to use! Very versatile.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5tzaPQq.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Maria, the notorious outlaw with a deadly aim. She’s one of the main protagonists from Rail Heist! Which is sad that you can just let her fucking die in the tavern, like I did, not even knowing it was her. I love Rail Heist ): Oh well, more excuse to play the game again!! Maria is a bit of a rogue who deals deceptive amounts of damage.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/03NIp10.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Pearl, a tall elegant amazon rich girl. She’s a tank who hits like a truck. Very similar to Bull in that wy, but she has some more magic abilities and is well equipped for using heavy gatling gun weapons.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SAV4HkA.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Rufus, the one eyed dog. Lily O’Mule’s dog, Rufus has the unique skill of Dog, which says: “Is a dog. Cannot be controlled.” IS A DOG, CANNOT BE CONTROLLED was a MASSIVE meme of my run, and of course I used Rufus. Rufus is a barkserker, he attacks on his own, and while his accuracy is kinda shit, he hits like a mother fucker. Very glass cannon, but he has very good evade.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sDXbmaN.gif" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" />
Umbra, the mystic. Umbra is special in that she directly learns magic abilities from wild animals, who give her two options to choose from. This means she’s very versatile, and can either be your white mage, red mage, or straight up black mage. Her spells are VERY useful and she is, IMO, the best character hands down. She was the last member of my team.</p>

<p>Huge thanks to Llamakazi for these gifs, which they made for their Steam guide. You can see it here: https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3337445448</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w02SBYG.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While this is a turn based JRPG, very similar to Final Fantasy 1, it’s a BIT more than that. The combat has a meter system. If you time your hits correctly, you hit. So you have to be constantly paying attention, no just spamming attack over and over and falling asleep like a lot of classic JRPGs. This is a hardcore NES style RPG, with all the grinding and lack of explanations that implies, but even more intense cause you can’t just use speedup and zone out. If you hit the red, too, you get a critical hit! I missed these, A LOT, which is why Umbra’s magic attacks were so damn useful. I don’t have good timing. It’s also worth noting that while it’s a very FF1 JRPG, it does NOT have random encounters. Enemies appear on the world map, and move as you do. You can kite and outsmart them, if you play your cards right, but if ANY of your four units are hit by an enemy, it’s battle time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BZhwmNC.png" alt="Grimstone" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I seriously cannot suggest Grimstone enough. While it’s that NES style RPG, it is much more accessible than the other RPG of the pack, Divers, and easier to grasp. The story is actually really nice, with good little story moments for your characters. The setting is REALLY cool and exciting, I LOVE wild west hell. The aesthetics are all fantastic. It’s long, exciting the entire way through, has a lot of potential for replaying, and especially challenge runs. I’ve already heard of a lot of solo dog runs being done. There’s even a code to play a team of FOUR DOGS! Sadly no way to save, which is suffering in a 15 hour RPG. I will eventually do this run, I promise.</p>

<p>10/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 39 - Star Waspir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-39.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 39 - Star Waspir" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50#39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/19/UFO50-39.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MISQch2.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another Shmup, it’s been a little bit! And this one is a VERY classic top down shmup. Humans have been living immortal thanks to the Blue Flower, a magic flower they found on a planet that is inspired by a painting they have hanging in the UFOSoft Offices. Things were good, until a horde of bugs came out of nowhere and started destroying everything. Now, you have to fight back! Choose one of three ships, each with a different attack pattern and option pattern, and go on a bug hunt!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0UmWblQ.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Star Waspir is a little unfortunate. I think most people don’t like it very much. And uh, I’m sorry to say, I’m kind of most people. I like shmups, I do, I really like shmups. But uh, this one has some issues. It’s JUST a top down shmup with no actual stage gimmicks, think something like 1942. This is fine for the early 80s, but in 1988, it’s very disappointing, especially compared to Caramel Caramel, which had interesting stage gimmicks and concepts, and game out YEARS prior. The most interesting thing is the stage where there are enemies that are like long walls, and you gotta blow up the correct part of the wall before it reaches you from the top. But the rest of the stage gimmicks aren’t anything too special, though they DID try to make the levels unique, with new enemies and hazards. But they failed in some ways. We’ll get to it. There’s also a mechanic where you’ve got two bullet types, one where you tap A, and one where you hold A. Usually holding A does more damage, though you move faster if you just tap, so you need to jump between them for when you’re focusing between bullets or trying to get away fast.</p>

<p>Other than just being a shmup, this game has one gimmick. As you blast away enemies, they drop the letters “E” and “G”, in the pattern of “EGG”. You can spell a few things with this. EEE and GGG give you options, which block shots as well as shoot. This actually fucking sucks ass, My options blocking shots just throws me off, and ends up destroying the fucking options, which is another thing I need to focus on. In game iwth a shit ton of bullets, like this, I am weaving in and out of bullet fire all the time, and I can’t ALSO be careful that my mother fucking options aren’t getting hit too. You can spell “GEE” for a bomb, though honestly this isn’t too helpful from my experience, and you can, of course, spell EGG. Ahh, Petter. EGG will increase your multiplier, and is going to be your #1 goal in this game. Weave through bullet fire, and spell EGG. That’s the game. I actually kinda like the idea?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MuZl7aM.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The concept of a shmup where you’re constantly spelling EGG is one I really like on paper. It adds a nice challenge, more to focus on without like, being too much or annoying, like the options thing is. Its not constant, you don’t HAVE to spell EGG. But it gives you score! And score gives oyu lives! So you want to do it, because you will die, a lot. Star Waspir is, in my personal opinion, the hardest game of the entire 50, and that’s saying a lot, some games are very hard. Rakshasa and Fisthell are no cakewalk, but this beats them both by a wide margin, I think.</p>

<p>The speed is just way, way too much. This game moves too fast. If it was 70-50% slower, I think it’d actually be REALLY interesting? But unless you are a bullet hell genius, you are going to struggle really hard to spell EGG and also dodge bullets and also hit enemies and also keep your options alive and also spell GGG when your options die because they will, all while the game moves at a million miles per hour. And that’s not even mentioning stage 3. Stage 3’s grave sin is a really bad gimmick. This stage is filled with asteroids that you break up as you shoot them. Okay, that’s fine? No big deal? Except the asteroids are a dark purple. On a black background. They look SO MUCH like background scenery that I, and literally everyone I have EVER seen get to them, just fucking runs right into them as they’re trying to dodge the onslaught of bullets. It’s really bad design.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vXF1G8M.png" alt="StarWaspir" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And like I said, I like shmups. I’m not very good at them though, especially not bullet hells. This isn’t a bullet hell, but it’s actually worse, IMO. Cause it’s a LOT of bullets, a WHOLE lot of them, and bullet hells throw out a million bullets, but they are in patterns. You need to be able to read the pattern and quickly dodge them, it’s hard sure, but there’s a pattern. In this game, there’s like, 20% less bullets than a bullet hell, but there’s no real pattern. They fly all over the fucking place and you’ve gotta weave on the fly and it’s way, way too much at the speed the game moves.</p>

<p>So yeah. That’s a LOT to say I think Star Waspir is a really good idea, on paper, but is executed pretty poorly. Actually fun fact, if this game IS too fast for you, you can easily test my theory that it’d be better at 60% speed by changing the FPS of the game. Many modern games tie the speed to the framerate, and this game is no exception. At 30 FPS, the game will move half as fast. While I didn’t rely on this playing it, cause it felt like cheating, if you don’t have those qualms, or just want to see if my theory is correct, you can try it. I HAVE looked to see if it’s better, and yeah, I still think it is. If this game was like 60% as fast, it’d be a 7/10 maybe, cause it looks cool, has a cool concept, and has great music. But the speed and difficulty, on top of the few bad design choices, make this just kinda unfun.</p>

<p>4/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 29</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/19/OOCY29.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 29" /><published>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/19/OOCY29</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/19/OOCY29.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/02RCq2W.png" alt="&quot;It's not because I like boo- breasts! I'm groping you because I like you, Subaru! It's not for any perverted reason whatsoever!!" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>For the LIGHTEST bit of context, this is very consensual.</p>

<p>source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>