<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-11T12:02:42-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 121</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/11/OOCY121.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 121" /><published>2025-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/11/OOCY121</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/11/OOCY121.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bac0KLy.png" alt="Angry woman is at a bar thinking to herself. 'Whats so wonderful about het couples... Whats so great about them?! Contributing to the country's birthrate?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sevendays</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sevendays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 16-20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/09/LizstartrekDS97-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 16-20" /><published>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/09/LizstartrekDS97-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/09/LizstartrekDS97-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Vf2hKzS.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Inter Arma Enim Silent Leges</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j3joEyT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Rolumans are still a… tough group to get along with. But Bashir is going to a conference on Romulus! Hopefully he can help bridge that gap between their cultures! Garrak thinks Bashir is a dumb optimist. Bashir wakes up in the middle of the night with a bad feeling though, turns on the lights, and finds… SLOAN!</p>

<p>Remember Section 31? Star Trek fans are unhappy that THEY remember Section 31, considering the recent shit that came out. Well, Bashir is technically associated with Section 31. Section 31 are the Secret Police, who do what they want. They’re awful. And they decided Bashir is part of the team now, even though he’s disgusted by them. But Sloan is like “oh you’ll work for us. You are a man who loves secrets.” He’s basically saying “You love James Bond movies, so you’d be great as a spy”. Anyways, Bashir is basically going to be a double agent, working with Admiral Ross, the only good Admiral we’ve ever met, against Sloan.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dgSb9hr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sloan explains to Bashir what he’s there for. There’s a Romulan politican who is likely to be promoted soon, a Tal-Shiar operative named Koval. He’s also BIG anti-Earth. But they think he might have a disease. So they want to accelerate the disease. Not NOW, of course, this is just here to try and figure more info out. After they find this out, Ross is like “okay I’m arresting him. He also probably has an accomplice, so be on the look out” and then is suddenly thrown in the med bay with a sudden case of Being Sick. Hmm. Sus.</p>

<p>Bashir has no one else to turn to. He thinks a senator will be killed, even if that would help Earth, he can’t let that happen. He’ll do the right thing. So he goes to Cretak. Cretak was the Romulan working with DS9, she’s a patriot but a nice enough woman. She’s the only one he can trust. But they’re caught, and Koval tortures Bashir to get info on who he’s working with. He and Cretak are then dragged before the council, and the trial starts.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F1aK3Ry.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Bashir comes clean and explains that Section 31 is trying to kill them. It might destroy their alliance, but it’s the right thing. Koval is like “Ahhh but there’s more to the story”, and brings out Sloan. He then explains that Section 31 is not real, and does not exist. It’s a fake plan made up by Sloan, who’s here for revenge to kill Koval for killing his mentor. Sloan is shot and killed, and then Cretak is censured and taken away for working with Federation intelligence and betraying Romulus. Bashir is allowed to go, he was basically just a sap in all this.</p>

<p>Something doesn’t sit well with Bashir though, and he realizes what’s wrong. He goes to Admiral Ross, and tells him he knows, and Ross spills his guts. I KNEW there were no good Admirals! It was all set up. Koval is their mole, and they were there all along to get Cretak fired, because they felt she’d turn on the Federation if it helped Romulus. And Sloan was teleported out just in time. Ross justifies himself by quoting Ciciero. Hey, that’s cool, remind me what happened to Ciciero again???</p>

<p>Sloan comes to gloat at Bashir, and thank him for doing EXACTLY what he knew he’d do. The right thing. Because that’s actually waht they wanted out of him the entire time. “Section 31 is here to protect people like you.” And it kind of… drowns Bashir in the sorrow of it all. And the episode ends.</p>

<p>Good episode. Kinda depressing, in a good way. I still don’t mind the Section 31 stuff… depending how it ends.</p>

<p><strong>Penumbra</strong> - DS9
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Utcnerp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Sisko and his girlfriend, Kasidy, having a sweet talk about what he’ll do when he retires. He got some land on Bajor, and intends to retire there. It’s cute. Meanwhile, turns out Worf is missing after his ship went down. Oh, that’s a swing.</p>

<p>The Defiant gives up the search. Things are too dangerous, and they aren’t even sure if he made it off his ship before it exploded. Sisko calls Ezri specifically to tell her this. I dunno why, she’s not his wife. She goes to Worf’s room, and has a bunch of flash backs to Jadzia episodes, and declares that she will find him. She steals a Runabout, and Sisko basically just LETS her go, which everyone acknowledges means she’ll prolly just die, cause a Runabout in Dominion space is a Bad Idea.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/D2p4mot.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a cute scene with Sisko and Casidy, and Sisko proposes to her. It’s adorable. It then jumps to Ezri about to vomit as she is flung around the violent storms of the Badlands. This episode has a tone problem. She finds Worf, and he’s a little shit about it, as he usually is. It’s VERY awkward. Ezri keeps trying to walk and be pleasant and Worf is, as usual, a little shit. They’re then caught and attacked, and crash land on a planet. Well now they have PLENTY of time to talk!</p>

<p>Everyone finds out Sisko is getting married, and all of the Bajorans on teh station are super exicted. They have kids asking if they can be a part of it. It’s gonna be the BIGGEST wedding! Welp, that IMMEDIATELY complicates things. That’s what you get for marrying Space Jesus, Kasidy.</p>

<p>Ezri and Worf get into a yelling match. Worf is being a little shit, I’m taking Ezri’s side here. He calls her a slur and then when she tries to slap him he grabs her and kisses her. I literally, out loud, went “What the FUCK?!”. They fuck, it’s EXTREMELY sudden, and then some Breen capture them and drag them away in a ship.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1Nny6UE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Also Gul Dukat is back and has a meeting with Damar! I’m sure that’ll be good. He asks Damar for one last favor, and then we find out he had some surgery to make himself look like a Bajoran. God, this is UNCANNY.</p>

<p>Sisko is given a vision by the Prophets, with his mom! Well, his ‘mom’. If you remmeber, his mom was possessed by a Prophet, so that they could make The Sisko be born. She tells him “Uh no, you’re not supposed to be married. That’s not your fate. Now go do what we want you to do.” Sisko is angry at first but then he’s like “Mommy :o” and they have a moment.</p>

<p>And then the episode ends. The rest of the episodes are gonna be pretty interconnected from here on out!</p>

<p><strong>‘Til Death Do Us Part</strong> - DS9
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X6e413w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kai Winn comes to congratulate Sisko on his marriage, but he’s like “I was told not to marry and I’m unsure what to do. The Prophets never explain themselves well”. She once again responds with “Well they’ve never spoken to me, I wouldn’t know.” WHY. IS. THIS. WOMAN. POPE?</p>

<p>Well, she does in fact get a message from the Prophets!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WvObvB7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She gets a vision, and they tell her EXACTLY what she’d want them to say. You are the only one who can save Bajor. You will help us. The Sisko has faulted. You are our last hope. They tell her that a messenger will come to help her. Ohhh man. EXACTLY what she needed to hear.</p>

<p>Sisko tells Kasidy he can’t marry her and she gets angry and storms out. Dog, my man. Just remind her that the last time you iognored their warnings, Dax died. Kasidy, do you want Dax to die AGAIN? WE’RE RUNNING OUT OF DAXES, KASIDY. Next time it’ll be a man, and the fandom will RIOT, KASIDY.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JlVmX0A.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gul Dukat comes, calling himself Anjohl. He’s just a simple farmer, here to ask Kai Winn for help. And, much like earlier, they say exactly what she wnats to hear. EXACTLY. Small code words that make her go “oh it’s just like that obscure prophecy I read about and I can insert myself into!” And he tells a fake story about how he was saved, and she’s like “Oh I did that! I rerouted the ship that would have killed you, during the occupation!” They are playing her like a fucking FIDDLE, it’s BRILLIANT!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/latstfW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then they fuuuuuck</p>

<p>The Breen are doing some brain stuff to Worf and Dax, and in Dax’s confusion she declares she loves Julian, and it makes Worf angry. This is stupid. When she wakes up he’s pissy and says she dishonors all of them. Yeah, Dax. You dishonor Bashir, can’t you TELL he’s gay? Him and Garak? THey hold hands every morning at their breakfasts.</p>

<p>Sisko decides to marry anyway. Kira is annoyed, cause she knows what it’ll mean, but everyone lets him do it anyway, it’s his mistake to make. I’m sure NO bad side effects will happen because of this, at all.</p>

<p>The Breen beam Worf and Dax over, and Weyoun announces that the Dominion and the Breen are now allied. That’ll be good, I’m sure.</p>

<p>Most of this was mid but I’ve really been enjoying the Kai stuff.</p>

<p><strong>Strange Bedfellows</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Nu9Aa6a.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Apparently the name of a high ranking Breen officer is “Thot”. They make the hos high ranking military officials. As it should be. Goo girl Breen tho Damar is ENRAGED by this Breen alliance treaty, because it appears to involve giving up a lot of Cardassian territory if they enter the war and help. Well if you can’t trust the fascist Dominion to ACTUALLY protect you and your people. To be fair to Damar, he did not ally with the Dominion. Damar is a VERY interesting antagonist, because he’s the wrong person at the wrong place at the wrong time. He’s a drunk incompetent toady who fell into leadership because of where he was and now he has to sit with it and it EATS at him. It’s like if Starscream actually became the leader of the Decepticons. What do you even do then???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/et9bX7i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I agree Dax, I wish Worf would shut the fuck up. Weyoun comes in and taunts them, because they’ll die in two days if they don’t give him military secrets. Worf breaks his neck. Weyoun died instantly. It is hilarious. Damar especially seems to think so. He’s SO amused he stops the guards from killing Worf, and laughs his ass off, and lets them be for the day, but not before telling them they’ll be executed in two days if they don’t give them what they want.</p>

<p>Weyoun 8 shows up, and is like “they haven’t decided to cooperate?” and Damar goes “No. Maybe you should talk to Worf again!” before laughing his ass off. God, that’s so fucking funny. He gets angry when he learns that the Breen are getting access to all of Cardassia’s military, though. Something rotten in the state of Cardassia.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QJ9I2ZP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The truth come out. Well, part of it. Winn realizes she’s working for the Pah Wraiths and NOT the Prophets now. She has a crisis of faith, and begs the Prophets to talk to her and tell her what to do. They don’t. I do wonder how much could be done to save the galaxy if they had just spoken to her ONCE and asked her to chill the fuck out. But they continue to ignore her. She’s like “WHAT HAVE I DONE TO BE FORSAKEN? AM I NOT WORTHY OF YOUR LOVE?” I dunno, maybe it was when you <strong><em>bombed a fucking school full of children in the first season</em></strong>. She goes to Kira, of all people, like “I am having a crisis of faith what can I do?” and she’s like “Well maybe they want nothing to do with you because you’ve given in to temptations of power” “Yes, I have done that” “So don’t do that anymore.” “Yes, you’re right.” “Good, I’m glad you’re stepping down as Kai.” “What? Why would I do that?” BITCH. ARE YOU SO FUCKING BLIND.</p>

<p>This is such a good view on fundamentalist religious fuckheads.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t4pTgLi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>More Cardassians die every day. “How many more sacrifices will my people be asked to make?” “YOUR people? We all serve the founders.” This is the final straw. Damar has been a laughing stock, and all he’s done is drown in alcohol. That changes. That changes now.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Vf2hKzS.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Great line. I hate this, but like, I hate it cause of how it makes Worf act. It’s well written if you realize Worf is a shithead and aren’t supposed to feel for him at all, but I LOVED TNG Worf. DS9 Worf fucking blows. Every time he’s happy with Ezri and the things she does and says, she’s Jadzia. Whenever he’s angry with her, she’s Ezri. It’s like a fucked up version of the Virgin Whore complex. Eventually though they come to a realization and talk it out, which is good, but the bad taste in my mouth is still there.</p>

<p>As they’re being taken away to be executed, Damar, kills the guards and sends them on the way. But in payment, they must bring a message to the Federation, that they have an ally on Cardassia. The revolution is beginning. He’s not OUT about it yet, but he’s working to undermine them, piece by piece. When the Founder calls Weyoun 8 to be talked to about the prisoners escaping, Damar is like “I’m sure she’ll understand. If not, I look forward to meeting Weyoun 9.” God he’s so fucking funny.</p>

<p>The episode ends with Kai Winn agreeing to become Anti-Pope for the Pah Wraiths. Anything to hold power, huh Winn?</p>

<p>This episode had a fun theme with multiple characters changing sides. As things reach their breaking points, what will you do to stand true of your ideals? Will you stand by them, or will you break? Damar stood true. Winn will not.</p>

<p><strong>Strange Bedfellows</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x9di9Bg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with the Breen attacking Earth, blasting the shit out LA. Things are ramping up. Weyoun congratulates the Breen on their brash attacks, but Damar warns them. They once praised the Cardassians as well. Now they blame them for not winning them the war sooner. If it goes on… the Breen might be next on the chopping block.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8WzIdj8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kasidy burns some of Sisko’s food, some peppers he’s been growing for months, and he’s dismayed about it. Maybe this is the endless sorrow the prophets warned him about.</p>

<p>Damar has a meeting with one of his oldest friends and trusted military officials. They’re planning a rebellion. His ally, Gul Rusot, laments that they’re hiding and sneaking in this war. What are they, Romulans? To me, they feel less like Romulans. I think they seem more like…… Bajorans :3</p>

<p>We jump between a few minor things. Trouble in paradise with Sisko and Kasidy. Kai Winn taking the necronomicom and studying it, even though it appears it have no words written inside. Worf and Ezri watch and comment on Julian, since Ezri is into him now. I like Worf FAR more as a sassy wingman than as an annoying jealous dickstick.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u8S7bRE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Defiant goes into a ship to try and stop the Breen assault. It ends poorly. They have to flee the Defiant, and we watch it explode. RIP to the Defiant. It was basically just a gun with an engine, but it was OUR gun with an engine. The Female Changeling declares that they should let the escape pods leave, because then they’ll be frightened and not fight back. Ah yes, the Tarkin Maneuver. That always works! Let’s let Sisko live, that’s a GREAT IDEA!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOFzMwp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Kai’s servant, Solbor, finds out through a blood test that Dukat is actually Dukat. And he tells Kai Winn, who is DISGUSTED by the fact that she let THAT tap it. Fair response. But then when Solbor is like “Wait you’re working with the PAH WRAITHS?! YOU’RE NUTS”, he’s stabbed. His blood activates the Necronomicon and shows ancient texts. And that call to evil… breaks her further. She can’t even resist GUL DUKAT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t412TV2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I am going to be using this image for a long time.</p>

<p>When everything looks bad, a message comes across all the screens. Damar announces the rebellion of Cardassia. They attacked their first target, the cloning facilities, so NO MORE WEYOUNS. We’re on our Last Weyoun. Damar is possibly the LAST HOPE for the Alpha Quadrant. We might be doomed.</p>

<p>I’ve really liked these past two episodes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievements Unmastered 2 - Final Fantasy 7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/09/RAUM2-FF7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievements Unmastered 2 - Final Fantasy 7" /><published>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/09/RAUM2-FF7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/09/RAUM2-FF7.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V6fo0Rc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I’ve been doing all the sets for each of the Final Fantasy games, but I’ve been dreading FF7. Not because of the game. I’d never beaten it and have wanted to replay it for years. No, its cause the RA set is actually just bad. It’s a bad set. I try not to use words like that for volunteer work, but there’s a reason I did not master this game, and never will.</p>

<p>But I DID still play it, and thats what matters, so let’s talk about Final Fantasy 7. This review WILL talk about spoilers to one of the most popular games of all time, which you’ve probably played. You’ve been warned.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wceg0SG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Final Fantasy 7 is the 7th FF game, obviously, unless you ignore those ones that don’t count, AND if you ignore the fact that it’s actually the fourth that came out here. Ohhh to be a Final Fantasy fan back then. Either way, this is the Big One. The series was popular before this, but this was THE big one. It was fucking MASSIVE. It still IS massive. There’s a reason Squeenix lit a billion dollars on fire to make a sequel, it’s cause it’s extremely beloved. Maybe the most beloved game I’ve ever even attempted to review. Other games have more rabid fan bases, but maybe none as rabid and LARGE. What are my thoughts on it? Well, we’ll see…</p>

<p>In FF7, you play as Cloud, a soldier and ex-SOLDIER. SOLDIER are like, a super soldier squad for Shinra, a mega corporation that basically rules the world. Unlike every Final Fantasy game before it, which were all high fantasy, FF7 is cyber punk-ish. It’s grungy, dark, and rusty. The game starts in Midgar, a megacity with shitty slums and violent megacorporations. It’s a significant departure. Cloud has been hired by Avalanche, an eco terrorist cell. Like, literal eco terrorists. Its leader, Barret, has hired you to blow up a reactor, because that reactor runs on Mako, which is the life force of the planet. Yes, this game has a VERY heavy environmental theme. A thing I feel very strongly about, personally.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EfuArA8.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The environmental message is strong, but it feels a bit mealy mouthed in parts. In the end, Barret realizes that blowing up that reactor was WRONG, because uh, violence solves nothing. Anyways Cloud let’s go kill this guy, Sephiroth. It could be a stronger message, tbh.</p>

<p>Let’s talk Sephiroth. Sephiroth is the “villain” of the game. Kind of. He’s an ex-SOLDIER too, the best of the best, but he disappeared a few years ago when he and Cloud went on a mission to Cloud’s home town. In truth, Cloud fought him, but barely remembers anything of it, because his memory is spotty. His friend Tifa was there too, but she’s cagey about the whole thing. But see, the thing is, Sephiroth is not really the villain of this game. We basically see Sephiroth one time in the whole game, in the flashback where we see him go insane and kill Cloud’s home town. Then he’s killed and thrown to his death. Every other Sephiroth we see is a meat virus called Jenovah masquerading as him, or some clones of him that are broken and unfinished. The REAL villain of this game is either Jenovah, who’s a barely sentient alien virus, or Hojo, who’s the kind of mad scientist dumbass who thinks that a human-like species and a dog should fuck, or that the next stage of human evolution is A Pile Of Meat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yvCMSxZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Honestly? I don’t like Sephiroth. I find him boring. And that’s ignoring the fact we barely see him, even if we consider ALL Sephiroths we see as Sephiroth, as one unified Will, he’s not interesting. He’s a muahaha I will take over the world villain in a very boring way. He’s not as austentatious as Ex-Death, nor as fun as Kefka. He’s taken as this serious cool badass bishonen and then he does silly stupid stuff, but it doesn’t hit like Kefka’s silly stupid stuff, because you don’t think it’s SUPPOSED to be silly and stupid. But it is.  I genuinely do not get why people fell in love with him so much. Like, I do, he looks</p>

<p>The best part about Sephiroth is the stuff AROUND him more than him. And by that I mean his connections to Cloud. See, Cloud isn’t who he thinks he is. The entire game, lies are CONSTANTLY being fed to you, both by Cloud’s own fallible memories, tampered by drugs and experiments, and by ‘Sephiroth’ planting lies in his head and manipulating him through their Jenovah connection, cause Cloud has Jenovah cells in him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Uxra15G.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Though that’s an important thing about Final Fantasy 7. Those cool moments with Cloud being unsure who he is, and of the game lying to you? It’s hard to follow, because of just the NATURE of that, and also the game kind of being poorly written/translated in parts. It can be VERY hard to follow what’s going on, you basically need someone reading a wiki page, and that wiki page is using information from future FF7 games to explain what the fuck is going on. It’s hard to follow to a fault. And the translation is pretty infamously rough. THey did their best. It was one dude’s work, and he was no Ted Woolsey. But This Guy ARE Sick. Also the r-slur is used, which is fucking terrible.</p>

<p>How is the gameplay? It’s good! It’s typical Final Fantasy, though with a few twists. All your characters are KIND of blank slates. The way it works is, they’re kind of blank slates with unique limit breaks and weapons, but they can be augmented with Materia, which is solified Mako that grants magic. It’s an evolution of FF6’s Esper system, and it’s done MOSTLY well, but by the end I found it very unwieldly. If you want to use it effectively, it takes a LOT of AP grinding. If you don’t want to grind, you can’t use it very well, or at all. And you don’t NEED to? But it makes it WAY easier.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SHwJeRH.gif" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You may be thinking I’ve been very harsh on this game. And I have been. I actually like it quite a bit, and there’s a lot to like. I like all of the characters. Cait Sith and Yuffie fall a bit more flat to me, and Red XIII feels so poorly utilized, his ONE major plot point is the worst part of the game. Bugenhagen lied to Red XIII about his dad for years, AS A JOKE. But the rest of them are great. Ilike Cloud, he’s SO different form how people pretend he is. They pretend he’s a stoic badass emo boy. No, that’s Squall. Cloud is a massive dork who loves his friends. Barret is cool as hell. Aerith is cute AND a horrible Goblin, which I appreciate. Cid can be awful but in a way I kinda love. And of course Tifa is perfect, and my wife.</p>

<p>The thing about the story and characters is that they are good, but there are a lot of lulls. The start of the game is by FAR the best part. The first like 6-7 hours are Midgar, and those are very, VERY good. Once you get out of Midgar the game slooooowly slumps, and it never really improves. All the fun scenes and interesting story are replaced for a while by weird gimmick mini games, which this game fucking LOVES, and they are VERY bad for pacing and vibes.</p>

<p>The most famous scene of the entire game, a major character death, is IMMEDIATELY followed up by Cloud doing a fucking snowboarding mini game segment, which is SUCH a tonal whiplash. Like, what the fuck.</p>

<p>A lot of this game astounded me, because I had no idea why they designed things they way they designed. As I delved deeper, into specific mechanics and bonus content, I was ASTOUNDED by how weird all of it was. Why did they build it this way? As a joke? Like for example, the end game dungeon. You split up your party, and who you send where determines what items they find. But some characters can’t find some items, so there’s an optimal way to send them, and you can ALSO circle back to get their items, doublign items. Why? There’s a LOT of stuff like that, where there’s an optimal way to do things, and you need to look them up cause they are NEVER explained and hard to figure out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yNI4NPG.gif" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In all, I like FF7, but it’s nowhere near the perfect experience people make it out to be. That’s why I was optimistic about FF7 Remake. This story, and its characters, could be cool with a bit more of a modern retooling, and I think the remake fixed a lot of the issues. But I honestly HATE FF7R’s gameplay, and its pacing has some issues. But thats a story for another day.</p>

<p>In the end, I’ve played FF1-3, and 5-7 all the way through semi-recently. I skipped 4 because I don’t like it and the set was pissing me off, I’ll get back to it soon, I promise. But of those, I’d say FF7 is… 4th place. Behind FF6, 5, and 3. Yes, I liked 3 more, honestly. Depends on the day, prolly, but TODAY I like 3 more.</p>

<p>Still a good game. Please don’t kill me.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PS1" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Unmastered" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 158 - Catrap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 158 - Catrap" /><published>2025-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JS9Pthf.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I played a homebrew NES game called Witch n’ Wiz recently, and it was a cute little puzzle game. As I was playing it someone in chat went “Huh, this is kinda just Catrap”. And then I played Catrap and uh, yeah. It’s the same game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Mx3p01H.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Catrap you play as two people cursed to become cat people. Oh no, uh, how horrible. They can ‘break’ the curse though, by defeating all the enemies! It’s 100 levels, infinite lives, and it saves. This game is shockingly ahead of its time for 1990. Anyways, you can play as either the catboi or the catgirl, and they play exactly the same except for ONE thing I’ll mention later. You can defeat enemies by walking into them, but only from the side, otherwise they’re platforms. And with that, push blocks and use sand effectively to make your way through 100 levels!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ty0mfwO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Catrap is a fantastic puzzle game, with great puzzle design, and I’m frankly stunned by how ahead of the curve it is for 1990. It’s got a few fun gimmicks too, like some levels have you control both girl and boy, and swap between them with select, making for fun twisty levels. The one thing that got me though, is that the set has some “beat this level as fast as you can” achievements. Which y’know, is fine. You can basically buffer your inputs, so as long as you remember where to go, it’s honestly easy. The DIFFICULT part was that, in one of the challenges, I just couldn’t do it. I was like 2 seconds off. I watched a TAS. I was following it EXACTLY, still couldn’t get there. Why? What was I doing wrong? Then, I found out…. the boy is faster. Their climbing animations are different, and the boy’s is much faster than the girl’s. That’s it. It CONFOUNDED me. So I had to play as the boy for those levels, sadly.</p>

<p>The only thing the actual GAME has against it, IMO, is the music. It’s pretty rough, even for 1990 Gameboy standards. Like, we’re quite a ways off from Pokemon TCG, sure, but this is honestly kinda bad.</p>

<p>But yeah, fantastic game, and if you like puzzlers, you should check it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Catrap" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 120</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 120" /><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7Axr1s3.png" alt="'I was going to let you take control today, but in the end you still backed down. I think that side of you is cute, but... I also have my limits...' 'E-eh?! Wait, hold on!' 'I'm done waiting.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Day I Tried to Go on the Offensive</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Day I Tried to Go on the Offensive" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 119</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/04/OOCY119.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 119" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/04/OOCY119</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/04/OOCY119.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/liwD1AY.png" alt="'There... there are still holes?' A girl awkward says as another clings to her" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yumimi Mix</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yumimi Mix" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 157 - Fisher Price - I Can Remember</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/04/RA157FisherPrice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 157 - Fisher Price - I Can Remember" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/04/RA157FisherPrice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/04/RA157FisherPrice.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wlvqHTE.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I was hanging with a friend and for SOME DAMN REASON I decided this is the game we should play. I don’t know why I thought that was a good idea. This is Fisher Price: I Can Remember, an obscure NES game, licensed by Nintendo, with that Nintendo seal of quality, and it’s an “educational” game. It’s not. There’s no educational value at ALL in this, as there probably couldn’t be on the NES for a game for 2-3 year olds. This game is, instead, fucking product placement advertising, in a way that kind of pisses me off.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OTp1rjm.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The “game” is simple. You flip over spots to reveal all the WONDERFUL FISHER-PRICE TOYS YOU SHOULD ANNOY YOUR PARENTS TO BUY YOU, and then if you match the same one, you get a point! Pretty hard, huh? There’s a point system that’s nonsense, it’s VERY slow paced and boring, and there’s like 5 rounds of this. You can play VS others, or with a computer. And that’s it. I thought this would be goofy and fun but it kinda just annoyed me in the end.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NEs" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Fisher Price" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 156 - Chrono Trigger</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/02/RA156-ChronoTrigger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 156 - Chrono Trigger" /><published>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/02/RA156-ChronoTrigger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/02/RA156-ChronoTrigger.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OfRXBcI.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I do a thing on my stream called RPG Night. I hang out with my friends and play RPGs and we all do silly voices as I play. We usually try to 100% the games, and get a mastery (though some games make that very hard, lookin’ at you FF7). I’ve done lots of games already for this. But this one is special. This GAME is special. Chrono Trigger has the distinction of being probably the best RPG ever made. I do not say that lightly, and I’ve played a lot of games trying in vain to find any others that could topple it. Some come close. But none succeed. I feel like a sheep saying this, but yes, Chrono Trigger is essentially infallible. I’ve played it several times in my life, and each time, I’m kind of blown away.</p>

<p>So if you come into my reviews with NO knowledge, somehow, of Chrono Trigger, sit down and buckle up. I’ll give a brief review.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yMQP0eF.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chrono Trigger was an RPG made by Squaresoft in 1995, at the end of the SNES’ library, and it’s basically a sendoff of the console. All the biggest minds at Square at the time basically converged to make this one game. A lot of Final Fantasy people especially, which makes sense, because at one point this was slated to be a Final Fantasy game. FF5, I think? The SNES era of FF is nuts with stuff like that. There were like, 4 RPGs that were at one point going to be a Final Fantasy game that did not end up being a Final Fantasy game, or got cancelled. Anyways, it had a lot of people working on it. Three directors, most namely Sakagushi, the lead FF guy. Four different writers, most namely Yuji Horii, the creator of Dragon Quest. Four artists, most namely Akira Toriyama. And two composers including Yasunori Mitsuda, most famously, in his first actual composition role, instead of just sound effects. This game would rightfully launch him. Oh, I’ll get into the music later.</p>

<p>So yeah, this team was internally known as “The Dream Team”, which is very funny. It was the super group of JRPG teams. But could they live up to their hype? Uh, yes. Fuck yes, they could.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xC9lyoN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Chrono Trigger, you play as a young man named Crono. All of the characters are like, 17-19, which sets it apart from a lot of other RPGs where the characters are 13 year olds fighting God. Anyway, Crono lives in a pleasant Fantasy Kingdom in the year 1000AD, near his childhood friend Lucca, a brilliant inventor. It’s the Millenial fair, and you decide to go visit! While there, you bump into a young woman who calls herself Marle, and she asks you to show her around the fair. The two of you have a good time, then visit Lucca’s show, where she’s showing off a teleporter she made. However, the teleporter goes wrong, reacting to Marle’s necklace, and she’s sent into the portal, disappearing to somewhere. You pick up the necklace she dropped and hop right in after her to rescue her, sending yourself back 400 years, into your kingdom’s past, to the middle ages.</p>

<p>This is a time travel story that sends you aaaalll over the place. This game can kinda be described as a bunch of smaller stories and plot points that converge on one singular main point and plot. Like, you go back in time and find out that Marle, your time’s princess, was mistaken for this time’s princess. Unfortunately this causes a paradox, because they stopped looking for THEIR time’s princess, and Marle ceases to exist. You have to go rescue the REAL princess before something bad happens to her! Or later on, where you’re going back in time to prehistory to find a valuable rock that doesn’t exist anymore. After partying with the local people, your time travel device is stolen by local reptile people, and you need to get it back. Stuff like that, that’s all connected by one singular thing, and that’s Lavos. Most of you probably already know what Lavos is but I don’t want to spoil it for those who don’t.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/r2HLTCx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chrono Trigger to me, is characterized by its utterly fantastic writing, story, and characters, and the vibrant and beautiful world that it takes part in, which you feel you NEED to save. There are 7 major characters, and one of the game’s major flaws is you can only use 3 of them, because ALL of them are good and you’ll like all of them by the end. You’ll use all of them by the story’s end, as some are required for different points in the story, but by the end my main party was Crono, Marle, and Ayla for this playthrough. I usually use Lucca or Robo, but I wanted to give Ayla some love this time. Anyways, I seriously can’t overstate how well crafted this game is.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZarmyFK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But how’s the GAMEPLAY? Chrono Trigger uses a typical ATB battle system, which was very common place at the time, where everyone in a battle has gauges that fill up based on a speed stat, and then once it fills up, they can move. It’s semi-turn based, in that way. On top of that, Chrono Trigger has a system for proximity. Enemies and characters are on the field, and enemies will wander around. Their attacks, and your’s, will vary based on how close the target of their attacks are. You also have special tech attacks that care about things like proximity, or even attacking in a straight line. While it’s still, at its heart, a traditional JRPG combat system, it’s one of the more engaging ones from its time period. I tend to find combat systems from this era to be a bit dull, and often mash through them without thinking, and that can happen a bit in Chrono Trigger, but it’s okay, not everything can be Panzer Dragoon Saga. I’ve often said if there was a game with PDS’s combat system and Chrono Trigger’s story and characters, it would be the best game ever made.</p>

<p>Oh, and of course, I’d be remiss if I didn’t talk about the soundtrack. This was Mitsuda’s first actual soundtrack he worked on, and it is fucking fantastic. In my opinion he’ll outdo himself soon with Chrono Cross, the best video game soundtrack of all time, but seriously, this one is so good. It’s so good it coined a term called “The Mitsuda Lick” which I hear people talk about legitimately during musical discussion. Here, have a cover of some really damn good music to close out this review.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IAzPRupcTjQ?si=rMqkaHQ8PYoIbPZn" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>All together, Chrono Trigger is the real deal. I know public consensus says its one of the best games ever made, and so people go “pff, public consensus is always wrong, it can’t be that good”. I get it. I can be a bit of a hipster too. I JUST mentioned Panzer Dragoon Saga in the last paragraph for fuck’s sake, I LOVE my obscure shit no one cares about. But no, Chrono Trigger is actually really that good. Public consensus got it right. If you’ve never checked out Chrono Trigger, I highly advise you to. It’s worth at LEAST a try.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNEs" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Chrono" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 118</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/02/OOCY118.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 118" /><published>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/02/OOCY118</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/02/OOCY118.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SZVw4h1.png" alt="A girl throws some yen into a new years shrine. 'I wish my little brothers won't catch the flu... I wish for my thighs to lose some fat... and also...' An image of her hot friend pops in her mind" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn’t a Guy At All</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn&apos;t a Guy At All" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 16 - 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/02/LizstartrekVOY4-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 16 - 19" /><published>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/02/LizstartrekVOY4-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/02/LizstartrekVOY4-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oPqZ08e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Prey</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2kQtuQz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s the return of both the Hirogen AND Species 1234569. We start with the Hirogen hunting a Species ship, talking to each other about how the prey is reacting. One of them is played by Kurn’s actor, and his voice is very hot.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Voyager, Seven needs some compassion classes. This might be one of those episodes.</p>

<p>A Hirogen ship suddenly comes up on Voyager, one life sign, eratic, so they beam over to help. Seven is like “This is stupid, the Hirogen won’t accept your compassion”. Janeway SHOULD have responded with “ weird, it worked for you”, but instead she just goes “I’mma do it anyway”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CboMGs6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They rescue the Hirogen, who is pretty against working with who he views as his prey, but eventually agrees to let them treat him, albeit in a grumpy fashion. Yay for me, the Hirogen who’s still alive is the one with the sexy voice. They also learn more about the Hirogen, which seems to go against what we learned LAST EPISODE. They had a communications network, what do you mean they have no worlds and are nomadic. More Hirogen are also on the way, but before they can deal with THAT, the Species breaks its way into the fucking hull and into the ship. It sneaks around in antimatter injection ports and then attacks the Engineering team. It does NOT appear to  goo them like they did, with Harry.</p>

<p>Okay, so I guess Seven’s “compassion classes” are she thinks they should just kill the species, and Janeway goes “No”. No? NO? People are dying and WILL die, Janeway, I get it, but Seven is ACTUALLY right this time. She ALSO releases the Hirogen from his containment after he says he wants to finish the hunt. My girl, do you think this guy ISN’T GOING TO KILL THE SPECIES???? What the hell is wrong with Janeway in this episode.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9zQ556t.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode then becomes Aliens. Chakotay is in charge of keeping an eye on the Hirogen, which I would TOTALLY trust him with. Shockingly, the Hirogen attempts to kill the Species, and has to be shot to be stopped. No way, what a surprise. Also now that Kes is gone, it’s telepathically communicating with Tuvok instead. It tells Tuvok that it’s just trying to get home, and Janeway wants to do everything she can to get it home. She’s like “this isn’t a hunt, it’s a slaughter”. MFer that’s what a hunt is? Janeway is REALLY holding the idiot ball this episode. when she gives her reasoning and position, like, I get it? But it’s poorly written, and clearly written by people who have NOT been in a life or death, or even leadership position before.</p>

<p>Janeway stands by her ideals and refuses to give the prey, or the hunter, to the Hirogen. This is a very stupid idea because they’re up against six ships that can easily blow them the fuck up. They blow off TWO NACELLES. THAT’S BAD?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2zkTGC0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Hirogen breaks out and attacks the Species. Seven takes matters into her own hand and teleports both of them off the ship (a bit weird since it’s been stated they can’t be targetted but okay). Everyone is enraged by Seven about this, and Janeway removes her access and rights as a member of the crew over this. How DARE she SAVE THE CREW??? WHAT A FUCKER.</p>

<p>This is the dumbest thing I’ve EVER seen Janeway do. Stupid as fuck. Seven rightfully calls her out it, but god. I can’t tell if they’re trying to make Janeway or Seven the one in the right here, it’s open ended, but it SHOULDN’T be. Janeway should get her comeuppance.</p>

<p><strong>Retrospect</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qLdpujc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A weapons dealer is on Voyager, selling them a cannon. Janeway deigns to let Seven work with him, because they “work well together”, apparently, even though Seven states she does not like him (he is inneffecient). During installation, he pushes her out of the way, and she immediately decks him in the face. Everyone is like “what the fuck”, and she can’t really explain herself. She also freaks out when the Doctor tries to scan her. The doctor notices something strange in her brain. He does a hypnosis thing to try and figure out what the issue is. In the hypnosis flashback, she sees the weapons dealer, Kovin, performing surgery on her and extracting Borg technology. She uses the word “violate”, which is rough.</p>

<p>This could go okay, or very, vERY poorly.</p>

<p>It explains, in long excrutiating detail, her memory of what happened. They drugged her and harvested borg technology from her, before setting her back where she was and explaining it was a weapon overload that stunned her. Tuvok is skeptical, not for any BAD reason, just because this kind of memory recovery has been unreliable in the past. He intends to investigate. And to Janeway’s credit, she’s like “this is very important, and I will do what I can to get to the bottom of it”. When the trader is like “You’d risk trade negoations for the possibily her delusions are true?!” Janeway is like “Yes. I would.” Good on you for that. The Doctor is EXTREMELY in on this. He’s DISGUSTED by the concept of what Kovin did, and is fully behind Seven. Possibly to a… pushy degree? Like, making shit up. Hmm.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ae9F5YD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get a local Magistrate to investigate with them, for an impartial investigation. It’s not impartial enough for Kovin, so he pulls a gun on them and beams out. When they chase, he hits them with a pulse and disappears. They chase. Everyone is like “The investigation HAS been impartial, but we all had our preconceptions about him”. Hmmmmmmmm.</p>

<p>They find evidence that proves Kovin is probably not guilty. Seven is so SURE of what she saw, and they all agree she believes what she believes. She doesn’t react to this well, especially not when the Doctor “turns” on her about it, basically. They find out it’s some stuff playing with her borg implants and making her think things were happening when they weren’t. They catch up to Kovin, tell him “We know you’re innocent, don’t worry” and he just shoots at them without saying anything. His weapons overload and he blows himself up. And everyone is beating themselves up over this. No, he was being a fucking asshole. This episode FEELS like it’s a “THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS WHEN SEXUAL ASSAULT ALLEGATIONS ARE TAKEN TOO FAR, YOU’LL HURT INNOCENT PEOPLE”, but no, he’s being a fucking dumbass. I hate this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gDvO76k.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This all blows.</p>

<p>And the Doctor feels the most guilty cause he was the MOST cancel culturey, and so asks to be turned back to factory standard. This is such a weird leap. What the hell?</p>

<p>This episode is just Male Victimhood Fantasy and I wish it didn’t exist.</p>

<p><strong>The Killing Game</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qLdpujc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Is that a Hirogen in a fucking nazi uniform???</p>

<p>Yes, actually, it is. The Hirogen appear to have taken control of Voyager, and are putting the crew through simulations to test them. They’re rewriting their memories about who they are. First they make Janeway think she’s a Klingon warrior, which is hot, then they do THIS to her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bouDVW9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway dons her best Lesbian Suit, like holy HELL. This is basically Casablanca. Janeway is a resistance member in France who owns a bar. Seven sings at the bar and is secretly their munitions expert. Tuvok is Janeway’s friend and ally. The other Hirogen seem very confused about what they’re even doing, but the one in charge views this as a game. The others are like, seemingly kinda pissed they even gotta put up with this.</p>

<p>Neelix is riding around town with baguettes in his bike, as if you didn’t already know this was France.</p>

<p>LOL okay the Hirogen think the Nazis suck. When even your Space Predators think Nazis suck, maybe your Nazis fucking suck. He chokes out a nazi and tells him “You’re superior to no one, and if you think you are, you’ll die when the hunt turns back on you. Pathetic.” I hate that I love that.</p>

<p>We learn a bit more when one of the Hirogen get bored and shoot Seven of Nine and Neelix. The Doctor is still normal, and treating who he can. This seems like it could maybe be a deal they put together so more of them don’t die (though some of them ARE dying). Kim is outside the simulations, working on the ship at the Hirogen’s demands. He’s also forming a resistance cell within the ship, which is a fun dichotomy alongside the resistance cell happening INSIDE the simulations.</p>

<p>We learn more of why the Alpha Hirogen is doing this. He’s a progressive! Y’know, for a Hirogen. He believes that in order for his people to survive, they must adapt, and reform an actual civilization. Of course, the hunt is still important. They’ll just adapt. They’ll use this holodeck technology to continue the hunt, in a new society. It’s some SWEEPING changes he wants to make, and it’s fascinating. The other Hirogen seem to be more traditionalists.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gLJkicW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On the eve of the Americans re-entering the city, Seven is put back in the simulation. The doctor made is so she remembers who she is… unfortunately this means she doesn’t know wtf World War 2 is, and she’s an important part of the simulation, so that’ll be… worrying. This is a tense situation, but she manages to interface with the holodeck and release the prisoners JUST as soon as Janeway is about to shoot Seven, thinking she’s a nazi. Unfortunately, they know she’s free, and immediately go to recapture her. But everyone fights back. For the resistance!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hpBc0kA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We see a Nazi building explode and they do a sick-ass dive. The explosion blows its way into other decks, releasing the simulation. I mean, they DID turn off the safeties, makes sense that a fucking missile would do that. Holographic soldiers and real soldiers (our crew members) break their way out of the simulation… TO BE CONTINUED…</p>

<p><strong>The Killing Game, Part II</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3Ab58ON.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>…right now! Enjoying the commonality of two parters mid season now. Janeway and Seven are moving around the ship, beating up holographic nazis where they can. But they’re going to need help. Time to get the French Resistance to help. Janeway plays the simulation well. She knows her World War 2.</p>

<p>There’s some stuff with Paris and Torres’ characters in the simulation being in love, which is kind of unimportant and distracting from the actual plot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5gLnG2M.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway and Chakotay, still thinking he’s an American soldier, go to meet Janeway’s “contact”. But first they need to “go through caves”. These caves are the other holodeck, which has the Klingon simulation, and Neelix drunk off his ass as a Klingon. She contacts the Doctor, and gets her plan. She heads to sick bay ,but not before placing some charges on the thing that keeps their neuro transmitters in check. Janeway is shot, and the others are recaptured JUST as soon as they’re freed from the neurotransmitter.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Th5Sxao.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway is brought to the alpha Hirogen, and explains to her WHY he’s doing what he’s doing. With the holodecks, they can continue the hunt without killing others, and themselves, as readily. And he appreciates Humans. He and Janeway come to an agreement, and decide a cease fire. Janeway will give them Holodeck technology, and they will leave. Remember season 1 where they refused to give those aliens replicator technology?</p>

<p>He calls for a cease fire to his hunters, but one of the nazis in the simulation convinces him to continue. The more conservative, traditionalist hunters connect with the fucking nazis, over the progressive, who connects with the allied forces. This episode knows what its doing. The Nazis break the cease fire. Man, if you can’t trust the Nazis. The 2nd in command, the one who listened to the nazis, kills the Alpha Hirogen, and then chases Janeway around. Janeway STILL has a bullet in her leg. Now we have an injured Janeway in a sexy outfit running from a Nazi Hirogen and outsmarting him, it’s great.</p>

<p>Things are looking grim. The Nazis have our heroes up against the wall… and then!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oPqZ08e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE KLINGONS ARE THE BIG DAMN HEROES! Klingons killing nazis NOT something I knew I needed, but I did need it.</p>

<p>Janeway kills her hunter, and the remaining Hirogen agree to the truce again. She gives them the technology after all. Their leader’s ideals were unconventional, but maybe things can get better. Heavy casualties on both sides, the Voyager continues, freed.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>