<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-18T12:28:33-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 14 - 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/18/LizstartrekVOY3-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 14 - 19" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/18/LizstartrekVOY3-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/18/LizstartrekVOY3-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2jhMYsD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Alter Ego</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7F6VuNE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is directed by the Doctor. Gee, it’s like they’re running a directing school here.</p>

<p>Voyager is looking at an “inversion nebula”, whatever that is, and Harry Kim goes to Tuvok like “Hey, can you help me remove my emotions” and Tuvok is like “it’s kind of not that easy, why?” and Kim is like “cause I’m in love with a Holodeck program” and Tuvok is like “lol you’re in love with A PROGRAM SUBROUTINE??? YOU NERD” and Kim is like “aww”</p>

<p>I wonder if Kim’s girlfriend just doesn’t matter anymore. I wonder if we’re even gonna bring it up.</p>

<p>Tuvok: “Vulcans don’t have friends. We have fellowships and the like.” Tuvok. My man. I know that’s wrong, because they made <strong><em>THREE MOVIES ABOUT THE TOPIC</em></strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fOPxHIk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This holodeck character, Malayna, is very very lifelike. Like, all holodeck characters are lifelike. But she’s very perceptive, going beyond her coding as a beachside instructor. She’s very logical, calcualting, but also friendly and inviting. This comes to a head as Tuvok also becomes interested in the woman, who is putting the moves on, something fierce</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rxO46nr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I don’t like this. Stop. This man is married. He has several kids and has been married for like 80 years. You can ship anyone else on this ship, have them all be in one big fuck pile if you want, but leave Tuvok out of this. Like, cheating and things don’t sit well with me, and Harry is TECHNICALLY dating someone, but like, after two years, I’ll accept that. It feels weirder for Tuvok, who is long lived, and WILL be alive and fine in 80 years when they get back home, everything can return as normal.</p>

<p>Anyways Kim and Tuvok get in a bit of a jealousy spat, and Tuvok deletes her from the Holodeck, but she just puts herself in Tuvok’s room instead, and is like “Hey, you’re move~” putting the hots back on him. THANKFULLY, Tuvok is immediately like “nope, all my hots are gone, this is clearly bad and this woman is a threat to Voyager” and calls security. Okay good. I was checking out SO HARD from this, but this helps. Anyways, Malayna has control over the ship’s functions, and she stops the alarms and zoops out of there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JGNmmEd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ten minutes earlier “I would NEVER be a threat to you or your ship!” Ten minutes later, she’s strangling B’elanna, and going “GIVE ME VULCAN DICK OR I WILL LITERALLY DESTROY VOYAGER”. Lady. He’s just not that into you, and you are going WAY too far for this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3IZECG5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways she’s actual an alien on a nearby station that looks over the nebula, and she’s alone. And very lonely. She hacks nearby ships that pass by to look into them and see what they’re about. Have you every considered like… saying hi??? I mean she technically did here, but then it went too far, she fell in love with Tuvok, and now she wants him so much she’ll do murder. I cannot relate to her in any way lol. She literally says “I chose a life of isolation here and I want to be here, alone”. So why would I feel bad about this?? Anyways he destroys her with Facts and Logic, and she sadly lets him go. He tells her to go back to her own kind, if this assignment is fucking with her THIS badly and she’s like “woah I didn’t think of that, huh”. THIS LADY THOUGHT SHE WAS LOGICAL ENOUGH FOR A VULCAN?? The episode ends with Tuvok apologizing to Kim, which fair, he did treat him kinda like shit, and teaches him a Vulcan board game.</p>

<p>Neli gave a good analogy. A ranger is alone in the forest and sees a group of hikers. He talks to one of them, likes them, and then kidnaps them and says “I will kill the others if you don’t fuck me”, and then when suggested to just… not be a ranger, cause clearly it’s damaging their psyche, they go “huh I hadn’t thought of that”.</p>

<p>This episode blows.</p>

<p><strong>Koda</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cM0TJ9H.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway and Chakotay go on a shuttle, and it goes down and crashes onto a planet. Why the fuck would they put the two highest ranking officers on the same shuttle? Aren’t there rules for this? Anyways, Janeway dies in the crash. Pretty bold of the show to kill off the main character. Chakotay manages to revive her. They’re REALLY trying to make the thing between them a thing. I don’t want it. I hate it. Please.</p>

<p>Anyways turns out they were shot down by Vidiians, who come in and kill Chakotay and strangle Janeway to death. Then they wake back up on their shuttle. They appear to be in some kind of time loop. The Vidiians kill them AGAIN, but the third time they manage to disrupt the loop and escape the ships, making it back to Voyager. When they get back, suddenly Chakotay doesn’t remember the timeloop. And when the doctor examines her, apparently she’s infected by the phage. No idea HOW, but one of the phage’s side effects is that it can cause hallucinations, apparently, so that explains that.</p>

<p>When she awakes 40 hours later, Doctor goes “Nope, can’t find a cure. Guess I’ll have to kill you :(“ and poisons her with a neurotoxin, and we see her painfully dying. What the fuck??</p>

<p>Back to the anomaly. They can see it physically, and then Janeway sees Chakotay trying to revive her body, from that first time. She’s suddenly in a It’s A Wonderful Life situation, watching everyone react to her death.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X94IKoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kes seems to feel that she’s there, cause psychic, y’know. The rest of them take any chance to save Janeway, and Janeway stands there watching, as her dad shows up like “Hey honey, you’re dead, like me! Come join me in the afterlife :D” Janeway keeps holding on, until she sees everyone give up on her, and hold a eulogy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WL0cEP6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>…But even after, no, she has to stand by them. She’ll just watch, it’s fine. She’ll be with them in spirit, and a captain never abandons ship (Incorrect, you’ve abandoned ship a few times already, but thats okay)</p>

<p>She starts seeing flashes of the Doctor trying to resuscitate her, and determines THIS isn’t real, and her dad is trying really, REALLY hard to convince her to just give up and die, which is not at all what her father would do. She asks him if he’s an alien, and yes, okay, he is, but he’s here to make people crossing over into the next life easier. Uh, no, clearly not. He’s basically a vulture, feasting on dying people. But she makes it back, and everythings okay.</p>

<p>I found this episode pretty interesting… at least, the second half. The first half was uh… what does that have to do with anything???? It feels like they wrote an episode, didn’t know how to end it, and just wrote a completely different episode.</p>

<p><strong>Blood Fever</strong> - VOY
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kA1fReZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Y’all remember PON FAR?! One of the Vulcans on board is undergoing it, and asks Torres to be his mate. It’s a very “I assure you, I am quite fertile” moment. Anyways when he gets… handsy, Torres fucking decks him. Go Torres. The Doctor tries helping him, but the pon far isn’t a thing people talk about. It’s a private matter. The Doctor is annoyed by how Victorian Vulcans are about the whole sex thing. I agree. The only thing they CAN do here is just let him meditate, which doesn’t seem to be helping.</p>

<p>Torres, Neelix, and Paris go into a cave and do some climbing to find some minerals they need. Torres is very… harsh, fast paced, high energy. When their climbing equipment fails, Neelix is injured, she’d lightly hurt, and gets VERY angry at him. When Paris tries to stop her, she bites him, and is like “what the fuck?!”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cuty6Am.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Turns out Vorik, the Vulcan, mind melded with Torres briefly and now SHE’S experiencing Pon Far. They go after her, and some aliens come out of the rocks, and consider her hostile… because she is. An earthquake happens, and her and Paris are seperated. She refuses to accept something is wrong with her, and no one wnats to explain Pon Far to her. Just say its Vulcan Mind Meld Fuckery, seriously.</p>

<p>The Doctor develops an alternative for Vorik. He makes a Vulcan blow-up doll on the holodeck. No joke. It’s VERY funny. He’s basically teaching Vulcans how to masturbate.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Pwo78lf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, because it’s a Love Pollen episode and Torres and Paris are alone, Torres wants to fuck Paris. At least, benefits to Paris, he’s not IMMEDIATELY getting it on. Even HE realizes the ethical fuckery of this, but it is indeed, fucky, and VERY uncomfortable to watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UGgU2vl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She tells him she’s ALWAYS been interested in him like he has in her, but like, no, you’re clearly saying that for sex,. and even after a kiss, he’s not comfortable with fucking her. God bless, thank you Paris. Thank GOD. But after Chakotay and Tuvok rescue them, they determine that they MUST fuck, or she’ll die. Vorik sneaks down to the surface, the masturbation not helping, and declares ritual combat. Y’know, the thing that Spock did to Kirk. Torres tells him to go fuck himself and declares herself as her OWN defender, and beats the shit out of him. The Blood Fever is over.</p>

<p>Torres tries to avoid the subject later on with Paris, who tells her she’s being ridiculous and he didn’t mind it THAT much. What a TERRIBLE start to their relationship. And then they find Borg corpses on the surface, which means this episode is kind of important. Oh no.</p>

<p>This episode made me feel gross.</p>

<p><strong>Unity</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2jhMYsD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay and an Ensign who’s prolly gonna die later are lost in space, and Will Robinson is nowhere to be found. They get the lead of a Federation beacon and head to it, but it’s a planet, not Voyager, and the people on the planet recognize them as Federation. They’re still pretty far out, so that’s intriguing. When they land, there are people there to meet them, who just start blasting for some reason. The Ensign is killed, of course, but Chakotay is saved after being injured. He’s saved by a Human who explains that she, and the others on this planet, were kidnapped by aliens and stranded here. There are some Klingons, Cardassians, and all kinds of other things on this planet. She demands he rest for a bit.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Voyager is floating through a large expanse of nothing, bored, and then find… A BORG CUBE! It’s powered down and seems dead, so they send an away team to scavenge it and see if they can find anything that could help against future Borg attacks that will TOTALLY happen if we’ve seen hints of the Borg two episodes in a row.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lGdP8xA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay thinks the human he met, Riley, is kinda sussy, so he follows her outside and finds… BORG! They’re all Borg! She explains that yes, they WERE Borg. She was from Wolf 359. But after their Cube broke down, they escaped and regained their personal selves. They just want to make a society on here, and live happy lives. Chakotay is weirded out but hey, they can’t help having originally been Borg. Anyways Chakotay is dying and some Borg technology can help him, and the post-Borg can help him basically, temporarily putting him into the collective. Chakotay is a Borg Racist though and is like “NO FUCK THAT SHIT”, but eventually y’know, he’s about to die, so they welcome him into the collective briefly with a simple thing placed on his head, and easily removed after. It shows an interesting representation of what the Borg is, what it’s like being Borg, in a way that’s less threatening. Borg that wants to help and protect each other… but even then, the violence they’ve committed still bleeds through. They can’t escape it. I like that, it’s interesting.</p>

<p>Voyager shows up and saves Chakotay. Riley goes up to explain a plan they have. They’ll reactivate the Borg cube, for a minute, which will allow them to start a new collective, reconnecting their minds for good, and allowing them to peacefully assimilate all the raiders who are attacking them. While that isn’t bad, and she doesn’t think these people are bad, that forceful assimilation is still…. forceful, which is fucked, and also it might attract other Borg to the area, which is VERY bad, so Janeway says no. They accept her decision, and they go about their way.</p>

<p>Ha ha, no, they use the link they had established with Chakotay to force him to go into the Borg Cube and activate it. Like, they’re under attack by Raiders and about to die. They feel threatened and they have no other choice, I get it, but it’s still… unfortunate it had to come to this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zuRotSx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay reactivates the Cube, which allows them to assimilate the violent raiders, but also activates the Borg, who immediately get ready to fire on Voyager, but the New Cooperative, as they call themselves, blow up the Cube, sever the link, and say goodbye. Chakotay and Janeway wonder if they WILL be better than the actual Borg, because they DID force their will as soon as it suited their needs… and hoped that it would go better this time.</p>

<p>Pretty interesting episode, especially for a Chakotay episode!</p>

<p><strong>Unity</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5dKL38i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got a Kes episode! Voyager meets some aliens, the Travelers, who explore space willy nilly. They look like Bajorans but their nose ridge is white, they CLEARLY are re-using makeup lol. They’re friendly enough, but often just go by their own whims. They’re willing to trade medical stuff and information to Voyager, to help them out, and Kes is working with one in particular, one named Zahir. He’s a bit different, very friendly and helpful. The Doctor, meanwhile, doesn’t like them and tells Kes to keep away.</p>

<p>At the same time, the Doctor is researching ancient people, and trying to implement their personalities into his own. This is… obviously a bad idea, and Torres calls it out as such, especially after the Doctor flirts with her and places his fucking hand on her thigh and she is like “I WILL find a way to break you, Doctor”. Changing your personality is DRASTIC, and dangerous. He just wants to improve his bedside manner and be more friendly, which makes sense. But this is noooot the way.</p>

<p>Kes and Zahir start a relationship, of course, and Kes is thinking of leaving Voyager to join him in his journeys.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ETNIsk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Late at night, Zahir is attacked and thrown in a ravine, and his friend is attacked and burned… by the Doctor! Who’s acting all evil and fucked up. They get the Doctor to help him, and he’s… perfectly pleasant, but Torres notices a problem in his personality subroutines. Something fucked up with it and he’s degrading, so she tries to work on him… and is attacked by his Evil Version. It’s a Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde situation. He’s unhinged, they do something with his eyes, and it’s PERFECT at making him seem unstable and evil as shit. His actor is FLEXING, and is SO good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FLJ2vkp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He kidnaps Kes and tries to escape to the planet, booking a ship to flee, with Kes as his… slave? I dunno. She eventually surmises that actually it’s the good parts inside of him trying to protect her. They chase them to the planet, and he threatens to throw them off a fucking cliff. But they catch them with the teleporter, and fix the Doctor, and all is well.</p>

<p>This episode is very entertaining, I didn’t wanna really type to distract myself. Good damn episode, let the Doctor flex more please. It ends with him reciting the Hippocratic oath… good episode.</p>

<p>…And thank God we ended on this episode, or this would be a very rough night.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 53 - Lightly NSFW</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/18/OOCY53.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 53 - Lightly NSFW" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/18/OOCY53</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/18/OOCY53.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G0V26PK.png" alt="&quot;How about I go take you for a walk? Oh, but you'll havbe to make me cum first, got it?&quot; &quot;If that's what my master wants, then I'll send you to heaven &lt;3&quot; *time skip* &quot;You sure talk big for someone who can't even handle that much&quot; &quot;...I apologize for my existence.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Cynical Dog</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Cynical Dog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 52</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/17/OOCY52.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 52" /><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/17/OOCY52</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/17/OOCY52.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DAT71SU.png" alt="&quot;Ehh?! I... I'm becoming yuri?! I'm gonna end up being yuri?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yuri is Taboo to a Yuri Otaku</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuri is Taboo to a Yuri Otaku" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 120 - Pokemon TCG Neo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/17/RA120-PTCGNeo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 120 - Pokemon TCG Neo" /><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/17/RA120-PTCGNeo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/17/RA120-PTCGNeo.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CBvhtIZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Early on in this year, I played Pokemon TCG, and Pokemon TCG 2. These are both RPGs on the Gameboy where the battle gameplay is the Pokemon TCG, using cards from the early sets. I had the first as a kid, and the second never came out here, but I played it and loved it, it might be even better than the first. And then… that was it. Nintendo never made another one of these. No clue why, they were genuinely fantastic. But what if they HAD?</p>

<p>This is a romhack of the original Pokemon TCG, which adds in Gen 2 cards. Cards from Neo Genesis all the way to Skyridge have been swapped in. Nothing else is changed, mind you. It’s the same adventure through the 8 clubs to get the 8 medals. It’s just… re-experience the game you already love, but this time you can use a Totodile. Which, frankly, improves it for sure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/r4BSprj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I know how to make utterly busted decks in TCG 1 and 2, but for this one I had a bit more trouble. In TCG 1 you can always go Haymaker, prolly your best bet. And in TCG 2, I made this stupid fucking Zapdos deck with only 2 copies of Zapdos, to take advantage of the lack of a mulligan rule. For this game, I made my own deck concept, a Slowking + Typhlosion combo. Typhlosion deals a LOT of damage, but it’s lowered by the damage counters on it, and Slowking can move damage counters off other Pokemon and onto it, or another benched Pokemon. It was a good deck, though I eventually swapped to a deck similar to my Zapdos one, but using a Celebi. Not nearly as effective, that Zapdos is busted as hell, but still good.</p>

<p>The cards aren’t exactly correct, and not every card is here. It prolly has to do with ease of programming. We don’t have the stupid Slowking that dominated that format, for example, which makes opponents flip coins when they try to use a trainer. That card sucked, so it’s not here. And I think some other cards are changed, but I don’t know the format nearly as well as I do the earlier formats. I wasn’t playing during this era.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9K3HrMg.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’d also be remiss if I didn’t talk about the art. The art in the original TCG game was fantastic, honestly kind of mind blowing. It’s really damn good here, too. This game takes the art from the cards and translates it VERY faithfully onto a system that can usually only show four colors in a square of space. That’s EXTREMELY impressive, I cannot understate it. Also, because it’s the TCG, a lot of the art is utterly fantastic. Here’s this.</p>

<iframe src="https://clips.twitch.tv/embed?clip=PoisedStupidRaisinNinjaGrumpy-OsAfk5Zd-I0NI2Tn&amp;parent=www.example.com" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" scrolling="no" height="378" width="620"></iframe>

<p>Pokemon TCG Neo is a pretty sick romhack, honestly. It’s just a fun way to re-experience the TCG if you haven’t played it in a while, and I recommend it! Here’s a link to it:</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="romhacks" /><category term="Pokemon" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 119 - Mario Paint</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/15/RA119-MarioPaint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 119 - Mario Paint" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/15/RA119-MarioPaint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/15/RA119-MarioPaint.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/za6MdG3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I didn’t own a SNES when I was a kid, but when I was like, 13-ish in the mid 2000s, my brother’s girlfriend gave us her childhood SNES. It had three games: Inspector Gadget, Super Mario World, and Mario Paint. Out of those three, Mario Paint was prolly my most played, even as a cynical and grumpy 13 year old. And as a cynical and grumpy woman in her 30s, it’s still one of my favorite SNES games. And it really didn’t need to be this good. Mario Paint was built to be a way that kids could play games that could be CONSTRUCTIVE, and usually attempts at that failed, especially with art, and especially back in the day, and <strong>especially</strong> on consoles.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ddzNaLL.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s literally just an art program. That’s it! That’s all it is! But it’s a… pretty good one? With nice AI. If you compare this to something like Art Alive on the Genesis, it’s stunning. That game is clunky with a dated AI. And don’t even get me started on Color a Dinosaur. But this has aged amazingly, it feels TIMELESS. And it’s smooth and has lots of tools to express your creativity.</p>

<p>You’ve also got the side content. I was really into the music maker in the mid 2000s, I loved watching Youtube videos of people making songs in it. Today, it’s still good, but I’m not as into it. And you’ve got the mini-game “Gnat Attack” too, where you swat gnats. Honestly, the worst part of the package to me? It’s not bad, at all, but if Gnat Attack didn’t exist, it wouldn’t effect my opinion of Mario Paint in any way. Ironically, Gnat Attack was like 70% of the achievement set for this. I had to beat a loop of it, which is pretty hard.</p>

<p>If you’ve never played the original SNES Mario Paint, you might not know it used a mouse. A lot of consoles back then had mice. I have lots of opinions about these mice, as I own a lot of them. The SNES one is one of the better ones, though it’s still clunky and rough, by today’s standards. But most mice were back then.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xlrdBxb.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mario Paint is beloved, and even today is 100% worth playing. There’s something really fun about using archaic art programs to try and make something actual artistic. Both of these works were made by me, by the way. Shout outs to Bob Ross. This and Kid Pix are the standouts of child’s paint programs. Today I guess they have like… Clip Studio Paint. Which is technically better in every way. But it doesn’t have Totaka’s Song.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Mario" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 51</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 51" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HdbAXcG.png" alt="&quot;Whether I'm a guy or a girl... nothing changes." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Boyfriend Sometimes Girlfriend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Boyfriend Sometimes Girlfriend" /><category term="genderbender" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 50</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/14/OOCY50.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 50" /><published>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/14/OOCY50</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/14/OOCY50.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RTDyMEd.png" alt="A woman pinches herself as she wakes up in bed next to her wife" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>(By the way this is one of the best yuri manga ever and is highly recommended if you’ve never seen it before)</p>

<p>source: Yuki and the Authoress</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuki and the Authoress" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 118 - Mother 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/14/RA118-Mother3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 118 - Mother 3" /><published>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/14/RA118-Mother3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/14/RA118-Mother3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PfMlAEM.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It took me about a month before I picked up Earthbound and played through it, after Mother 1. After Earthbound, I picked up Mother 3 the following day. And after starting it, I did almost nothing else but play it, for a full on week. Mother 3 is one of those… very special games, and I had never actually beaten it before. I HAD played it, and got to chapter 5. But, much like how it had been with Earthbound, I kind of bounced off of it. Years later now, I gave it another try. Andyeah. This game is amazing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Za9RgR9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mother 3 is pretty much exactly what I wanted after Earthbound. It takes all of the improvements of Earthbound in the system, and SAYS something, and not only that, it says something new. As much as I like Mother 1 and 2, the characters aren’t really characters. And since the characters are the exact same from Mother 1 to Mother 2, that feels exhausting. Like, you’ve got baseball cap nice kid. Magic girl. Smart boy. These aren’t really characters. But the characters in Mother 3 <strong>are</strong> characters, and not only that, they are intentionally built to contrast with their previous counterparts. Ness was a baseball wielding tough but nice kid, a solid home life, and lots of friends. Lucas is a crybaby with a stick with a miserable home life, and is ostracized from his village. Paula is a sweet little demure magic girl with magic that can blast you into kingdom come, or gently smack you with a frying pan. Kumatora is a beartiger. She is a butch spellcaster who punches her enemies, and she cannot stop swearing. Jeff is a smart and competent nerd. Duster is a doofus with a limp who is here because it’s the right thing to do. And King, Ness’ dog, is a coward who refuses to join your party after the intro, while Boney is THE BEST BOY IN VIDEO GAMES, and will follow Lucas to the <strong>ends of the Earth</strong>. All of these characters are not only fun to play with, they’re fun to interact with, and they’re ACTUAL characters. They have goals, aspirations, emotions, and we see them, as opposed to in Mother 1 and 2, where they’re just implied.</p>

<p>The story of Mother 3 is rather simple, kind of. We start in an idyllic little village. They all live happily. There’s no one to even man the jail, because no one’s needed to be put in the jail. They have no concept of money, you just take what you need and leave what you don’t at the general store. They are at peace and one with the land. But then a strange force called the Pigmask army comes, starts changing animals into horrible mechanized hybrids, and lights the forest on fire. And after ruining Lucas’ life in chapter 1, we see them slowly and insideously corrupt the village in chapters 2 and 3 by introducing…. CAPITALISM.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TV7eHiI.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>YES. This game has some messages and themes it wants to tell, and one of those themes is that CAPITALISM FUCKING BLOWS. It corrupts and twists everyone in the town from people who are rushing out to find Lucas, his brother Claus, and their mother in the middle of the night after they’ve gone missing, to people who ostracize them because they still refuse to get a happy box (a tv), and upgrade their lives to modern society. This theme is apparant RIGHT in the logo of the game, and it handles this theme very, very well. It’s maybe heavy handed, but it makes you ANGRY, seeing how this society is corrupted and shifts, getting worse and worse with each chapter, and you can barely hang on, with no change of stopping the downward spiral.</p>

<p>The other theme this game tackles is, of course, the usual Mother series theme of Love and Family. I’m a bit worried talking about all of this, because this game’s story and plot is quite powerful and emotional, and I don’t want to spoil it. I’ll just say, it handles this topic quite well. It could maybe tackle the found family trope too, because by the end, Lucas, Kumatora, Duster, and Boney are BLOOD BROTHERS.</p>

<p>Also, the game improves on Earthbound’s actual gameplay in a lot of ways, which is impressive cause I only disliked a single thing about Earthbound’s gameplay, and that’s the damn item management. It’s still not perfect in this game, but it’s better. You’ve got item box guys all over the place, instead of having to call your sister and wait. That item box guy is the realest, btw. He’s just a hobo who believes in you. I love him. On top of that though, they did add in the rhythm mechanic. As you attack, you can tap A to the beat of the music to get up to 16 hits on an enemy. On emulator this is hard, but it’s a really cool extra little tihng, and it’s neat to get better at it and learn the songs. I don’t want to like, get 16 hits on every single song, cause some of them are fffffucked (some are very VERY fucked), but it’s still cool.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ORYW5t3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I should also mention that this soundtrack is fucking fantastic. Probably the best in the series, And that’s impressive considering it’s <strong>on the GBA</strong>, which is NOT a good system for music. But damn, they made this fucking thing sing.</p>

<p>Mother 3 is utterly fantastic. If there’s ONE thing that fell flat to me though, it’s the ending. I… don’t really want to talk about it, cause spoilers, but it feels like an anti-climax after everything that precedes it, and it confounds me. I don’t know what it’s trying to say, or imply, or mean. I have my own interpretation of it though, which I like. I’ll let you come to your own conclusions though.</p>

<p>In the end, I think Mother 3 is by far the best of the trilogy. However, I might still love Mother 1 more, for the nostalgia factor, and also what it’s TRYING to say. It fails at it a bit, ngl, it’s a very old school game and is held back by that. Can’t wait for that Mother 1 remake fans are making!!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="GBA" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Mother" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 49</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/13/OOCY49.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 49" /><published>2024-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/13/OOCY49</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/13/OOCY49.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SWAdvTK.png" alt="&quot;I NEED ROMANCE!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This would probably work on some people</p>

<p>source: El Goonish Shive</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="El Goonish Shive" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 48</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/12/OOCY48.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 48" /><published>2024-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/12/OOCY48</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/12/OOCY48.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/svW86Yn.png" alt="&quot;We're going to be the best fake girlfriends!&quot; &quot;BOOBS BOOBS BOOBS BOOBS BOOBS&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While you were dating girls in highschool, I was studying the kiss- wait.</p>

<p>source: Seven Days in Silverglen</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Seven Days in Silverglen" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>