<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-03T13:54:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 41</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/03/OOCY41.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 41" /><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/03/OOCY41</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/03/OOCY41.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cr8Le7i.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Shit, now that people aren’t immediately being thrown in jail for being gay, you see gay people all the time. I wonder why that is.</p>

<p>source: Ayaka is in Love with Hiroko!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Ayaka is in Love with Hiroko!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 40</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/01/OOCY40.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 40" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/01/OOCY40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/01/OOCY40.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sckDqCq.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>By the way I uploaded yuri yesterday too but I forgot to hit go live until like midnight lol oops, so go back and look at that yuri too</p>

<p>source: Questionable Content</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Questionable Content" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 39</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/31/OOCY39.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 39" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/31/OOCY39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/31/OOCY39.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8hJG52L.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UvtaDgn.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bovsomU.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Moon on a Rainy Night</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Moon on a Rainy Night" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 38</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/29/OOCY38.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 38" /><published>2024-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/29/OOCY38</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/29/OOCY38.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OcFYC3x.png" alt="Soft and springy white bread with a gentle sweetness, or rough and hard black bread? Which do I like? It has to be white bread! That's why I love girls!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Princess of the Princess</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Princess of the Princess" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 38</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/28/OOCY37.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 38" /><published>2024-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/28/OOCY37</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/28/OOCY37.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oUPqony.png" alt="&quot;Ah! A pretty girl!&quot; &quot;Eh?! Where?&quot; *T-poses*" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Princess of the Princess</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Princess of the Princess" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 117 - Earthbound/Mother 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 117 - Earthbound/Mother 2" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m40cwUj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>A month ago, September 20th in fact, I mastered Mother 1, and made a post about it. I should go back and change that post. I feel like I was focusing a bit too hard on Mother 1 and comparing it to Mother 2, and didn’t talk enough about what I liked about it. I’ll try to do a little less of that this time, though some of that will probably come out anyway. These two games are VERY comparable, because they’re very similar, at least in how they present themselves.</p>

<p>Earthbound, or Mother 2 in Japan, is often considered one of the best RPGs of all time. It is HIGHLY influential. And it booooombed. It did NOT do well over here, though giving credit to it, it DID actually come out here, unlike its NES prequel, Mother 1, which got translated but was never released. When I was a kid, I played Mother 1 thinking it was this game, and didn’t learn that I was wrong for like, months. When I DID finally play this game, I got into it, and stopped playing prooolly around after Threed. And that’s about the way it was, for years. This is the best RPG ever, you HAVE to beat it, I’d pick it up, play until around Fourside, and then stop.</p>

<p>This year though, I FINALLY beat it. And yeah. It’s good. Pretty good! I do see why people like it. But some parts of it fall…. flatter than I’d hope.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y1CHXvR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Earthbound is about a young boy named Ness, who lives in the town of Onett in Eagleland. One day, he’s woken up in the middle of the night by a meteorite falling onto the hill near his house. After some shenanigans with his bratty neighbor Porky, a fly named Buzz Buzz comes out, claiming he’s a hero from the future who is here to warn Ness, the Chosen one, that evil is on the rise. An evil named Giygas has come to destroy the world, and Ness must gather three friends and stop him. And then Buzz Buzz is swatted like a fly and dies.</p>

<p>That’s kind of how I’d describe this game. It’s got a big plot about friendship and banding together to overcoming terrifying odds and circumstances, and then its also filled with very goofy funny moments. It’s maybe a little jarring? You’ve got funny goofy moments that are nonsensical, like oh hey, you need to move forward but there’s a big metallic pencil in your way. Well don’t worry, just get your handy dandy pencil eraser, which will erase any pencils! And then you have scenes like the one where Poo is meditating and a spirit comes to rip off his arms, legs, eyes, ears, and brain, violently, and horrifyingly.</p>

<p>It’s got a little bit of a tone problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q62vZen.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s not to say that either of these moments are bad. They’re both good. And this game is really quite funny. I love the little inconsequential dialogue, I went around speaking to everyone, cause it’s just funny and enjoyable. Everyone’s got something weird to say.</p>

<p>Let’s talk about gameplay for a bit. There’s no run button, which IS pretty painful. The first game didn’t have one either… except for the American Beta, which added a run button. So this is kind of a step back, actually. It’s slow and plodding, which is a little painful tbh. IMO the pacing of this game is off, and it’s not jsut with how slow it runs, the game REALLY drags in the middle, and then it doesn’t pick up for a while. But anyways, the gameplay is still a Dragon Quest-ish JRPG, though this time you can have up to four characters. The backgrounds aren’t all black now, you’ve got some really frekaing cool effects back there, I’m a big fan. Also a big fan of the new rolling health system. As you take damage, your health ticks down. If you win before it ticks to zero, you live, and your health stops falling! You can also do a quick heal as it’s ticking down to save yourself. IMO this is an ingenius invention, and GREATLY improves things. As you panic and quickly mash through menus to heal Paula for the millionth time, it keeps turn based combat exciting and fun!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y7AeldK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One of the things that feels a bit downgraded over the NES version is actually the world itself. The NES game takes place on one giant contiguous map. You go out, you explore the world. You see how places connect and move together. This doesn’t quite have that. It’s more like, a few dozen maps stitched together with doors to and from. I don’t think it’s a big deal for most, but for me, it feels like a downgrade. You know what’s also a biiiit of a downgrade? The music. I know, I know, I KNOW you’re booing, but look, Mother 1’s soundtrack is fucking fantastic, and while Earthbound’s is very, very good, and I like it a lot, it doesn’t have a Pollyanna, or a Paradise Line, or a Bein’ Friends, or an All That I Needed, and definetely not an And Fallin’ Love or a Mother Earth. Sometimes I heard tracks from Mother put in this game as a remix and I got VERY excited, but they’re few and far inbetween. You hear a relaxing heartwarming rendition of Polyanna in Ness’s house, and a great remix of Youngtown in Paula’s house, but that’s about it. again, this is not to say the soundtrack is bad. It’s very good. And it’s got a LOT of really interesting things about it, and a lot of references.</p>

<p>Okay, let’s talk theming. Mother 2 has, in my opinion, a bit of a theming problem. Like I said, it’s a game about friendship and banding together to overcome powerful odds, constantly pushing through even if it’s scary, because that’s what you have to do. That second part, I think the game handles quite well. The final area is really intimidating and scary, and it and the final boss emphasise this part of the theme very well, in my eyes. It’s the friendship part where IMO the game falls flat… I don’t think I can imagine these people as being the best of friends. Poo shows up randomly and says “I am your friend now” and then leaves with the exact same energy. Jeff leaves the game with a “Well, call me if you need some appliances fixed”. All of the characters talk about have a bit more character than their counterparts in Mother 1…. maybe. Honestly it’s about the same. There’s not a lot of character here, and because of that, I can’t really feel like they’re best friends who are banding together. They’re just random characters being shuffled together as fate decides, because a psychic child had a dream that said they’d be best friends.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hIMnDYG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This also leads me to one of my other major problems with Earthbound. It’s a big retread of the previous game, and yet it also has NOTHING to do with it. The only thing that links these two stories together is the main villain, Giygas, who might as well be a completely different character. The game does nothing to actually explain the connecting bridge between the two games, and if you didn’t even know Mother 1 existed, like kids didn’t in the early 90s, you wouldn’t expect anything is out of line. Ninten, Ana, Lloyd, and Teddy might as well not even exist. They’ve been replaced. Now we have Ness, who is just Ninten again, Paula, who is just Ana again, and Jeff, who is just Lloyd again. Teddy has been replaced ENTIRELY with Poo, who’s his own thing, at least. But there’s a LOT of retreat ideas. Area under attack by zombies? Yep. A desert filled with a monkey cave? Yep. Collecting 8 parts of a musical piece? Yep. Musical act scene? Yep. Gotta do a thing so that the pubic transit works and you can go through the tunnel? Yep. Like, the thing is, most of these would feel like references to JP kids who played both, or at least I think it was intended to feel that way, but it feels more to me like they were just trying to make Mother 1 again. There are plenty of unique ideas, and they’re all quite good, but a lot of the retreating feels like it doesn’t fit the themes and is just… there. And yeah, there’s no connection to Mother 1 despite all this. I know a lot of fan theories, like Giygas erased Ninten and his family from the timeline, which broke him because he also erased his mother. Or Ninten is Buzz Buzz. I’ve heard all these theories. But that’s all they are, theories.</p>

<p>This doesn’t actually make the game bad in any way. I’d give this game an 8/10, it is a very good game, and I totally get why parts of it are very influential. But people kinda ignore the most obnoxious forgettable moments, and especially the pudgy middle section, as they just re-do the same really interesting parts over and over, like the final Giygas battle, which is VERY influential, and yes, quite good.</p>

<p>Well, there’s Mother 2 done. I really only have one more thing to do…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Mother" /><category term="Earthbound" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 36</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 36" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B7NVOLu.png" alt="&quot;Hey Aya, when we kissed and did that lewd stuff, what exactly were you thinking?&quot; &quot;This rocks. I'm so glad I'm alive right now. Thank God my parents made me take aikido classes.&quot; &quot;Noooo don't think about your parents while we're doing it, dammit!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Yuri Story About a Girl Who Insists “It’s Impossible for Two Girls to Get Together” Completely Falling Within 100 Days</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Yuri Story About a Girl Who Insists &quot;It&apos;s Impossible for Two Girls to Get Together&quot; Completely Falling Within 100 Days" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 8-13</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/27/LizstartrekVOY3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 8-13" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/27/LizstartrekVOY3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/27/LizstartrekVOY3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JD9myCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Future’s End II</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P5ZqPsw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Aaand we’re back. Tuvok is getting some burritos, hes a big fan of tex mex. I guess the whole “the Voyager appeared in the sky aand everyone saw it” thing isn’t really important, okay. They hand wave it with a “people think it’s faked”. Sure, I guess.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JZ85vJB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay, the more I watch this villain, the less I like him. He legit feels like a fucking mary sue in a fanfic. Oh, he had holo-emitters set up in his office, of course. Also he already reverse engineered a holo-emitter device that allows the doctor to move around freely. And he can use an apple PC to outsmart Voyager. Yes he’s using 500 year technology on them but that’s not how technology works, and that’s not how this works at all. If you give a computer to a dude from the 1100s he would be able to use it to defeat a conquistador, is what I’m saying. This ENTIRE concept is completely out the window, none of them are selling it, and since it’s the entire basis of the episode, it makes it less and less likable the more they push it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JYKtC69.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They warp Elon Musk up, which they should have done ages ago, with Sarah Silverman helping them out now. But of COURSE Elon Musk has a fucking machine that makes it so he can disrupt transport, which seems like a BAD idea, but also he’s a fucking dumbass. It DOES make Chakotay and Torres crashland in Arizona though, where they’re found by anti-government farmers who capture them, accuse them of beign spies, and threaten them with SPAS shotguns. Where the mother fuck did these people get military grade weapons? Also they keep insulting Chakotay because he’s a native. I hate this episode, I think. I think they’re implied to be WACO? JFC.</p>

<p>Elon Musk is trying to go to the future so he can steal more technology and sell it. It’s “for the betterment of mankind”. Eat my ass. Anyways he escapes, there’s some chase scenes, they also get Chakotay and Torres out. And when Elon Musk tries to fly in the future, they just blow him up with a sneaky photon torpedo. Then Braxton shows back up and takes them to the future. This episode made the first part worse by comparison. All the worst parts of the first episode are the parts this episode focused on. I’ll just pretend the Doctor can walk around freely now cause they bought it from a merchant or something.</p>

<p>This episode was originally planned to be a FOUR PARTER. Thank the fucking lord. Also, they wanted to bring Silverman on as a main character. That would have been SO GOOD, and made the episode at least okay. But no. Apparently Berman heard their offers and went “Absolutely not &gt;:(“ Cause MORE WOMS ON MY SHOW? ABSOLUTELY NOT. Fuck Berman.</p>

<p><strong>Warlords</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/65RG1O3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Neelix in the holodeck getting a foot massage, which seems like it might be a sex thing for them? Foomox.</p>

<p>Anyway this episode has nothing to do with that. They rescue three people from an exploding ship, though one of them dies as Kes is working on him. Kes immediately starts acting kinda weird, and breaks up with Neelix in an awkward scene, and then when they go to drop them off, she and the two survivors hijack a shuttle and fly down. Turns out that the guy who died, Tieran, is a mind jacking virus basically, who swaps bodies when he host dies. 200 years ago he was the ruler of this world, and he’s been working on starting a rebellion to place himself back where he belongs. So now Kes is an evil psychotic bitch, and is very, very sexy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ZdV98s.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She also seduces the 2nd son of the Autarch, after murdering his father right in front of him. So like, Tieran is a man. He was a man in life, he’s still assumedly a guy at heart. But I guess for a mind swapping virus, gender means little. But like, still a guy. And here he is, seducing a guy. This is one of the gayest things ever seen in Star Trek.</p>

<p>Tieran stays in Kes’s body because she has psychic powers and he can use it to kill and coerce people. Kes being evil is very hot, btw. Have I mentioned that? This episode is a lot less interesting for its actual plot and more for the weird kinkiness of all of it.</p>

<p>They try rescuing her, sending Tuvok on a solo mission. Tuvok is caught. They plan more things, but it seems like they may not need to. Kes is starting to win out in a mental battle, there’s a big “fight inside the mind” scene, I love those.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EEHyF2K.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually, Tieran focusing on the battle within and becoming unstable makes his empire crumble around him. His fortress is stormed, and the Voyager crew go and take him out using a medical thingy the doctor made, wiping him out first from Kes, then from a person he tried to jump to again. The episode ends with Kes having severe PTSD about all the people who died cause of her hands. Also, she and Neelix just aren’t together anymore. Even though Tieran is the reason they broke up, she had no control. It’s never really explained, and there’s no conclusion. That’s weird.</p>

<p><strong>The Q and the Grey</strong> - VOY
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vTrO6uc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Q shows up and asks Janeway to fuck him. Hey, remember when we saw Q last time? In that episode, he was a sexist pig who treated Janeway like shit. Now he’s like “you’re so hot, fuck me”. This is EXACTLY how I expect weird sexist assholes acting. Hating on women but god damn they wanna get in that pussy. Anyways, he’s really, REALLY pushy, and I kind of hate it. He’s like “oh I’ve been lonely, havign dated anyone for a billion years”. I guess Vash is nothing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zYvKjSh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey, a female Q! She’s apparently basically married to our Q. She’s also played by Key’lar, the half Klingon who fucked Worf, and one of the hottest people in Star Trek. She’s a haughty bitch who hates everything here.</p>

<p>Anyways Q teleports Janeway to a civil war representation and explains to her that he started a war in the continuum, based on Quinn’s teaching, the Q that killed himself earlier in Voyager. So now he needs Janeway’s help, because he thinks if they make a new species with a half Q and Human, it’d end the war. I don’t see it, but I dunno. He also talk about how this has never been done, Q are beyond sex, no Q has ever done it. Uh, you rememebr that TNG episode with the Q that had a kid who didn’t know she was a Q? Cause the writers did not!</p>

<p>Anyways, this war is causing stars to go supernova, so it’s actually VERY bad. The female Q is stuck in subspace, without her powers for some reason, and she works with the crew to sneak through a supernova, while Q and Janeway are in the Continuum, represented by the American Civil War. They try to get a cease fire, and the traditionalist Q are like “Nope. Time to kill you both :)” and are only stopped cause the Voyager crew somehow show up loaded up to the gills with the Q’s own weapons, somehow. Q and Q fuck, which makes this the first time completely uncensored sex was shown on screen, and Q has a baby. I still don’t get this plan, but it works, I guess. No more explosions.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V1kVfEy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode kinda blows.</p>

<p><strong>Macrocosm</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RUDGoWy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway and Neelix are returning to Voyager after a chat with some new aliens that Janeway pissed off. They scan the ship to find it’s floating dead in space, and some interference is making it so they can’t scan for life signs. They wander around, trying to find out what happened, but find no one, like the crew just disappeared in the middle of what they were doing. Systems are failing all over the ship, including environmental controls. And they find signs of Goop burning holes in the hull. Yep.</p>

<p>We’re doing an Alien.</p>

<p>Neelix gets gooped and feels sick. Janeway leaves him to grab a medkit, and he screams, disappearing shortly after. Now it’s just Janeway, a missing crew, and an unknown alien. What does she do? That’s right.</p>

<p>Go full Ripley.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JD9myCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is legit one of the best fucking things, already.</p>

<p>The episode now becomes Alien meets Die Hard. It’s actuallty badass. She sneaks around, sending out an SOS. Meanwhile, some weird bugs are floating around, and they sting Janeway. Uh oh. She continues to go around, and finds the crew all piled up, alive, but barely, sick with something.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3EXS5z0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway blows away a buzzing alien whatever it is, and then makes it to Medbay, where the Doctor is, of course, still alive. Thankfully he hasn’t shut down yet. He tells a story about how they were called to help some miners on a nearby planet suffering from an outbreak. When he beams back, they accidentally spread the virus, and it gets out of hand. The Doctor can’t explore, because his holo emitter gives off infrared, which the viruses use to track their victims.</p>

<p>The Doctor and Janeway work together to release the cure onto the ship, as the aliens from the start come to “purify” them, cause the only cure is to blow them the fuck up :) Janeway convinces them to hold off for an hour, as she tricks the viruses into the holodeck in a very funny scene, and then fucking bombs it with a grenade.</p>

<p>Good episode, big fan. And not JUST cause Kate Mulgrew is hot as fuck.</p>

<p><strong>Fair Trade</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TTAsYI3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix is acting weird. He’s trying to get In with all the people on the ship, trying to get more jobs on, and he’s kinda just getting in the way. I wonder what that’s about. Meanwhile, they come across The Nekrit Expanse, a vast uncharted section of space. To go in prepared, they go to a local trading depot. The person who owns it takes 20% of all deals and is a grumpy guy, but he’s fair, and willing to help Voyagert get supplies. While on the station, Neelix finds an old friend, Wix, who he parted on bad terms with. Apparently Wix basically took a bullet for him years ago. Neelix feels awful and wants to help his old friend, who tyells him to not worry about it. Seems HIS life is going better, but Neelix explains how worried he is. He’s never been past the Nekrit Expanse. His job, as a guide, will soon be moot. So that’s why he’s trying to get more jobs. It’s understandable. He wants to stay on board.</p>

<p>Things get a biiiit worse. Wix wants Neelix’s help (using Voyager’s tech) to help him covertly secure a deal. Yep, it’s drug. He’s smuggling drugs. And after Neelix has to defend himself, with a phaser, he’s now implicated in all this, as they realize that the phaser was from Voyager, and are searching for either someone on the crew smuggling drugs, or someone who stole a phaser.</p>

<p>Neelix is now caught in a hard place. He has a friend, who he feels indebted to, and also the crew he’s a part of. It’s a bunch of awkward situations. Especialyl as the episode devolves with Neelix asking the crew about their histories, and what they’d do in a situation like his, basically. And all the guilt weighing on him. It’s not at all bad, in any way, but I don’t personally like it. Those kinda things just get to me and make me very upset.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FYNeT99.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He has to steal some warp plasma to pay off the drug dealers. I guess they’re gonna like, snort it? Warp Plasma Challenge, let’s gooooo. But he doesn’t do it. He can’t. I mean, he asks what did Paris in, and Paris responds with “I think my biggest downfall was I didn’t tell the truth”. Like, how can you fight that? That was set up way too well. It’s like they all KNOW Neelix is actually doing it.</p>

<p>Neelix and Wix manage to confess, but strike a deal, turning in the drug dealers in exchange for them not being charged.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QzZWEU3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some REALLY good alien designs in this episode. Anyways, Neelix outsmarts the drug dealers with a clever venting plasma scheme.  The episode ends with Janeway giving Neelix a “I am very disappointed in you, but we are family. We’ll get through this” speech. It’s a good Janeway moment. And now Neelix’s job as guide is done, and we’ll move on. This is good, in a way. One of the issues with the first two seasons was the feeling we kinda weren’t going anywhere.</p>

<p>This episode was fine. It did have “very special episode” energy, but not nearly as bad as that one TNG episode.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dream Journal 10/27/24</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/27/Dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dream Journal 10/27/24" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/27/Dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/27/Dream.html"><![CDATA[<p>Had a dream last night that Games Done Quick was taking place in my Elementary School’s cafeteria this year</p>

<p>They had a giant pool installed in the ground, and one of the most anticipated runs of the year was a real life run where my friend Dowolf was going to swim, with no gear, in the pool, and the walls and floors would rise up and move out and try to squish him, and he had to dodge them.</p>

<p>This seemed COMPLETELY normal to me.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="dreams" /><category term="dream journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Had a dream last night that Games Done Quick was taking place in my Elementary School’s cafeteria this year]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 35</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/26/OOCY35.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 35" /><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/26/OOCY35</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/26/OOCY35.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3cEuRpR.png" alt="&quot;That's what I... love about you&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mTshXK4.png" alt="Oh shit I said it face" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Hana Ni Arashi</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Hana Ni Arashi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>