<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-12T13:01:46-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 22</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/12/OOCY22.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 22" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/12/OOCY22</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/12/OOCY22.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L7KFuQy.png" alt="A girl freaks out in a photo booth and throws hands" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Rutou-san ni ha Kanaimasen</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Rutou-san ni ha Kanaimasen" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 14 - Block Koala</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50-15.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 14 - Block Koala" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50#15</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50-15.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IHT4K7Z.png" alt="Koala" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I don’t think any game fell for me harder than Block Koala.</p>

<p>When I first opened Block Koala, I was ecstatic! It’s a sokoban game! I love sokoban! Unfortunately, it seems I forgot the unfortunate truth. Not every sokoban game is Void Stranger. Most are not.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wnPSr0K.png" alt="Koala" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is a pretty standard sokoban title, with the twist of a few unique mechanics. Basically, blocks are weighted, and they can only push other blocks if they’re of a greater or equal weight. You can push blocks onto one blocks to add to them, which will help you push heavier blocks you need out of the way. There are a few other unique mechanics down the way too, like a clone movement guy, and blue blocks that can ONLY be pushed by other blocks, but other than that, pretty bog standard.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Blhej7N.png" alt="Koala" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If there’s not much in terms of mechanics, a sokoban title lives or dies on its good level design. And the level design here is… okay. It’s okay. Not very interesting. And there’s SO MUCH OF IT. This is one of the longest games in the entire collection, at a whopping FIFTY levels. I liked it for the first ten or so and the last 40 were honestly mostly boring. A LOT of what the levels are is what I call “big loops”, where you just loop shit around over and over. It’s a common sokoban thing but it doesn’t GOTTA be. Y’know, Void Stranger.</p>

<p>I might be a little spoiled by Void Stranger being so good.</p>

<p>It feels soooo long by the end. A video of perfect level clears and nothing else is an hour and twenty minutes, so you can guess how long it’d take someone to beat it trying to actually solve the damn puzzles.</p>

<p>It’s cute and charming, sure. The weight mechanic is kinda interesting but honestly a little confusing at first, it takes trial and error to learn how it works, cause y’know, no manuals or in game instructions. And it has a level editor feature which is real impressive for this era, but eh, I can’t be bothered.</p>

<p>One of the more interesting things about this game is the backstory that LX Systems is STILL trying desperately to get people interested in their games in other ways. There was a level design contest for this, which is pretty neat.</p>

<p>6/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 14 - Bushido Ball</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50-14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 14 - Bushido Ball" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50#14</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50-14.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EwYGOT0.png" alt="Bushido" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One new staff member for this one, Lanila Baler, who’s brought on for additional graphics staff. The office is quite packed. Also, I forgot to mention Joy Akebi joined for Avianos, which is wild cause she’s one of my favorite members of staff, so I went back and fixed that.</p>

<p>So, LX Systems has made 13 games now, and uh, it’s not going amazingly. They’re losing money, and with having to hire more and more staff, it’s catching up. They’re trying to do more unconventional methods of advertisement, like with this game, where they put on a tournament at a local bar to drum up excitement. This bar, and the winner, are credited in this game. I like that idea, it’s a cool idea, though I wish they had done it for a more interesting game. This is also one of the first games where Chiffon Bola took a more important role, as the lead gameplay designer, but like… it all kinda falls flat for me.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QDS7cPX.png" alt="Bushido" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Bushido Ball is a sports game, the first true sports game of the company, and I don’t really like those much, but they CAN be good. And this is clearly inspired by one of the best ones ever: Windjammers. The game is a pong-like sports game, where a ball is in the middle, and you control a person running around. You need to hit the ball with your weapon to try and get it past the opponent. After hitting the ball twice, you gain half a meter. This meter can be used for a special move by double tapping attack, or for a full charge hit by holding A, using up a whole meter bar.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/baCiTLd.png" alt="Bushido" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s also worth noting on top of VS, it also has co-op, to become a kind of doubles tennis game, which is neat, but I have no friends, so I can’t experience it.</p>

<p>There’s really not much more to it than that, to be honest. Like, there’s no sound or music during the game, except for when a player wins a round, a little jingle plays. The art is really nice, and I like the different character designs. They’re all varied, and have unique abilities that seem quite balanced. And like I said, Windjammers is king, but it’s too slow and clunky compared to Windjammers, which is smooth and exciting and FUN. This is just a bit boring. It’s not bad conceptually, but I just find I don’t care about it, at all.</p>

<p>Sorry, Chiffon ):</p>

<p>5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 13 - Mooncat</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50-13.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 13 - Mooncat" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50#13</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/12/UFO50-13.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t7347JZ.png" alt="Mooncat" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It is 1985, and while it’s important to note that Thorson Petters has worked at the company the entire time since he originally made Barbuta in 1982, he has not really headed a project SINCE then. He’s made all of the music and sounds for the past 11 games, but never has he directed his own specific game, since Barbuta. Why is that? Well, this game is the answer. Mooncats is the spiritual sequel to Barbuta, and Petters has been working on it for the past two years. The game has no credits, it kicks you right back to the menu after you beat it, so I assume Petters made it ENTIRELY by himself. Once again, Petters shows himself to be the Artist of the group, the weird one who created the weirdest god damn things. Like this.</p>

<p>Also, outside of the meta narrative of UFO 50, this game is one of those games that was released as something else before being put here. This game was made by Eirik Suhrke, the musician for UFO 50, in 48 hours for Ludum Dare 34. It was called “..and the mooncats”, and it got 8th place. I don’t know Mr. Suhrke, or anything about him other than that he solo made this, Barbuta, and all the music, so I imagine he’s a bit of an IRL Thorson Petters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WJn98Fy.png" alt="Mooncat" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When I first saw the next game I had to play was called “Mooncat”, I was really excited, because I like cats, and I like the moon. Put em together! What greets you when you start the game is a weird little spotted sausage on legs, and the most CONFOUNDING controls you’ll ever experience. You’re floated into the first area, and with no prior knowledge, will press the D-pad to the right. This makes you walk left. You press the d-pad left. This ALSO makes you walk left. You try another button, pressing A. This makes you walk to the right.</p>

<p>Mooncat is like a video game from another universe, and not even the universe all the other UFO 50 games are from. Its controls are like nothing else I’ve ever experienced, like a universe where the d-pad was never invented. It’s extremely interesting. Mooncat is a two button videogame. And to simulate that, the entire d-pad is one button, and A and B are the other button. So you can just play it by pressing up and A for the entire thing. The left button makes you move left, the right button makes you move right. When you press them together, you jump, in the direction of the first button you were pressing when you pressed both together. You can press then together again in mid air to do a ground pound to hit enemies and bounce, or to drop through platforms. You can double tap a direction to roll and dash for a little bit.</p>

<p>Your goal is that you’re plopped into a level. Platform through it. You have your traditional exit through each level, but levels might have secret hidden portals as well. These can be found by looking for flowers, which will hint that a portal is nearby, or just looking for any platforms and paths that look out of the way and hard to reach.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jsrloGx.png" alt="Mooncat" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There are a few other little tricks. You can bounce some enemies to other locations with ground pounds. Jumping over a skull on the ground can cause secret platforms to appear. Stuff like that. There are three endings you can reach, by going through different portals. They’re not difficult to find, per-se, but the exploration is part of the fun.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UYPwwFC.png" alt="Mooncat" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The other part of the fun is how god damn weird this game is. Nothing is explained. You press start, you’re thrown into it. What you are is not explained. What you do is not explained. Nothing is explained. You see yourself as a weird fetus at one point, and you’re going out hunting for eggs, which contain random things, like slime, a reference to Barbuta, or a red mantis, which will appear in later LX Systems games down the line. If you’re supposed to be like, a newborn baby, this game is BRILLIANT, because it fucking feels like it. Trying to learn how to control it is difficult, but you get your footing little by little, until you’re doing some complex platforming. The platforming is never like, fucked. It’s less than Mario 1. But it’s complex for a newborn, which is what you are.</p>

<p>This game was fucking weird as hell, but that is its charm, and it really grew on me. I think it succeeded in its mission extremely well. Just don’t ask me to explain the Lore of the Barbuta-verse to you.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 12 - Avianos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 12 - Avianos" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50#12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-12.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uEJP5VD.png" alt="Avianos" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the most out there games of the entire collection, just showing that despite LX Systems not really having much commercial success in this period, they were making some REALLY out there and fascinating games. And, frankly, EXTREMELY uncommercial. Fuckin’ look at this thing.</p>

<p>This is also the first game in a bit with some new members of the crew, joining the team with the start of 1985. Y’all, meet Ester Mac and Shayn North. Ester is a programmer, and did the AI here, and Shayn is a graphics guy. We’ve also got KC Levin on testing, and Smolski’s nephew, Boby Smolski, who helped with dinosaur fun facts around the office. And we’ve also got one additional member of the crew, one of my personal favorite members of staff: Joy Akebi. Joy Akebi was brought on to help with sound and music, which makes sense cause it was just Petters before now, though it’s funny it was THIS game cause it doesn’t have much sound. Joy Akebi will become a major force of good in the office, in my opinion, and a lot of great ideas and choices can be directly attributed to her input.</p>

<p>The office is getting pretty packed! It’s also worth noting that of the 10 different staff members, 4 are women. That’s <em>unheard of</em>. I mean, there were LOTS of women in tech in like the 50s 60s and 70s, but they had pretty much been kicked out of the profession by men by that point. LX Systems was a very progressive studio, in a lot of ways.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tP7S01s.png" alt="Avianos" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Avianos is a 4x game. In 1985. It’s the far future, Humans blew each other the fuck up, and now it’s the reign of the birds. But they’re going down the same dark path as the mammals, and waging war, worshipping ancient Dinosaur gods. In this 4X strategy game, your goal on each map is to keep and hold 4 or more fortresses. You do this by praying to your gods, which each do three things when you pray to them. These things range from moving units to another square, taking ownership of it, gathering resources based on your buildings, building new buildings, recruiting units, or using magic spells like freezing enemy units or spying on how many units are in a space. Every two times you worship an ancestor, their favori will increase, allowing you to upgrade one of their three actions to a better form. This results in a LOT of variance and strategy.</p>

<p>Seriously, this game is pretty deep, and I bet multiplayer is WICKED.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nwOFhZJ.png" alt="Avianos" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When your units collide, the game enters an auto-combat mode. The only things you can tell your units to do are to attack, hold, run, or destroy your own buildings if you know you’re going to lose and don’t want the enemy taking it. It’s shockingly deep. A lot of my strategy WAS just to build a Giant Murderball, but hey, what works works, y’know? There’s a lot of good strategies that work.</p>

<p>This game is some wicked fun, and is SUPER interesting. But also very intimidating, and you’ll have NO clue what you’re doing at first. It’s like a little boardgame more than a video game, but hey. I like board games. Prolly not for everyone, but really cool.</p>

<p>8.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 11 - Kick Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 11 - Kick Club" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50#11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-11.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/crDGaLM.png" alt="Kick Club" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This one is one of my favorites of the collection. Kick Club is a single screen action arcade game, in the same vein as Bubble Bobble. Games like this, inspired usually by Bubble Bobble, were quite commonplace back  in the day, especially in arcades. They were tough as nails, and fun as hell with friends.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vxVSBO.png" alt="Kick Club" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Kick Club you play as either a guy or a girl running through sports themed worlds. You’ve got net sports, olympic sports, ice sports, and ball sports. Your only defense against the denizens of these worlds is your trusty soccer ball, which you can kick, aiming with the d-pad, to defeat enemies. As they’re defeated, you’re awarded junk food. Quite fitting for a fitness themed game, obviously. You can chain enemies to get better junk food. Go for the high score!</p>

<p>It’s a simple game. Ten levels for four worlds, the last level being a boss fight. There’s not much to it and it’s not too long, but it is a tricky little game. Quite challenging. You’ve gotta learn all the enemies and their patterns! It’s a really fun one though, and the music is REALLY catchy. I wake up some days with this in my head.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QIFnFYX.png" alt="Kick Club" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I don’t have much more to say about this one. The credits give special thanks to Chun and Smolski’s childhood coach, and the local burger joint, but it’s still made by the core team. It’s just a cute and very fun game. Apparently there was a VS mode that was planned, but didn’t make it in in time. Honestly, the game is fine without it. The co-op is prolly loads of fun, too.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 21</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/11/OOCY21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 21" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/11/OOCY21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/11/OOCY21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YCcHDX7.png" alt="A woman holding up a smart phone. &quot;We need to get rid of this oppressive symbol of reality.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Futari Escape</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Futari Escape" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 20" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R0AaJwj.png" alt="&quot;A woman kabedoning another with her leg&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Black &amp; White</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Black &amp; White" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 9 - Attactics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 9 - Attactics" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50#9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-9.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EUTyCA2.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>We’ve got the core team for LX Systems, there won’t be too many changes for at least a little while, so there’s not much to say about this game other than to talk about the game itself.</p>

<p>Attactics is a strategy action game that’s pretty different from anything I’ve played. It’s a realtime turnbased game. You’ve got a 5x8 grid, and units will spawn randomly on each side of it. Those units will then move every single turn, depending on what kind of unit they are. Turns go automatically, every few seconds. However, you can grab and shift your units, moving them up and down, or back. You can shift and swap units this way, as well, for maximum strategy. When a unit kills another, it gets a promotion and deals extra damage. The goal is to just get enough units to the enemy’s side, to knock down all their flags, and you win!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/McWFLo1.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got a bunch of unit types, each with different strengths and weaknesses. Grunts will be immune to melee damage if they’re in a column of 3 or more units. Archers will shoot from afar if a unit is in their sight, instead of moving. Shieldmen are tanky as fuck and can block arrows. Cavalry move twice, good for sneaking through weak spots and getting quick damage in. Spearmen attack two spaces instead of just 1, through units, good for hiding behind shieldmen. Assassins will throw daggers up and down as they walk. Sappers will explode when they die, which blows up the enemy, but can ALSO blow YOU up. Aaand then there’s heroes, unique units that happen every 5 promotions on certain stages, and they move twice as far, pierce two stages, and start promoted like, 5. They’re good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9TJpbvh.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And that’s it! Battles are tense and hectic. The AI can’t move at all, so it usually gets like, 70% more units to compensate. I imagine multiplayer is WILD. The description of the game explains that the game was delayed cause the devs just wouldn’t stop playing it, and the credits show that “Chiffon the Strong” was the office champion. It just shows how the vibe was in those days at the office. Their games aren’t selling… amazingly, but they’re loving what they’re doing.</p>

<p>This one was pretty alright, and then grew on me a bit more. It’s nothing amazing, but it’s fun for what it is. And not super long.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 10 - Devilition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 10 - Devilition" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50#10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-10.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tInZkFa.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Devilition has an interesting IRL story behind it. So I’ve been talking about the in-universe characters who supposedly made these games, and are credited as such, but there’s a REAL actual team of actual people who made them, and they kinda split up the work, each person creating a few different games. I’m not sure who created what, exactly, except for a few of them where it’s obvious (Hello Velgress/Upwell). In this case, it’s obvious, because in 1999 Derek Wu created a game called Diabolika. That game was repurposed for UFO 50, with some touch ups and changes. Apparently in the original, the little devils had big swinging dongs. They don’t got that here. There’s a few other changes, too, I’ll get into those.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EjakEoN.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Devilition is a puzzle game where you play an alchemist trying to keep a town of puritan-esque settlers alive from a horde of Demons. Each round, devils are placed randomly about the board, and then you can place your pieces anywhere on the grid. When these contraptions explode, they explode in different directions, signified by the colors emenating from them. So you’ve got ones that explode in a cross, an X shape, you’ve got ones that blast out further, ones that blast all around, ones that do 3 spaces in front of them, ones that only do side to side, aaaand the rocket, which will blast up then fall on a space, blasting all around. Your goal is to try to kill as many Devils as you can this way, while avoiding the settlers. At the end of a round, if the settlers outnumber the devils, you move on. If not, you lose, start over. If you get rid of ALL the demons, you get an extra settler. You can kill your settlers all you want, which is fucked up, all that matters is that they are equal or outnumber the demons. After ten rounds, you fight a boss, who’s actually extremely easy, and you’re given a score based on your time, pieces used, and settlers left.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a0Lz65u.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And that’s it! It’s not a very complex puzzle game, and while it seems okay at first, it falls a bit flat to me on repeat plays. I acknowledge I’m not very good at this game. It is not kind to those with ADHD. I get distracted and suddenly forget an entire third of the board is there, or think I planned out a way to deal with THAT ONE devil, and nope, I forgot about it again. But the real thing about this is that it’s a bit of an RNG fest. The game can absolutely give you unwinnable situations, especially if it clumps a bunch of the devils together that take two hits to kill, with no room to put anything near them. I had that once. It tends to spawn things away from your already set up contraptions, and I had one left over by accident, and whoops, giant clump in the corner :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dIyrft7.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s FINE, it’s a fine game, but the music, setting, idea of it, all of it just doesn’t really speak to me. It’s notable though that this setting of all settings will be re-used later, far, far down the line, and for MUCH better effect.</p>

<p>5.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>