<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-06T13:05:35-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 171</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/04/OOCY171.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 171" /><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/04/OOCY171</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/04/OOCY171.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mEvxKEn.png" alt="'Her girlfriend got stolen away.' 'Wassuuuuup! Can you see us? You were always going behind her back with other girls and making her cry, so we're giving her an extra special good time today!' 'Ahhh... I'm so sorry, Yuuki...' 'Your skin's so smooth~' 'WHAT THE HELL?! THAT'S SO FUCKING HOT! You're telling me I still get to watch this for free?!' 'But she's complete trash, so it was no problem.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Amazaki Suika</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Amazaki Suika Comic Collections" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 195 - Dragon Quest 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/04/RA195-DragonQuest5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 195 - Dragon Quest 5" /><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/04/RA195-DragonQuest5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/04/RA195-DragonQuest5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sHV0TKH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I finally played all of the Dragon Quest games on the NES. So it’s only fair I jump to the next console too, right? There’s plenty more Dragon Quest games to play.</p>

<p>This one never actually came out here. After Dragon Quest 4, or Dragon Warrior as it was called here, came out, the series went slightly dormant for a while in America. Frankly I’m stunned DQ4 came out here, but the prevailing idea was that as RPGs were becoming more and more popular in Japan, the American market was dead. So what was the point? This version has NEVER been released over here, so all we get is fan translations, but that’s okay. This actually got two re-releases. A PS2 remake, and then a DS remake, which we FINALLY did get. But enough about the background, how’s the game?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7Asm3gN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Dragon Quest 5 is considered one of, if not the best, games in the entire series. I think it’s… good! If I had to rank them for you, I’d put the series right now at 4 &gt; 3 &gt; 5 &gt; 1 &gt; 2. So, in the middle right now, but that doesn’t mean it’s bad. 3 and 4 are just fantastic. This game is better than all those in one particular standpoint: It’s story.</p>

<p>Dragon Quest 5 is about the life of a single guy. I called him Abel. Abel’s mom was stolen by demons as a kid, and his dad has basically been doing his best raising this son and also trying to find his wife. He’s also the king of a foreign country. Anyways, you play as Abel, starting as a young child, making friends, and throughout the game you go through like, 20-30 years of life.</p>

<p>The game doesn’t do an amazing job of showing this? Like, you leave your friend prince’s castle, take a boat, and go to another continent. You do one quest there, and go back, and your friend is like “damn, it’s been a few years! You’re lookin’ good, I got married! :D” and I’m like “it’s been 20 minutes”. There are time skips that are more visible, but that’s the general vibe you’re gonna get. Your wife gets pregnant and gives birth in a 15-30 minute dungeon.</p>

<p>Oh, yeah, your wife. This game has a Wife feature. You have two wives to pick from. One is your childhood friend you fought ghosts with, and have a connection with, and one is this random rich girl you met for 2 minutes who is clearly into someone else. So like, it’s not really that much of a choice.</p>

<p>Two other fun things about this story. 1: It’s a continuation of 4! You almost couldn’t tell, because the world map is so drastically different, but it’s the same world. One of the dungeons is the same thing, but falling apart from age, and the Dragon God is here. The other fun thing is that you are NOT the legendary hero. This world, as most DQ games do, has a Legendary Hero who is supposed to save the world from the coming darkness. That is NOT you. At no point do you overcome that like it’s some Wind Waker plot, no, it’s just not you. It’s your son instead :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Hg4p53y.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I do like the plot, it’s really good and makes you feel some things in a lot of moments. But I’m just not as into the world and dungeon design. DQ4 had a fun story with great characters, but it also was fun to play for me, with a big fun world and dungeons to explore, but this for some reason wasn’t quite as fun. I dunno. Maybe it was the mood I was in? Who knows.</p>

<p>Oh, it does have one other feature to set it apart. This game has monster catching! Monsters have a percent chance to ask to join your team after a battle, based on the type of monster. Some monsters can’t join, but there’s a wide selection to choose from. This wasn’t as in depth of a system as like, Megami Tensei to me, and you don’t get to name your monsters, instead they come pre-named based on their type. But it’s not a BAD system. I’ve just played better.</p>

<p>Over all, good game! Like an 8/10, it comes recommended. I hear DQ6 is a serious letdown compared to 4 and 5, so I’m taking a break before tackling that. I think I’ll work on another RPG series…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 194 - Mario’s Point &amp;amp; Click</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/03/RA194-Mario'sPointandClick.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 194 - Mario’s Point &amp;amp; Click" /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/03/RA194-Mario&apos;sPointandClick</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/03/RA194-Mario&apos;sPointandClick.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eH8JnvO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the wildest things I’ve ever experienced. So, did you know the N64 had a mouse? It was made for the N64DD, and therefore has very little use, but it DOES exist. Well, someone took those protocols, and made a version of Mario 64 that uses mouse controls. Yes.</p>

<p>It’s literally just Mario 64, entirely, with no changes. Except when you click someowhere, Mario moves there. When you right click, a menu pops up, and you can select from a long list of commands. Things like jump, long jump, attack, etc, as well as a variety of effects you can turn on and off, like wallkicks or crouching.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t2oUzDW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It DOES have one unique area added for the hack, a tutorial area designed to teach you the mechanics. But other than that, nothing is changed. And it’s 100% completable. Not a single thing is impossible. You look at it, and immediately go “there’s no way”, but yes. Nothing is impossible. I did it all.</p>

<p>That’s not to say it’s easy. The slides are HELL, and any moving platform is the most evil thing on the planet, but you can overcome it. See, this hack turns Mario 64 from a 3D platformer collectathon to a puzzle game. And it’s WEIRDLY fun? I replayed Mario 64 the other year for the first time in a while. It was…. fine. Not as good as people say, but also not as aged as others say. It’s like, an 8/10, good game, but some of the later levels are so frustrating. But here? I had a WEIRDLY fun time trying to maneuver Tick Tock Clock. Playing it casually with normal controls, I was getting annoyed, but I died a BUNCH here and didn’t care at all, just hopped back into it.</p>

<p>I really recommend this, it looks intimidating and very much a “what the fuck” kinda thing, but it was a LOT of fun.</p>

<p>Oh also, I made this set. I guess I should mention that. I was given this as a Kusogrande match and loved it so much I had to make the set and then beat it lmfao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="N64" /><category term="Romhacks" /><category term="Mario" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 170</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/03/OOCY170.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 170" /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/03/OOCY170</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/03/OOCY170.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KPD4752.png" alt="Yako-san is super thrilled. 'We've gotta have each other's backs for stuff like this!' Yako-san suddenly looks less thrilled, with KILL in her eyes, 'and the fact that we live in a society where gay partners have to expend this much effort simply because they want to live together never fails to stoke the smoldering rage in my soul! :D' 'The rage is showing in your eyes, Yako-san!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She Loves to Cook She Loves to Eat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 19 - 22</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/03/LizstartrekVOY7-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 19 - 22" /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/03/LizstartrekVOY7-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/03/LizstartrekVOY7-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5UJb0zM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Q2</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZXNgynX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Q is back! And he brought his son! Remember Q? Q is Q’s son. We saw Q and Q have raw unsafe sex on screen, not a joke, and then Q was made. Janeway is Q’s godmother. Everything about those sentences is 100% accurate. This kid actually bears a striking resemblance to John De Lancie. There’s a good reason for that, cause he’s his son and everything. Q leaves Q, who I’ll just call Q2 now, on Voyager, aaaand he’s very annoying.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KWNxXrt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He makes a dance rave in the engine room. He tries to embarass Seven by vorping away her clothes. She doesn’t give a shit, so he gets bored of her and leaves. Seven is the ONLY person immune to Q. They need someone to rein him in. Enter Neelix, the person on the ship who’s best with kids. It doesn’t go well. He loses his vocal cords.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Qq3WS8B.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually it hits a head when he wants to see what humanity is like under pressure, and sends some Borg over who almost kill everyone before Q fixes it. Q goes to Janeway for advice, and basically, in the end, Q has to shape up in seven days, or he’ll be turned into an amoeba for all eternity, and he’s turned into a human for those seven days.</p>

<p>It starts well enough. They kind of set him up to fail, but he can actually do things well when he wants to. The problem is, he doesn’t want to, and he starts to use Icheb and other people’s kindness to make him do thing for him. But Janeway is smart enough to know immediately what happened, and gives him ONE more chance, but it’s no longer hands off. They are now rough on him, but it works out very well. He actually becomes a pretty good person after a few days. But turns out that’s not good enough. He’s becoming a good Human. Q doesn’t want a Human. He wants a Q, whatever that is, because our “miniscule minds” can’t understand it.</p>

<p>Janeway offers for him to just stay a Human instead, but he doesn’t want that either. He wants to be a Q, like his father. Aww.</p>

<p>Q2 decides to just hide so he’s not turned into an Amoeba. Weird flex, cause you’d still stay a Human that way, but alright. He basically kidnaps poor Icheb, his only real friend here. Icheb is NOT happy. They also immediately get fired upon and almost killed. Icheb gets horribly injured this way. And Q refuses to heal him, because that’s just another lesson. Welp. Poor Icheb.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RH1IWco.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Q2 steps up and goes back to the people who fought him, accepts full responsibility, aaaaand it was all a test by Q. This actually makes sense, the one time we saw Q test Q, it was when Q was made a Human and the test was passed when he offered to die for someone else. Buuuut it’s not enough. We see Q in those stupid fucking outfits again, yaaaaay, but then they give him a LESSER sentence of staying a Human. But once Q says he’ll quit being a Q if they do this, they decide not to. Apparently. Q says so, at least. If you MUST know, there were a few minor concessions.</p>

<p>As payment for helping them, Q gives them a few year boost on their journey. Now it’s only… 50 more years. Yay!</p>

<p>It was fine, I liked it. Q2 was fun, well acted. Felt his turn around was a little too sudden. He goes from lazy to hard worky to bored in between single hard cuts.</p>

<p><strong>Author, Author</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FR8F0gQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with the Doctor in a swanky suit, looking like Atrus about to write me a book to Riven, and we hear that book, then we get the Doctor walking around behind himself, saving the edits to his new book. Ooh.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Reg, Seven, and Steven develop a new setup that will allow for 11 minutes of live video communication every single day. They have a face time, and they also show a live feed of Earth, that’s cute. So now there’s a line forming, set up by slots, on who gets to talk first. The Doctor gets first dibs, and uses it to talk to a publisher about a new holonovel he’s writing. It’s… sophisticated art. Paris decides to experience it, cause he’s the person on the crew most interested in holo novels. It’s a little long winded. And then we get the first chapter and we see some of the characters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5UJb0zM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>BAJORAN CHOKIE. BAJOKIE. Look at his fucking face tattoo holy shit. The Bajoran symbol with a Cardassian snake on the pike. Christ.</p>

<p>Anyways the characters are huge assholes. Very accurate. Bajokie demands the doctor heal a certain character first. When Paris refuses, Fake Janeway comes and shoots the injured crewmen instead and goes “now no one is in line.” He tells the others about it, who find it mostly funny and laughable, but decide to check it out too. It’s kind of an interesting reprise of the episode where there was a holo novel about a revolt.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y4Z7mLz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sexy Tuvok with a goatee appears on screen. “Say the words, Liz”.</p>

<p>The Paris Clone makes the doctor leave so he can fuck a crewmate in the medbay. Human Torres Clone is like YOU ARE A TOOL, NOTHING MORE. The holo emitter is 50 kilos. Someone should ask the Doctor if he’s okay. This is Republican level “I’m a victim”. There’s also a sub plot with Seven of Nine’s clone trying to help him escape, but it fails. And the main point of the holonovel is stated, outright: He has no rights.</p>

<p>Janeway is NOT pleased, but the Doctor makes it clear, it’s not about them at all. It’s about the Alpha Quadrant. His fellow holograms like him are scrubbing garbage scows. And he thinks that this will bring their plight to public attention. Understandable. But he doesn’t care if he hurts his friends feelings to do that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QFuSY0G.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor goes to make a few edits to his novel and finds that it’s been edited, and cannot be turned off. It’s now about a sleezy Doctor. That fucking hair. The doctor is OFFENDED, but hey. It’s not about the Doctor! He just kinda looks like it. When he gets pissy as Paris, it hits REALLY hard. Paris handles it amazingly. “I thought I was starting to make you view me in a better light. I’m just worried that I haven’t been. Here’s your holo novel back.”</p>

<p>Neelix liked the Doctor’s novel, that’s cute. The Doctor wants to rewrite it though, and Neelix offers his call. What… what was Neelix going to use that call for? was he just gonna call a random fucking person on Earth?</p>

<p>There’s also a subplot about connecting and reconnecting with family. Seven is observing the others as they do their talks. Torres reconnects with her father after decades.</p>

<p>Weeeeelp, the Doctor asks them to hold back on publishing the holonovel, but they do it anyway. Why? Cause it’s good for them, and the Doctor has no rights in Starfleet, cause he’s a hologram. Whop whop whop. The point of the holonovel was pretty accurate and true after all. Tuvok now has to do Picard’s job and give the Doctor rights, 11 minutes of a time. It doesn’t go well, cause lol who cares about hologram’s legal rights. Dude I thought we solved this 20 seasons ago, back in TNG.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9xi3cFf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But the Doctor has one thing up his sleeve. Friends. People who care about him, and will help him gain his rights. Even with how the Doctor has treated the others and said in his novel, he’s still their friend, and they’re still going to help him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RtRe857.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>As a finish to the subplot, Seven talks to her aunt, her only living relative. It’s cute.</p>

<p>The judge eventually says “I’m not going to say holograms are people because lol I dunno. But sure, he can legally recall his book”. Holo victory in a few ways. Especially since so many have already played it… but you know who’s playing it the most. All the holograms currently mining and cleaning up trash. We get an end shot of these holgrams slaving away.</p>

<p>This doesn’t feel quite Measure of a Man, but it was very good. I dunno if anything will COME of this, it feels like it should, but we’re kinda running low on season for it to get a conclusion. I mean, I don’t like the plot point. We’re a post scarcity socialist utopia, why are we CONSTANTLY obsessed with creating slave labor??? But its fine.</p>

<p><strong>Friendship One</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tyRRI2D.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a cold open of a thing landing in a planet as people study and go “wtf is that”</p>

<p>Janeway is talking to an Admiral about the Voth. Too bad we’ll never see them again, they sound important. Anyways he tells her about a new job they have for her. “Friendship One” was a probe from 2066 that they sent out that kept giving out a message of peace and outreach. It should be nearby, so we need to go collect it. I dunno, last time we did that, Chakotay had a weird-ass meltdown.</p>

<p>Belanna wants to go on the away mission, Paris says no cause she’s pregnant. She agrees, but next baby they have, he has to carry it. He says deal. Man, too bad Voyager ended this season. We could have gotten an M-Preg episode! Now we have to wait till Enterprise. Anyways they land. It’s a poisonous frozen wasteland. While down there, they find example that people lived here long ago… Or now. They pull weapons on Paris, Neelix, and rando. Back on the delta flyer, Kim and Chakotay are attacked and Chakotay makes them just fucking leave, abandoning the away team. Alright then. They DO collect a guy who tried to sneak on board though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/e8rmICb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Verin, their leader. He demands they help his people off the planet, in exchange for the hostages. The guy they collected explains that they used the info from the  probe to make antimatter… and it blew the fuck up, irradiating the entire planet. They believe it was intentional, some evil act for some fucking reason. Obviously not, and they want to do what they can to help, but it’s hard when you’re not trusted.</p>

<p>So it’s time to make some trust. Janeway listens to the person they have, a scientist, asking his advice and thoughts. Paris tries to befriend a little girl. Neelix tries to connect to them by explaining the Metron Cascade. It doesn’t always work. The adults make the girl stay away, and they get a little offended by Neelix trying to connect him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3AE5Lhp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They offer to send food and medicine in exchange for one of the hostages. They send Joe Carey, a guy who’s been around for a VERY long time. He was the guy in season 1 who was going to be head engineer and butted heads with Torres. And now he’s dead. He’s sent with a hole shot in his heart, as a sign of “no, we will not compromise at all”. Fucking cold.</p>

<p>Paris delivers a baby, and Tuvok and the Doctor comes and saves the hostages, doing a trick and a Uhura maneuver. A bit of a false flag operation, nbd. They send the baby up with them for treatment. Janeway is ready to send the baby back after treatment with food and medicine and leave. Neelix and Paris, the two hostages, refuse to leave. Cause what the fuck, we NEED to help these people. Yes they killed Carey, and they said they don’t really want our help, but we need to do our best to help them, anyway.The scientist they got originally helps them, and most of them are willing to hope… not the dude who murdered Joe, but fuck that guy I guess.</p>

<p>Well, fuck that guy doubly. He decides to send a fucking nuke at them. But everyone turns on him. Good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dX6Og4o.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everything worked out. At a high price. Yes, Joe Carey was only a minor character in a few episode, but he was here for seven fucking seasons. He was building a Voyager in a bottle ): Anyways, good episode. As a note, the rest of my group watching this with me did not like this episode very much.</p>

<p><strong>Natural Law</strong> - VOY
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/74PbmBL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On a way to a conference, Chokie and Seven (God don’t put these two together) are observing nature when they hit a weird barrier and crash land on the planet instead. Whoopsies!</p>

<p>At the same time, Paris is flying in the Delta Flyer and gets a message that he broke a law. He was going too fast and he penalty is a 3 day safety flying course. Here’s Memory Alpha’s description of the episode:</p>

<p>“En route to a scientific conference on Ledos, Chakotay and Seven’s shuttle is driven out of control by a force field layer over a wilderness area. Meanwhile, Paris gets a speeding ticket in the Delta Flyer, and is sentenced to a three-day safety course.”</p>

<p>What an incredible use of meanwhile. That’s a fucking TNG Season 8 description if ever I’ve seen one.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J4jXGcc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find some native people on this technologically advanced planet. Chakotay’s injured himself and has to stay near them even though he’s like “we can NOT interract with these people”. He’s found cause he’s sitting RIGHT fucking next to them, and then when they treat his wounds, he’s like “Welp guess we’ll just break the prime directive, whatever”. Fucking Chokie. They don’t communicate, and were kinda spooked by the com badge, so they broke it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eTn6fhz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh I’m sorry, this isn’t a picture from this episode. But it really worries me that it’s hard to tell a difference. I never say this, but can we focus on the B plot? This is just a bunch of Native American stereotypes. It’s… extremely painful. I thought we were past this, y’all. I mean obviously we were not, you hired a KNOWN FRAUD as your Native American instructor, but I thought we were beyond… <em>waves hand wildly</em> THIS. And Chakotay is throwing himself into it. He’s learning their hand signal language, says goodbye like them. Like, yes, I’d prolly try to do a similar thing if I was in this situation? I guess I don’t begrudge him that, but I would have done everything I could to not contaminate this culture because that’s MY JOB AS STARFLEET. I’d put in more effort is what I’m saying.</p>

<p>And Seven is struggling alone now, trying to get stuff from the crash. She don’t want to communicate or help the native cause <strong>that’s their fucking job</strong>, and is suffering cause of it. She’s the bad guy in this :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GbcGOqq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode can bite me. This girl who took an interest in her helps guide her, but she guides her to… enjoy some scenery. See, Seven, you were trying to escape the crash landing too much, you should have stopped and smelled the roses while hanging with the pre-bronze age civilization that’s going to make you a God.</p>

<p>We learn what’s the deal with the area. The civilized aliens here are the Ledosians. The people inside as the Ventu, basically a pre-evolved version of them. Centuries ago the Ledosians were fighting the Ventu for land, and polluting their spaces, so an alien species saw this and built the barrier. But as a result, the Ledosians, even centuries later when they’ve gotten better and wouldn’t hurt the Ventu, have no way of lowering the barrier.</p>

<p>Luckily, Seven and Chakotay lower the barrier from the inside out. But it ends up hurting one of the Ventu. Seven stays behind to help her, the girl who was so curious about her. The girl gives her a blanket as a gift, which is sweet I guess. I much prefer this, and kind of would have liked a “Seven meets a pre-vocal civilization and befriends a girl there” episode, but I dunno. Anyways all’s well that ends- oh whoops, the Ledosians are now moving in, and are like “Now that the barrier’s down, it’s time to colonize :D We can educate them and get so much more land~” Ohhhh no.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WqPoMlQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They try to teleport back their thing keeping the barrier down. They fire on Voyager instead to lower their teleporters. While Paris is doing his test, he gets orders and violates every single law of space flight they have to get the teleporters back. It’s KIND of fun!</p>

<p>The Ventu had a profound impact on Seven. She’s sad about what might happen to the Ventu if the Ledosians ever find a way to lower the barrier using her technology. Maybe she shouldn’t have developed it. He goes “Well, if you hadn’t, we’d still be there, and I’m glad to be here”. Yes Chakotay, we know you don’t care about those aliens’ well being or their culture.</p>

<p>Compare this to the TNG episode where Picard’s people interrupts a pre-warp civilization, and they form a religion about TNG, and how that’s handled, and you’ll agree with me that this episode is bad, especially in comparison. The Paris stuff was funny.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episodes 1 - 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/03/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episodes 1 - 3" /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/03/LizstartrekSNW3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/03/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Hegemony Part 2</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEvb4AL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Following directly after last season, the Enterprise is surrounded by Gorn, and some of their people are captured on the Gorn ship. The Enterprise is forced to retreat… but not before tagging the Gorn ship with a dud missile that’s actually a secret beacon.</p>

<p>Pike’s girlfriend, Batel, is infected with Gorn Babies and they might need to kill her, but to prolong things, they’re freezing her in a block of ice. Specifically SHE’S the one asking them to kill her if they need to. Well, at least that’s the PLAN, but turns out she’s allergic to being stuck in a block of ice, which I imagine I’d be too. Now Nurse Chapel is stuck trying to figure out how to cure Being A Gorn Mom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vvOBev.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Admiral April is like “we have to just ignore all this and let the Gorn capture neutral people” and Pike, being Pike, says fuck that shit, we’re being treated as Prey. And April agrees, unofficially, their rules are to punch the Gorn in the nose and show they’re not prey. Meanwhile, in Engineering, Scotty and Pelia the Warpcore Witch are trying to get a Gorn Cloaking Device up. Scotty says it’s impossible. Pelia is like “we’ll have it done in an hour sir”. Scotty is, one day, gonna be REAL good at doing the impossible on a deadline, and he’s gotta figure out how to get good at it real fucking fast.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Gorn ship, La’an wakes up and punches her way out of a Gorn sack. She rescues the other members of the crew captures, including Sam Kirk (Kirk’s brother), Doctor M’Benga, and Ortegas (who has had half her hand melted off). They want to get out… well, three of them do. La’an decides then and there, she’s going to save ALL the other colonists. Good luck.</p>

<p>Y’all remember Mitchell? She was a very minor background character in season 1, had some minor roles in 2, and now she’s on the bridge and refuses to leave until they can solve this. Yay, Mitchell!</p>

<p>They have some SMALL hope. Batel has a 14% chance of survival if they use Una’s blood. Yay! Also the Gorn seem to go to sleep when a certain kind of star flare happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jFp5msI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FkBzvR4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit is going way, WAY worse. Man this is tense. While exploring a weird binary star that seems to hide the Gorn homeworld because of radiation, they find a BUNCH of Gorn ships blasting out of the zone and going towards Federation space. Now Pike has a choice. He might lose the tag on the colonists and his crew if he leaves to warn Starfleet, but they are NOT prepared for an invasion. So he makes the impossible choice and leaves them.</p>

<p>Pike seems so fucking done. He’s EXHAUSTED, he’s worrying about every single little thing. And can you blame him? When he goes to Scotty and Pelia like “Hey can we make a solar flare” and Scotty is like “what the fuck no. Not without doing this this that and this which will blow up the ship” Pike is like “Sure just do it without the blowing up the ship part” and everyone just… stares at each other.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of “have faith” talk in this episode, which we keep making fun of by posting Star Wars memes. It doesn’t help when Ortegas takes over a Gorn ship and flies them out in a scene that is VERY Star Warsy. Also Ortegas becomes massively injured in the skirmish, but sticks too it. Poor Ortegas, she can’t catch a break ):</p>

<p>We get a fuzzy fisheye scene with them in the radiation, but it works. They use the flare to trigger a hibernation in the Gorn, as they come back to go eep. Ortegas raises her deathflag REALLY high but is saved just before dying, thank fucking God. <em>sees death flag in Ortegas’ mouth</em> WHAT DO YOU HAVE THERE? PUT THAT DOWN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/evmRMxM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Batel is saved, Spock and Chapel have a moment of acceptance, and the Enterprise is beat to fuck. But alive. It ends the “have faith” talk with Pike thanking God for some reason.</p>

<p>I thought it was alright! Not blowing me away, but good! Excited for more.</p>

<p>I’ll be editing this page every week and reposting it with the new episodes as they come out =w=</p>

<p><strong>Wedding Bell Blues</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9FnKzZH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s 3 months after the nightmare of the last two episodes, and the Enterprise is repaired and ready! Everyone is going to a gala to try and relax! I’m sure this’ll go exactly as expected! To try and get into the spirit, and to practice for getting things going well with Nurse Chapel, Spock is practicing dancing with La’an.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Yol3Cdf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>BUT NOT A BRAIN! :D</p>

<p>Anyways, Chapel comes on board with the doctor she’s been working with for three months, Roger Korby. He’s a very friendly guy, but a bit eccentric. Anyways Spock almost makes an ass out of himself before we find out Korby is, in fact, dating Chapel now. Whoops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AkPLZfu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy HELL, Uhura’s outfit is on point.</p>

<p>Ortegas is doing better. Physically, at least. We meet her brother, who is flirting a bit with Uhura, who seems reticent. Ortegas isn’t into it, though.</p>

<p>Everyone gets together to drink a bit. Spock is, as usual, awkward. He steps away for a drink at the bar, and we get this like, weird Mxptlk mother fucker who’s tending bar. He appears as a Vulcan to Spock, but to us, he’s a weird mother fucker. He gives Spock a drink, who…  wakes up later that night next to Chapel. They’re getting married! Oh boy! I’m sure Chapel will handle this very well!</p>

<p>This Mxptlk ass dude is basically acting as wedding planner and getting everything all right and dandy. Is he a… shipper? Of Nurse and Spock?? I will say, over all, I haven’t really… been into the Chapel and Spock thing? It’s not JUST cause I know it won’t go anywhere, but also cause of how they just… don’t go together lmfao which I think this episode is doing its best to try and show.</p>

<p>Korby is the ONLY person who seems to realize something is wrong. He can remember things how they SHOULD be, and is trying to subtly sabatoge the wedding. Spock catches him, and he explains that this is all wrong. Spock punches him out, but then for some reason remembers that yes, this IS wrong, and… well yes, feels bad, but most importantly is like “this needs to be fixed”. He and Korby work together, they’re both smart science boys, and though they love the same woman, they have to work together to figure out what’s wrong.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3XmlT3E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s kinda fun to watch these two try and wander around a changed reality, testing at the waters and touching the boundaries to find where they are. Spock tries to get others to realize something is wrong. He tries to get Kirk to punch him. He insults his mustache. It doesn’t work.</p>

<p>When they confront the Wedding Planner about this, he reveals he’s a giant fucking baby and this is all a game to him, which they’ll have to play, or he will wipe everyone from existence. Welp. Korby and Spock change up their plan and yeah, the only thing they can possibly do now really, is try to go along with it. When Korby DOES act up, he’s turned into a dog, and no one else seems to care. They’re really just his puppets.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JsdWJEP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually Chapel snaps out of it too, thanks to Spock, and when the Wedding Planner announces everyone is going to die. But he’s interrupted by his… dad. Who is, in fact, played by John de Lancie. Hmm. The bartender is just a kid, and he’s made to clean up his toys. Everyone is like “WELL THAT WAS WEIRD” and then tries to celebrate the actual reason they’re there, the Cenntenial. La’an dances with Spock, who has no regrets. We have one of the three armed aliens from TAS, who joins the crew as their bartender, yay! Aaaaand Ortegas has a PTSD episode. Yay!</p>

<p><strong>Shuttle to Kenfori</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uMeF8wz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Somehow, the Gorn Tissue has returned. Patel is still sick cause of Gorn, but they think they have a way that can fix it. It takes a flower, but it can only be found in a no-fly zone that would cause a Klingon War if they went to it. So Pike does an off the books mission, setting himself up as the person who’d take the fall if it goes bad. Mbenga goes with him, cause y’know, it’s a medical thing. It’d be a good idea to bring a Klingon War Vet to this possible Klingon area~ And on the way they get a warning beacon of “GO BACK OR DIE”, which is weird to have on a planet where no one’s supposed to be there.</p>

<p>There are no life signs on the planet. It’s a jungle, but no animals, at all. And they find a corpse that probably died after the evacuation. Welp, it’s Aliens time or some shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vZ8WhBe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While going through an old building and gathering their flowers, a Klingon shuttle (the first in the series? At least that I’ve seen) comes and blows their ship up. Now they’re being hunted by some Klingons, oh boy! It’s two guys and a woman who appears to be in charge.</p>

<p>The Klingons get them, but then they’re attacked by… zombies. Just, straight up zombies. They eat a Klingon alive. Jesus CHRIST. I dunno if we’ve ever seen ANYTHING like this in Trek? It’s now a fucking zombie horror movie. By the way, this planet, Ken Fori, is named after Ken Foree, the lead actor in Day of the Dead.</p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, they plan how to rescue their crew. Still radio silence, they dunno what happened, they just haven’t heard anything from the ground team, so they go after them with a very slow, but safe tactic. Ortegas is VERY unhappy about this and pretty insubordinate. La’an is worried about her health, which we know isn’t doing very well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XiJNsUb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So this flower causes genomes to like, fuse, basically. Hybridize people into different things. They tried to use it on a moss that could grow anywhere to make a super food. It accidentally hybridized with corpses and now there are zombies. Mbenga refuses to call them Zombies. Pike keeps using the “Z” word. And now that he knows what the Chimera Flower does, he knows that it’ll turn her into a Gorn hybrid. He is NOT happy about this, but it was her decision, and is the only way anyone knows to save her.</p>

<p>They get chased by more Zombies, and find themselves with the Klingon girl behind a force field. She stabs Pike, and we find out that she’s the daugher of Dak’Rah. Remember him? He was the dude from last season who was a straight up war criminal who was trying to act like he had changed, and was killed by M’Benga in a scene where it’s not clear exactly what happened, if it was self defense or not. Now it’s coming back to bite him. She hated him so it’s no problem there, but she’s sure that if SHE had killed him, she would have brought honor back to her house, and now she has to kill his assassin. And M’Benga admits that he intentionally killed Dak’Rah, it was NOT self defense.</p>

<p>We get PTSD War Hero M’Benga again.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8tXJNvH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a fight scene between M’Benga and this Klingon, fighting with D’ktaghs. In the fight, they damage the force field generator, which is probably not good. M’Benga then wins the fight and chooses not to kill her, which is maybe the rudest thing you can do to a Klingon. So she chooses an honorable death by sacrificing herself. No one will know, but she will. And so with M’Benga, who respects the choice.</p>

<p>Some good flying by Ortegas gets them to save the away team, though Una is VERY unhappy with how Ortegas has been acting. And now Pike has to decide whether or not to turn M’Benga for doing a murder. But luckily, M’Benga only told a story to save Pike’s life when there was a knife to his throat, so, y’know, checks out.</p>

<p>Uh oh. Ortegas intentionally did a bad job so they’d do her idea instead. It was unneccesary, because Pike and M’Benga were going to get on a shuttle anyway and would be safe, and she endangered everyone. So she gets a slap on a wrist, but a “please do not EVER do this again”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5tW9bd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel and Pike have a heart to heart about it. He’s like “why didn’t you tell me?” “Because it wasn’t about you, and we both know if I did tell you, you’d tell me not to do it and find another way even though there is no other way”. Which y’know, he did. On the planet. So she’s right. And then it just… ends. I guess we’ll find out next week how it goes!</p>

<p>This one was uh… fine. I dunno how much we needed zombies in Star Trek but that’s fine. Fun Klingon fight!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 169</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/31/OOCY169.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 169" /><published>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/31/OOCY169</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/31/OOCY169.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fmUJpe6.png" alt="'Fufufu, I made you moan &lt;3' The other girl, Ritsuka, reacts by getting bashful and biting her. 'Wah! What the?! It hurts! It hurts!' Jump cut to the next day, with her dressed up in a heavy scarf. 'Why have you been wearing a scarf all this time, Kozuka-san?' 'Ah... well... a cat bit my neck...' 'Eh?! Are you okay?!' &quot;Eehehe...' then, internally, 'curse you, Ritsuka!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Even If It Was Just Once, I Regret It</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Even If It Was Just Once I Regret It" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 193 - Dragon Quest 1 &amp;amp; 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/31/RA193-DQ1+2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 193 - Dragon Quest 1 &amp;amp; 2" /><published>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/31/RA193-DQ1+2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/31/RA193-DQ1+2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jjlm4fx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So after playing Dragon Quest 4, I was in a bit of a Dragon Quest kick again. I decided to take advantage of this by playing one of the many, MANY re-releases of the games that exist, starting with Dragon Quest 1&amp;2 on the Gameboy. This is a combo package of… well, DQ1+2. Its what it says on the tin.</p>

<p>This came out in 2000, so over a decade after Dragon Quest originally did. Though it’s not actually the first re-release. DQ1 and 2 also got a release, as a single package, on the SNES. Obviously this is nothing like that, because that’s a major graphical overhaul. I’ll have to play it someday.</p>

<p>I played this off stream, because DQ1 is such a chill cozy game to me. It’s a nice grindy game to relax to while watching something, and I beat it in like 4-5 hours. I know it very well by this point. DQ2, on the other hand, was a bit more effort. I had only ever beaten DQ2 one other time before this, last year, so I didn’t know it NEARLY as well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R2g0vmi.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The games are MOSTLY the same, but there are some significant differences. The graphics, of course, but there’s some different equipment in 1, backported from 2, and it felt like the grind went even faster than it does on the NES, so maybe numbers were upped too. Oh also the translation is different, so she’s no longer Erdrick, she’s Loto now. I prefer Erdrick. In DQ2, numbers were upped a bit again, it’s still kinda hard and rude, but it’s a lot less rude feeling than it was on the NES. The most notably differences, however, is you can get puff puff in DQ1 now, and in DQ2, there’s a scene where the Prince, the 2nd character you meet, gets sick and you need to heal him to get him back in the party. Which is NOT needed to beat the game, so you  can beat the game with only two characters from that point on. As a challenge, I guess. I did not do that.</p>

<p>Dragon Quest, and many games from this point on, would begin re-releasing their older games adnauseum. But most of the time these days, it’s a super up to date version, or just the old version again with no differences. This was interesting. They could have made DQ1+2 on like, PS1 or something, but they didn’t. They used an 8-bit machine. So it’s really just DQ1 and 2 again, but with slightly different graphics, and slightly updated UI. Which hey, I like those games, so why not, right?</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievements Unmastered 4 - Digital Devil Story - Megami Tensei</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/30/RAUM4-MT1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievements Unmastered 4 - Digital Devil Story - Megami Tensei" /><published>2025-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/30/RAUM4-MT1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/30/RAUM4-MT1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/acCOcH6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I made the Unmastered series of posts to showcase games that I beat, did not master, but still wanted to review. This is a bit different. I actually did not beat this game. But I’m playing the sequel, and loving it, and expect to master it, so to talk about it, I wanted to talk about this one too, for context. There’s also a lot to talk about.</p>

<p>Megami Tensei is one of the most important RPG series of all time. Kind of. See, Megami Tensei was pretty popular, then it got a spinoff series called Shin Megami Tensei, which superceded the series and became so much more popular people forgot the original existed. And then that series got a spinoff series called Persona. And now some people don’t even know about SMT. And even LESS know about and remember MT. Even even LESS know about and remember the fucking book series that this game was based on. But is that fair? Let’s see where this series started, and determine if it’s unfairly forgotten…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rXevEMk.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Megami Tensei is a sequel to the novels. Basically, the idea is that Nakajima invented a computer program that let him summon Demons into this world. He used it to try and get back at and scare some bullies, but it went WAY too far, and now he’s trying to stop the Demons. There’s also stuff about him and his gf Yumiko being a reincarnated God, I dunno, I didn’t get to any part where that’s mentioned, if it is in this game. This game is VERY low on story, character, or plot, but the basic idea is you need to traverse this labyrinth and find and defeat Lucifer. Along the way you’ll explore different areas and defeat the generals there before finally fighting Lucifer. There aren’t really any smaller stories in this areas either, it’s pretty straight forward.</p>

<p>And now, the gameplay. Megami Tensei is a dungeon crawling RPG in the style of Wizardry. In fact, it’s basically just a Wizardry game. And, look… I like retro RPGs. A lot. I REALLY love NES era RPGs, ones people say “aged poorly”. I will happily play Dragon Quest 1 until the cows come home. But this… this feels like it goes beyond aged poorly. It’s missing so much shit that we take for granted today, and utilizes it in ways that fucking hate the player. This game is very, VERY rude. And it, like Dragon Quest, is almost completely a grind-fest. But it does NOT make that easy, or pleasant, to accomplish.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mtIcl6u.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You have stat allocation. Be sure to allocate it correctly, or you’re fucked. There’s a single place to save the game, heal, fuse monsters, and cure status effects. You can get spells to do some of these things, but if you get to the deeper areas, and Yumiko gets hit by a numb status effect, you gotta wander aaaalll the way back to undo it. While draining health, and being attacked by a ridiculous encounter rate. When you enter a door, the encounter rate is like, 60%. Also, the game crashes. A lot. A LOOOOOT.</p>

<p>But that pales in comparison to the #1 most fucked up thing I’ve ever seen in an RPG like this. Some enemies have attacks that drain your levels. Yes. ENTIRE LEVELS. Just, boom, hit by this enemy? Your levels are gone. You can run sure, but you’ll probably fail running at the worst time… and since you’re grinding like crazy, you’re probably on autopilot anyway, so you’ll miss that you’re fighting the level draining enemies, and suddenly whoops, 2 hours of effort is gone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dNFgWp5.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, what DOES Megaten bring to the table? It’s not just a rehash of Wizardry with really rude mechanics. It DOES have a lot of cool ideas, but they’re also implemented…. weirdly. This game has a monster catching mechanic! You can befriend monsters then summon them using your computer. They drain resources when they’re out, but you usually make back more than you drain if you’re just killing everything. They gain no levels, but are invaluable. You can also fuse them together to create new demons. Very useful, and neccesary to continue. It’s confusing and needs a guide for you to get anything done, but still, cool idea.</p>

<p>What ISN’T cool is the monster catching itself. In later games, you can influence it slightly. In this game, it’s all RNG baybee. Good fucking luck. And many demons just can’t be tamed, so you’d never fucking know, but they can and WILL take your bribes, just like all the ones that can, so you’ll just assume you’re VERY unlucky.</p>

<p>Megaten is… a rough game. It was cool for the time and had some good ideas, but frankly, there’s no reason to ever go back to play this now. Just play Megami Tensei 2.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Megami Tensei" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Unmastered" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 168</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 168" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PDdBpKW.png" alt="'Two girls look back at each other, one on a train that's about to move away. The train girl is pulling down her face mask to reveal her blushing face'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oJHRxce.png" alt="'Train girl leans her head down bashfully as the train rolls away'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n3Jgc2r.png" alt="The girl outside of the train starts blushing 'CUTE! OH MY GOD SO CUTE!! SHE'S SO CUUUUUUTE!!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: From Aiu Station on the Hiragana Line</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="From Aiu Station on the Hiragana Line" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>