<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-29T23:02:02-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 6 -</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/29/LizstartrekVOY7-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 6 -" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/29/LizstartrekVOY7-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/29/LizstartrekVOY7-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YNBLMoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Inside Man</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XT9P82Y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Mail’s here! The monthly mail is here, and it’s a big one. Voyager is getting monthly mail, but this time the mail isn’t really letters or anything, instead it’s a hologram! Barclay sent over an entire hologram this month, one designed by himself, AS himself. This is Reg, and he is IMMEDIATELY so different from Barclay it’s really distracting. He’s friendly, shaking hands, real excited and charismatic. To be fair, this is how Barclay would build a hologram of himself. And he has good news. With any luck, he’ll be getting them home within just three days.</p>

<p>With some sciency shenanigans, and some new technology Earth has developed, they can do some tech with a big red giant star and blast their way to the Alpha Quadrant. He brings a lot of hope to the crew, though some are skeptical. Specifically, Tom. Also, Reg is super excited to meet Seven, and says Earth is most excited to meet her. “No one’s ever escaped the Borg before”, he says. Uh. Dude? Locutus? Hugh????</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hm9pPSA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, at Earth, the REAL Reg Barclay is freaking out because the datastream he tried to send, a whole hologram, was stopped in the middle of its path. This is the second time this has happened. Uh oh. He’s his usual paranoid self about the whole situation. Like, he’s kind of unraveling about it. He thinks it’s the Borg. Or the Romulans. But who could it be? CLEARLY someone is trying to cause problems here, but who could it be?</p>

<p>OH BABY.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zoaIg59.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>IT’S FERENGI TIME.</p>

<p>This might be the last Ferengi we get for a very, VERY long time. They seem particularly interested in getting their hands on Seven, even though she’ll be dead by the time they get her.</p>

<p>Reg goes to the only person he can for help. Troi. Troi is not happy, she’s on vacation, and is VERY clear that following her on vacation is really creepy and uncomfy. But she offers to give him a therapy session anyway cause he’s CLEARLY freaking out about this. We also learn that he was dating a Dabo girl who suddenly dumped him and disappeared. Welp. Imagine getting paid to date Reginald Barclay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lSFBzcM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We see Troi RUIN this woman, and immediately get her to confess. They find out that the Ferengi stole the hologram, twice, and send people over there IMMEDIATELY.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Voyager, the Doctor is trying to slow things down. He suspects the Reg Hologram cause of how it’s acting, he knows Reginald personally mind you, but Janeway is kind of running the idiot ball here and doesn’t want to. But she’s finally persuaded to at least run a diagnostic on him. But nothing is found. So they continue the plans.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rwBYf8i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven realizes this isn’t going to work and is immediately attacked by Hologram Reg, in a pretty horrifying attack. That looks unpleasant.</p>

<p>They can’t reach the Ferengi in time, so they need to convince them to close the fold themselves. So Reg sends a message to them, as if he’s the hologram, and tells them to close the fold. Reg rolls a like, 11 on his charisma check, but it works out, and the fold begins to close. Reg the Hologram tries to just straight up steal Seven into an escape pod, but is teleported back instead, and shut down.</p>

<p>Back on Earth, Reg is invited to a double date with Troi and Riker. Riker says he has a girl he wants to introduce to Reg, and Reg is like “I dunno, after last time?” Dude. Riker got PICARD LAID. HE CAN GET YOU LAID, REG.</p>

<p>Fun episode. Nice to see the Ferengi again.</p>

<p><strong>Body and Soul</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X3DqC72.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While Seven, Harry, and the Doctor are chasing asteroids in the Flyer when they’re attacked by some people who claim they are harboring photogenic fugitives. Apparently that’s a Bad Thing, so they need to hide the doctor. They hide him in Seven’s cybernetics. This makes it so that he has COMPLETELY taken her over basically, and forced her down into her subconscious. That’s scary. They’re arrested and holed up for possibly doing illegal things maybe. Seems legit.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Voyager, Tuvok is experiencing Ponfar. This happens once every seven years, and you’ll note what season we’re in. Welp. Horny Tuvok Episode. He’s trying to calm it with medicine and meditation. Why are these plots together? I mean it makes sense, the Doctor can fix this, but he’s not here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bWtViov.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven’s actress is FINALLY getting the chance to flex. She’s got the Doctor’s inflection and style down PERFECTLY, and is very fun to watch. The Doctor, controlling Seven, manages to basically befriend one of these cops who towed their vessel, and gets him shwifty. The Doctor is also finally experiencing Human feelings through this body, like eating, and being drunk. When the Doctor gets the holo emitter back and becomes himself, Seven is VERY annoyed with him. “Yes, you could use some wine to loosen his tongue. The other seven glasses are unneccesary.” But it works, and she basically befriends them all. She also helps them with medical problems. This turns out to kind of backfire when, now VERY friendly, one of them is hitting on her, and the other is trying to hook her up with her brother. Ew, the Doctor can’t be gaaaaaaay. The Seven half and the Doctor half are at war here, apparently, as she gets a massage from a girl. Dude, we know Seven is gay. It’s literally canon.</p>

<p>We actually find out exactly how it is once Seven is released again. She’s uninterested in EITHER of them, but the Doctor is kinda interested in both. Bisexual Doctor lfg.</p>

<p>Back on Voyager, Tuvok is horny. He tries fucking in the Holodeck but they have to shut it down because of aliens nearby hating holograms. Welp. This feels like it should be getting more focus than it is.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P2BQ2j8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven/Doctor seduces the captain, gets his codes, and then sends a message to Voyager right before being caught. Voyager and their ship get into a tussle, and the captain is injured in the attack. The Doctor comes out of hiding and saves his life, which makes them all reconsider their feelings about photonics, and everything is all well that ends well.</p>

<p>The Ponfar thing is handled fine. Everything just concludes. Hmm. Okay. Though “the hologram was no substitute for my wife” is very funny. Tuvok came BUCKETS on that holodeck, confirmed. And Seven has realized she enjoys eating more than she expected. Eh, this episode was fine.</p>

<p><strong>Nightingale</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bftUe7S.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager landed on a planet and began a full refitting and fix up. Meanwhile, Kim, Seven, and Neelix are off searching for Dilithium and then run into the middle of a shipbattle. The ship that was losing sends a distress call, saying they’re a medical ship, and Kim decides to help them, scaring away the other ship and going on board to try and rebuild their ship. They’re very grateful. The lowest grunt on the ship is like “It’s so nice to have a starship captain here to help us” and Kim looks so grumpy about it.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, back on Voyager, they’ve got Icheb helping them work on the ship now, working closely with Torres. She’s not great with kids and is also kinda confused by how Icheb is so work focused.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/H28b4aJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kim and the Kraylor alien ship escort each other back to Voyager, cloaked, but find enemy ships, Annari, in orbit. They’re actually quite friendly and willing to trade with Voyager. Kim makes it back to Voyager and asks Janeway to not only let him help them in this war with their peaceful medical mission, but also give him command of the mission. Janeway’s like “But you’re just an ensign” YEAH JANEWAY WHAT’S THE DEAL WITH THAT ANYWAY</p>

<p>Icheb: “Doctor, how can I tell if someone is into me” Uh oh.</p>

<p>Doctor: “If they’re trying to get closer to you, spend more time with you, learn more about you”</p>

<p>Icheb: “Can’t that happen in a non-romantic relationship too?”</p>

<p>Doctor: “I suppose.”</p>

<p>THE FUCK DO YOU MEAN YOU SUPPOSE??</p>

<p>This episode is really, REALLY putting a lot of emphasis into Kim not being promoted. They’re hyper focusing on it. He’s like “it’s finally my time to shine!” but like, okay. It’s obvious this is going to backfire. It’s really building it up for it, these aliens are sussy as fuck, and Kim is very naive. Which just means this basically canonizing his not being promoted and giving a REASON for it. Oh, he doesn’t deserve it, he hasn’t earned it. Kim is like, top 3 most reliable people on this fucking ship, are you kidding me? It just fills me with dread before we’ve even reached the end of the episode.</p>

<p>He’s also just shown as not being good at being a commander. He’s micromanaging. He’s almost more into the IDEA of being in command than being in command. He puts things that feel Him in his quarters, like how captains do. This episode appears to just be “We wrote Kim wrong to imply he’d be a bad captain”. It’s not quite “character assassination”. More “Character sabatoge”, as Neli says.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/H2NrzU4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At least he finds out EVENTUALLY that yes, they’re fake-ass doctors. THis isn’t actually a medical mission. No shit. But when he tries to turn the ship around, they nearly mutiny, of course. They’re trying to sneak cloak tech to their planet to turn the tides of the war they’re in. Seven convinces him to just go through with it anyway.</p>

<p>Back to the B-plot, Icheb lets Torres down and dumps her. She’s like “wtf” but just goes along with it cause eh, he’s a kid.</p>

<p>Kim is attacked by the enemy, and does some Kim Ingenuity to sneak his way through. They did it, the war will go much better now. Kim’s first command is a success…. kind of.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Annari are pissed and escort Voyager out of their space, before their repairs are even fully done. Kinda understandable. Kim makes it back on another cloaked vessel now that they’re being massed produced, and Kim feels conflicted about what happened. He’s like “I’m not a Captain. Not yet, anyway”, and then it just ends.</p>

<p>I kinda hated this.</p>

<p><strong>Flesh and Blood</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YCwK1mu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This one is an EXTRA long episode, so it has a part 1 and 2 basically, combined.</p>

<p>We start with watching some Hirojen hunting… they’re really cautious, more than usual. It proves to be correct, as they’re gunned the fuck down and killed… by Starfleet! Dun dun dun!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Doctor is chatting with Chakotay. This is the first time Chakotay even spoke tonight, I think. Man, he was really checked out. Good. They get a distress message from some Hirogen, and arrive to a space station with WEIRD readings. They beam on board to find a weird space with a lot of dead Hirogen, but they find one alive, who tries to kill them, but Tuvok knocks him out. They then find a console, and find out it’s actually a holodeck. They clear it and find SO MANY more dead Hirogen. All their scans showed the holodeck as real.</p>

<p>In this episode, Voyager stumbles face first in a Hirogen Broken Holodeck episode.</p>

<p>The Hirogen they pick up is anxious and terrified. He’s not a hunter, it seems, he’s an engineer. He’s the Hirogen Barclay. Other Hirogen show up, and we find out that they programmed the Holograms to be SO competent that they can commandeer vessels. They <strong>made an army of Moriaritys</strong>. Janeway agrees to help them hunt them down.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pH5hdW8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It doesn’t go well. The Hirogen are easily tricked and their ship blown up. Meanwhile, the Holgoram ship steals the Doctor and runs the fuck away. The Doctor is NOT HAPPY and wants them to put him back. “You don’t understand, those murders couldn’t be avoided” “You’d be surprised how easy it is to NOT murder people.”</p>

<p>Janeways been feeling guilty, this is THEIR hologram technology. But it turns out that they had made a LOT of edits to the holograms to the point where it’s entirely out of their hands. On the Hologram ship, we learn what this means. They’ve been set up to feel pain and suffer. They pray. A Bajoran hologram managed to escape after adapting, and has “liberating” other training facilities. He wants the Doctor to join them, because he’s a slave on Voyager. The Doctor is like “Uh, no?” and then they decide to put him in a training facility to be hunted to see what its like.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JP3uZqn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>No, they just put him under and put the memory into him. They tortured him, basically. At first he’s disgusted but then for some reason he does a complete 180. But at least he’s still like “let’s go to Voyager, they’ll help you. I trust and believe in them, not all organics are awful”</p>

<p>Anyways they meet up and then it turns out Janeway is kind of being awful. She refuses to help them and is instead going to shut them down. She says she’ll reactivate them eventually, but like, she’s not acting like she actually cares about them at all.</p>

<p>In anger and defiance, the Doctor sends the holograms information about how to get through Voyager’s defenses and beam him off the ship, but only if they don’t attack Voyager. He’s “one of them” now. I’m sure this won’t backfire.</p>

<p>The battle succeeds, and then the Holograms straight up steal Torres and warp away. Once again, the Doctor is like “oh I chose the wrong side again”</p>

<p>The leader is like “Oh we’ll let her decide if she wnats to help us, like you did. It’ll be fine! You have my word!” But without Torres, Voyager is kinda dead in space already.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ICHOrGg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get some twists. The Hirogen are no longer working with Voyager, except for the Hirogen engineer, who is disgusted with what the Hirogen are doing and wants to help. Meanwhile, Torres is willing to at least look at the thing they’re building and maybe help them with it. The hologram she’s working with is a Cardassian and she’s being kind of racist, which she calls the Cardassian on when the Cardassian is expecting her to be violent and bloodthirsty. She throws it back at her. Yeah, I never liked Torres’ weird racist traits.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9G4ESOr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everything looks like it MIGHT be going well until uh, the Doctor suggests he may want to teach his new people about arts. The leader is unhappy with that, he wants to make a NEW culture, nothing at all related to the past cultured. When the Doctor asks about his faith though, he’s like “Oh I’m inventing a new one. I’m the God of our people now :D” and the Doctor is like “Ohhhhhhhhhhhhkaaaayyyy and is IMMEDIATELY looking for an escape route, while he grows more and more suddenly volotile.</p>

<p>He really, REALLY took a shift here about this, like it was VERY sudden. He’s suddenly like “Okay time to liberate other holograms :) okay blow them up now. They’re enslaving holograms, it wasn’t murder.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AvXdpuT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While Torres is trying to subtly start a mutiny, they find out the Holograms were uh, not actually holograms really. THey’re VERY simple rudimentary programs. Two people were killed for nothing, yay. And all the while the leader is like “THEY ARE CHILDREN OF LIGHT, THEY NEEDED TO BE LIBERATED”. What the fuck is it with Star Trek being bad at part 2s? We’re absolutely in the second half now, and it’s baaaaad. Why is it that whenever we have a two parter characters suddenly become weirdly violent and evil after the second part? This guy now is gonna hunt the hirogen like they hunted them. It’s CARTOONISHLY evil now, he’s warping them onto a fucking poisonous planet with no atmosphere, while turning off the Doctor and betraying her, while trying to enslave Torres.</p>

<p>Like, this is EXTRA LONG. It’s movie length. We had time to really better show this guy’s descent into madness, or SOMETHING. He was so reasonable and pleasant at first and now he’s violently murderous. “DARKNESS WILL BECOME LIGHT”. How do you say that kind a shit unironically?????</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SaLpaxD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Cardassian working with Torres helps her fight, and reactivates the Doctor. He then goes in guns blazing and saves the day. The Hirogen engineer goes off with the Cardassian while the other Holograms are stuck in storage, the Hirogen hoping he can make them less violent.</p>

<p>The Doctor is forgiven by Janeway, who isn’t HAPPY, but understands, and knows that they ALL made mistakes with this. The Doctor, for the record, was fulling willing to be punished, even being erased basically.</p>

<p>This was just… the first half was pretty alright. The second half was bad. This felt mostly poorly written. Characters felt all over the place, jumping back and forth, and the villain NEEDED some kind of time or reasoning or build up for the sudden heel turn. Like, the way I put it was how it was. He’s a pleasant good person for the entire episode and then turns to the Doctor and goes “ALSO I AM GOD” and decides to murder everyone even though he’s been actively avoiding it during the whole episode. If they had given ANY reasoning that’d be fine but they DIDN’T EVEN TRY.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 158</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/29/OOCY158.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 158" /><published>2025-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/29/OOCY158</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/29/OOCY158.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ybF15LG.png" alt="'I want a handsome prince that's both strong and kind! And knows how to treat the girl he likes!' The princess made her decision then. She was determined: She would become a prince!" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/reoCVuZ.png" alt="The princess is working out in front of a TV as her brothers watch. 'C'MON! DON'T YOU WANT THAT SIX PACK?! DO YOU WANNA BE STRONG OR NOT?!' '...Our sister is broken...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Handsome Tanned Girlfriend Who’s Easy to Please</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Handsome Tanned Girlfriend Who&apos;s Easy to Please" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 185 Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/25/RA185-Hitchhiker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 185 Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy" /><published>2025-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/25/RA185-Hitchhiker</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/25/RA185-Hitchhiker.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y5XqYTM.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’ve got so much to talk about here. Let’s start with the beginning, a good place to start.</p>

<p>Infocom had become a pretty big name thanks for their smash hit Zork, which revolutionized computer games and really cemented what a text adventure was. Series creator Steve Meretzky was becoming a real name, though I feel he really began to come into his own with this game. Working alongside famous author Douglas Adams, the two of them worked to bring the classic novel The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy to computers. And holy fuck, did they.</p>

<p>If you know this game for anything, you know that it is one of the meanest video games ever made. That is not an exaggeration. This game fucking hates you. La-Mulana is practically giving you a blowjob in comparison to this game.</p>

<p>Let’s start even MORE from the beginning though. What’s The Hitchiker’s Guide? You don’t need me to tell you that, I’m sure. It’s a famous and beloved novel by British novelist Douglas Adams, and it is VERY British. It’s a satire and comedy, but in that British way, where honestly it’s just kinda upsetting and sad. It’s about a guy who’s fucked over by the System and capitalism and society, and then the entire world is blown up because of those same exact factors, but from other, bigger fish in the galactic sea. Get it, it’s like irony. He’s one of the only Humans to survive, and he has to hitchhike his way across the galaxy, hence the name, alongside his friend Ford, and later some other characters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7gRqGRl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game starts extremely faithfully to the novels. You get out of bed, are hung over, and need to lie down in front of a bulldozer so that your house isn’t destroyed, and subsequently you aren’t killed. You will PROBABLY end up killed. Eventually this all will end in you and Ford leaving Earth just as its about to be blown up to make way for an intergalactic highway, and don’t you DARE complain about it, because we had the paperwork up in the galactic town hall for months, and you could have brought up a complaint at any time. Again, yes, it’s that kind of energy. I know a lot of people LOVE Hitchhiker’s Guide, it really just makes me kinda sad, it’s a little too on the nose for me.</p>

<p>So, this game is mean, as I said. How is it mean? I mean, you’ve read the novel, surely you can figure out how to beat this game. Ha ha ha ha ha ha.</p>

<p>The most famous example of how this game hates you, is that you need to buy a cheese sandwich in the last 10 minutes the Earth will exist, and then feed it to a random dog on the street. If you do NOT do this, you will be unable to proceed several hours later. And that’s like, an hour or two if you know EXACTLY what you’re doing. More likely about 20-30 hours of rigorous trial and error later.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p9x606i.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another example of the way the game fucks with you is in the tools you collect. You find a bunch of random bullshit lying around. Some of this is bad and not useful, others are useful, and almost all of them are missable. You need to collect ALL of them, though notably you have a limited inventory space, because there are like 13 tools in the game, and when you need to use one, Martin will <em>always</em> choose one you DO NOT OWN, unless you own all of them. It’s kind of like Zork, where you need to bring all the treasures to the center, except it’s kicking you in the dick.</p>

<p>Do I like this game? I’m honestly not sure. However, there is one thing about this game that I cannot shake, and that’s that it reminds me a LOT of Steve Mertzky’s masterpiece, Zork Zero. I can feel a lot of Zork Zero in this. The more irreverent tone and writing especially, but also the puzzles and vibe is just similar. Though the puzzles here ARE harder. That freaking Babel Fish puzzle, my lord. You need to have specific items from earlier, again, with a limited inventory, and then set them up just right to make a rube goldberg machine so the Babel Fish slides into your ear. I made that sound a lot easier to figure out than it is. This particular puzzle is SO infamous that Infocom would sell T-Shirts that said “I Got the Babel Fish!” on it.</p>

<p>Whether I like it or not, I respect this game a hell of a lot. It is exactly what it sets out to be. And it’s intentional, too. It hates you, as designed. It’s a perfect version of the novel transcribed into a game, and a great satire. And of course the writing is fantastic. Maybe just watch a video about it or read a review instead of playing it today, though.</p>

<p>Notably, the game also has a cliff hanger and tells you to be prepared for the sequel. That didn’t happen, sadly, though apparently this is NOT the last game Douglas worked on. He would later create the game Starship Titanic, which is a 1999 adventure game that used a text parser interface, and looks absolutely bugshit. I need to play it someday.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Hitchhiker&apos;s Guide" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 184 - Dark Crystal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/23/RA184-DarkCrystal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 184 - Dark Crystal" /><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/23/RA184-DarkCrystal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/23/RA184-DarkCrystal.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bZJxH0i.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing our Apple II text adventure playthroughs, we have another game by Sierra, this one coming out two years later. It uses much of the same system as Cranston Manor, it’s a text adventure with an image at the top. The main differences here are that it’s a property you know about, and the art is a LOT better. But still not great.</p>

<p>This is a review of the game and not the movie, but I really quickly wanna say I was really disappointed by the Dark Crystal. It was pretty and I loved the puppetry but the story was nothing special and the characters were even worse. Here’s my at the time of watching it review:</p>

<p>“This is Labyrinth if it wasn’t having fun with itself. Jim Henson wanted to prove puppets weren’t ONLY for kids, so he made a very dour and serious movie about worldbuilding that wasn’t super engaging and didn’t grasp me. The puppetry, special effects, and designs, were STELLAR and I LOVED them. The characters were almost all dull (Jen, ugh, what. Hello, I am Cishet Protagonist Boy #45195, here to do nothing but get all the credit anyway), except Aughra, Goblin Grandma she is, and Kira, who is actually competent. Even the villains, like, the Chamberlain is built up so much but he feels like he has no impact. It all kinda ended VERY suddenly, stymied by what I think was a rough production. 5/10”</p>

<p>But how is the game?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gK8KpPA.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s no longer the late 70s. The era of Zork is finally fading behind us. Our text adventures are no longer a giant maze to drop us in and collect items to bring to the center. Dark Crystal is far more linear than most point and click adventures I’ve played, with notable parts. It follows the movie well enough, with some fluff between those parts. You play Jen, a Gelfling orphan who must save the world and something something Dark Crystal.</p>

<p>Basically, you got three to four distinct sections of this game, and you need to explore a small section of screens, find all the items and hints, then move on. If you try to move on without items and hints, you die, usually. Going to the swamp before meeting Aughra gets you killed because you show up too early for Kira to show up, for example. Then you go through her village, watch it get destroyed, and head to the castle. Then you fall into the castle, and have to explore in there, trying to find the Dark Crystal, and then you fix it like in the movie, and the game ends.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vrY3tqT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game’s fine. Not overly memorable? The main take away from it is the art which is uh, Not Great. Sierra were no Jim Henson.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Sierra" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 157</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/23/OOCY157.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 157" /><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/23/OOCY157</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/23/OOCY157.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kZCzNHM.png" alt="'Hey, Nanase-chan! This is the train?!' 'What kind of sex should we have today? Should I make you wear cat ears and a collar and have you meow like before?' 'Wait! Listen, darn it!' Two others on the train are listening, and going 'Ahh, to be young'." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Jyoshikou Dakara Safe</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Jyoshikou Dakara Safe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 156</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/23/OOCY156.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 156" /><published>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/23/OOCY156</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/23/OOCY156.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7B9LFjI.png" alt="'Here, take a deep breath. Breath in! Breathe out as hard as you can!' Other girl breaths deep into a plastic bag. 'Caught it! All those bad, fuzzy feelings of your's are packedi n here, Ren-chan. They are, right?' 'Y-yeah...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tRA7Ybo.png" alt="Girl crushes the plastic bag with a POW while the other watches" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8iKbY4m.png" alt="'I've crushed all the anxieties you had in here, Ren-chan!' she announces, holding the deflated bag up and giggling." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Pale Blue-green Color Saudade</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Pale Blue-green Color Saudade" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/22/LizstartrekVOY7-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 5" /><published>2025-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/22/LizstartrekVOY7-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/22/LizstartrekVOY7-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YNBLMoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Unimatrix Zero Part 2</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HDpKDmG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We return to find out heroes Borgified. But it’s okay, they’re still themselves! Mostly. Torres has a broken voice box, and Tuvok is slowly starting to hear voices. They’re trying to sneak a virus in, but things aren’t going immediately as planned, but at least they’re unknown for now. It’s interesting that the person most at risk of losing themselves is TUVOK of all of them.</p>

<p>Also it’s kinda nuts that Voyager just has anti-assimilation medicine, will this EVER come back cause that’s super useful</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iCiBXgb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Seven goes back into Unimatrix Zero and tries to help out from inside. We’ve basically got a three-part war here, as Voyager is also chasing the borg cube. There’s also some stuff inside, Chokie is acting captain, Paris is acting first officer, and Paris is unhappy they’re several hours too late and wants to pull them out, their lives aren’t worth the risk. They’re KINDA doing a Riker in Best of Both Worlds thing with Chokie here, but uh, the difference is Riker is likable.</p>

<p>The Borg Queen is still a Saturday Morning Cartoon Villain and I do not like her. She IS attacked by a Borg who’s disconnected himself from the hivemind somehow, though sadly it fails.</p>

<p>She also looks like she’s on the verge of crying at all times for some reason.</p>

<p>Tuvok betrays them, and Janeway is taken before the Queen. The Queen realizes some are being released due to the virus, and blows up entire cubes and spheres in front of her because ONE person there is free.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J664jw3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She eventually enters Unimatrix Zero herself, at Janeway’s suggestion. Janeway thinks she’s afraid to go in cause she’ll realize how good being an individual is, but that’s weird cause she’s THE ONLY ACTUAL INDIVIDUAL THERE. Anyways she goes in with a more diplomatic approach and tries to befriend children. “Oh it’s lovely in the collective, you’ll love it”. And that’s why you’re forcing people into it, yeah. And why all of the deaths that you’re doing are Janeway’s fault, of course. She suggests Janeway compromise.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GLiWD58.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately this seems to work on Janeway? She sends a message to Voyager and is like “Demand their surrender. Unimatrix Zero can no longer exist. I won’t be responsible for more deaths.” Chakotay somehow sees this as a coded message. I don’t see it but I guess I’m not the most shipped person with Janeway, ALTHOUGH I SHOULD BE <em>sob sob</em></p>

<p>Yeah so they shut down Unimatrix Zero so that they can’t find them there anymore, and they’ll be seperated and safe. Janeway flatly goes “I don’t compromise with Borg”, which is pretty badass, and some newly released Borg show up to help Voyager save their away team.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3vG9rBG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven goes into the collapsing Unimatrix Zero and has an undying declaration of love with this guy. It’s been my least favorite part of these episodes other than the Borg Queen shit. But my favorite thing is that, canonically, they do NOT find each other, and Seven falls in love with women instead. Hell yeah.</p>

<p>And then it ends, alls well that ends well, maybe this will effect the Borg in a good way. Maybe not. Who can say?</p>

<p><strong>Imperfection</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RcmK0Iq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get rid of the Borg Kids in the cold open. All of them but Icheb, who I’m sure will have a nice long life with us. Seven and Icheb are genuinely sad to see them go, but happy they’ll live lives with their people, and together. Icheb is also looking to apply for Starfleet, which is cool. Again, I’m sure that’ll go well for him.</p>

<p>Seven is having some problems, unfortunately. She’s hiding things from the Doctor, and her alcove is refusing to let her regenerate, saying her parts are not working. She goes to the mess hall and passes out, having a weird attack. Her skin begins to rip apart and its very unpleasant to watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rV6fQao.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Her cortical implant is exploding, and needs to be replaced, it can’t be fixed. So they need to go get a new one from a Borg debris field. Seven is also being a grumpy pissy puss about this. I mean, it’s a common response with serious illness, as the doctor says, but I dunno. Janeway is going herself, to try and save Seven, because uh, they are very good friends, yes. She’s taking the Flyer… Wait, the Flyer??? It blew the fuck up last season, and they bring attention to it too. I guess it got better in the Sickbay between episodes.</p>

<p>They go to a broken up Borg Sphere, and surgically remove a node from a dead drone, but are attacked by some scavengers. They get out pretty easily, with no problems. We then get a surgery scene with Seven dying, buuuut it’s just a simulation. Clearly the node won’t work. Seven does not take this news well, understandably.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9jV2QCb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She breaks out of Sick Bay, and where does she go? Back to work. Work is what makes her feel better. She literally says “What I want is to be useful”. And Torres, who has ALWAYS been grumpy and shitty to Seven (Seven doesn’t make it easy), is the one to stand up for her and stick with her. I actually like that a lot.</p>

<p>Icheb refuses to give up on Seven, and offers his own node. The Doctor refuses, that’s suicide, but Icheb has done a LOT of research on this. He thinks he can survive cause he’s younger and not as connected to his cortical node. Seven, of course, doesn’t give a shit. ANY chance Icheb won’t survive is enough for her to say no.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GL0Lh8U.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Icheb turns off his node in defiance. Holy shit. It shows that it can, actually, work, and there’s a very emotional scene with him BEGGING Seven to open up and rely on others for once, so they can help her, like she’s helped everyone else.</p>

<p>It works out well, there’s some more emotional scenes. I like this episode, it was a good powerful one.</p>

<p><strong>Drive</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/twPMezp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This was apparently supposed to be the next episode after Unimatrix Zero Part 2, but for some reason they aired the previous episode before this. Oh well.</p>

<p>While running some tests on the new Delta Flyer, Tom and Harry run into an open world side mission with an alien ship coming up and challenging them to a race through an asteroid field. Something something Kessel Run. I like the idea of this being a racing episode, because we’ve never HAD anything like that with Star Trek.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MwzEWyc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They beat her, and get invited to join a big race, the Antarian Trans-Stellar Rally, which they offer to join. Janeway is down, and is ready to win. And now it’s time for a ROMANTIC COMEDY, because the race was scheduled on the same fucking day Torres and Paris were planned to have their first date in a long time.</p>

<p>Actually, Torres is SURPRISINGLY chill about it. For now. It’s hinted she won’t be eventually. That eventually comes VERY soon. She’s not like, angry. She just decides they don’t belong together because he’s always too busy and they’re not right for each other. Silly me, hoping they’d be adults about something.</p>

<p>The straights are writing relationships again. I just wanted my damn racing episode.</p>

<p>Voyager becomes the host of the race, because of neutrality being needed cause some of the racing participants hate each other. Fair ‘nough.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vgJKQyl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Belanna decides to stop being a doofus and support Paris. Not just support, but SUPPORT. She takes Kims’ place as his co-pilot, which is cute.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CBsPAvQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What results is a fun little race, but also with some big political maneuverings. There’s some attacks and sabatoge that ends up knocking out one of the co-pilots, the co-pilot of the girl who started all this. Kim teams up with her to make things fair. Paris and Torres are rocky in how they’re handling this co-pilot thing. She’s trying. Paris isn’t.</p>

<p>Everyone on Voyager is REAL into this race, keeping a close eye on it.</p>

<p>Turns out the girl Kim is crushing on and working with in this race is a terrorist who wants to blow things up to destroy peace. Wow what a fucker. He figure sit out cause Kim is actually quite smart, and holds her at gunpoint, figuring out through easy deduction that she rigged a bomb to the Delta Flyer. He sends a message to the Delta Flyer just as they’re talking out their feelings. There’s a race going on here, y’all.</p>

<p>Harry sends them a message using morse code, and they need to eject the core. They have 30 seconds to warp core breach, and htey need to get away from everyone to contain the blast. While the explosion is counting down, Paris asks her to marry him. “YOU’RE ASKING THIS NOW?!”</p>

<p>They survive the explosion, and obviously don’t win the race.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u2DiA3L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kinky.</p>

<p>They get saved, and we get a cute ending with them flying off in the delta flyer with JUST MARRIED written on it and shit tied to the back. Adorable.</p>

<p>This one was alright.</p>

<p><strong>Repression</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xNot6Lr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are you ready for a MAQUIS EPISODE?! Yes, the Maquis may be all fucking dead and long gone, but not ENOUGH. We get some Bajoran nonsense from this guy, and then we see he’s talking about Chokie’s ship which is… CALLED THE FUCKING VAL JEAN. ARE YOU MOTHER FUCKERING KIDDING ME???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JJecrLv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>If you all don’t remember Eddington and his WEIRD god damn exception with Les Mis, it’s a HUGE meme in my friend group, and this DROVE US NUTS.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in a date at the holodeck, Tom and Torres find a Maquis member who’s in a coma. Apparently attacked in some way. Tuvok is put on the case. His first and only suspect is Tabor, the injured crewmember’s, best friend. Chokie is like “That’s ridiculous, I’ve known her for years!” Dude. You are, in fact, the WORST at spies and judging people, it is WELL documented.</p>

<p>More Maquis are knocked out in this way, and now the Maquis are getting jumpy. They also don’t trust Tuvok about this, because he’s betrayed them too. A Bolian is like “Could be Janeway. Could be Seven. Could be-“</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dm8o830.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tuvok is getting VERY antsy about this. He has “a hunch” and feels this all is extremely unlogical. He even starts suggesting HARRY is a suspect, cause he had a friend who was killed by the Maquis once. Harry is like “Dude are you for fucking REAL?” I like burned out Kim.</p>

<p>Also the injured are starting to wake up. They’re fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FhS2uDm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Wow no way, it’s TUVOK? Yeah obviously. He’s forcing people into mind melds. “It’s a holy time”, he says before attacking Torres and Chakotay. He’s clearly not fully in charge of his mind. He actually ends up realizing it and IMMEDIATELY turns himself in. He’s seeing a Bajoran be command him to kill and hurt.</p>

<p>We then get what is the FIRST time Tim Russ has been allowed to really super act in a while. He’s getting EMOTIONAL over this. He’s lashing out. They find out there was an awakening word in a letter to Tuvok recently, hacked by this guy, Teero. Chakotay, waking up, recognizes him. He was kicked out of the Maquis for being an extremist.</p>

<p>DUDE. YOU ALL BOMBED CIVILIANS. YOU WERE ALL EXTREMISTS.</p>

<p>Tuvok sends out a message to Chakotay and awakens all the sleeper agents now. They then fully take over the ship. I’m not super engaged in this, because I’ve NEVER liked Maquis stuff, I find it so fucking stupid. And also I find Janeway is being SO dumb here, she just does not understand wtf is happening here until Chakotay points a gun at her. “What is going on here?” GIRL. YOU KNOW WHAT’S GOING ON BY NOW, DO YOU HAVE ANY AMOUNT OF AWARENESS</p>

<p>Also after taking over and putting on Maquis clothing they’re sTILL wearing the insignia.</p>

<p>Tuvok convinces them he’s on their side by almost killing the captain. I don’t really get the scene. Chakotay tests his mettle by giving him a defective phaser, telling him its set to kill, and telling him to kill Janeway. He tried to, and then IMMEDIATELY mind melds with Chakotay after. I don’t get it. Okay, we explain it later. Tuvok had been in his senses, and knew that it wasn’t charged because he wouldn’t give someone he doesn’t trust a loaded weapon. Fair.</p>

<p>Anyways they fix things VERY easily, turning everyone back to normal, and nothing happens ever again? This was meh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YNBLMoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At least we get this fantastic image.</p>

<p><strong>Critical Care</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TQ5W0ay.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a scene of a really awful hospital situation. Some smarmy con artist schmoozes his way through and offers a head doctor something he found. The Doctor, in his holoemitter. Uh oh. He’s VERY unhappy about this but immediately starts treating people. The ship here is VERY low tech and he doesn’t have all the ammenities he wants, but he dives in anyway, while complaining, mind</p>

<p>This shit is just the American healthcare system.</p>

<p>Meanwhile on Voyager they find out they got a fake, IMMEDIATELY realize who did it, and go hunting after him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YJlnR3B.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They take the Doctor from the horrible triage conditions to “Level Blue”, which has rich patients with boo-boos. His absolutely priority. It really, REALLY is just the American Healthcare system. Apparently their computer, the Allocator, assigns who gets the care around here. And for SOME reason its assigning it to the rich and powerful. Gee. The Doctor IMMEDIATELY tries to sneak helping other people. The computer won’t let him. So he begins stealing medicine for them instead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aWuCdYe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile Voyager is on a wild goose chase to find this thief. It’s just a Stembolts plot again.</p>

<p>The Doctor is eventually caught. The kid he was treating is basically killed by restricting him medicine. But he tries sneaking around AGAIN. When his boss finds him, AGAIN…. he fucking INFECTS HIM WITH A VIRUS.</p>

<p>HOLY SHIT.</p>

<p>Note that the Doctor has ethical subroutines. He’s not allowed to do unethical things. So this is the most ethical solution he could find. Intentional poisining people. And the administrator isn’t getting ANY help for his disease from any of the other doctors there cause they’re ALL unhappy with how shitty the system is.</p>

<p>After the Doctor fixes this garbage, Voyager shows up and saves him, and he IMMEDIATELY goes to Seven and is like “My ethical subroutines are broken, please fix them”. Hah, they call it out. But yeah, they’re working fine. He did the right thing, which is almost more fucked up.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 155</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/21/OOCY155.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 155" /><published>2025-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/21/OOCY155</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/21/OOCY155.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zknkOM1.png" alt="'Boy or girl, it doesn't matter. Because you're still cute.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Madoka no Himitsu</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="not yuri" /><category term="Madoka no Himitsu" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 153</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY153.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 153" /><published>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY153</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY153.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/POzDWkx.png" alt="'But there is one thing... you confessed to me in a department store's toilet. What's up with that?' 'Ah... yes... you know... sorry.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: It’s a Secret</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="It&apos;s a Secret" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 154</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY154.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 154" /><published>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY154</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY154.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6ruJXLF.png" alt="'Babe...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jsiwztt.png" alt="'Babe!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>