<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-21T12:21:43-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 201 - Iron Helix</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 201 - Iron Helix" /><published>2025-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V2ZWD1o.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This could double as an Obscure Games You Probably Haven’t Heard Of post. I’m a huge fan of Iron Helix, and have been for a long time, but it’s completely forgotten by this point. This game is extremely important, for a few reasons I’ll get into. But first, this is the second of the two Sega CD games I made sets for! I made one for Kids on Site, and this. Someone might have made a Kids on Site set without my help, but no one would have ever made this, and that’s a promise.</p>

<p>Iron Helix is an early 90s PC-ROM survival horror game by Drew Pictures and Spectrum HoloByte. It’s possibly one of the FIRST modern survival horror games. It’s no Sweet Home or anything, but it has a lot of that Survival Horror style. You’re exploring a dangerous place, alone, and being hunted by an impossible to overcome force, while trying to solve mysteries and find clues to what happened here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IjMTg5G.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Iron Helix starts with an intro that tells the story. Some Earth Force ships are doing military training on the edge of the neutral zone, essentially. But one of them, the Obrian (it’s gonnna be SO hard not to type O’Brien) suddenly veers off, losing control. It targets a peaceful neutral world of the other super power in the galaxy, the Thanatosians. We’re in a cold war with them, but this will make it run hot, and kill an entire planet of innocent civilians too. A message from the ship’s captain explains: They’ve been infected by an unknown virus that’s weakened their immune systems and changed their DNA. The ship’s AI Defender no longer recognizes them as Human, and assumes they’re invaders, killing them. Believing they’re at war, the ship goes to blow up some Thanatosians. Nothing can be donw.</p>

<p>Except… you’re the only ship in the sector! But you’re just a scientist, onboard the exploration ship Indiana. And it’s not like you can board the ship, you’ll get infected and killed too. You’re contacted by Earth’s Forces and asked to stop it, by sending drones into the ship, and blowing it up before it can reach the Thanatosians.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/92gXUmAWv24?si=U5ehhNHeqwmiuG39" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>I think it’s a rather compelling plot. Then you’re hit with the sickest fuckin’ title theme of the early 90s, and you begin. Choose your difficulty level and dive right in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xPMWjBU.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Iron Helix plays like you’re controlling a little drone through a computer screen, which you are. It’s clunky and awkward, because it would be. You move up and down the pathways of the ship, which you can see through surveillance maps that you’ve hacked into. You always know where the Defender is, though when you interract with things on the ship, it knows where you are too, and will hunt you down. You gotta dodge it by running through access tubes and running away, though you can also use battery life to jam the Defender and stun it for a time. The Sega CD version is quite clunky about this and slow paced, the PC version is much faster.</p>

<p>Your goal is split into chunks. First, collect DNA. The Humans were killed, but the ship responds to their DNA still, and not all of it has become changed. You can find hair follicles, chunks of skin, etc, all over the place. Scanning an area, you can release your access arm and pick up DNA, which will allow you through doors to deeper parts of the ship. Once you have all the DNA you need, usually by collecting the captain’s DNA, you can access everywhere, including the information terminals.</p>

<p>The Humans on the ship were trying to stop this before it began, but couldn’t. But they left breadcrumbs for you. They have access codes that they’ve set up to do different things, like blowing up the warp manifolds, or shutting down the Defender. You need to find a code for blowing up the ship, and a code for stopping the Defender, before proceeding. Then you shut down the Defender, then blow up the ship, in that order. Otherwise the Defender will just stop you. And once that’s done, you win!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dBUaPvC.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You can beat Iron Helix in like 9 minutes on this version. Way less than that on PC. If you know what you’re doing and where you’re going, it’s easy every time. Buuuut it’s not easy the first time. If you’ve been reading this review, you’re probably picturing the game in your head and going “woah that sounds sick as fuck???” and it is! On paper. But the Sega CD version is very flawed. The PC version shows you when DNA is nearby. The Sega CD version does not, you have to scan every single square of the ship. It’s also direction sensitive, so you need to check all four sides. It’s AWFUL.</p>

<p>And it’s not very replayable. Once you beat all three difficulties, that’s it. All the difficulties do is shift the DNA and codes around. The codes are different for each difficulty, too. In the first one there’s a code for just turning off the defender. But after that, you need to use yourself as bait to bait the Defender into the cargo bay, and then vent the whole thing into space.</p>

<p>Iron Helix is also built around an FMV base, which at the time was cutting edge, but is now MASSIVELY funny and outdated. You can barely make out these characters, the quality is so low. And their acting is Rather Rough. The best part is Commander Arbok though, your advisor, who after you succeed, rewards you with a job well done by… torturing you for information and killing you. Uh oh, we’re actually the bad guys.</p>

<p>Yes, there’s a hidden thread of information in Iron Helix. I’m telling you this because I doubt you will ever actually play it. You can find logs about destroying the ship, yes, but also ones about the Iron Helix, which is a secret weapon Earth is developing with the capacity to blow up entire planets. It’s highly dangerous, and highly illegal. So to keep their information a secret… they’ll need to silence you. It’s a downer ending! Yay!</p>

<p>Iron Helix is an extremely interesting game for the time, but all of its ideas will be done better down the road, and it’s pretty rough to play these days. I still love it though, it’s very special to me.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pzkFXilM4ls?si=M5tqcRRnh33VzRtO" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Before I forget though, here’s the PC installer for Iron Helix. Absolutely beautiful. It has a lot of charm to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Iron Helix" /><category term="Horror" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - JJ Trek Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - JJ Trek Movies" /><published>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>Note: This isn’t complete yet! We’re watching the first one for now. We’ll watch the others after a few Enterprise seasons.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Star Trek</strong> - 4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YHsmYFt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>As we discuss this movie, I want you to forget about it being a Trek movie. Don’t think of it as that. Think of it as JJ Abram’s demo reel for Star Wars, the thing he actually wanted to do.</p>

<p>We start with a ship in the middle of nowhere under attack. The captain is called to the enemy ship, which EASILY defeats them, and he gives command to his SO, a man named George Kirk. The captain is asked a few questions, where is Ambassador Spock, what is the stardate. And when he answers, he’s then impaled. Kirk then needs to stay on board, distracting the enemy ship as escape pods launch. We get a VERY drawn out scene of him sacrificing the ship as his wife gives birth on the escape pods. As George is about to die, he agrees to name him “Jim”. And then his ship explodes. Hell of a gender reveal party.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iaRqICf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1nd5ibe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then we get the scene made for the trailers. A young James T. Kirk steals his shitty abusive father’s car, as the Beastie Boys blasts out of the car. He’s chased by the cops and drives the car off of uh… whatever the fuck this thing is. The great gorge in the middle of Iowa. You know, what one. Then he says “MY NAME IS JAMES TIBERIUS KIRK.” End trailer! Boom!</p>

<p>On Vulcan, we see a young Spock getting bullied by some very unvulcan vulcans, and he’s beat up by them. He then gets in trouble with his dad for reacting to their bullying, as if them bullying isn’t the problem, it’s the fact that you reacted to it. I fucking HATE shit like this.</p>

<p>Time jump. We get Adult Spock. And if there’s one thing I can say about this movie, it has some AMAZING casting. My only major issue is that the Spock they get is VERY smirky. He’s in front of a board of ministers accepting him into the Vulcan Acadamy of Sciences. He ALSO applied to Starfleet, but they’re like “unneccesary” and deem it dumb to even conside going to Starfleet. Yeah cause Vulcans NEVER join Star Fleet???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oNKfx2w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Kirk being a very uh… “suave” little shithead? He meets Uhura and flirts with her cause of course he does. That alien in the middle should have been one of Morn’s species, tbh. Some Cadets beat the shit out of him for being a little shit, and then he’s saved by… CAPTAIN PIKE! He begs Kirk to enlist in Starfleet, and in 8 years he can captain his own ship. Pretty sure the enlisted don’t… do that. Aren’t they like, O’Brien?</p>

<p>That’s a major thing about this movie. If you peel back the layers and look at it under the hood, even for a fucking MINUTE, it’s stupid and makes no sense. Because JJ Abrahms doesn’t know anything about Star Trek and doesn’t care to make Science Fiction, just Science Fantasy. I could easily whine about shit like… George Kirk’s shitty little ship has the same crew retinue as the fucking Enterprise E. Or “why is the villain’s ship screaming, and why does he not look ANYTHING like a Romulan”. also “Why is his ship FUCKING HUMONGOUS AND POWERFUL BUT A MINING SHIP”. (it’s like if a bulldozer went back in time and blew up the British navy). But it doesn’t matter. This is a late 2000s action movie. Who the hell cares.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Z0y6HAq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We jump through a lot of scenes. Hello, Bones. Karl Urban is good casting. We get more of the villain, Nero, who wants to “make him watch”. Kinky, dog. We also get Kirk fucking a green space babe, and he wins the Kobayashi Maru by hacking the test. It’s like someone read a wikipedia article about Captain Kirk and tried to distill him down in 4 minutes. Keep in mind that, IMO, that’s impossible, because Kirk in the original series is a mad man with four distinct personalities that depend on who writes him through the episode. You either remake Kirk with SOME of his traits, or make him a madman. They kinda went with madman.</p>

<p>While Kirk is getting yelled at for cheating at the Kobayashi Maru by Spock, the maker of the test, they get a distress call from Vulcan. And apparently the only ships in the sector who can reach Vulcan are…. the fucking Cadets at Earth? WHERE ARE ANY OF THE OTHER SHIPS?! Everyone is split off into different ships. Kirk is left at home cause he cheated, but Bones is a bro and basically sneaks him on board. While the ages don’t really fit for making them all be cadets together, I kinda like the Bones and Kirk “roommate buddies from college” energy. Not ALL the characters are perfect here. I don’t like overly confident Uhura here, SNW self doubt but very good at her job Uhura feels more believable to me. Sulu is also here, piloting the Enterprise, but he’s young and inexperienced. And also Chekov is here, again, age problems. And his whole thing is he talks weird. Nurse Chapel also gets mentioned, cool.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t4SwLxG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nero, the villain, is attacking and blowing up Vulcan. They think it’s something natural, but they’re being attacked, and Kirk knows this because its the same thing that happened when he was born. If he can coem to that conclusion anyone should, because it’s not like it was a small problem, lots of people died. We get Kirk, having an allergic reaction, running through the Enterprise screaming and trying to communicate in a funny way to Uhura that they’re about to witness an actual genocide. This movie has a tone problem. Trek has always toed the line between humor and seriousness. It does that well. But it usually doesn’t involve ACTUAL PLANETARY genocide.</p>

<p>Pike leaves Chekov in control of the bridge to go be a hostage. What the fuck? Why him? Chekov is only like, 6 years old. He was just born yesterday, and you’re putting him in command? He also promotes Spock to Captain and Kirk to first officer. Why? Who the fuck knows. Bones is also now chief medical officer cause all the doctors fucking died. Pike sends Kirk Sulu and some shmuck to do an orbital fall to Vulcan to try and destroy this thing they’re using to destroy the planet.</p>

<p>Oh no, one of the people Kirk is going with on this mission is wearing a red shirt. Dude, I’m so sorry for you. There’s like 6 things JJ knows about Star Trek, and that’s one of the top ones. He died because he’s being a fucking idiot. It’s okay, I saw his parachute. Like, literally.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fYI07oO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a fight scene on this orbital platform that’s moving to the planet’s code. Sulu apparently brought a MOTHER FUCKING KATANA to this fight. Why? Because he’s Japanese of course!! This is the scene I remember from this movie most of all. I remember thinking it was sick as hell.</p>

<p>This movie is very loud.</p>

<p>The Romulans are making a black hole at the center of Vulcan, which is of course, destroying the planet. He goes to the planet and evacuates his parents, though his mom dies in the process. The temple they’re all in appears to be a Sith Templ- I mean uh, the Katric Chamber. Yeah. Holy shit we finally get silence in this movie, and it’s to mourn Spock’s mom’s death. For like 20 seconds, then it’ll be loud again.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3K7nSIa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A whole hell of a lot of people are dead now. Also Uhura makes out with Spock. It’s literally a student fucking their instructor, don’t worry about it. We all consume questionable stuff. But it wouldn’t be MY ship. Spock needs his lips ready for Kirk.</p>

<p>We find out Nero’s purpose here. He’s from a future, and his super ship nothing can beat is a fucking mining vessel. In the future, Romulus blew up, and he blames the Federation for not helping, especially Spock, so he decides to go back in time and get revenge.</p>

<p>Spock and Kirk get in an argument so Spock literally jettisons him off his ship to an ice planet (that claims is M class, it’s not) onto a fucking ice floe. Was Spock trying to literally murder Kirk? Because he nearly succeeded. Kirk is freezing to death and gets hunted by some alien beasts. What the FUCK, Spock??? You’re the good guy?! Also for some reason there’s an M Class ice planet that’s right next to Vulcan. Okay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vZ8FxrJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Congrats Kirk, you were saved by a 150 year old Vulcan. Kirk just RANDOMLY runs into Spock on this fucking planet. Why? I dunno, JJ Abrahms wanted to make a part of this movie that’s very reminiscent of Star Wars Episode 5. Old!Spock teaches Kirk what happened in the past/future. This part is canon. This movie? Not canon, it’s an alternate universe. But a supernova happening to Romulus DID happen. This causes a lot of awful prime timeline shenanigans. Also there’s a Federation outpost nearby. Why wasn’t Spock ALREADY THERE???? WHY WAS HE JUST LIVING IN A CAVE?!</p>

<p>Sorry, I am TRYING to ignore the stupid bullshit in this movie but it is very, very hard.</p>

<p>Anyways we’re about to get to the best casting of this movie. Karl Urban is #2. This is #1.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sJ7HOOB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Scotty’s actor is the only person here, other than Nimoy of course, who knew fucking ANYTHING about Star Trek before joining this crew. And he fits this perfectly. He’s pretty great.</p>

<p>Old!Spock demands that Kirk not tell Young!Spock that he exists. Because it’s his Destiny. WHAT DOES THAT MEAN? WHY DOES THAT MEAN? Whhyyy? Spock also claims he learned how to cheat from an old friend. I bet he’s gonna teach Kirk about Fizbin sometime.</p>

<p>Oh you know what, it’s been a while since we’ve had some scene where people run around with slapstick! We get a scene where Scott is beamed into Enterprise’s water tubes, and there’s some giant chopping blades that the water flows to. Good thing there’s no one currently in Engineering???????</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AInxFB5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Under Old!Spock’s suggestion, Kirk just pisses Young!Spock off enough to make him attack him, which will make it obvious he’s not fit to lead. He relinquishes command and now NO one is in command. Why are the only people on the best ship in the fleet Cadets? Well, we DO have a captain now. Kirk WAS made the acting first officer, so now he’s captain. You know, Spock was removed from captaincy cause he was emotional compromised, but this Kirk is ABSOLUTELY not emotionally compromised.</p>

<p>Spock comes to because his dad said he loved his wife, and sets himself as the new first officer. Status quo achieved!</p>

<p>Loud flicky pew pew action scene, oh boy. Scotty beams them to what he thinks is an unoccupied part of the ship. It’s not. Fight time. Luckily all these enemies are very bad. They’re attacking JUST as the ship starts to bore a hole in Earth like it did for Vulcan, almost blowing up the Golden Gate Bridge. Been a while since we saw it blow up! Also now that Spock and Kirk have fought together in a SINGLE fight, Spock is on a first name basis with Kirk and calls him Jim. This movie has some problems with pacing.</p>

<p>Nero: “I WILL DEPRIVE YOU OF YOUR LIFE, JUST LIKE I DID YOUR FATHER”</p>

<p>How the shit did you know that you killed his dad, you never interracted with him. Okay, man. It’s not like I’ve never made writing plothole mistakes before but whoof. This villain isn’t TERRIBLE, but I don’t like him that much. This is what everyone thinks Shinzon from Nemesis is.</p>

<p>Spock is going to sacrifice himself and blow up the red matter, but the Enterprise comes in like Big Damn Heroes to save the day. He crashes the ship with the red matter into Nero’s ship, creating a black hole, just as Kirk saves Pike and Spock is warped away. Was Spock trying to kill Kirk again while doing this? Yes. Yes, he was straight up going to kill him.</p>

<p>Wow this movie has a lot of flashing effects.</p>

<p>THey eject the warp core, and by that I mean like 8 of them, I dunno why they have 8 of them, and let the blast carry them away from the singularity. What if we had more flashing and more shaking effects? Lovely. And then they surfed the wave while listening to rock music. Wait, wrong movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9KjYFUy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a goodbye to Old!Spock as he meets Young!Spock. He explains he lied about it, because it’d make Kirk and Spock be friends. Fair enough.</p>

<p>All the cadets are still there, despite the fact that ALL of the ships they were all put in were blown the fuck up earlier in the movie, sure, okay, that’s fine. They make Kirk captain, give him a medal, and all cheer him on. Also Pike is in a wheelchair now! All is right in the fucking world.</p>

<p>The movie ends with them blasting off. Punch it chewie, etc. And then we get Old!Spock doing the voice over. These are the missions of etc etc. That’s pretty emotional. And we get a reprise of the original theme! Cool.</p>

<p>Obviously this movie is like, not great. It’s kinda bad, in many ways. But it’s not unenjoyable? My friend Elle in my group watch said it best. “This movie is a 40 minute carnival ride that lasts for two hours”. It is shlocky action that is poorly directed, because JJ Abrahms is not a good director. Also we all make fun of the lens flares and weird scaling but the REAL problem is that it was loud, too fast, and the fucking flashing was nuts. This movie is so bright, and so loud. It’s like getting flashbanged by a mediocre book.</p>

<p>At least the soundtrack is pretty good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="JJTrek" /><category term="Movies" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - TNG Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekTNGMovies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - TNG Movies" /><published>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekTNGMovies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekTNGMovies.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>Note: This isn’t complete yet! We’ve only seen three of the movies. We’re holding Nemesis off until after Voyager is done.</p>

<p>EDIT: WE’RE FINALLY WATCHING NEMESIS, HOLY HELL THIS WAS LIKE 2 YEARS AGO. Nemesis review is tacked onto the end!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Star Trek: Generations</strong> - 2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g8xHqkU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The movie starts with like, a 3 minute scene of a bottle flying through space. It feels like they just up and ripped off the opening Myst.</p>

<p>Anyways boom it’s for the Christening of the Enterprise B! We’ve got some TOS characters back with us, Kirk, Scotty, and Chekov. It was GOING to be Bones and Spock with them, but Spock was like “not unless you change the script, because what’s written here, anyone could be saying these lines”. And then they proved it, by replacing them. Anyways, they leave space dock around Mars or whatever, and get a distress call. Some energy field is b lowing up some refugee ships. 3 light years away, but they’re the only ship in range. Did the Borg destroy the entire fucking Federation fleet several years in advance???</p>

<p>Well considering they’re rescuing El-Aurian refugees who are RUNNING from them, I mean, maybe? But nah we don’t gotta worry about where the El Aurians are going.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/14wRE20.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This entire scene is like, about Kirk wanting to take over the Enterprise, but it’s not his place no more. When the captain needs to do some dangerous engineering stuff, he tries to put Kirk in command but Kirk is like “no, this is your place now, I’ll do it”, which is weird. Are there no engineers on this ship???</p>

<p>Also there’s a cameo, one of the El-Aurians is Guinan! Ah, she’s fleeing her planet, and just now appearing on Earth…. EXCEPT THAT WE’VE SEEN HER ON EARTH IN THE 1800S. My chat had to tell me to “stop thinking”. This is gonna be hard.</p>

<p>Anyways yeah the dangerous situation Kirk put himself into for no reason pays off and he fucking dies. The entire deck he’s on is ripped off, and he’s presumed dead, no body ever found.</p>

<p>78 years later!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0IjdcjZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the ACTUALLY good parts of this movie, a cute scene where they’re all on the Holodeck goofing off to celebrate Worf’s promotion. There is something… weird, though. Data appears stunted, despite being here for 7 years with friends, he doesn’t understand spontinaity and humor in a way that causes him to throw Crusher overboard. Riker is gushing over women. Picard gets bad news and then locks himself in his mind palace, refusing to talk about it.</p>

<p>It’s like all the characters very suddenly reverted character growth they had gained over the past 7 years of their lives. In order to make these characters someone you can get into as a newcomer to Trek, they are dumbed down to their most basic components. Maybe I’m reading too far into it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ElGvrmu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Data is like “Clearly my not having emotions is bad cause I hurt a friend, so it is time.” and they pull out the Emotion Chip! Yes, Data originally was like “No I can’t use this cause when I DID feel emotions I was manipulated to hurt my friends”. Now it just makes him hate alcohol. Another actually good scene.</p>

<p>They get a distress signal from a research station under attack. On it they find dead Romulans searching for Trilithium (I know we’ve had Trilithium do something before, it’s new and does other stuff now, don’t think about it), and a living guy, Dr. Malcom McDowell. I mean, Dr. Soran, who we saw at the v ery beginning begging that he NEEDS TO GO BACK, and here he’s… very clearly evil. When he demands to go back on the station to get research, and Picard says no, he gives a weird villain monologue about how time is running out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZHcGQcN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay, two things about visual things this movie is doing. 1) The lighting is dog shit. Everything is so fucking yellow, or way too dark. Why. It’s like, SHOCKINGLY bad. The only scenes with good lighting were the first scene, and the one where they’re literally outside on a boat. And 2) The costuming. Half of them are wearing TNG uniforms, and half are wearing DS9. Why? Why?????</p>

<p>Data has a scene where he constantly makes jokes. I know big movies need like, a comic relief, but why did they make it Data? The emotional center of the entire cast?? I only have one thing I can say about this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aRI9eLT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways woah no way, Soran is evil! He’s actually developing a weapon that blows up suns. He attacks Geordi and Data (who is stunned by fear), and managed to escape with the weapon and Geordi as a hostage as he’s rescued by his benefactors, Lursa and Betor. Y’know, the Klingon sisters. He also tortures Geordi and is like “TELL ME ALL YOU KNOW ABOUT TRI-LITHIUM”. My man. YOU’RE the one who made the bomb. You’re the leading expert. It’d be like me kidnapping the WR holder of Mario 64 and being like “TELL ME ALL YOU KNOW ABOUT TALL: TWINS TOWER.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gSlLHqA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We learn more about Soran through Guinan. Apparently he and she were both in The Nexus, a kind of thing that travels in an energy ribbon. It’s “like being inside of Joy” itself. So a Lotus Eaters situation, kinda. Though the details are murky and it kinda makes little sense.</p>

<p>Anyways there’s a stupid situation where they do a prisoner exchange between Geordi and Picard (for some reason they negaotiate with them I dunno why), and Picard goes down to try and negotiate, because Soran is gonna blow up a sun to drag the Nexus towards him, which will also blow up a planet with millions on it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BUDD6iD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This scene happens.</p>

<p>The Sisters have hacked Geordi’s VISOR, and wait until he goes into Engineering so they can find out what Shield Frequency they’re at. Then they attack through the shields and blow them the fuck up. Riker is very VERY bad at being in charge (JUST ROTATE THE SHIELD FREQUENCIES, OR FIRE SOME TORPOEDOS RIKER? WHY ARE WE DOING THIS FANCY SHIT WITH THEIR WARP COILS?) but eventually, many casualties later, they manage to blow up the Bird of Prey, killing the sisters. Oh well, our major Klingon villains are dead. I guess now we need to make Gowron a villain now.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7o9oEKs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh no, the attack causes a WARP CORE BREACH! Instead of ejecting the warp core, or like, trying anything, Geordi goes “NOTHING WE CAN DO TIME TO EVACUATE”, and they prepare to seperate the saucer from the rest of the ship. They have to MANUALLY seperate the ship, which uh… is not how that works.</p>

<p>Look, half of this movie can be summed up as “Rick Berman did not know how anything in Star Trek ACTUALLY worked”.</p>

<p>They finally put Troi in charge of piloting the Enterprise btw. And now this happens. (tbf there was no actual helm control)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9csyEG9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I really cannot stress enough, it’s really stupid that what is described as a 20 year old junker Bird of Prey beat the Enterprise in a fight (yes they also died but they TOOK OUT THE ENTERPRISE). In an episode, if a Bird of Prey fired upon an unshielded Enterprise, it wouldn’t matter, cause the Enterprise would spin around and blast them the fuck away. Maybe they’d get a few casualties, maybe if they’re LUCKY they hit the warp core and there’d be an ejection. But they’d have to be REAL lucky to get that hit in. But no, here, Riker just kinda spun the Enterprise around and showed them their ass and let them get eight to ten shots in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tKvlWkF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I guess none of it really matters though, because Soran shoots a missile to the sun, which reaches it in 5 seconds (I guess it’s going at warp??????), and the wave takes Soran and Picard away, while everyone else is seen, on screen, fucking exploding. Rip to EVERY member of the Enterprise I guess.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eaTIPc7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard is now in the Nexus, living a happy life with a family he never got to have. I guess he’s always wanted to have a Victorian era british family or some shit like that. But he realizes this is wrong. He can leave, though, if he breaks away. And he can go to any time, because time has no meaning, so he’s gonna go back to right before Soran blew up the star. Uh, I’d think maybe go back before that, but whatever works. An Echo of Guinan tells him all this. Though he needs help. Luckily, there’s someone else here in the Nexus with him…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vkjzou5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kirk meeting Picard should have been more exciting.</p>

<p>Anyways, Picard tries to convince Kirk that he needs to go with him to save millions of lives. Kirk is like “fuck that shit I wanna make eggs kiss my wife and ride horses. Because all captains need to ride horses.” Also his wife here is  uh, Antonia. Apparently it was SUPPOSED to be Carol Marcus, but Paramount demanded it changed. Why? Why???</p>

<p>Obviously Kirk comes around, because nothing here is ACTUALLY real, nothing matters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FFFhZHv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kirk goes back, and the two of them fight. It’s three old men fighting on a big metal thing. It’s not quite as good as Metal Gear Solid 4, though I would love if Soran kissed Picard in the middle of this. There is a lot of stupid shit in this fight scene. Soran installed a cloaking device on his missile for no reason. Malcolm McDowell gives a really weird expression as he explodes. And THE stupid thing happens. An event so legendary that it changed pop culture lexicon for ALL time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iunedsM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They dropped a bridge on him.</p>

<p>Apparently Malcolm McDowell took this job EXPRESSLY because he was going to be the man who killed James T. Kirk, which is the best shit, and I love it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qPYSOSb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Plot conclusion. Picard finds out that Riker destroyed the Enterprise, which was prolly a big fucking shock. The Enterprise couldn’t be salvaged, but they go aboard the rubble and find what they can. Data saves Spot (also he keeps his emotion chip, which… feels weird cause I feel it never comes up again), and Picard throws some of his important memorabilia away, only collecting a family portrait, cause that’s what’s important I guess, and it also fits the thesis of the movie. And then they leave the Enterprise just sitting there on the planet, forever. Yeah just…. leave Federation secrets sitting on this fucking planet, okay whatever.</p>

<p>This movie is bad! It is not good! Like, duh, it’s really bad. A lot of the ideas of it are just, bad. The major ORIGINAL concept and thesis for this movie is “we need to kill Kirk”. That’s it. That’s the plan. And they fucked even that up. Almost every plot point is very poorly concepted. The Nexus is stupid, Data’s emotions are unpleasant to watch except for a single scene and a bad waste of Brent Spiner acting. They bring back Kirk and don’t give him a big damn hero moment, and no, jumping one foot onto a collapsing bridge does not count as a big exciting heroic sacrifice.</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek: First Contact</strong> - 2/10</p>

<p>Goddddd this one is even wooooorse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5KdndxA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard has a bad dweam about his time as Locutus of the Borg.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PTEo8ic.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s a good image here that I did not edit in any way, it is VERY wide.</p>

<p>Anyways I’m sure there’s no reason this is important. Oh wait no, the Borg are back and attacking!! The Enterprise is told to fuck off to the Neutral Zone and make sure the Romulans don’t attack. Everyone is offended by this, cause &gt;:( How DARE THEY not send us to fight, but the reason is because Picard used to be Locutus and that might be bad. I DO get it, tbh.</p>

<p>Anyways the pacing so far is VERY VERY weird. We have a new Enterprise, the Enterprise E. It’s not explained. Geordi doesn’t have his VISOR, and has implants, even thoguh we were told that’d be impossible before. It’s not explained.</p>

<p>The Federation gets their life fucking obliterated, and the Enterprise comes to save the day because of course they do. The Defiant is here, and they save it from being exploded, saving Worf, who beams over and is now part of the crew again. Can’t have TNG without Worf! They blow up the Borg Cube, but it releases a Sphere which blasts off to Earth and goes through a temporal wormhole back to the past. The Enterprise chases, and as they go, they scan that all of Earth is now Borg. They’re safe though, cause of the Temporal Wake or whatever.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dYstxkg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s now 10 years later after WW3, and the Borg are attacking, the day before First Contact with the Vulcans.</p>

<p>One of the issues I had with the previous movie is that it was absolute terrible with its humor. It decided that Data was the comic relief character, and some of it was good, but msot of it was bad. Data’s first thing in this movie is they’re being attacked by someone with a machine gun, and he’s like “I can handle this”, and just walks at her like a terminator, soaking up all the bullets lol. THAT’S good Data comedy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L0bxDMh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Turns out the Borg snuck onto the Enterprise! Through teleporting before their sphere blows up, I guess. I know we can scan for teleporters but ignore that here. Anyway, so they’re killing and assimilating people. Apparently it’s THAT EASY and FAST to assimilate people now??? This movie is playing it really fast and loose with everything. I guess there’s no time. But to keep the Borg away so they can escort people out of Sick Bay, they summon an EMH! EY, IT’S THE BOY! He’s used as a glorified distraction but that’s okay. Nice cameo.</p>

<p>The Enterprise is getting all tubilated. I really, REALLY feel a way about this. It would have been more effective and powerful if we saw the Enterprise and its crew getting slowly and painfully assimilated, but also this is a replacement enterprise that we unceremoniously have now. So maybe it wouldn’t have.</p>

<p>Instead now, the Borg are straight up zombies. They can assimilate you now with a single touch, but boop, nose boop, you’re now a Borg. It’s kind of stupid and I really don’t like it actually. It’s kinda ruining the Borg and turning them into something they never were. They were ALREADY scary and intimidating, because of what they were. They were many, infinite, and all powerful with disgustingly strong tech. Now they’re easy to blow up, easy to kill, but repopulate themselves through touch. Might as well be zombies.</p>

<p>This movie then splits into two bits. We’ve got Geordi, Troi, and Riker on the ground, trying to talk Dr. Cochrane into doing his flight that’d cause the Vulcans to show up and instigate first contact. On the Enterprise, it’s the Borg assimilating everything and killing everyone, with graphic gross body horror all the way. They saved a woman on the ground, Cochrane’s friend Lily, and she basically takes Picard hostage cause she’s terrified. Eventually Picard calms her down by showing her they’re in space, through a window. Oh sorry, not a window. A force Field hole in the Enterprise. Why? What is the purpose of this room that just has a single hole into space????</p>

<p>This movie seems to exist entirely on Rule of Cool but it is NOT cool enough to justify that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3LSikDc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look we have a villain. Apparently the people in charge complained that the Borg were just zombies, so they needed to make a leader for the Borg. MAYBE IF YOU DIDN’T MAKE THE BORG EVEN MORE ZOMBIE LIKE THIS WOULDN’T BE AN ISSUE??? Anyways, this is the Borg Queen. The details around her are hazy and not well explained, but she’s here to be sexy towards Data to convince him to go over to their side.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ArHN4oj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gonna be difficult, movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cONTLx2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Borg chase Lily and Picard into the Holodeck, with a kinda fun scene where they’re in a Dixon Hill novel, and Picard starts firing his gun wildly into the crowd. Fucking wild.</p>

<p>Oh hey Reg is here too. Everyone is being hero worshippy towards Cochrane, and he’s fucking weirded out about it, cause he’s a grumpy and drunk old man. He tries to run away and Riker just fucking shoots him and tells them off for weirding him out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FzT6uWO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I watched this movie once as a child, and this is basically the ONLY part of the movie that I remembered. Worf, Picard, and some red shirt are doing chip swaps and nipple twisting in zero grav on the surface of the Enterprise, while the Borg try to turn the Deflector Dish into a beacon for present-day Borg to come and assimilate Earth. The Borg occasionally go over to stop them, because the Borg kinda sometimes don’t wanna bother fighting people. But only sometimes. I remember SPECIFICALLY thinking that Hawk was Riker in this scene as a kid, cause he gets assimilated and then killed.</p>

<p>Back inside, everyone is like “Captain, the Enteprise is overrun, we need to self destruct and escape on the escape pods”. Picard refuses. Everyone like “what why” “Because I said so. None of you understand the Borg like I do, so you all have to kill yourselves for this.” Everyone goes with it, except Worf who’s kicked off the bridge for speaking up, and Lily, who’s like “You’re being a sick mother fucker who just wnats to hurt the Borg back because they hurt you.” She’s totally right.</p>

<p>And he’s being a fucking idiot. He’s EXTREMELY out of character with this. He’s angry and pissy and lashes out, breaking shit and acting like a spoiled baby. “I WILL MAKE THEM PAY FOR WHAT THEY’VE DONE”. We’ve seen Picard dealing with the trauma for this for years. He breaks down. He cries. He freezes up. He DOES get annoyed and give up his “modern sensibilities” to do things he’d consider inhumane, like with Hugh, but… Murr. I hate this, I really do.</p>

<p>Anyways Lily convinces him to blow up the Enterprise, so he does. He puts in the self destruct sequence and everyone else escapes, when he hears a whisper of Data. Uh oh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7woQcai.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Also back on the Planet, they’re blasting off. Chochrane blasts some rock music as they blast off. What a goofball. The planet stuff for this is actually pretty good, I’m a fan. Feels MUCH more Trek than the action sequence up above.</p>

<p>Picard stays behind to try and save Data, and we get some Historical Revisionism. Locutus’ whole job was apparently to be a king for the Borg Queen, basically. A “bridge between humanity and borg”, that’s why he’s so important. Unfortunately, she’s found a NEW one for that. Data, who’s become an evil humonculus mother fucker. She demands he turn off the self destruct and give her control over the ship thropugh the encryption codes. He does. Oh no! She tells him to blow up Cochrane’s ship, so he fires Photon Torpedos at it. He does, but they miss. Oh, he’s been good this whole time! He says “RESISTANCE IS FUTILE”, then busts off the tanks of the reactor.</p>

<p>So uh yeah. Why did he turn off the self destruct, why did he give them control, why was he pretending at any point? I mean it DOES work out in the end, the reactor kills all the borg, cause the Queen falls in it, and all the Borg die cause she dies. Also he had a VERY easy chance to do that earlier, because she let him go and wander around. He could have broken the reactor then. But okay then. It all worked out in the end.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4Hyl4wK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Vulcans show up, and first contact happens. It all goes well, they leave, using the Moon’s something something to hide from the Vulcans. And boom, they’re done. Uhh, gg.</p>

<p>I hated this movie even more than Generations. I kept watching Generations, I wasn’t checked out. I was checked out here. This is not a Trek movie, it’s a shitty action movie. The characters are barely anything (Geordi and Crusher might as well not be here. At least Troi gets a scene where she’s drunk thats fun, but she still might as well not be here), and the ones that ARE here a lot are AWFUL, and out of character. What the FUCK, Picard? He’s so out of character and awful. You should not have put Picard screaming and swinging around a tommy gun murdering his OWN people who were assimilated, with him going “they were assimilated there’s no way to save them” WHEN HE WAS ASSIMILATED, AND THEY SAVED HIM. I hate what they did with the Borg. I hate what they did with Data. They murdered SO MANY of the Enterprise’s crew, and barely even talked about it. There was no emotional THERE there. And the pacing is all SO terrible.</p>

<p>I hated this. I think Generations is like, bad, but I watched it, and felt kinda not a lot. Mostly annoyed at Data. This was bad, and I ACTIVELY disliked it.</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek: Insurrection</strong> - 7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ERXeuJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our movie starts with an idyllic paradise-like world. It’s a very “Look at the birds, daddy!” moment. This is a clearly pre-space flight civilization, and we’ve got Federation people there watching them with hidden bunkers and people in cloak suits. Cause I guess the federation has cloaking suits now. Data is apparently going hay-wire, and rips off his suit, so he’s just a floating head, terrifying the fuck out of the aliens, the Baku, and annoying the Feds. Data then blasts the bunkers, getting rid of the holograms and revealing them to the Baku. Oh no!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a93IIyh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, they’re having a fancy dinner to welcome some new aliens into the Federation. Apparently the Dominion War and the Borg have uh, made this all exhausting. Understandable, so they’re trying to find new allies. Interesting that they can just have some fancy dinner function in a war, though. IMMEDIATELY, this movie is more quippy. And not in a bad way, I LIKE Trek quipping. While on their way to the function, hey, Worf is here. He literally goes “I was in the neighborhood”. Not even coming up with a good reason to have Worf here, but at least he’s here.</p>

<p>An Admiral calls the Enterprise like “hey, send me Data’s schematics, he’s having issues. Do not come. We don’t want you, things here aren’t safe for your crew so please stay behind.” So obviously they show up anyway. The Federation is working with this people, the Son’a, who are kinda sketchy conquerors, so no one really knows WHY the Feds are working with them while studying the Baku.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qxvsXhS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the Son’a leader. He’s a smarmy sassy mother fucker, got some gay villain energy, and he has his flesh like, hooked and stretched all over him, it’s fucking creepy but not in a bad way.</p>

<p>Anyways so they hunt Data, who’s been attacking the Federation with a stolen ship. Picard decides its HIS job to take Data out, he’s his captain, and friend. So they go in a shuttle to fight him, and he’s clearly still functioning enough to have tactical reasoning. So how do they outsmart him? They distract him with GIlbert and Sullivan. This is very, VERY silly, and a little random, but I kinda don’t hate it. I weirdly love it. They manage to capture him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VQDew4g.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard and crew then go to “rescue” those who are being held by the Baku after Data’s rampage, and we learn about them. They are actually VERY intelligent, very technologically advanced. They once had ships and warp drive capacity, but don’t really want it. “If you use machines to take the job of a man, you remove a part of the man”. They’re THOSE kinda people. They do yoga.</p>

<p>Also there’s some scenes where Riker and Troi are rekindling their relationship. (I originally had this as “Crusher and Troi”, because freudian slip I guess) They’re very random and don’t quite fit here, but it’s very cute actually. I love them. They are the most queer straight couple in the federation.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F9Oftsi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, this ends in Riker’s beard being shaved off. 0/10. Worst movie in the entire series. This goes against everything I believe in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f6l7hIJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Though to be fair, if Marina Sirtis says “I will kiss you but only if you shave your beard”, that beard is getting shaved, I don’t care who you are.</p>

<p>The quips and writing in this movie are really on point so far. The actual budget feels like it’s less than the previous movies, some of the green screening is low quality. But honestly I couldn’t care less about that. Its OBVIOUS this movie is trying to be more humorous, which is interesting since the topic is so heavy.</p>

<p>So what HAVE the federation been doing? They’ve built a fake ship that’s just a holodeck that simulates the Baku’s planet. They were GOING to capture them and just kick them off the planet. That’s pretty fucked up. Why? Well, Picard figures it out fast. The planet’s rings cause a radiation that gives immortality, and increased vitality. Apparently this small group of Feds, working with the Son’a, are trying to steal it from them. Pretty heavy, literal colonialism. But Picard isn’t going to let them! GOD PICARD IS SO MUCH BETTER IN THIS MOVIE THAN THE LAST MOVIE, FUCKING CHRIST.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RQ0O86e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The things this radiation can do are incredible, and it makes SENSE why they’d WANT it. Geordi’s eyes are healing, and he’s seeing a sunrise for the first time. This is the best moment Geordi has had in 3 movies. In the second movie he did nothing. In the first movie he was tortured. Let the man rest.</p>

<p>So yeah, the Admiral explains his reasoning. He’s acting on orders from the Federation council. Due to semantics, the Prime Directive doesn’t apply here because of two reasons. 1) They don’t want it to. And 2) These people aren’t from this planet so they weren’t “meant to be immortal”, whatever that means. 3) It’s JUST 600 people :) Who cares?</p>

<p>Yeah it’s obviously extremely evil. And it does make sense, you get it. It’s just… how people work. And it’s all politics. Apparently the Son’a are going to blow up the planet to get all the particles and use them to fix their conditions immediately, so the Federation are doing this to SAVE the Baku in their eyes. Cause otherwise the Baku would have just killed them, blowing it up. But yeah, it’s orders. Picard has to stop.</p>

<p>So he doesn’t. He quits. He tries to leave quietly, but everyone else notices. And what to do they do?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v6b3hNU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Exactly what you’d expect.</p>

<p>The Baku leave to try and reach some caves, which will block teleporters. They’re trying to keep people on the planet long enough for the Enterprise to go and make things Political.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Sqhfjyg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got some character stuff here. Data’s role here is to connect to a kid, and try to figure out what its like to be a kid. Picard is having romance moments with a lady who’s lived here for 300 years. Troi and Crusher get to shoto guns. Worf is uh, going through puberty. Lots of jokes about Klingon puberty. Data makes a joke about his tits. Okay, not ALL the jokes land. Those are huge anti-jokes. Poor Worf. I guess we have too many characters in this show for ALL the characters to be good and have things to do in a movie. Unlike y’know, a tv show that’s 1/4th the length.</p>

<p>Riker and Geordi are on the Enterprise trying to escape, but are attacked, while being negatively effected by the briar patch. They’re hit really hard, and have to eject the warp core, but at least we get to see the Enterprise-E DO something.</p>

<p>There’s also a Trill pilot on the Enterprise. Riker says he’s going to release the ramscoop and shove it down the Son’a’s throats, and she gives him this look.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zEghUXy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Christ on the cross, she can shove her ramscoop down MY throat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xpVKQvG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Romantic moment with Picard and the older lady. She almost dies from a cavein, but he distracts her enough to keep her with them. It’s not bad. I’m not super into the romance, but it’s not the worst. But as they escape, both Picard and the lady, Anij, are teleported off the planet.</p>

<p>But we get a plot twist, something Crusher finds out. The Son’a and the Baku are the same people. The Son’a broke off years ago from the others, wanting to go back to being space faring peoples, and were exiled. Now enraged and seeking revenge, they really actually want to just kill their own people. Also this being an internal fued within a species, this now makes it a prime directive matter. Which makes sense why the Son’a never brought it up. The Son’a leader murders the Admiral with a face stretch scene thats horrifying.</p>

<p>Picard convinces the villain’s second in command to turn on him, in a good scene. “You disgust me. A coward too scares to stop an atrocity.” “Is this how the Federation pleads for its life?” “I’m not pleading for my life. I’m pleading for your’s.” And it WORKS. This is how you write a Picard. Kill them with words. Not with a tommy gun.</p>

<p>They manage to outsmart them by making them shift their shield for a small second, and while they do, they teleport them into the holodeck ship. And while they fuck around on that, the others teleport onto the Son’a’s ship and take over. There’s a GREAT scream from the villain, Ruo’fo, as he fidns out what happens. It is VERY funny and goofy. “UUWAAOOOWWW!”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9EGlmoZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard and Ruo’fo teleport onto the collector, Ruo’fo to make it launch, Picard to stop him, and it becomes a giant action fight scene in the collector that’s gonna blow up the ship. It ends with Picard potentially sacrificing himself as it explodes, but the Enterprise makes it JUST in time (after the Enterprise plays chicken with them), and Ruo’fo explodes. They COULD have saved him I guess, but eh. Whatever. Fuck him I guess. It’s an actiony movie, it fits. Though it IS weird of them lol</p>

<p>The Son’a 2nd in command reunites with his mom, and all’s well that ends well. The Federation is “halting the Baku relocation” to do some checking to see if it’s very illegal (it is), Data frolicks in the hay bales and has fun, before its time to go home, his mom is calling him. But they can’t stay, it’s time to go home, and leave the Baku to where they want to be.</p>

<p>Movie over, GG.</p>

<p>Maybe it’s cause I hated the last two so much, but this was pretty good? Good crew moments, good quips, maybe a little too much jokes, but still very enjoyable. It’s like, on par with Star Trek 3. A fine movie. Pretty Trekky. Very inconsequential to the plot of the series as a whole, but eh, whatcha gonna do. Not their fault they kept bringing back the Borg Queen instead of the Son’a.</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek: Nemesis</strong> - 6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v9iTr64.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’re FINALLY watching Nemesis! It takes place directly after Voyager is done, so we had to wait for Voyager to be done. This, to me, ends the 90s era, even if it came out in 2002. Here we go.</p>

<p>We start with some Romulan military people making a proposal to the senate, which is rejected. A senator steps out over this, and I’m like “oh shit we about to get a coup”. We do in fact get a coup, a thing she left behind very conspicuously, which she had been playing with, opens up and creates water droplets. These water droplets cause the Romulan senators dry up violently and painfully and they turn to stone and shatter against the  ground as they fall. If I saw this as a kid it would have given me nightmares. Reminded me of the Tuxedo, the only movie I’ve ever seen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0UMGVca.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>When did Star Trek get so woke?</p>

<p>Troi and Riker are married now! They’re gonna be going to a ship called the Titan for this, and Picard is sad but also happy. This is very funny considering the finale of season 3, like 10 years before this, where he went “what the fuck are you still doing here, Will”. Also, Worf is here. He’s just a part of the crew still. It’s not explained. It was barely explained in Insurrection but it’s even LESS explained here, he’s just here for the ride. I mean obviously he’d be here for the wedding, but ah.</p>

<p>While heading to Betazed to deliver the newlyweds, they’re pulled off course by a strange reading. Positronic readings, some kind of Data Brainmeats on a remote planet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TnJh9oE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the stipulations Picard had for being in this movie was that he demanded to drive a dunebuggy. This is a little silly but that’s okay, I don’t mind too much. Patrick Stewart looks so happy to drive it.</p>

<p>That happiness is cut out pretty quickly as they find the causes of the positronic signals. Some data-like body parts, strewn about. An arm. A leg. And finally, a head. It seems like Data’s head, who responds with a “fascinating”. Then suddenly it becomes a mad max movie as some natives of the planet come at them with buggies and machine guns. It’s a turret vehicle section, in my Star Trek. I never much liked how the TNG movies try to be like, action movies.</p>

<p>They escape, and that’s it. The action sequence means nothing to the rest of the story. They reassemble this Data, find he’s some kind of prototype named B-4. He doesn’t know why he’s there, but he’s friendly enough.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EZNkqz1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Say hello to the reason we waited like 2 years to watch this movie. A fucking cameo. She’s here to tell them to go to Romulus. She’s an admiral now which is cool. And then we’ll never see her again… until Prodigy! :D Bye, Janeway!</p>

<p>They’re sent to Romulus. Troi and Riker are still here, I guess. Apparently a “Reman” is now the praetor, which seems to be an underclass in their society. A slave class. Seems to be a coup of some kind, possibly military coup? Also at the same with they download Data’s… data into B-4. As they sit over Romulus, they’re kept waiting for a long-ass time, but eventually a dangerous looking ship appears and gives them transport coordinates, and we go to meet Shinzon, the new leader of Romulus.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X7iWbET.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shinzon is a creepy little fucker. He’s “never seen a Human woman” and wants to touch Troi’s hair. But he’s also offering peace with the Federation, which is nice. But he’s also shrouded in darkness. And also obviously a Human. Not Romulan, OR Reman. He’s a bald little fucker, and he also has a lot of… similarities as Picard. And he’s NOT subtle about this. “Come to dinner, just the two of us. Or should I say, just the one of us”. He cuts his fucking hand and gives the blood to them, and is a weird little mother fucker.</p>

<p>Sure enough, yes, he’s Picard’s clone, according to the blood. Also he’s played by Tom Hardy pretending to be a young Patrick Stewart, which isn’t 1 to 1, but it’s better than some CGI monstrocity. Also, his viceroy, a Reman, is played by Ron Perlman doing a growly voice in heavy makeup. Man, Ron Perlman will do whatever, won’t he?</p>

<p>We also see Shinzon talking to his advisors. A Romulan commander is a little shit about the whole thing, confused why the hell the Enterprise is here, and why aren’t they nuking the Federation yet, he just really wants to see some Federation people die, please, just this once. Shinzon tells him to fuck off. And the other commander is the girl who did the assassinations of the senate, and she tries seducing him, but he’s fucking disgusted by it, and claims “You are not a woman, you are a romulan”. Yay racism? Shinzon DOES mention something about “Romulan lashes” so clearly he has history.</p>

<p>At the dinner date with Picard, he explains. He was a clone which the Romulans made, considered a failure, and threw in the Reman dilithium mines cause fuck it who cares. The Remans took pity on him and treated him as a brother. He’s here now to be like “We should ally and be friends! I want peace!” Man, I’m so glad this movie is going to immediately end with no problems at all and we all become friends :D No obviously not. Picard goes “yes I’d love to be friends but we’ll need to make sure y’all are actually good for it first” and leaves. And of course shit isn’t all above board, it’s pretty obviously. Someone has apparently hacked into their computers, and there’s some very deadly radiation that they’ve found scans of.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EpdhYto.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the things I knew about this movie was that it had a very troubled production, and they cut out a lot of scenes. Like, a lot. Way too many. But then why the FUCK did they leave THIS in??? Troi has sex with Riker, but then he turns into Shinzon who appears to be sexually assaulting her through psychic stuff???? I dunno. Like… it’s so bad and all out of nowhere. And does not matter to anything, just… wow look at how evil this guy is he mind raped Deanna. We already saw him do a political coup, killing dozens, and is planning some evil shit, we did NOT need this too.</p>

<p>Suddenly Picard is kidnapped, and B-4 is with him! Shenzon explains that as long as Picard lives, he’s nothing but his shadow. That… that comes out of nowhere, for being his main driving force? Like, I like the stuff about him viewing himself as Reman culturally, not a Human, and not Romulan. It’s a Nature VS Nuture argument, and that’s cool. But “I can’t live as long as you do”? That doesn’t make any sense to me. Like obviously he’s not 100% mentally stable. But I don’t find that super compelling unless it’s like, over the top? And he can’t be the dashing brilliant foil to Picard who outsmarts him at every turn while also being coo coo bananas with flawed logic and reasoning.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tqBofQX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Data was B-4, take a drink! Yes, they actually saw this COMING and replaced B-4 with Data! Now Data and Picard gotta break out of the ship. They actually have a teleportation thingy but it’ll only work for one person. It turn turns into an action movie again, Picard dual wielding phaser pistols and shooting down a bunch of random guards. Okay, again, I don’t like how they tried make TNG action movies, but this is SO much better than it was in First Contact, with Picard screaming as he fired a tommy gun. I still don’t think we needed to try and make Star Trek into Star Wars, but if we have to, this is as good as we can do, honestly.</p>

<p>Data and Picard break out with another action scene, using a shuttle they steal to blast down some tunnels in this giant ship they’re in, like it’s fucking Descent. Again, pretty okay actually. They make it back and warp the fuck out, with Shinzon planning to chase.</p>

<p>There’s a scene where Data deactivates B-4 because he’s dangerous. It’s pretty sad tbh. Poor B-4. He doesn’t understand what’s going on. We also learn Shinzon is apparently dying due to Clone-itis. Okay, NOW the cloning blues makes some more sense.</p>

<p>They determine that he has a radiation weapon that can destroy Earth, the same radiation that did the Tuxedo stuff from the start that freaked me the hell out. So they prepare for battle and go to meet some of the Federation for backup. Also there’s a scene with Data and Picard, Picard going “He’s what I could have become, he is me” and Data is like “No sir, that’s stupid”. I guess it’s the thesis of the movie. Needed a bit more than a one and a half minute scene.</p>

<p>Shinzon’s ship easily disables the Enterprise and then Shinzon sets up a hologram in Picard’s ready room. Hey, remember when we were trying to make this technology a thing for like 8 episodes? Still dunno why we just kept wanting to make TNG Star Wars.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5YrLllp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is actually a good scene tbh. Picard tries to petition to Shinzon’s morality, and say “you can be better than this, you can grow as a person” and he eventually rejects it. He is what his life has made of him. And he has to do this. And once he does, Picard will be nothing in the end but a dim memory, as his name echoes through history. It’s a good scene. And it’s nice to see Picard actually do speeches, you know, the thing he’s good at.</p>

<p>Shit seems bad, but the Romulans from earlier who were working with Shinzon show up and go “yeah fuck this guy, let’s kill him together”. Temporary alliance maybe (they literally did this so that they could destroy the Federation), but alliance nonetheless.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/H9tfA7C.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a pretty neat fight, which we lose, pretty heavily Our allies don’t DIE but are dead in the water quite fast. Though clearly Shinzon is struggling with his clone-itis.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/h3sw1Fl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The sexual assault scene from earlier comes back, unfortunately, but Troi gets her revenge, using the psychic link that Shinzon’s viceroy made with her to allow him to sexually assault her to control him just long enough so they could hit them where it hurts. She even does a “Remember me?” line. Hell yeah, I love Metroid Other M (I do not, actually). Also hey, return of the eye-lighting from TOS. Always a cool effect.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nsWZ5LU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They lose. Shinzon has them dead to rights. They’re floating in space, all weapons dead, basically, and there’s a hole in their fucking view finger. Several people are dead, and Troi has to fly the ship now. Shinzon is sure, because he’s Picard after all, that Picard would surrender and save his crew. He does not. He flies the fucking Enterprise DIRECTLY into Shinzon’s ship. People love to point to this scene as “hurr hurr Troi is woman who can’t drive”. Bitch, she was told to do this.</p>

<p>It’s a cool scene ngl. They seem to do a LOT more damage to Shinron’s ship than he does to them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/obqh8hR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Riker is fighting the Viceroy, Shinzon’s 2nd in command, who tried to physically take the Enterprise. Their fight goes to…. I don’t even know. It’s a giant vertical shaft with a rickety-ass bridge over it. It breaks, and Riker holds on for dear life as the Viceroy falls miles down into… again, I dunno. Where the fuck is this?! Did Cetacean Ops fucking drain??? This is the silliest thing in this fucking movie.</p>

<p>Both ships are basically dead, so Shinron decides he doesn’t NEED to live after all. His body is basically becoming mouldy cheese at this point. He’s going to send out the radiaton and kill all of them, then fly to Earth, while dying, and blow it up. Their mission WILL succeed even if he doesn’t live to see it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DK5Ccp3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard beams over to fight Shinzon one on one. It’s a suicide mission. Teleporters immediately go offline after that, of course. But Data is having one of it… He THROWS himself out of the fucking Enterprise through one of the open holes in the walls and flies towards Shinzon’s ship in a scene I probably should not be laughing at but absolutely am.</p>

<p>Picard kills all of Shinzon’s guards and assistants, but refuses to kill him, and they struggle. He has a gun, but he won’t shoot Shinzon. Well of course. You wouldn’t expect Picard to KILL people, would you??? <em>glances over at all the fucking corpses surrounding Picard</em></p>

<p>I guess if he did we wouldn’t get a cool climactic final fight but come on, Picard.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SaUkKQd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shinzon impales himself, then DRAGS HIMSELF on the pole towards Picard, staring at him and grabbing him. Picard doesn’t like, leave in order to stop the radiation. Or do anything. He just stands there in shock for some fucking reason. Picard, my mans… wh- why? Why??? You’ve killed before, you’ll kill again, and you didn’t care about killing all those random people, but now that your evil clone has impaled himself you FREEZE UP??? Data comes in, teleports Picard off with his little tleporter button that he mentioned earlier, and then blows up the ship, saving everyone but sacrificing himself. Rest in peace, Data.</p>

<p>It’s okay, I can see his parachute. He literally set up his parachute earlier in the fucking movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TklwWXT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone drinks to Data. Riker starts the ceremonies of talking about the positives about Data. It feels awkward, like no one wants to hear it.</p>

<p>We get a scene with Riker FINALLY leaving the ship, as was set up this entire time. He’s leading a task force to make an alliance with the Romulans.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8kQhCd2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard reactivates B-4, who again, had Data’s memories downloaded into him earlier, but it didn’t seem to work. B-4 isn’t Data. But some parts of him are starting to come back through. Yep, we’re ALREADY getting the replacement Data set up. I guess we’ll see that in Picard, huh? And then the movie ends!</p>

<p>Also, we watched some deleted scenes. All of these were deleted for reasons we cannot possibly understand. Like, it was a very long movie sure, but apparently Berman just said “fuck this we need to make the movie make less sense”.</p>

<p>We get a scene with Wesley Crusher, who WAS in the movie as a cameo, but here he’s like “Yeah I’m excited to serve on the Titan :D.” WHAT? WTF??? He QUIT Starfleet and is now a fucking God, why would he serve on the Titan?! Okay, THAT scene can be removed, sure.</p>

<p>The next deleted scene is Picard talking to Data about why he’s happy AND sad that so many people are leaving the Enterprise. About how they’re like his children, and he’s seeing them grow up. It’s a good scene and helps set up the themes of the movie. But we had to keep the Troi scene in, so it could set up a scene later that didn’t actually do anything :)</p>

<p>There’s also a scene where they introduces Shinzon’s assistants earlier, alongside Shinzon. They removed it so that the scene with Shinzon being shrouded in shadow hits harder. I guess that makes sense.</p>

<p>Another scene with Riker and Troi talking with Worf about their happy honeymoon plans. Removing this means Worf only had like 7 lines in the movie. We also see Data teaching B-4 to eat. This scene can also go, that’s fine. Though I do love Brent Spiner.</p>

<p>Another Worf scene, one where he is racist against Romulans and gives in a suggestion which Picard ignores. We actually get a conclusion to this scene down the way with him going “the Romulans fought with honor”. That seemed out of place tbh. This saved what, 40 seconds? Keep it in. Let Worf earn his pay.</p>

<p>Most of the things they cut were just… more set ups for the themes of the movie. Unneccesary cuts.</p>

<p>OH MY FUCKING CHRIST, THERE WERE TWO RAPES IN THIS MOVIE ORIGINALLY?! THEY ACTUALLY CUT ONE?! WHAT THE FUCK, RICK BERMAN?! WHAT THE FUCK?!?!</p>

<p>One more deleted scene, showing the new First Officer who was replacing Riker. Riker tells him that Picard likes being called “Jean-Luc”. It doesn’t go over well. It’s pretty funny, and would be a more pleasant ending than the ending we got which was like, kinda flat. They end the movie properly with a “where no one has gone before” and it’s kinda nice tbh, with a glory shot of the Enteprrise. A fine final scene.</p>

<p>Over all, the movie is fine. Lots of stupid decisions and weird moments but over all, it was entertaining enough, and actually had ideas and a theme to say rather than whatever the fuck the first two movies were saying. It’s messy though. It has a lot of unneccesary stupid scenes and ideas for a movie that appears to be missing 25% of its fucking scenes that were shot for it. I do wish we had gotten a better TNG sendoff, but I’m not unhappy with this. It’s fine.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="TNG" /><category term="Movies" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 177</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/16/OOCY177.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 177" /><published>2025-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/16/OOCY177</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/16/OOCY177.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kVbTIrB.png" alt="A page from 'She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat'. One woman is staring at another, who's just sitting there, and she's freaking out a bit, before finally going 'um...! how.... how much of you can I touch...?' while the other just stares." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She Loves to Cook She Loves to Eat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 176</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/14/OOCY176.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 176" /><published>2025-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/14/OOCY176</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/14/OOCY176.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rvUJkOc.png" alt="A panel from 'For Some Reason Suddenly I Wanted to... With the Coworker Who Sits Next to Me.' A woman is staring forward, blushing, and exclaiming, 'I asked you to come over because I wanted to have sex with you, is that so wrong...?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: For Some Reason Suddenly I Wanted to… With the Coworker Who Sits Next to Me.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="For Some Reason Suddenly I Wanted to... With the Coworker Who Sits Next to Me." /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 200 - Kids on Site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/12/RA200-KidsonSite.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 200 - Kids on Site" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/12/RA200-KidsonSite</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/12/RA200-KidsonSite.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V2ZWD1o.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I can’t imagine a better game 200.</p>

<p>Kids on Site is a very, VERY special game. I was doing a thing years ago where I was playing every Sega CD game. I hated it. There were so many awful FMV shlock and anime shlock that it wore me down… but there was some good FMV shlock too. And this was the best of them. This game made me so happy to play.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CrkrlpS.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s hard to describe Kids on Site. It’s a collection of silly FMV videos, almost like an interactive movie. You are a kid on a construction site earning some merit badges with different pieces of dangerous equipment. Some adults are there to guide you on what to do. You can move to different screens with A or C (there are 4 screens per level, and each level is a different kind of machine, like steam roller or wrecking ball). B has you perform an action on that screen with your machine. Sometimes there’s more actions than one on each screen. And that’s it!</p>

<p>Each of the levels is literally just “press B on the correct screen a few times” level of complexity. This is for very little kids who like heavy machinery and want to see it go vroom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wbiol67.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The REAL reason to play Kids on Site are the actors and the wild shit they get up to. This game looked like a LOT of fun to shoot. Everyone is doing those over the top “we’re filming for kids” voices. You know, the <em>clown walks on stage</em> HI KIDS!!!~ kinda voice. And everyone is a huge manchild with no common sense or empathy. You know, for kids.</p>

<p>It mainly revolves around two characters, Dizzy and Nuts. They’re both idiots, and it’s a big slapstick kinda thing, because Nuts keeps getting injured over and over. And of course since it’s for kids, injured is “gets run over my a steamroller, and is a paper thing on the ground going MMM! MMM! instead of violently murdered by the steamroller”</p>

<p>The things they recorded for this are very silly. You can go bowling with a wrecking ball. You squish multiple kinds of fruit. You dump dirt all over the place.</p>

<p>Frankly, it’s just a lot of fun to watch, and I highly, HIGHLY recommend people check it out. I made this set myself, because I KNEW I just had to, and there was an event going on for making Sega CD games.</p>

<p>Roses are red, violets are blue. Bulldozer, bulldozer, I love you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Kids on Site" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 199 - Solomon’s Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/12/RA199-SolomonClub.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 199 - Solomon’s Club" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/12/RA199-SolomonClub</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/12/RA199-SolomonClub.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P3Bbgh9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, last year I played Ice n’ Fire for the first time. It’s the sequel to a game called Solomon’s Key, which I had heard of but never played, and I LOOOOVED Ice n’ Fire. So I decided to play Solomon’s Key. But the thing about Solomon’s Key is it’s hard as a mother fucker. Like, really, REALLY hard. So I couldn’t beat it, of course. I decided to check out the other game in the series instead, which is basically the same thing, just… not absolute bullshit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/M4p7Zwm.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Solomon’s Club is basically just Solomon’s Key, on gameboy, and minus all that obscure stuff you gotta do to get the good ends. In this game, you still have to do that stuff to get the good end and final world, kinda, but you get the seals for free, so it’s fine.</p>

<p>You play as Dana, a wizard, and you’re doing… something. It’s not really explained. And go through a couple worlds of ten levels each, which are filled with monsters and traps. Dana can create and destroy blocks to the side and below him. He can use this power to climb up, climb down, and reach the exit of each level, all while avoiding the enemies.</p>

<p>You can also collect items and gold as you go along. These items are things like boots to make you go faster, hats to help you break blocks above you faster by bonking into them, fire to kill enemies, water to put out fire, hammers to break enemy spawners, things like that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I0VUjWP.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game is really easy in terms of puzzles, the actual problem is the platforming and action, that’s what makes it hard. At least until the final world, the bonus challenge world, which has some genuine brain twisters and uses the music from Solomon’s Key, which I really love, so it was nice and exciting.</p>

<p>Over all, this is an extremely fun little puzzle game for the gameboy. If Solomon’s Key kicked your ass too hard, I recommend checking this one out. Or just play Ice n’ Fire, which is one of the best NES games. Either or.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Solomon&apos;s Key" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 175</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/12/OOCY175.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 175" /><published>2025-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/12/OOCY175</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/12/OOCY175.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X4BSWyR.png" alt="An excerpt from My Goddess Spurs Me On. Two women are facing each other, blushing, their hearts are beating fast. 'Is this also something you saw on the net that you're trying out?' one asks, as the other reaches and grabs her hand, pulling it up to her face. 'N-no... this is... I just wanted you to... touch me, Issei.' They both blush deeper as they stare into each other's faces." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: My Goddess Spurs Me On</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="My Goddess Spurs Me On" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episodes 1 - 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episodes 1 - 5" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekSNW3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Hegemony Part 2</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEvb4AL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Following directly after last season, the Enterprise is surrounded by Gorn, and some of their people are captured on the Gorn ship. The Enterprise is forced to retreat… but not before tagging the Gorn ship with a dud missile that’s actually a secret beacon.</p>

<p>Pike’s girlfriend, Batel, is infected with Gorn Babies and they might need to kill her, but to prolong things, they’re freezing her in a block of ice. Specifically SHE’S the one asking them to kill her if they need to. Well, at least that’s the PLAN, but turns out she’s allergic to being stuck in a block of ice, which I imagine I’d be too. Now Nurse Chapel is stuck trying to figure out how to cure Being A Gorn Mom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vvOBev.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Admiral April is like “we have to just ignore all this and let the Gorn capture neutral people” and Pike, being Pike, says fuck that shit, we’re being treated as Prey. And April agrees, unofficially, their rules are to punch the Gorn in the nose and show they’re not prey. Meanwhile, in Engineering, Scotty and Pelia the Warpcore Witch are trying to get a Gorn Cloaking Device up. Scotty says it’s impossible. Pelia is like “we’ll have it done in an hour sir”. Scotty is, one day, gonna be REAL good at doing the impossible on a deadline, and he’s gotta figure out how to get good at it real fucking fast.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Gorn ship, La’an wakes up and punches her way out of a Gorn sack. She rescues the other members of the crew captures, including Sam Kirk (Kirk’s brother), Doctor M’Benga, and Ortegas (who has had half her hand melted off). They want to get out… well, three of them do. La’an decides then and there, she’s going to save ALL the other colonists. Good luck.</p>

<p>Y’all remember Mitchell? She was a very minor background character in season 1, had some minor roles in 2, and now she’s on the bridge and refuses to leave until they can solve this. Yay, Mitchell!</p>

<p>They have some SMALL hope. Batel has a 14% chance of survival if they use Una’s blood. Yay! Also the Gorn seem to go to sleep when a certain kind of star flare happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jFp5msI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FkBzvR4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit is going way, WAY worse. Man this is tense. While exploring a weird binary star that seems to hide the Gorn homeworld because of radiation, they find a BUNCH of Gorn ships blasting out of the zone and going towards Federation space. Now Pike has a choice. He might lose the tag on the colonists and his crew if he leaves to warn Starfleet, but they are NOT prepared for an invasion. So he makes the impossible choice and leaves them.</p>

<p>Pike seems so fucking done. He’s EXHAUSTED, he’s worrying about every single little thing. And can you blame him? When he goes to Scotty and Pelia like “Hey can we make a solar flare” and Scotty is like “what the fuck no. Not without doing this this that and this which will blow up the ship” Pike is like “Sure just do it without the blowing up the ship part” and everyone just… stares at each other.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of “have faith” talk in this episode, which we keep making fun of by posting Star Wars memes. It doesn’t help when Ortegas takes over a Gorn ship and flies them out in a scene that is VERY Star Warsy. Also Ortegas becomes massively injured in the skirmish, but sticks too it. Poor Ortegas, she can’t catch a break ):</p>

<p>We get a fuzzy fisheye scene with them in the radiation, but it works. They use the flare to trigger a hibernation in the Gorn, as they come back to go eep. Ortegas raises her deathflag REALLY high but is saved just before dying, thank fucking God. <em>sees death flag in Ortegas’ mouth</em> WHAT DO YOU HAVE THERE? PUT THAT DOWN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/evmRMxM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Batel is saved, Spock and Chapel have a moment of acceptance, and the Enterprise is beat to fuck. But alive. It ends the “have faith” talk with Pike thanking God for some reason.</p>

<p>I thought it was alright! Not blowing me away, but good! Excited for more.</p>

<p>I’ll be editing this page every week and reposting it with the new episodes as they come out =w=</p>

<p><strong>Wedding Bell Blues</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9FnKzZH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s 3 months after the nightmare of the last two episodes, and the Enterprise is repaired and ready! Everyone is going to a gala to try and relax! I’m sure this’ll go exactly as expected! To try and get into the spirit, and to practice for getting things going well with Nurse Chapel, Spock is practicing dancing with La’an.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Yol3Cdf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>BUT NOT A BRAIN! :D</p>

<p>Anyways, Chapel comes on board with the doctor she’s been working with for three months, Roger Korby. He’s a very friendly guy, but a bit eccentric. Anyways Spock almost makes an ass out of himself before we find out Korby is, in fact, dating Chapel now. Whoops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AkPLZfu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy HELL, Uhura’s outfit is on point.</p>

<p>Ortegas is doing better. Physically, at least. We meet her brother, who is flirting a bit with Uhura, who seems reticent. Ortegas isn’t into it, though.</p>

<p>Everyone gets together to drink a bit. Spock is, as usual, awkward. He steps away for a drink at the bar, and we get this like, weird Mxptlk mother fucker who’s tending bar. He appears as a Vulcan to Spock, but to us, he’s a weird mother fucker. He gives Spock a drink, who…  wakes up later that night next to Chapel. They’re getting married! Oh boy! I’m sure Chapel will handle this very well!</p>

<p>This Mxptlk ass dude is basically acting as wedding planner and getting everything all right and dandy. Is he a… shipper? Of Nurse and Spock?? I will say, over all, I haven’t really… been into the Chapel and Spock thing? It’s not JUST cause I know it won’t go anywhere, but also cause of how they just… don’t go together lmfao which I think this episode is doing its best to try and show.</p>

<p>Korby is the ONLY person who seems to realize something is wrong. He can remember things how they SHOULD be, and is trying to subtly sabatoge the wedding. Spock catches him, and he explains that this is all wrong. Spock punches him out, but then for some reason remembers that yes, this IS wrong, and… well yes, feels bad, but most importantly is like “this needs to be fixed”. He and Korby work together, they’re both smart science boys, and though they love the same woman, they have to work together to figure out what’s wrong.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3XmlT3E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s kinda fun to watch these two try and wander around a changed reality, testing at the waters and touching the boundaries to find where they are. Spock tries to get others to realize something is wrong. He tries to get Kirk to punch him. He insults his mustache. It doesn’t work.</p>

<p>When they confront the Wedding Planner about this, he reveals he’s a giant fucking baby and this is all a game to him, which they’ll have to play, or he will wipe everyone from existence. Welp. Korby and Spock change up their plan and yeah, the only thing they can possibly do now really, is try to go along with it. When Korby DOES act up, he’s turned into a dog, and no one else seems to care. They’re really just his puppets.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JsdWJEP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually Chapel snaps out of it too, thanks to Spock, and when the Wedding Planner announces everyone is going to die. But he’s interrupted by his… dad. Who is, in fact, played by John de Lancie. Hmm. The bartender is just a kid, and he’s made to clean up his toys. Everyone is like “WELL THAT WAS WEIRD” and then tries to celebrate the actual reason they’re there, the Cenntenial. La’an dances with Spock, who has no regrets. We have one of the three armed aliens from TAS, who joins the crew as their bartender, yay! Aaaaand Ortegas has a PTSD episode. Yay!</p>

<p><strong>Shuttle to Kenfori</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uMeF8wz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Somehow, the Gorn Tissue has returned. Patel is still sick cause of Gorn, but they think they have a way that can fix it. It takes a flower, but it can only be found in a no-fly zone that would cause a Klingon War if they went to it. So Pike does an off the books mission, setting himself up as the person who’d take the fall if it goes bad. Mbenga goes with him, cause y’know, it’s a medical thing. It’d be a good idea to bring a Klingon War Vet to this possible Klingon area~ And on the way they get a warning beacon of “GO BACK OR DIE”, which is weird to have on a planet where no one’s supposed to be there.</p>

<p>There are no life signs on the planet. It’s a jungle, but no animals, at all. And they find a corpse that probably died after the evacuation. Welp, it’s Aliens time or some shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vZ8WhBe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While going through an old building and gathering their flowers, a Klingon shuttle (the first in the series? At least that I’ve seen) comes and blows their ship up. Now they’re being hunted by some Klingons, oh boy! It’s two guys and a woman who appears to be in charge.</p>

<p>The Klingons get them, but then they’re attacked by… zombies. Just, straight up zombies. They eat a Klingon alive. Jesus CHRIST. I dunno if we’ve ever seen ANYTHING like this in Trek? It’s now a fucking zombie horror movie. By the way, this planet, Ken Fori, is named after Ken Foree, the lead actor in Day of the Dead.</p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, they plan how to rescue their crew. Still radio silence, they dunno what happened, they just haven’t heard anything from the ground team, so they go after them with a very slow, but safe tactic. Ortegas is VERY unhappy about this and pretty insubordinate. La’an is worried about her health, which we know isn’t doing very well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XiJNsUb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So this flower causes genomes to like, fuse, basically. Hybridize people into different things. They tried to use it on a moss that could grow anywhere to make a super food. It accidentally hybridized with corpses and now there are zombies. Mbenga refuses to call them Zombies. Pike keeps using the “Z” word. And now that he knows what the Chimera Flower does, he knows that it’ll turn her into a Gorn hybrid. He is NOT happy about this, but it was her decision, and is the only way anyone knows to save her.</p>

<p>They get chased by more Zombies, and find themselves with the Klingon girl behind a force field. She stabs Pike, and we find out that she’s the daugher of Dak’Rah. Remember him? He was the dude from last season who was a straight up war criminal who was trying to act like he had changed, and was killed by M’Benga in a scene where it’s not clear exactly what happened, if it was self defense or not. Now it’s coming back to bite him. She hated him so it’s no problem there, but she’s sure that if SHE had killed him, she would have brought honor back to her house, and now she has to kill his assassin. And M’Benga admits that he intentionally killed Dak’Rah, it was NOT self defense.</p>

<p>We get PTSD War Hero M’Benga again.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8tXJNvH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a fight scene between M’Benga and this Klingon, fighting with D’ktaghs. In the fight, they damage the force field generator, which is probably not good. M’Benga then wins the fight and chooses not to kill her, which is maybe the rudest thing you can do to a Klingon. So she chooses an honorable death by sacrificing herself. No one will know, but she will. And so with M’Benga, who respects the choice.</p>

<p>Some good flying by Ortegas gets them to save the away team, though Una is VERY unhappy with how Ortegas has been acting. And now Pike has to decide whether or not to turn M’Benga for doing a murder. But luckily, M’Benga only told a story to save Pike’s life when there was a knife to his throat, so, y’know, checks out.</p>

<p>Uh oh. Ortegas intentionally did a bad job so they’d do her idea instead. It was unneccesary, because Pike and M’Benga were going to get on a shuttle anyway and would be safe, and she endangered everyone. So she gets a slap on a wrist, but a “please do not EVER do this again”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5tW9bd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel and Pike have a heart to heart about it. He’s like “why didn’t you tell me?” “Because it wasn’t about you, and we both know if I did tell you, you’d tell me not to do it and find another way even though there is no other way”. Which y’know, he did. On the planet. So she’s right. And then it just… ends. I guess we’ll find out next week how it goes!</p>

<p>This one was uh… fine. I dunno how much we needed zombies in Star Trek but that’s fine. Fun Klingon fight!</p>

<p><strong>A Space Adventure Hour</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/62SIAKV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ohhhh no, those outfits. Holy SHIT, La’an is on point.</p>

<p>So, I’ve not been enjoying this season as much so far. But I’ll stick with it, maybe it’ll get better! Anyways this episode starts with one of the best scenes I’ve ever seen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P7kebx2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Kirk’s actor, Chapel’s actress, and Ortegas’ actress doing some… kind of thing here. It’s obviously a pastiche of TOS. Though I WISH TOS looked and acted like this. It’s got a lot of really like, Dr. Who style models and special effects, and it feels more like an adventure serial of like, the 40s. But Kirk’s actor is here doing an EXTREMELY good Shatner impersonation. The intro is for this Space Adventure show, and it’s great.</p>

<p>Anyways back to actual Star Trek. The Federation is developing a new kind of technology. It’s for entertainment on long-term space exploration voyages. It’s called The Holodeck. THIS MEANS THIS IS THE CANONICAL FIRST HOLODECK GOES WRONG EPISODE? YAY! Pike gives testing to La’an and tells her to push it as HARD as she can.</p>

<p>We get more La’an and Spock dancing, as Spock seems to be continuing dance training. He’s ABSOLUTELY, CLEARLY making moves on her. I was not expecting Spock to be the horndog of SNW? I don’t HATE the idea, though this is maybe better. La’an is one of the characters we don’t know what happens to after this, clearly Chapel and Spock aren’t dating in TOS era, soooo, this works better.</p>

<p>La’an decides to give the computer a challenge. She really loves detective novels, and asks it to…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iXIxKLc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>LA’AN, NO! THIS IS HOW WE GET MORIARITIES!!!</p>

<p>You KNOW they did this on purpose to get this reaction. We’ve been here before!! This is a good style of “We’ve been here before” though. It’s not retreading it in a boring way, but it’s an exciting idea we’ve had before that lights up your day.</p>

<p>We get a murder mystery story with La’an investigating the murder of a TV executive. The show he was in charge of was getting cancelled and someone in the room murdered him, so she has to go through all the suspects. Everyone is played by Trek actors, because canonically the best source of high def recordings they have are transporter buffer scans, so they go with those. The show was, of course, the shitty Trek pastiche from earlier. We watch as La’an solves the case (it’s Una, who’s the exec’s ex-wife) but the game changes the rules and ups the difficulty, killing her basically. La’an decides she needs help to put this story to its end, and enlists Spock. Oh boy, pushing THAT ship still. Also all the acting here is top notch.</p>

<p>Meanwhile energy is fluctuating on the Enterprise and poor Scotty is running overtime to fix it.</p>

<p>There’s some themes in the investigation. Emotions and romance getting in the way of things. Huh, funny that. Anyways La’an is almost killed in a trap set by the murderer, aaand is actually injured. Whoops, the holodeck is malfunctioning! Who could see THAT coming?! :D Scotty is already on it, but it seems the only way to fix it is if La’an solves the case from the inside.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w6ry2wT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They give Uhura’s character a speech about how important Trek COULD be. It shows the lense of people’s lives through rubber masks and science fiction. It can inspired generations of kids! That’s wonderful that they gave this speech to her of all people.</p>

<p>The stakes are raised as the Enterprise is about to be destroyed by some radiation that’s coming their way, and they don’t have the energy to dodge it. Gotta solve stuff fast!</p>

<p>The solution to the murder mystery is actually a really fun twist. I won’t spoil it.</p>

<p>La’an’s assessment is that the Holodeck is NOT a good idea for starships to have installed on at this time. Scotty asks for a footnote to be added that maybe if they fix the energy problems. Pike wants it buried in a box in a basement somewhere. Then Una is like “Scotty why the FUCK didn’t you ask any of the rest of us to help you??? We could have died” and the answer is PTSD. Una’s job now is to try and wrangle PTSD addled kids on this fucking starship.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/860zCki.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get one last dance scene and Spock and La’an and they kiss, of course. This is the third woman Spock has made out with in three seasons. Down, boy.</p>

<p>But that’s less important than THIS:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xqdvmxK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>CHEESY TOS ERA BLOOPER REEL!</p>

<p>This episode was just loads of fun. Okay, good. We can still do stuff I absolutely love.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 198 - Final Fantasy III DS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/10/RA198-FF3DS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 198 - Final Fantasy III DS" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/10/RA198-FF3DS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/10/RA198-FF3DS.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4hAVPl7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Last year I played Final Fantasy 3 for the first time ever. I also beat FF5, which is basically FF3-2, and LOVED it. I wanted to play more FF5, so I played it three fucking times for Four Job Fiesta. And even after ALL of that, I still kinda wanted to play more… so I pulled out FF3 for DS.</p>

<p>When I’m playing all these old games I try to go older to newer, and I usually go for the oldest version first. This means I usually don’t get to remakes. There’s too many games to play and I don’t replay games often. FF3, however, I loved so much, AND people were gushing about the remake as I played the NES version, so I was excited to play it. Funnily enough, as I played this version though, people’s tunes changed, and they were like “Oh, this version isn’t very good, it has too many flaws, it’s too difficult”.</p>

<p>Now, FF3 is the hardest Final Fantasy game I’ve ever played. And people were telling me that this was harder. I was surprised. How could it be? So I’ve now beaten it, and I can say, they were wrong. This is not harder.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6UBahEh.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There are a lot of changes between FF3 and FF3DS, but less than you’d expect. When they were remaking the first Final Fantasy games around this time, they mostly updated the graphics and mechanics, on the GBA. FF3 took longer to make though, because they apparently lost the source code and had to do it from the ground up. So it came to the DS, and direct remakes were less in vogue then. You needed to spice it up. PLUS it was 3D now, so they decided to take the time to completely redo the vibe and story… kinda. I was expecting more. These are now characters. In FF3, they were all just blank slates. They talked and existed as characters but they were blank slates to put your thoughts and characters into, really. Here, they are characters. One is a generic hero, his childhood friend who’s shy and sweet. An independent fiery blacksmith’s daughter, and finally a royal knight who joins them. But they still do and say basically the same things as the original game, so it doesn’t really add as much as you’d expect.</p>

<p>The best thing about it is that these character designs were made by the same artist who made Bravely Default, and I love the designs.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HjwktBG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You still meet the same characters, go on the same mini stories, and do the same dungeons. Even the dungeon and level design is pretty much the same. There were a COUPLE of rooms and floors that were changed, but it was shockingly accurate to the NES designs. Even some of the suspect stuff. The NES had dungeons that I was like “woah, this is fucked up and rude”, like the mini and frog dungeons, the Dark Dungeon, or the final Dungeon, the most fucked up final dungeon I’ve ever seen. None of that is toned down. It’s the same as it was in the NES verison. But I still think the game is easier, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>One, in the NES version, you could fight up to 9 enemies at once. Here, it’s 3. Their health is increased to account for this but it’s still easier to take on 3 tankier guys than 9 slightly weaker guys. Secondly, the numbers are just… a bit nicer. I didn’t have to grind as much to handle the Dark World. In the NES version I had to grind HARD, but here, nope. I could beat the game without much worries. Even the fucking Garuda fight, which again had an achievement where I had to do it without Dragoons, was SO much less of a problem in this version, and this version’s achievement was HARDER. In the NES achievement, it didn’t matter how many of my units died, but here they all had to be alive, AND not use any Dragoons. But I still found it easier, just cause the numbers were nicer.</p>

<p>There was just one problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V3GFYwy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Iron Giant is a bonus fight made for the DS version, and he is fucked up. I literally had to grind to level 99 to handle him, and it still took me like two tries. TBF, I also had to beat him with no one dying, but like, he’s REALLY tuned. But that’s a bonus boss in an RPG, like, they’re all overtuned, and I won’t hold that against the rest of the game.</p>

<p>Over all, I liked this version. The music is, for the most part, better. The story changes didn’t add as much as I’d hoped, and I think I prefer the NES graphics, but it certainly wasn’t ugly. It being on the DS added literally nothing, the touch screen basically did nothing. You COULD use it but why would you? All in all, it was another pleasant way to play a good game.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="DS" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>