<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-16T11:55:32-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 124</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/16/OOCY124.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 124" /><published>2025-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/16/OOCY124</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/16/OOCY124.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XrtPgPi.png" alt="A woman sits there thinking, then thinks of when she asked another girl out, then screams into a pillow as she kicks her feetsies" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Huh?</p>

<p>source: Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 160 - Shining in the Darkness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/15/RA160-ShiningintheDarkness.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 160 - Shining in the Darkness" /><published>2025-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/15/RA160-ShiningintheDarkness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/15/RA160-ShiningintheDarkness.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bK2x9Mq.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I recently decided to tackle the Shining series. This was a series of RPGs made by Sega in the early to late 90s, and the first series that beloved studio Camelot is known for. Before they made Golden Sun and were locked in the Mario Sports Mines for the rest of time, they made things like this. Though in this case, I’m a bit confused. The early era of Camelot is shakey, and I see a lot of conflicting information. Because there was ANOTHER company that worked on this game as their first game, and that’s Climax Entertainment. Their standout hit down the way would be Landstalker, but they’d also work on Shining Force alongside Camelot… I think. See, Wikipedia claims Camelot is “credited” on those two games, though it also claims they didn’t exist until 1994, and this is from 1991. Other sites I look up the info on have different information. Look, it doesn’t matter that much. My guess is a lot of the people who made this went on to form Camelot, and both Climax and Camelot basically own it, because one of the characters for this game would be put in Climax’s Time Stalkers years down the way, and of course Camelot continued the series later. So who the hell knows, they both own the series and the game. Or more likely Sega does. Whatever. Let’s get on with it.</p>

<p>The Shining series is of course mostly known for Shining Force. A lot of people entered my stream as I played this and went “Wow this looks cool, the art reminds me of Shining Force” and I had to go “funny thing about that”. Shining in the Darkness is just not as well known as Shining Force, it’s the first game in the series, but is nothing like the rest of it… except for Holy Ark, but I’ll get to that one eventually.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n8FfB3u.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In SitD, you play as a young knight named Hiro, who’s knight father has gone missing. At the same time, the princess has been kidnapped by an evil being who is translated as Dark Sol. You might know that’s the villain of Shining Force, but actually this is not Dark Sol, that’s a mistranslation. This is his son, meaning Shining Force will be a prequel to this game. Anyway, you need to go into The Labyrinth, the training round for knights in the Kingdom, to try and save your father and the Princess. At first it’s just you, but you’ll eventually be accompanied by your friends, Pyra the Elven Mage, and Milo the Hobbit cleric. Milo is your traditional D&amp;D Cleric, with maces and axes and heavy armor. You’re basically a straight up warrior with no magic. And Pyra isn’t USELESS in combat, but she’s a bit weaker, and uses magic as her main damage, though she can ALSO use whips that hit entire groups. She’s also HORRIBLE. There’s a scene where she bumps into a guy and is annoyed he doesn’t apologize, so she casts slow on him as he enters the Labyrinth and is like “He’s gonna have a real surprise when he runs into the monsters!”</p>

<iframe src="https://clips.twitch.tv/embed?clip=ScaryGlutenFreePepperKlappa-JcZLjQE56UqIRHhq&amp;parent=www.example.com" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" scrolling="no" height="378" width="620"></iframe>

<p>It’s great.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/krZn5Id.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Unlike the later games in the series, SitD is a dungeon crawler. It’s a good ol fashioned Blobber, where your entire party is in one square and you walk square by square around a 3D environment. In my opinion, SitD is basically the perfect example of that very early version of the genre. It’s the quintessential 80s Blobber, even though it’s from the 90s. It doesn’t try too many new ideas. It’s very accessible, anyone can pick it up and enjoy it. And it looks AMAZING. This game’s style is off the charts. That’s one of the best things about early Shining Force especially, the art and the style are so good. The UI is simple and pleasing, the characters are varied and fun even for a game with barely any story or plot like this one. And of course not everyone is a boring Human. We’ll see that even more on display in the Force games, but it’s seen here too. We’ve got Hobbits and Elves, but we’ve also got Wolflings and Lizardfolk. And most interestingly, you can find some Gelflings. GELFLINGS. From Dark Crystal! That’s wild. They never appear ever again, but SUSPICIOUSLY some similar looking creatures called the Kyantol would appear later on, so that’s prolly where they went.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZVa9PWS.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s very simple. You explore a 3D dungeon, run into random encounters, the combat is turn based and easy to grok. There’s no map, you make your own. There’s a FEW new ideas here, like you can go back to town and get new items with your gold, but later in the game you can also use the blacksmith to forge special equipment for each character using Mythril for some of the best equipment in the game. There’s also Cursed items, which in PYra’s case is her best weapon, IMO.</p>

<p>The level design is also pretty good, IMO. There’s some fun puzzles, but the real great thing IMO is how they handle delving deeper into a dungeon then needing to dip back out to heal and save. That’d get very annoying very quickly. So what, is there a scroll of town portal? Not quite. You DO have the classic Egress spell to teleport back, but you have to walk back. But it’s not that big of a deal, because the first 60% of the game is right on the first floor of the Labyrinth. You first need to solve The Four Trials, which are accessed on the first floor, and are their own floors, so you don’t need to go in deep to get to them. Once you finish THOSE, you start climbing up to the fifth floor, and you also get an item, the Gold Coin. You can toss it into Golden Wells you come across, to make those your teleport spot. Interestingly though, in order to make another one your teleport spot, you need to fish the coin out of the previous one. So you need to make SURE you can safely reach the next well before you try. It’s a neat mechanic, IMO.</p>

<p>In the end, I do like Shining in the Darkness quite a bit, though it does overstay it’s welcome a tad, and it doesn’t try a WHOLE lot new with the formula. Like I said, it really just makes it easier to approach, and really pretty. I’d give it a 7.5/10. If you like grinding through legions of monsters so you can safely reach the next floor for 30 hours, go right ahead, it’s well worth your time. If not? Eh, maybe consider the rest of the Shining series instead.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Genesis" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Shining" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 123 - Lightly NSFW</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/14/OOCY123.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 123 - Lightly NSFW" /><published>2025-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/14/OOCY123</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/14/OOCY123.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bMMcj3Z.png" alt="A naked woman in bed with another woman holding her phone up excitedly, going 'That's it! I love the internet!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Huh?</p>

<p>source: Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 159 - Sutte Hakkun</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/12/RA159-SutteHakkun.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 159 - Sutte Hakkun" /><published>2025-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/12/RA159-SutteHakkun</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/12/RA159-SutteHakkun.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EJFXz4D.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Sutte Hakkun is a fascinating little game by Nintendo, made for the SNES. Sort of. See, the SNES had an add-on in Japan called the Satellaview, which allowed you to download games via satellite broadcast. A lot of the more popular games for the system are the Nintendo properties, like Mario and Zelda, and those are cool. They were like, weekly broadcasts with voice and a story and whatnot. This is not one of those kinda things. This is a collection of puzzles, which were broadcast, with new ones being added every now and then, until they released the whole thing as a stand alone cartridge. In 1998.</p>

<p>1998 is a very late time to be releasing Super Famicom games, but what do I know? Sutte Hakkun has since become a kind of dark horse cult favorite among the people who’ve ACTUALLY tried it, cause it certainly never came out here. What’s it like?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x1Y2XOQ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Sutte Hakkun, you play as, well, Hakkun. He’s a little glass bird thing, and he’s pretty cute. He can move, jump, and <strong>succ</strong>. If he sucks and there’s something to suck up, he’ll grab that thing into his body, which he can then carry around and spit back out somewhere. Things like blocks, rocks, little dog friends. You can also hold the spit button and a direction to place things more deliberately and specifically, which is useful. You can also suck up colors. There are three colors, which will effect objects in a specific way depending on the color.</p>

<p>If you have a red block, it’ll move up and down. Blue blocks move horizontally. Yellow blocks go diagonally. You can also color the dogs, which will become bouncy and squishy if red, walk back and forth if blue, and slam the ground over and over if yellow. That last one is good for hitting switches.</p>

<p>Other than that, you’ve got rocks, smug little mother fuckers which can break glass floors if dropped from high above and cannot be moved through. Blocks CAN be moved through btw. The rocks also limit your jump. You’ve got fake blocks that can’t be sucked up but can be scared away by sucking at them. And uh… I think that’s it!It’s not an overly complex system.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FG54aNO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But with those simple foundations comes a very deep and enriching experience. Sutte Hakkun is some REALLY good puzzling. Puzzles get very brain tickly, and what starts as a simple cute time will make you sit there like Gendo for like 3 minutes trying to figure out wtf to do.</p>

<p>The game ALSO has a score system, a rather unique one. It’s based on movement. If you move, or do ANY action, the number goes down. Try and get the highest score. That’s it. It’s not really something you need to interract with much, but it’s cool to have for those into it. There’s ALSO some bonus levels you can unlock after the game is done, which is really cool. This game’s got a shocking amount of depth. It’s also real pretty, the music is very nice, and its cute and charming as hell.</p>

<p>All in all, I had an fantastic time playing Sutte Hakkun, and if you’re into puzzlers, especially puzzle platformers, it comes highly recommended. I basically haven’t had this good of a time with a puzzler since I picked up Ice n’ Fire. I wish we had gotten more from this little fella, but apparently there are some Satteliview levels that didn’t get ported to this version, so maybe I’ll have to check those out someday.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Sutte Hakkun" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 122</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/12/OOCY122.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 122" /><published>2025-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/12/OOCY122</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/12/OOCY122.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yvtF8pf.png" alt="Woman with a blank expression, zoomed in on her face in three different angles as she goes 'huh?' over and over" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Huh?</p>

<p>source: The One Within the Villainess</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The One Within the Villainess" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 121</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/11/OOCY121.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 121" /><published>2025-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/11/OOCY121</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/11/OOCY121.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bac0KLy.png" alt="Angry woman is at a bar thinking to herself. 'Whats so wonderful about het couples... Whats so great about them?! Contributing to the country's birthrate?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sevendays</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sevendays" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 16-20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/09/LizstartrekDS97-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 16-20" /><published>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/09/LizstartrekDS97-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/09/LizstartrekDS97-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Vf2hKzS.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Inter Arma Enim Silent Leges</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j3joEyT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Rolumans are still a… tough group to get along with. But Bashir is going to a conference on Romulus! Hopefully he can help bridge that gap between their cultures! Garrak thinks Bashir is a dumb optimist. Bashir wakes up in the middle of the night with a bad feeling though, turns on the lights, and finds… SLOAN!</p>

<p>Remember Section 31? Star Trek fans are unhappy that THEY remember Section 31, considering the recent shit that came out. Well, Bashir is technically associated with Section 31. Section 31 are the Secret Police, who do what they want. They’re awful. And they decided Bashir is part of the team now, even though he’s disgusted by them. But Sloan is like “oh you’ll work for us. You are a man who loves secrets.” He’s basically saying “You love James Bond movies, so you’d be great as a spy”. Anyways, Bashir is basically going to be a double agent, working with Admiral Ross, the only good Admiral we’ve ever met, against Sloan.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dgSb9hr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sloan explains to Bashir what he’s there for. There’s a Romulan politican who is likely to be promoted soon, a Tal-Shiar operative named Koval. He’s also BIG anti-Earth. But they think he might have a disease. So they want to accelerate the disease. Not NOW, of course, this is just here to try and figure more info out. After they find this out, Ross is like “okay I’m arresting him. He also probably has an accomplice, so be on the look out” and then is suddenly thrown in the med bay with a sudden case of Being Sick. Hmm. Sus.</p>

<p>Bashir has no one else to turn to. He thinks a senator will be killed, even if that would help Earth, he can’t let that happen. He’ll do the right thing. So he goes to Cretak. Cretak was the Romulan working with DS9, she’s a patriot but a nice enough woman. She’s the only one he can trust. But they’re caught, and Koval tortures Bashir to get info on who he’s working with. He and Cretak are then dragged before the council, and the trial starts.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F1aK3Ry.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Bashir comes clean and explains that Section 31 is trying to kill them. It might destroy their alliance, but it’s the right thing. Koval is like “Ahhh but there’s more to the story”, and brings out Sloan. He then explains that Section 31 is not real, and does not exist. It’s a fake plan made up by Sloan, who’s here for revenge to kill Koval for killing his mentor. Sloan is shot and killed, and then Cretak is censured and taken away for working with Federation intelligence and betraying Romulus. Bashir is allowed to go, he was basically just a sap in all this.</p>

<p>Something doesn’t sit well with Bashir though, and he realizes what’s wrong. He goes to Admiral Ross, and tells him he knows, and Ross spills his guts. I KNEW there were no good Admirals! It was all set up. Koval is their mole, and they were there all along to get Cretak fired, because they felt she’d turn on the Federation if it helped Romulus. And Sloan was teleported out just in time. Ross justifies himself by quoting Ciciero. Hey, that’s cool, remind me what happened to Ciciero again???</p>

<p>Sloan comes to gloat at Bashir, and thank him for doing EXACTLY what he knew he’d do. The right thing. Because that’s actually waht they wanted out of him the entire time. “Section 31 is here to protect people like you.” And it kind of… drowns Bashir in the sorrow of it all. And the episode ends.</p>

<p>Good episode. Kinda depressing, in a good way. I still don’t mind the Section 31 stuff… depending how it ends.</p>

<p><strong>Penumbra</strong> - DS9
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Utcnerp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Sisko and his girlfriend, Kasidy, having a sweet talk about what he’ll do when he retires. He got some land on Bajor, and intends to retire there. It’s cute. Meanwhile, turns out Worf is missing after his ship went down. Oh, that’s a swing.</p>

<p>The Defiant gives up the search. Things are too dangerous, and they aren’t even sure if he made it off his ship before it exploded. Sisko calls Ezri specifically to tell her this. I dunno why, she’s not his wife. She goes to Worf’s room, and has a bunch of flash backs to Jadzia episodes, and declares that she will find him. She steals a Runabout, and Sisko basically just LETS her go, which everyone acknowledges means she’ll prolly just die, cause a Runabout in Dominion space is a Bad Idea.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/D2p4mot.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a cute scene with Sisko and Casidy, and Sisko proposes to her. It’s adorable. It then jumps to Ezri about to vomit as she is flung around the violent storms of the Badlands. This episode has a tone problem. She finds Worf, and he’s a little shit about it, as he usually is. It’s VERY awkward. Ezri keeps trying to walk and be pleasant and Worf is, as usual, a little shit. They’re then caught and attacked, and crash land on a planet. Well now they have PLENTY of time to talk!</p>

<p>Everyone finds out Sisko is getting married, and all of the Bajorans on teh station are super exicted. They have kids asking if they can be a part of it. It’s gonna be the BIGGEST wedding! Welp, that IMMEDIATELY complicates things. That’s what you get for marrying Space Jesus, Kasidy.</p>

<p>Ezri and Worf get into a yelling match. Worf is being a little shit, I’m taking Ezri’s side here. He calls her a slur and then when she tries to slap him he grabs her and kisses her. I literally, out loud, went “What the FUCK?!”. They fuck, it’s EXTREMELY sudden, and then some Breen capture them and drag them away in a ship.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1Nny6UE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Also Gul Dukat is back and has a meeting with Damar! I’m sure that’ll be good. He asks Damar for one last favor, and then we find out he had some surgery to make himself look like a Bajoran. God, this is UNCANNY.</p>

<p>Sisko is given a vision by the Prophets, with his mom! Well, his ‘mom’. If you remmeber, his mom was possessed by a Prophet, so that they could make The Sisko be born. She tells him “Uh no, you’re not supposed to be married. That’s not your fate. Now go do what we want you to do.” Sisko is angry at first but then he’s like “Mommy :o” and they have a moment.</p>

<p>And then the episode ends. The rest of the episodes are gonna be pretty interconnected from here on out!</p>

<p><strong>‘Til Death Do Us Part</strong> - DS9
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X6e413w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kai Winn comes to congratulate Sisko on his marriage, but he’s like “I was told not to marry and I’m unsure what to do. The Prophets never explain themselves well”. She once again responds with “Well they’ve never spoken to me, I wouldn’t know.” WHY. IS. THIS. WOMAN. POPE?</p>

<p>Well, she does in fact get a message from the Prophets!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WvObvB7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She gets a vision, and they tell her EXACTLY what she’d want them to say. You are the only one who can save Bajor. You will help us. The Sisko has faulted. You are our last hope. They tell her that a messenger will come to help her. Ohhh man. EXACTLY what she needed to hear.</p>

<p>Sisko tells Kasidy he can’t marry her and she gets angry and storms out. Dog, my man. Just remind her that the last time you iognored their warnings, Dax died. Kasidy, do you want Dax to die AGAIN? WE’RE RUNNING OUT OF DAXES, KASIDY. Next time it’ll be a man, and the fandom will RIOT, KASIDY.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JlVmX0A.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gul Dukat comes, calling himself Anjohl. He’s just a simple farmer, here to ask Kai Winn for help. And, much like earlier, they say exactly what she wnats to hear. EXACTLY. Small code words that make her go “oh it’s just like that obscure prophecy I read about and I can insert myself into!” And he tells a fake story about how he was saved, and she’s like “Oh I did that! I rerouted the ship that would have killed you, during the occupation!” They are playing her like a fucking FIDDLE, it’s BRILLIANT!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/latstfW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then they fuuuuuck</p>

<p>The Breen are doing some brain stuff to Worf and Dax, and in Dax’s confusion she declares she loves Julian, and it makes Worf angry. This is stupid. When she wakes up he’s pissy and says she dishonors all of them. Yeah, Dax. You dishonor Bashir, can’t you TELL he’s gay? Him and Garak? THey hold hands every morning at their breakfasts.</p>

<p>Sisko decides to marry anyway. Kira is annoyed, cause she knows what it’ll mean, but everyone lets him do it anyway, it’s his mistake to make. I’m sure NO bad side effects will happen because of this, at all.</p>

<p>The Breen beam Worf and Dax over, and Weyoun announces that the Dominion and the Breen are now allied. That’ll be good, I’m sure.</p>

<p>Most of this was mid but I’ve really been enjoying the Kai stuff.</p>

<p><strong>Strange Bedfellows</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Nu9Aa6a.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Apparently the name of a high ranking Breen officer is “Thot”. They make the hos high ranking military officials. As it should be. Goo girl Breen tho Damar is ENRAGED by this Breen alliance treaty, because it appears to involve giving up a lot of Cardassian territory if they enter the war and help. Well if you can’t trust the fascist Dominion to ACTUALLY protect you and your people. To be fair to Damar, he did not ally with the Dominion. Damar is a VERY interesting antagonist, because he’s the wrong person at the wrong place at the wrong time. He’s a drunk incompetent toady who fell into leadership because of where he was and now he has to sit with it and it EATS at him. It’s like if Starscream actually became the leader of the Decepticons. What do you even do then???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/et9bX7i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I agree Dax, I wish Worf would shut the fuck up. Weyoun comes in and taunts them, because they’ll die in two days if they don’t give him military secrets. Worf breaks his neck. Weyoun died instantly. It is hilarious. Damar especially seems to think so. He’s SO amused he stops the guards from killing Worf, and laughs his ass off, and lets them be for the day, but not before telling them they’ll be executed in two days if they don’t give them what they want.</p>

<p>Weyoun 8 shows up, and is like “they haven’t decided to cooperate?” and Damar goes “No. Maybe you should talk to Worf again!” before laughing his ass off. God, that’s so fucking funny. He gets angry when he learns that the Breen are getting access to all of Cardassia’s military, though. Something rotten in the state of Cardassia.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QJ9I2ZP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The truth come out. Well, part of it. Winn realizes she’s working for the Pah Wraiths and NOT the Prophets now. She has a crisis of faith, and begs the Prophets to talk to her and tell her what to do. They don’t. I do wonder how much could be done to save the galaxy if they had just spoken to her ONCE and asked her to chill the fuck out. But they continue to ignore her. She’s like “WHAT HAVE I DONE TO BE FORSAKEN? AM I NOT WORTHY OF YOUR LOVE?” I dunno, maybe it was when you <strong><em>bombed a fucking school full of children in the first season</em></strong>. She goes to Kira, of all people, like “I am having a crisis of faith what can I do?” and she’s like “Well maybe they want nothing to do with you because you’ve given in to temptations of power” “Yes, I have done that” “So don’t do that anymore.” “Yes, you’re right.” “Good, I’m glad you’re stepping down as Kai.” “What? Why would I do that?” BITCH. ARE YOU SO FUCKING BLIND.</p>

<p>This is such a good view on fundamentalist religious fuckheads.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t4pTgLi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>More Cardassians die every day. “How many more sacrifices will my people be asked to make?” “YOUR people? We all serve the founders.” This is the final straw. Damar has been a laughing stock, and all he’s done is drown in alcohol. That changes. That changes now.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Vf2hKzS.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Great line. I hate this, but like, I hate it cause of how it makes Worf act. It’s well written if you realize Worf is a shithead and aren’t supposed to feel for him at all, but I LOVED TNG Worf. DS9 Worf fucking blows. Every time he’s happy with Ezri and the things she does and says, she’s Jadzia. Whenever he’s angry with her, she’s Ezri. It’s like a fucked up version of the Virgin Whore complex. Eventually though they come to a realization and talk it out, which is good, but the bad taste in my mouth is still there.</p>

<p>As they’re being taken away to be executed, Damar, kills the guards and sends them on the way. But in payment, they must bring a message to the Federation, that they have an ally on Cardassia. The revolution is beginning. He’s not OUT about it yet, but he’s working to undermine them, piece by piece. When the Founder calls Weyoun 8 to be talked to about the prisoners escaping, Damar is like “I’m sure she’ll understand. If not, I look forward to meeting Weyoun 9.” God he’s so fucking funny.</p>

<p>The episode ends with Kai Winn agreeing to become Anti-Pope for the Pah Wraiths. Anything to hold power, huh Winn?</p>

<p>This episode had a fun theme with multiple characters changing sides. As things reach their breaking points, what will you do to stand true of your ideals? Will you stand by them, or will you break? Damar stood true. Winn will not.</p>

<p><strong>Strange Bedfellows</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x9di9Bg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with the Breen attacking Earth, blasting the shit out LA. Things are ramping up. Weyoun congratulates the Breen on their brash attacks, but Damar warns them. They once praised the Cardassians as well. Now they blame them for not winning them the war sooner. If it goes on… the Breen might be next on the chopping block.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8WzIdj8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kasidy burns some of Sisko’s food, some peppers he’s been growing for months, and he’s dismayed about it. Maybe this is the endless sorrow the prophets warned him about.</p>

<p>Damar has a meeting with one of his oldest friends and trusted military officials. They’re planning a rebellion. His ally, Gul Rusot, laments that they’re hiding and sneaking in this war. What are they, Romulans? To me, they feel less like Romulans. I think they seem more like…… Bajorans :3</p>

<p>We jump between a few minor things. Trouble in paradise with Sisko and Kasidy. Kai Winn taking the necronomicom and studying it, even though it appears it have no words written inside. Worf and Ezri watch and comment on Julian, since Ezri is into him now. I like Worf FAR more as a sassy wingman than as an annoying jealous dickstick.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u8S7bRE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Defiant goes into a ship to try and stop the Breen assault. It ends poorly. They have to flee the Defiant, and we watch it explode. RIP to the Defiant. It was basically just a gun with an engine, but it was OUR gun with an engine. The Female Changeling declares that they should let the escape pods leave, because then they’ll be frightened and not fight back. Ah yes, the Tarkin Maneuver. That always works! Let’s let Sisko live, that’s a GREAT IDEA!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOFzMwp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Kai’s servant, Solbor, finds out through a blood test that Dukat is actually Dukat. And he tells Kai Winn, who is DISGUSTED by the fact that she let THAT tap it. Fair response. But then when Solbor is like “Wait you’re working with the PAH WRAITHS?! YOU’RE NUTS”, he’s stabbed. His blood activates the Necronomicon and shows ancient texts. And that call to evil… breaks her further. She can’t even resist GUL DUKAT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t412TV2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I am going to be using this image for a long time.</p>

<p>When everything looks bad, a message comes across all the screens. Damar announces the rebellion of Cardassia. They attacked their first target, the cloning facilities, so NO MORE WEYOUNS. We’re on our Last Weyoun. Damar is possibly the LAST HOPE for the Alpha Quadrant. We might be doomed.</p>

<p>I’ve really liked these past two episodes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievements Unmastered 2 - Final Fantasy 7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/09/RAUM2-FF7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievements Unmastered 2 - Final Fantasy 7" /><published>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/09/RAUM2-FF7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/09/RAUM2-FF7.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V6fo0Rc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I’ve been doing all the sets for each of the Final Fantasy games, but I’ve been dreading FF7. Not because of the game. I’d never beaten it and have wanted to replay it for years. No, its cause the RA set is actually just bad. It’s a bad set. I try not to use words like that for volunteer work, but there’s a reason I did not master this game, and never will.</p>

<p>But I DID still play it, and thats what matters, so let’s talk about Final Fantasy 7. This review WILL talk about spoilers to one of the most popular games of all time, which you’ve probably played. You’ve been warned.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wceg0SG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Final Fantasy 7 is the 7th FF game, obviously, unless you ignore those ones that don’t count, AND if you ignore the fact that it’s actually the fourth that came out here. Ohhh to be a Final Fantasy fan back then. Either way, this is the Big One. The series was popular before this, but this was THE big one. It was fucking MASSIVE. It still IS massive. There’s a reason Squeenix lit a billion dollars on fire to make a sequel, it’s cause it’s extremely beloved. Maybe the most beloved game I’ve ever even attempted to review. Other games have more rabid fan bases, but maybe none as rabid and LARGE. What are my thoughts on it? Well, we’ll see…</p>

<p>In FF7, you play as Cloud, a soldier and ex-SOLDIER. SOLDIER are like, a super soldier squad for Shinra, a mega corporation that basically rules the world. Unlike every Final Fantasy game before it, which were all high fantasy, FF7 is cyber punk-ish. It’s grungy, dark, and rusty. The game starts in Midgar, a megacity with shitty slums and violent megacorporations. It’s a significant departure. Cloud has been hired by Avalanche, an eco terrorist cell. Like, literal eco terrorists. Its leader, Barret, has hired you to blow up a reactor, because that reactor runs on Mako, which is the life force of the planet. Yes, this game has a VERY heavy environmental theme. A thing I feel very strongly about, personally.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EfuArA8.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The environmental message is strong, but it feels a bit mealy mouthed in parts. In the end, Barret realizes that blowing up that reactor was WRONG, because uh, violence solves nothing. Anyways Cloud let’s go kill this guy, Sephiroth. It could be a stronger message, tbh.</p>

<p>Let’s talk Sephiroth. Sephiroth is the “villain” of the game. Kind of. He’s an ex-SOLDIER too, the best of the best, but he disappeared a few years ago when he and Cloud went on a mission to Cloud’s home town. In truth, Cloud fought him, but barely remembers anything of it, because his memory is spotty. His friend Tifa was there too, but she’s cagey about the whole thing. But see, the thing is, Sephiroth is not really the villain of this game. We basically see Sephiroth one time in the whole game, in the flashback where we see him go insane and kill Cloud’s home town. Then he’s killed and thrown to his death. Every other Sephiroth we see is a meat virus called Jenovah masquerading as him, or some clones of him that are broken and unfinished. The REAL villain of this game is either Jenovah, who’s a barely sentient alien virus, or Hojo, who’s the kind of mad scientist dumbass who thinks that a human-like species and a dog should fuck, or that the next stage of human evolution is A Pile Of Meat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yvCMSxZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Honestly? I don’t like Sephiroth. I find him boring. And that’s ignoring the fact we barely see him, even if we consider ALL Sephiroths we see as Sephiroth, as one unified Will, he’s not interesting. He’s a muahaha I will take over the world villain in a very boring way. He’s not as austentatious as Ex-Death, nor as fun as Kefka. He’s taken as this serious cool badass bishonen and then he does silly stupid stuff, but it doesn’t hit like Kefka’s silly stupid stuff, because you don’t think it’s SUPPOSED to be silly and stupid. But it is.  I genuinely do not get why people fell in love with him so much. Like, I do, he looks</p>

<p>The best part about Sephiroth is the stuff AROUND him more than him. And by that I mean his connections to Cloud. See, Cloud isn’t who he thinks he is. The entire game, lies are CONSTANTLY being fed to you, both by Cloud’s own fallible memories, tampered by drugs and experiments, and by ‘Sephiroth’ planting lies in his head and manipulating him through their Jenovah connection, cause Cloud has Jenovah cells in him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Uxra15G.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Though that’s an important thing about Final Fantasy 7. Those cool moments with Cloud being unsure who he is, and of the game lying to you? It’s hard to follow, because of just the NATURE of that, and also the game kind of being poorly written/translated in parts. It can be VERY hard to follow what’s going on, you basically need someone reading a wiki page, and that wiki page is using information from future FF7 games to explain what the fuck is going on. It’s hard to follow to a fault. And the translation is pretty infamously rough. THey did their best. It was one dude’s work, and he was no Ted Woolsey. But This Guy ARE Sick. Also the r-slur is used, which is fucking terrible.</p>

<p>How is the gameplay? It’s good! It’s typical Final Fantasy, though with a few twists. All your characters are KIND of blank slates. The way it works is, they’re kind of blank slates with unique limit breaks and weapons, but they can be augmented with Materia, which is solified Mako that grants magic. It’s an evolution of FF6’s Esper system, and it’s done MOSTLY well, but by the end I found it very unwieldly. If you want to use it effectively, it takes a LOT of AP grinding. If you don’t want to grind, you can’t use it very well, or at all. And you don’t NEED to? But it makes it WAY easier.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SHwJeRH.gif" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You may be thinking I’ve been very harsh on this game. And I have been. I actually like it quite a bit, and there’s a lot to like. I like all of the characters. Cait Sith and Yuffie fall a bit more flat to me, and Red XIII feels so poorly utilized, his ONE major plot point is the worst part of the game. Bugenhagen lied to Red XIII about his dad for years, AS A JOKE. But the rest of them are great. Ilike Cloud, he’s SO different form how people pretend he is. They pretend he’s a stoic badass emo boy. No, that’s Squall. Cloud is a massive dork who loves his friends. Barret is cool as hell. Aerith is cute AND a horrible Goblin, which I appreciate. Cid can be awful but in a way I kinda love. And of course Tifa is perfect, and my wife.</p>

<p>The thing about the story and characters is that they are good, but there are a lot of lulls. The start of the game is by FAR the best part. The first like 6-7 hours are Midgar, and those are very, VERY good. Once you get out of Midgar the game slooooowly slumps, and it never really improves. All the fun scenes and interesting story are replaced for a while by weird gimmick mini games, which this game fucking LOVES, and they are VERY bad for pacing and vibes.</p>

<p>The most famous scene of the entire game, a major character death, is IMMEDIATELY followed up by Cloud doing a fucking snowboarding mini game segment, which is SUCH a tonal whiplash. Like, what the fuck.</p>

<p>A lot of this game astounded me, because I had no idea why they designed things they way they designed. As I delved deeper, into specific mechanics and bonus content, I was ASTOUNDED by how weird all of it was. Why did they build it this way? As a joke? Like for example, the end game dungeon. You split up your party, and who you send where determines what items they find. But some characters can’t find some items, so there’s an optimal way to send them, and you can ALSO circle back to get their items, doublign items. Why? There’s a LOT of stuff like that, where there’s an optimal way to do things, and you need to look them up cause they are NEVER explained and hard to figure out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yNI4NPG.gif" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In all, I like FF7, but it’s nowhere near the perfect experience people make it out to be. That’s why I was optimistic about FF7 Remake. This story, and its characters, could be cool with a bit more of a modern retooling, and I think the remake fixed a lot of the issues. But I honestly HATE FF7R’s gameplay, and its pacing has some issues. But thats a story for another day.</p>

<p>In the end, I’ve played FF1-3, and 5-7 all the way through semi-recently. I skipped 4 because I don’t like it and the set was pissing me off, I’ll get back to it soon, I promise. But of those, I’d say FF7 is… 4th place. Behind FF6, 5, and 3. Yes, I liked 3 more, honestly. Depends on the day, prolly, but TODAY I like 3 more.</p>

<p>Still a good game. Please don’t kill me.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PS1" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Unmastered" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 158 - Catrap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 158 - Catrap" /><published>2025-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JS9Pthf.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I played a homebrew NES game called Witch n’ Wiz recently, and it was a cute little puzzle game. As I was playing it someone in chat went “Huh, this is kinda just Catrap”. And then I played Catrap and uh, yeah. It’s the same game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Mx3p01H.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Catrap you play as two people cursed to become cat people. Oh no, uh, how horrible. They can ‘break’ the curse though, by defeating all the enemies! It’s 100 levels, infinite lives, and it saves. This game is shockingly ahead of its time for 1990. Anyways, you can play as either the catboi or the catgirl, and they play exactly the same except for ONE thing I’ll mention later. You can defeat enemies by walking into them, but only from the side, otherwise they’re platforms. And with that, push blocks and use sand effectively to make your way through 100 levels!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ty0mfwO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Catrap is a fantastic puzzle game, with great puzzle design, and I’m frankly stunned by how ahead of the curve it is for 1990. It’s got a few fun gimmicks too, like some levels have you control both girl and boy, and swap between them with select, making for fun twisty levels. The one thing that got me though, is that the set has some “beat this level as fast as you can” achievements. Which y’know, is fine. You can basically buffer your inputs, so as long as you remember where to go, it’s honestly easy. The DIFFICULT part was that, in one of the challenges, I just couldn’t do it. I was like 2 seconds off. I watched a TAS. I was following it EXACTLY, still couldn’t get there. Why? What was I doing wrong? Then, I found out…. the boy is faster. Their climbing animations are different, and the boy’s is much faster than the girl’s. That’s it. It CONFOUNDED me. So I had to play as the boy for those levels, sadly.</p>

<p>The only thing the actual GAME has against it, IMO, is the music. It’s pretty rough, even for 1990 Gameboy standards. Like, we’re quite a ways off from Pokemon TCG, sure, but this is honestly kinda bad.</p>

<p>But yeah, fantastic game, and if you like puzzlers, you should check it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Catrap" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 120</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 120" /><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7Axr1s3.png" alt="'I was going to let you take control today, but in the end you still backed down. I think that side of you is cute, but... I also have my limits...' 'E-eh?! Wait, hold on!' 'I'm done waiting.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Day I Tried to Go on the Offensive</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Day I Tried to Go on the Offensive" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>