<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-29T22:33:27-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 168</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 168" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PDdBpKW.png" alt="'Two girls look back at each other, one on a train that's about to move away. The train girl is pulling down her face mask to reveal her blushing face'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oJHRxce.png" alt="'Train girl leans her head down bashfully as the train rolls away'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n3Jgc2r.png" alt="The girl outside of the train starts blushing 'CUTE! OH MY GOD SO CUTE!! SHE'S SO CUUUUUUTE!!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: From Aiu Station on the Hiragana Line</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="From Aiu Station on the Hiragana Line" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 192 - Dragon Quest 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/29/RA192-DQ4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 192 - Dragon Quest 4" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/29/RA192-DQ4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/29/RA192-DQ4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jjlm4fx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Last year I played Dragon Quest 1-3. I’d only ever beaten DQ1 before, but I was a huge fan of it as a kid, so I was excited to finally sit down and beat DQ2 and 3. I’d played them, but never got very far. This one I had barely played at ALL, and put off until this year because it’s the start of a new series! Dragon Quest 4 is a new step for the series, and I’d heard it was good, but I REALLY liked 3, so I didn’t expect it to quite reach those heights.</p>

<p>Uh, I was fucking wrong. Dragon Quest 4 blew my fucking mind. This might actually just straight up be my favorite RPG on the NES now. Mother 1 is still holding on, but I’ll be real, it’s close.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xpJGjhl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Dragon Quest 4 tries for a new thing for the series: a plot! That’s a joke, but also kinda not. DQ1-3 had very mild plots. 3 had a bit more of it, but it was really about the scene to scene stuff. This game not only has a plot, but it also goes about it in a unique and interesting way. This game has like 7 heroes, and it introduces you to each of them by each chapter, as they’re doing their own things. Finally, after all their chapters, you’re introduced to YOU, the main character, the chosen hero, and the game fully opens up, with you collecting the crew and saving the world. Notably, you can also be a woman! And the game actually acknowledges that fact and doesn’t just fucking ignore it, like it did in DQ3!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g5aODwl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The different chapters range from your typical kinda fantasy story to very unique weird shit. Like, it starts with a knight trying to find kids who’ve been kidnapped by monsters. By the later chapters you’re a merchant trying to save up money for his own store, with unique mechanics exclusive to him about trying to get as much money as you can.</p>

<p>So, other than the story, what does this game have going for it? Well, it’s more Dragon Quest! And I really like NES Dragon Quest. It plays well, is well balanced, has fun progression, and has a LOT of extra content. This is the first game with little medals, for example. And they’re VERY well hidden, too, as they usually are.</p>

<p>Frankly, I don’t have that much more to add?? Like… it’s just an EXTREMELY high quality NES RPG. It’s still an NES RPG. You will have to grind. You will get confused about where to go on occasion, though it’s got a lot of QOL shit that earlier games REALLY did not have. Shout outs to the Return spell taking you to any town, yay. I’m excited to replay this someday with the DS version. But for now, it’s just fantastic, and I highly recommend it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 191 - Where in Hell is Carmen Santiago</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/27/RA191-WhereInHell.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 191 - Where in Hell is Carmen Santiago" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/27/RA191-WhereInHell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/27/RA191-WhereInHell.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fhqU3q3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is maybe one of the more interesting games I’ve ever played for this project. This is Where In Hell Is Carmen Santiago, and first we have to discuss what it is. Retro Achievements describes it as a “homebrew”, though notably, it came out in 1990. Japan has a word for games like these: Doujin. Self published games. But English really only has the term Homebrew, which is a newer term and doesn’t quite fit. It’s good enough.</p>

<p>This game was made by St. John M. Morrison in 1990, and that man is a MASSIVE nerd. You’ve got to be a huge dork to make an Apple II homebrew, but this guy really was a huge computer nerd. But let me first put you in the mind of a nerd paying attention to Apple II products in the late 80s.</p>

<p>Carmen Sandiego was a huge hit, and many jokes were made about it. I remember one I often heard: Where the hell is Carmen Sandiego? Well, Mr. Morrison took that joke and decided to run with it. This is both a Carmen Sandiego game, and an ecucational game, teaching you all about Dante’s Inferno! Well, it’s not actually very educational, but that’s okay. I actually studied Dante in college and wrote my thesis on him so like, I’m at least well versed in this shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FKpqezW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Where In The Hell, you must walk through Hell and interrogate V.I.L.E members, who are souls burning in Hell for historical crimes, in order to find where Carmen Santiago lies. Hell in Dante’s model is basically a straight line, going deeper, with each layer having the souls suffer for a different sin. You can move up and down, use items you find, look around to learn more about the layer, search for items, or call a name. When you call a name, you have a list of the V.I.L.E souls, and must theorize about whether that soul will be in that layer. If you guess right, they’ll come out, and you can interrogate them and ask them for items to help you on your quest. These items are things that let you get past later obstacles, basically.</p>

<p>It’s not actually that educational and is a lot of trial and error. But eventually you’ll find Carmen and she gives you an item to escape. And that’s it, right? Nope! This game has a second mode, known as “Pit of the Programs”. Remember how I told you Mr. Morrison was a MASSIVE computer nerd? We’re putting that to the test.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ITdhFlp.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kvjcyDW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All of the historical souls are replaced with characters that are references to popular edutainment games on the Apple II, like Stickybear or Reader Rabbit, turning into Stinkybear or Reaver Rabbit. Or, they’re referencing computer concepts, like vaporware. The map of Hell is the same, but its WAY more trial and error to try and find out where the hell anyone is and what they do. And it’s all just one big joke. It’s kind of a funny joke! One I like. But a joke.</p>

<p>This is a fascinating little program. It’s mostly making fun of a popular game of the time, and is… interesting, but I dunno if you need to play it? But you SHOULD know it exists.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Homebrew" /><category term="Carmen Sandiego" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 167</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/27/OOCY167.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 167" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/27/OOCY167</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/27/OOCY167.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WOmnhfP.png" alt="'I think two girls clinging onto each other is a wonderful thing! Or rather, I'd like to do so!!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Couple Drifting in the Wind</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Couple Drifting in the Wind" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 15 - 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekVOY7-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 15 - 19" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekVOY7-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekVOY7-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/spOXX5x.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>The Void</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RENJoSO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While floating around aimlessly doing their thing, Voyager is pulled into a weird starless expanse by a gravitational surge, and are IMMEDIATELY attacked by a random ship. In the ensuing battle, 90% of their food stores and deuterium. Deuterium is a common fuel, you can find it anywhere… except here, apparently. Shortly after, another ship comes and is actually friendly! Its captain, a General Valen, explains that this is the Void. Ships cannot escape it. The only resources you can find are from the ships that come in here. Work with him, and they can survive longer by preying on the other ships. Give up on trying to escape.</p>

<p>Obviously they try to escape anyway. They have an ingenious plan to escape, but since they’re trying at the start of the episode, we know they’re gonna fail. They fail. Now low on power, with vultures circling them, they have to act quickly. They go after the ship that attacked them, but it’s already picked clean. They find a few things they can grab anyway, so they go in, and find someone who didn’t get picked up on the scans!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/udo2cAn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He can live with no atmosphere, is very skittish, and has no verbal skills. But he’s injured. They take him in, but he’s also VERY voracious and hungry. So is it a good idea to take him in now, while they’re so low on food already? Well, that’s just what we do.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1o2uC9R.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Their food is now with Valen, the original guy they met. He has their food now and refuses to give it back, so they take it with force. But even with it, they won’t live long. Chokie and Tuvok are like “Maybe we should actually be evil and violent, cause otherwise we won’t live”. Janeway has a different idea. She’ll bring Federation ideals to this lawless wasteland. She starts a formal alliance, to share supplies. Yes, this will dwindle their supplies that are already slim, but it’s a noble idea.</p>

<p>It’s slow going for now. No one is “officially” joining. And Janeway keeps giving away shit to try and make friends. “The best way to get help is to give it”. Tuvok thinks she’s illogical. Seven thinks she’s inefficient. But we’ll see how this morality play works out. I respect it.</p>

<p>The Doctor names this weird creature they find. He’s very intelligent, but can’t communicate well. He’s called Fantome, after the Phantom of the Opera. Seven and the Doctor develop a way through tones and beeps to communicate.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0utV62C.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>After a ship appears and Voyager protects it, and another prospective member joins in to protect it, more ships begin ready to join, now that the alliance has some semblance of strength. We also learn about Fantome’s people. They are “vermin” who reside here, apparently. The other members of the alliance view them as a drain on resources. Janeway offers to take them onto Voyager.</p>

<p>Things hit a low as their possible chance of survival involves going against the alliance ideals. They have to exile a member from the alliance over this. Making a Federation is difficult. Janeway isn’t bothered with kicking him out, she’s bothered with taking him in the first place. He was bigoted the moment we saw him so she takes this as a sign she should keep her ideals strict. This guy IMMEDIATELY tries to form alliances with others to attack Voyager btw, so y’know.</p>

<p>They need to escape before their enemies can attack. They tell the void creatures, Fantome’s people, that if they want to stay here they should leave. They want to stay here, it’s their home, but want to help Voyager after all the help they gave them. So they beam out… to the engine rooms of the enemy ships, just as they attack. We get messages from the enemy ships… musical beeps. Genuinely so pleasant to hear. Great job, Fantome.</p>

<p>They manage to punch it out into normal space. The lights finally turn on in the ship. Thank God, it’s like we were watching Discovery or Picard.</p>

<p>Fun episode</p>

<p><strong>Workforce, Part 1</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/C8rM5pU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Janeway walking through a factory in a jumpsuit. She appears to be in Riven. She reports to work, excited to start a new job. Her boss seems nice, and she’s very qualified to work here, so she’s treated well. Oh boy! Wait why the hell is Janeway working in a factory</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4rW1Eww.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We also see Seven! Or excuse me, Annika Henson. She’s the new efficiency coordinator. She gets in on Janeway and some guy chatting it up and tells them to cut out the fraternizing. We also see Paris trying to get a job at a bar. So apparently, everyone doesn’t have their memories, and always believes they’ve been here? And then we see a jovial, friendly, laugihng Tuvok. Holy crap, I hate it. It’s uncanny valley.</p>

<p>Janeway’s coworker is coming onto her pretty strong. Janeway, please stop falling in love with mediocre men. Seven is literally right there. She can help you with… coordinating your efficiency. He also helps her keep up to date on her “innoculations”, regular vaccines against background radition. Oh I’m sure. And Tuvok having a PTSD episode about the innoculations is nothing big I’m sure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SXsjZHB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chokie, Neelix, and Kim are returning home from a long away mission to find Voyager is… not anywhere. They EVENTUALLY find it to find the Doctor is the only one there. He’s in Emergency Commander Hologram mode. Basically, Voyager hit some kind of mine and got inundated with radiation. Everyone left on escape pods and they left the Doctor behind to try and fix things as the ECH. She abandoned the ship REAL fuckin’ quick. He hid in a nebula, and any attempt to leave, he finds ships hunting for him, their signatures matching the mine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dcYqeBa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Of course, they’re all captured and given these innoculations that dull their memories. Memories are still creeping back, though. Tuvok can KIND of remember that he knew Janeway, but when he brings it up, he just creeps her out.</p>

<p>Chokie discovers where the crew are being kept. An M class planet, but when he goes to explain what happened to them, the officials are like “None of these people know who you are? They’re all working comfortable happy lives at the same power plant, why would they want to join your ship? Go look for labor elsewhere”. Apparently there’s a severe labor shortage. Neelix and Chakotay decide to find jobs down there.</p>

<p>This episode basically keeps jumping between Chakotay and Neelix trying to find the crew, while we jump between the members of the crew basically living alternate universe existences. Paris works at a bar, hitting on single pregnant mother Torres, but offers to just be her friend to help her through the hard times. Janeway gets in a mediocre uninteresting romance. Tuvok has an existential crisis and mind melds with Seven of Nine. You know, normal things.</p>

<p>Chokie and Neelix straight up abduct Belanna in the middle of an alleyway, which causes Voyager to immediately be fired upon as they try and run away. And then Chakotay runs away, and it ends uh, with Chakotay standing by a random railing making the one single expression he can make. Alright then. How thrilling.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Z5Zk5vL.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>To be continued.</p>

<p><strong>Workforce, Part 2</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fytHg2y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We continue where we left off. Tuvok getting his brain scrambled. Torres back on Voyager, but they can’t fix her immediately. Janeway moving in with some boring guy. Chakotay on the run from the cops. But we also have the cops hunting for him now, and closing in, and we also have two new character. Both doctors, treating Tuvok for “Disphoria Syndrome”. I got that too, but I dunno if I trust them to help me with it. One is less willing to scramble brains about it, but it IS the suggested procedure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oW6qgHr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay is being a creepy mother fucker. He’s hiding in Janeway’s room in the dark with a gun, injured. Creepy, dog. But he just heard she was moving out and was using the apartment to hide, tbf. But after a bit of talking, she actually is willing to HELP him. And when he slips she’s actually the captain, at first she’s against helping him anymore, but when he just… dermal regenerates his face back from plastic surgery. Just that easy?? But once she tells her boyfriend about it, he alerts the authorities aaaand he’s captured. His cop assigned to him, the one working on the case, is suddenly relieved of duty and Chakotay taken away to Section 6, brain surgery basically. The pieces are very, VERY obvious, and FINALLY people are making it out. The nicer doctor figures it out, Seven is working with the cop who’s starting to piece things together, and things MIGHT possibly work out. But the evil doctor is doing a LOT of illegal shit and has a lot of backing from a few powerful people. Unfortunately, nice doctor is captured and being reprogrammed too.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9FLuUiN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone teams up to work together. The resulting scenes are climactic and honestly, quite exciting. It works out in the end, the conspiracy is clear, and all’s well that ends well. Janeway’s boyfriend is given a reporter cause his supervisor was fired. Something about illegal abductions and human trafficking? They give a last hug goodbye, and that’s the end. Thank you, Bland Love Interest #7.</p>

<p>This one felt a bit better than the first. Had some good moments!</p>

<p><strong>Human Error</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hZNPxmz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>In the cold open, Seven plays piano out of makeup. It was a little jarring, cause it just cuts out of nowhere.</p>

<p>We have Belanna’s baby shower. It’s cute with some good fun lines and gags. Seven is there, without her implants. She’s being… normal and pleasant! Then she’s called to Astrometrics. End program. She’s been trying to improve her social skills, awww. When she’s ACTUALLY invited to the baby shower, she’s a little anxious about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/spOXX5x.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>SEVEN OF NINE IN UNIFORM OHHHH NOOOOOO.</p>

<p>I AM GAAAAAAAAY.</p>

<p>She’s actually quite good with the practice. Seeing her be open and friendly is REALLY nice. She makes a date with Hologram Chakotay and despite it being Chokie, it’s so nice. It kinda feels like how I expect her to be when she’s older, in Picard. UNFORTUNATELY, this episode is kind of ruined by the background information. This episode was a bet. Beltran, Chakotay’s actor, was dating Seven’s actress at the time, and made a bet to the screen writer he couldn’t make a good romance between Chakotay and Seven. It’s… weirdly uncomfortable of a concept to me.</p>

<p>In the real life, Seven appears to be… not as good at everything as she is in the holodeck. She’s avoiding regenerating. She gives a baby shower gift at a VERY inoportune time, as Belanna is trying to do warp core surgery. Then she asks her about her hair care routine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uCnV5CZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay. I am uninterested in this romance. Like, just on sheer CONCEPT, I do not like it. And like, Jeri Ryan is doing her best, but her making out with a hunk of white bread is not titilating to me. I like seeing Seven trying to be and act more Human, but not if it means she has to make out with Chakotay.</p>

<p>I also don’t feel like you should be allowed to make crew members on the holodeck. And CERTAINLY not to date and fuck them. We had this problem with Barclay already. Are we just supposed to be okay with it now cause it’s a hot autistic woman instead of a goofy autistic man??</p>

<p>She’s in there way too much. Shirking her duty to be in there. 49 hours in 6 days. Damn, imagine like, playing games or something that much, ha ha ha… hah. She also LIES to Janeway about why she’s in there so much, when Janeway’s like “can you try to actually do your job please, your fuck ups almost blew up the ship”. Janeway is VERY understanding.</p>

<p>She tries to break up with Holo Chokie. He doesn’t handle it well, because of course he wouldn’t. It causes a weird scramble in her system and she basically suffers some kind of attack. Her implants are not working right. When she comes to, the Doctor coaxes it out of her. She also explains why she chose Chakotay to date. “He was a good choice. He has many admirable qualities”. We won’t explain what any of them are. Also, that’s really just like saying “He was better than nothing I guess”. Which is maybe accurate.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L9kNODC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor does some scans, and determines that when she gets too emotionally stimulated, her implants cause her brain to shut down. He can fix it with several difficult surgeries, but she refuses. These holograms were just fantasties, anyway. It’s kinda sad, but that’s just… the way the episode ends. With her deciding not to engage with humanity like that. Hmm. It feels like this episode has no real reason to exist, other than just being a way for a guy to win a bet.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 2" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekSNW3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Hegemony Part 2</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEvb4AL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Following directly after last season, the Enterprise is surrounded by Gorn, and some of their people are captured on the Gorn ship. The Enterprise is forced to retreat… but not before tagging the Gorn ship with a dud missile that’s actually a secret beacon.</p>

<p>Pike’s girlfriend, Batel, is infected with Gorn Babies and they might need to kill her, but to prolong things, they’re freezing her in a block of ice. Specifically SHE’S the one asking them to kill her if they need to. Well, at least that’s the PLAN, but turns out she’s allergic to being stuck in a block of ice, which I imagine I’d be too. Now Nurse Chapel is stuck trying to figure out how to cure Being A Gorn Mom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vvOBev.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Admiral April is like “we have to just ignore all this and let the Gorn capture neutral people” and Pike, being Pike, says fuck that shit, we’re being treated as Prey. And April agrees, unofficially, their rules are to punch the Gorn in the nose and show they’re not prey. Meanwhile, in Engineering, Scotty and Pelia the Warpcore Witch are trying to get a Gorn Cloaking Device up. Scotty says it’s impossible. Pelia is like “we’ll have it done in an hour sir”. Scotty is, one day, gonna be REAL good at doing the impossible on a deadline, and he’s gotta figure out how to get good at it real fucking fast.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Gorn ship, La’an wakes up and punches her way out of a Gorn sack. She rescues the other members of the crew captures, including Sam Kirk (Kirk’s brother), Doctor M’Benga, and Ortegas (who has had half her hand melted off). They want to get out… well, three of them do. La’an decides then and there, she’s going to save ALL the other colonists. Good luck.</p>

<p>Y’all remember Mitchell? She was a very minor background character in season 1, had some minor roles in 2, and now she’s on the bridge and refuses to leave until they can solve this. Yay, Mitchell!</p>

<p>They have some SMALL hope. Batel has a 14% chance of survival if they use Una’s blood. Yay! Also the Gorn seem to go to sleep when a certain kind of star flare happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jFp5msI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FkBzvR4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit is going way, WAY worse. Man this is tense. While exploring a weird binary star that seems to hide the Gorn homeworld because of radiation, they find a BUNCH of Gorn ships blasting out of the zone and going towards Federation space. Now Pike has a choice. He might lose the tag on the colonists and his crew if he leaves to warn Starfleet, but they are NOT prepared for an invasion. So he makes the impossible choice and leaves them.</p>

<p>Pike seems so fucking done. He’s EXHAUSTED, he’s worrying about every single little thing. And can you blame him? When he goes to Scotty and Pelia like “Hey can we make a solar flare” and Scotty is like “what the fuck no. Not without doing this this that and this which will blow up the ship” Pike is like “Sure just do it without the blowing up the ship part” and everyone just… stares at each other.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of “have faith” talk in this episode, which we keep making fun of by posting Star Wars memes. It doesn’t help when Ortegas takes over a Gorn ship and flies them out in a scene that is VERY Star Warsy. Also Ortegas becomes massively injured in the skirmish, but sticks too it. Poor Ortegas, she can’t catch a break ):</p>

<p>We get a fuzzy fisheye scene with them in the radiation, but it works. They use the flare to trigger a hibernation in the Gorn, as they come back to go eep. Ortegas raises her deathflag REALLY high but is saved just before dying, thank fucking God. <em>sees death flag in Ortegas’ mouth</em> WHAT DO YOU HAVE THERE? PUT THAT DOWN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/evmRMxM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Batel is saved, Spock and Chapel have a moment of acceptance, and the Enterprise is beat to fuck. But alive. It ends the “have faith” talk with Pike thanking God for some reason.</p>

<p>I thought it was alright! Not blowing me away, but good! Excited for more.</p>

<p>I’ll be editing this page every week and reposting it with the new episodes as they come out =w=</p>

<p><strong>Wedding Bell Blues</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9FnKzZH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s 3 months after the nightmare of the last two episodes, and the Enterprise is repaired and ready! Everyone is going to a gala to try and relax! I’m sure this’ll go exactly as expected! To try and get into the spirit, and to practice for getting things going well with Nurse Chapel, Spock is practicing dancing with La’an.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Yol3Cdf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>BUT NOT A BRAIN! :D</p>

<p>Anyways, Chapel comes on board with the doctor she’s been working with for three months, Roger Korby. He’s a very friendly guy, but a bit eccentric. Anyways Spock almost makes an ass out of himself before we find out Korby is, in fact, dating Chapel now. Whoops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AkPLZfu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy HELL, Uhura’s outfit is on point.</p>

<p>Ortegas is doing better. Physically, at least. We meet her brother, who is flirting a bit with Uhura, who seems reticent. Ortegas isn’t into it, though.</p>

<p>Everyone gets together to drink a bit. Spock is, as usual, awkward. He steps away for a drink at the bar, and we get this like, weird Mxptlk mother fucker who’s tending bar. He appears as a Vulcan to Spock, but to us, he’s a weird mother fucker. He gives Spock a drink, who…  wakes up later that night next to Chapel. They’re getting married! Oh boy! I’m sure Chapel will handle this very well!</p>

<p>This Mxptlk ass dude is basically acting as wedding planner and getting everything all right and dandy. Is he a… shipper? Of Nurse and Spock?? I will say, over all, I haven’t really… been into the Chapel and Spock thing? It’s not JUST cause I know it won’t go anywhere, but also cause of how they just… don’t go together lmfao which I think this episode is doing its best to try and show.</p>

<p>Korby is the ONLY person who seems to realize something is wrong. He can remember things how they SHOULD be, and is trying to subtly sabatoge the wedding. Spock catches him, and he explains that this is all wrong. Spock punches him out, but then for some reason remembers that yes, this IS wrong, and… well yes, feels bad, but most importantly is like “this needs to be fixed”. He and Korby work together, they’re both smart science boys, and though they love the same woman, they have to work together to figure out what’s wrong.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3XmlT3E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s kinda fun to watch these two try and wander around a changed reality, testing at the waters and touching the boundaries to find where they are. Spock tries to get others to realize something is wrong. He tries to get Kirk to punch him. He insults his mustache. It doesn’t work.</p>

<p>When they confront the Wedding Planner about this, he reveals he’s a giant fucking baby and this is all a game to him, which they’ll have to play, or he will wipe everyone from existence. Welp. Korby and Spock change up their plan and yeah, the only thing they can possibly do now really, is try to go along with it. When Korby DOES act up, he’s turned into a dog, and no one else seems to care. They’re really just his puppets.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JsdWJEP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually Chapel snaps out of it too, thanks to Spock, and when the Wedding Planner announces everyone is going to die. But he’s interrupted by his… dad. Who is, in fact, played by John de Lancie. Hmm. The bartender is just a kid, and he’s made to clean up his toys. Everyone is like “WELL THAT WAS WEIRD” and then tries to celebrate the actual reason they’re there, the Cenntenial. La’an dances with Spock, who has no regrets. We have one of the three armed aliens from TAS, who joins the crew as their bartender, yay! Aaaaand Ortegas has a PTSD episode. Yay!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So I Watched All Of Sailor Moon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/25/SailorMoon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So I Watched All Of Sailor Moon" /><published>2025-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/25/SailorMoon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/25/SailorMoon.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/isWoBPw.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I watched the entirety of Sailor Moon. Let’s talk about it. This is straight up going to be a ramble about all my thoughts on Sailor Moon and I DOUBT it will be entertaining.</p>

<p>Sailor Moon was one of those shows that was very important to me as a kid. I was a huge fan, grew up watching it, but I hadn’t watched it basically since I was 6. But every time I TRIED watching it I bounced off it. I finally got to watch all of it, because of my community! We decided to get together every Thursday to watch anime for 5 hours. This anime club actually started last year, with us watching the first three seasons. We put off watching season 4 and 5 until the past two months, because we’d heard bad things. But now, finally, a year later, we’ve seen everything. And I wanna talk about it. Just my general thoughts.</p>

<p>For the most part, Sailor Moon is… okay. Honestly on average, it’s mid to not great, but there are flashes of brilliance, and some seasons are real good. But it’s never AMAZING, and there was always something in a season that annoyed me.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0E4gYWb.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Let’s talk season 1 to start. Season 1 is, IMO, the 2nd best season, and a good starting point. But it’s VERY slow to start, and very episodic. That’s the main thing about Sailor Moon, it’s chock full of filler that’s basically the following: Current incompetent general to big bad guy harasses some Humans, Sailor Moon and her cohort are there, the general summons a monster of the week that’s themed around the theme, and then runs away as Sailor Moon and the girls can’t beat the monster, then Tuxedo Mask shows up and they beat the monster. That is, without any exaggeration, 80% of Sailor Moon.</p>

<p>But the main thing about season 1 is it introduces our characters. Now, who the best Sailor Senshi are is an age old debate. And I will wade right into that debate. It’s Ami, and it’s not even close. Sailor Mercury is the best, and my favorite. Followed by one from season 3, and then followed by Sailor Jupiter who is also amazing and is sadly sidelined. That’s one of the issues with this series too, it often just sidelines characters cause there are so many. But that won’t be an issue until season 4, where it becomes VERY obvious.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jdDKJui.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Anyways season 1 is fine. Season 2 comes out! First we have an entirely filler arc about an evil tree. It’s bad! Like, actually bad. I really did not like it. But after that’s done its never mentioned again so it’s fine. But that means season 2 is basically half the length, and even then, it’s not very great, though it has its moments. The main problem I have with season 2 is how it handles Mamoru. Mamoru is Tuxedo Mask, btw. So season 1 has him showing up and it’s a big will they won’t they moment with him and Sailor Moon, and then they get together and it’s fine. Season 2 has Mamoru like, have a dream he misinterprets, and he thinks he has to be a shithead to Usagi. It was NOT pleasant.</p>

<p>Season 2 DOES introduce the Black Moon Clan though, which were my 2nd favorite evil cast of the entire group. I liked season 1’s enough, but I liked these guys’ ending. It was fun. (the SNES game completely shit on this conclusion which I hated) the anime does this thing a lot where it changes the fates of characters, usually saving them or killing them in a different way. These guys are the poster childs to me, though shout outs to Nephrite from season 1.</p>

<p>Oh also Season 2 introduces Chibi-Moon. She’s Sailor Moon’s future daughter sent back in time by Sailor Pluto, the badass guardian of time, basically on vacation. She’s kind of hated in some fandom circles but I like her. Not a LOT, but I like her. She’s just like, a goofy 7 year old comic relief character. I love when she powers up to do her attack and it’s a little thing that just annoys people, it’s funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cAzWEVR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So season 3 comes out, and it’s actually very good! This is, in my opinion, the best Sailor Moon gets. But it’s not perfect. Let’s introduce the Outer Senshi! I was REALLY excited for this season, because of two reasons. One, my second favorite senshi is, and has been for a long time, Sailor Saturn. I love her story, her design, her character, everything. And the season was THE COUSINS! So we watched the modern translation, they were NOT cousins, but I find that whole situation so fucking funny. If you somehow don’t know, this season introduces Uranus and Neptune, who are lesbians, but they re-wrote them as cousins in the original English localization. So you have these two cousins staring longingly into each others eyes and grasping each others hands and it’s so so SO MUCH WORSE than it would have been if they had just left it the fuck alone.</p>

<p>But unfortunately, this is my #1 worst thing about season 3… Sailor Uranus. So I really wanted to like her. She’s the princely lesbian character, super fun, but uh, her and Neptune have this thing in this season where they refuse to work with Sailor Moon and the others because they’re so certain that they need to kill people, even though Sailor Moon keeps proving that no, we can save them, over and over. This made us theorize that Uranus and Neptune just really, REALLY want to kill people. Season 5 did not help this outlook. At all. I’ll get to it.</p>

<p>Season 3 also has the best villains, the Death Busters. Eudial is the closest to being competent, and Mimete’s death was SO JARRING that we talked about it for a LONG time afterwards. She’s in hell. It’s nuts.</p>

<p>Okay we have to talk about the bad now.</p>

<p>So far, it’s 3 &gt; 1 &gt; 2, with 2 quite a ways behind 1. Surely 4 won’t be- ohhhh no.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eIfVuB1.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I like how this cover has the outer senshi here, because they are not in this season. Sailor Saturn is literally a baby at this point.</p>

<p>Season 4 is no longer Sailor Moon. It’s Sailor Chibi Moon. Watching this season, I had some idea why Chibi Moon was hated. Like, I still didn’t hate her. She’s honestly fine in this season. But she’s now the main character, and has subsumed most of the plot. Usagi is basically just here, it’s now the Chibi-Usa show, and I like her, but I don’t like her THAT MUCH.</p>

<p>Season 4 has I think the worst villain cast, the Dead Moon Circus, starting with the Amazon Trio. Three animals turned humanoid. They need to find someone with a bright dream that holds a Pegasus so they can capture the Pegasus. They do this by going after people they find hot and trying to seduce them. When that doesn’t work, they just take their dream mirror anyway. The flirting and seducing is superfluous and unneccesary, and often very VERY uncomfortable. There’s three and they all have different targets. One is gay, he’s the best tbh, though he still has some VERY bad moments (though only the villains ever call him icky for being gay, the Senshi never really even point at it). There’s one who’s into older women. And theeeen there’s one who’s into… younger women. VERY young. Yeah. It’s EXTREMELY unpleasant to watch. This alone would make Season 4 bad, but the final episodes with the actual villain were just a bunch of nonsense that were not handled well.</p>

<p>Okay so that was Season 4. Surely season 5 won’t be worse than- OH NO.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9kUAz9L.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Season 5 actually starts very well! It basically takes the ending to season 4 and goes “whoops ignore that”, resets it, and then does it better. All the outer senshi return! Including Sailor Saturn, which I was SO hype for. Some days Saturn is my favorite of the cast, though today it’s Ami. Anyways, I love her. So yes, the first six episodes were actually very good! It was tense and exciting and a good battle! And then it just…. jump cuts to a completely different thing. It’s like there’s a mini season at the start, it’s VERY jarring.</p>

<p>The rest of season 5 is…. whoo boy. Okay so, they kill off Mamoru. Like literally, his plane is hit. No one even learns of this, because apparently a plane disappearing and everyone dying on it isn’t national fucking news. But if that plot hole was the biggest problem this season would be amazing. So yeah, Mamoru is gone. We instead get the Sailor Starlights.</p>

<p>I really wanted to like these three. And I like one of them! The Sailor Starlights are men who turn into women during their super form. It’s kinda interesting but they never really get into it much, so it’s basically just a thing that happens. The lead of them is Seiya, who is basically replacement Mamoru. He crushes on Usagi and you know what? I like it. I like it more than Usagi x Mamoru. Call it sacriledge, but I never liked their relationship that much. THis would work really well… If Mamoru didn’t already exist. But he did so you know it’ll just go nowhere.</p>

<p>The other two are possibly the worst characters in the entire series. They are important and in every episode, and they are basically Saturn Uranus and Neptune from season 3 taken to 11. You know how they had a murder boner and refuse to work with the Sailor Senshi for no reason? These two are like that, but even worse! It is ACTIVELY unpleasant to watch, and I hated it a lot. The best part about them though is that one of them has an attack that’s like “SUPER STAR UTERUS” or some shit. Every time it happened we’d chant “UTERUS! UTERUS! UTERUS!” in chat.</p>

<p>And then the ending… jesus fucking Christ.</p>

<p>The ending has so many bludners that, frankly, 5 is probably the worst season. Even with that good start, and the mostly mid middle, the ending is absolute dogshit. They kill off ALL the characters like 4 or 5 episodes before the end, so no Mercury, Mars, Jupiter, or Venus for the final 5 episodes. Instead, more Sailor Starlights! Oh and Uranus and Neptune BETRAY EVERYONE in the most fucking STUPID plan they’ve EVER had. They accept the villain’s power and <strong>straight up murder Saturn and Pluto</strong>. For the record, Saturn and Pluto are the strongest Senshi in the entire show. Saturn is literally a walking Nuke, she can explode and fix every problem, everyone just keeps stopping her from doing it because it’ll also kill her. But she gets fucking killed in a backstab that doesn’t even work. So yeah, there goes ANY enjoyment I have of these two characters. Even them being gay is ruined.</p>

<p>Sailor Moon is… a lot of things. It really cemented a genre. It’s got a beloved cast of characters. But it’s so easy to forget that there are so many things about it that are extremely unpleasant and unlikable. Should you watch it? Maybe watch season 1, the second half of 2, and 3. Ignore the rest.</p>

<p>Or maybe watch Crystal. I’ll get to it eventually but I do NOT want to watch more Sailor Moon right now.</p>

<p>Oh one more thing. I need to gush about yuri.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Eh45kzFSctY?si=VWrepco9TocdRbWy" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>So obviously Sailor Moon was pro-gay. It had multiple gay characters. One of its directors went on to make Utena. It’s got a lot of yuri energy. And Jupiter is literally canonically bisexual, there’s an episode with her crushing on Uranus. But Mercury is…. very, VERY gay. Like, the biggest things proving this, IMO, is season 4, and it’s my favorite stuff in season 4. In season 4 Ami started doing this thing where any time the character of the week showed up and all the girls fawned over him, she’d like, not be interesting, staring off at something else. She wore these EXTREMELY butch outfits. And then there’s the scene where she dances with Makoto. Ohhhh, be still my beating heart.</p>

<p>I do in fact ship these two. It’s canon, fuck you.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Anime" /><category term="Sailor Moon" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 166</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/24/OOCY166.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 166" /><published>2025-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/24/OOCY166</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/24/OOCY166.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zlqv2SJ.png" alt="'I think two girls clinging onto each other is a wonderful thing! Or rather, I'd like to do so!!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sixth year Class 3, by Suzuki</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sixth year Class 3 by Suzuki" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 165</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/22/OOCY165.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 165" /><published>2025-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/22/OOCY165</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/22/OOCY165.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X1IymIg.png" alt="'What's so bad about you being a girl? You know, Kanda-kun. I didn't fall in love with a guy or a girl. The one I fell in love with is you, Kanda-kun. The one and only.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ViyspZ8.png" alt="'So what if you're a girl? There's no problem as long as we're in love, right?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Handsome Girl and Sheltered Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Handsome Girl and Sheltered Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 164</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/21/OOCY164.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 164" /><published>2025-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/21/OOCY164</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/21/OOCY164.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZaOk6ne.png" alt="'Kanade, your boobs belong to you and no one else! So listen to your own feelings!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Innocent Orbs</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Innocent Orbs" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>