<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-27T09:31:26-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/26/OOCY8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 8" /><published>2024-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/26/OOCY8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/26/OOCY8.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4qLNfiq.png" alt="&quot;But what do you like about me? Everyone says I'm like an old man...&quot;&quot;I like everything about you. I like the sloppy way you get drunk and throw your clothes around the room. I like the way you chug energy drinks. I like how you eat really garlicky foods in the office.&quot; &quot;WHY ARE THOSE THE THINGS YOU LIKE?! Why do you have such bizzarre taste?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is legit my reaction when people tell me the reasons they’re into me</p>

<p>Source: The Marriage Partner of My Dreams Turned Out To Be… My Female Junior at Work?!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Marriage Partner of My Dreams Turned Out To Be… My Female Junior at Work?!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 111 - Emmy (NSFW)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/26/RA111-Emmy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 111 - Emmy (NSFW)" /><published>2024-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/26/RA111-Emmy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/26/RA111-Emmy.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xJc1rzt.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kfQqTDt.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uInF5xb.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kbtciO5.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing my PC88 kick, it’s about time I got to some porn. There is a LOT of porn on this computer. Technically two of my PC88 games I’ve done so far have already been porn, but they’re also like, games. One was a QIX clone with porn, and the other was a sliding tile puzzle. This game has literally no purpose other than to get a girl to take her clothes off. This is Emmy.</p>

<p>We should start by talking about ELIZA, a program from 1966. It was the first attempt by someone to make a program with a text parser that would respond to you based on the things you say. It was less a game and more a turing test. This follows a similar idea, though its text parser is actually more simple. ELIZA in its most famous iterations acted like a therapist, and would call back to previous things you said. Emmy will take her clothes off if you do nothing but praise her over and over.</p>

<p>That’s not to say it makes much sense! Here’s the plan: You call her cute, then introduce yourself with a simple hello and give your name. After that, repeat shit like “kimi ha suteki”, “kimi no me ha kirei”, “kawai ne”. Don’t repeat it TOO much, have a long list of things to say, because she’ll get annoyed if you say the same thing over and over. But it really is just that. You can also ask her things about herself, get a little dirty, but she’ll just giggle and not give much. If you annoy her too much she will literally show you the door, getting more and more grumpy.</p>

<p>For an example of what you could call an EXTREMELY early dating sim, it’s very interesting! And I like the art a lot, actually. It’s expressive, and I love her green hair. Like, it’s not hot. At all. But if I find a single hot PC88 game I’ll be <em>stunned</em>.</p>

<p>It was apparently kinda popular in Japan, there are a bunch of versions of it, and was inspirational. Apparently Emmies got put into games for a bit, as a reference. That’s kinda neat.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="Emmy" /><category term="Dating Sims" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="NSFW" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 110 - Hydlide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/26/RA110-Hydlide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 110 - Hydlide" /><published>2024-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/26/RA110-Hydlide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/26/RA110-Hydlide.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/D9IW8lI.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a6qintE.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OYKLzCu.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Oh boy.</p>

<p>Hydlide is a game series that’s pretty… easily mocked. And commonly! Ever since I heard about it from AVGN back in the late 2000s, I often hear it ridiculed as a terrible game. But at the same time, there’s a lot of Hydlide defenders out there. Self proclaimed Hydlide Sickos. And when people talk about Hydlide 1, the original Hydlide, they USUALLY actually mean Hydlide for the NES, which is a remake from 5 years later.</p>

<p>“Oh it’s not fair to Hydlide”, they’d say. “The original game out in 1984 on PC88 hardware. It was an innovator for its time. It was certainly good for its time, but when it came out on the NES, it was compared to technical advances like Zelda! It’s really not fair to the original game. The PC88 game is better to look at than the NES game”.</p>

<p>Okay. Well I looked at it. Can I unlook at it, now???</p>

<p>This game kinda blows lol</p>

<p>I TRIED, OKAY?? I TRIED TO GIVE IT A FAIR CHANCE! And I’m a fair and even handed reviewer. I can look at this game in the context of its original release. Yes, in 1984, there wasn’t anything like this. But this just isn’t it, y’all.</p>

<p>In Hydlide, the princess has been split into three fairies by the evil Varalys, and the only person brave enough to stop him is the valiant night, JIM! You play as Sir Jimothy as he explores Fairyland, levels up, collects items, get the three fairies, and takes on the evil fiend to restore Fairyland to its former glory. Simple stuff.</p>

<p>First thing, this game is obtuse. That’s not a thing I’ll hold over its head. Yeah it is pretty bullshit that in order to find one of the fairies, you need to hang out in a random room, get hit by five fire balls the wizards throw at you, then kill a fireball. That is really fucking stupid. And there’s no dialogue or hints in this game. But that IS how it was back then. That’s just what they did. Hasn’t aged well by today’s standards, fine for the time.</p>

<p>Second, the game is like, 90% grinding. I’ll also not be too harsh on that either. Without the grinding this game would be 6 minutes. It’s not a very big game, and we gotta pad to get our money’s worth. That’s fair. Also quite of its time. That hasn’t aged well either, but it’s fine.</p>

<p>But the gameplay and everything… okay, so, I was playing on emulator for Retro Achievements, and the setup that RA forces requires the game to run really fast. But I had it emulating the lowest end PC88 and it was still running really, really fast. I think that’s just how it is??? Unless you intentionally underclock it or something, which is against the rules for Retro Achievements, so I didn’t do it. This makes it really hard to actually react for the gameplay, which is Bump Combat. Ahhh, Bump Combat. A truly innovative nightmare. To do combat, you bump your character into an enemy. If they’re facing you, you fight more fairly, and they usually do damage to you. If you hit them from behind, you can do good damage and not get hurt. But they can do the same to you.</p>

<p>The issue is the game runs way too fast. In the end, I ended up spamming pause to pause buffer everything, ESPECIALLY for the final boss. Honestly it wasn’t TOO bad, until I had to grind for my last two levels against Blackams in the castle? You gain more health and damage with each level, but even at max level, Blackams kill you in like 3 hits. Here’s what my strategy was for the final 2 levels, which was like 400 Blackams killed:</p>

<p>Enter the castle at full health. If you stand in the entrance, they will only spawn from the right exit, so they’ll never sneak up on you. Stand there, running against the wall, until they finally show up. It can take minutes. Once you kill one, you’re at 1/3rd health, go out and heal. Healing takes a minute of waiting. Go back in, repeat. I got bored and changed my strategy a few times. It’s more unsafe, and I died a lot doing it, but you can stand away from the entrance and run up against the wall, and when they spawn, immediately hit them. You then have to quickly get out and leave, during which another can spawn and kill you. This happened a lot.</p>

<p>The other major issue is the final boss. Okay, so there’s one other mechanic I need to explain: Defensive and Offensive Mode. In Defensive mode, you take less damage, but also deal less. Simple. If you go up to Varalys, and even just stand next to him, he will instantly kill you if you’re in offensive mode. He just finds you too offensive. Jimothy is smelly. So you gotta be in defensive mode. Hit him 3 times, you’re almost dead. Walk away, go to the bottom screen, and sit in a little cubby. Every time an enemy runs past the cubby entrance, save, and reload if they run in to fight you, cause enemy pathing is RNG. Sit there and wait for several minutes to health up. Then go out and fight Varalys. This takes A VERY LONG TIME. Like, 8 rounds of healing up. It’s kind of ridiculous, even for the time.</p>

<p>Keep in mind, for the achievement, I had to beat this game without the shield and the sword. But they honestly don’t add as much as you’d expect.</p>

<p>OH, and I also forgot to mention the music. Here it is!</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pI--1wel-3I?si=Ajz98NK4xRI1yvdB" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>It’s bad!!</p>

<p>Look, this isn’t the worst game I’ve ever played. But the NES game is better. And you know how I know? Because <strong>I HAD IT AS A KID</strong>. PLOT TWIST! Yes, I own Hydlide on NES, which is actually called Hydlide Special in Japan, because it adds some content. It’s still the same game, basically, but it plays at a slightly better speed, has music from Hydlide 2 (it’s very Indiana Jones but that’s okay), and a magic system. The ONLY flaw is the save and load system, which is janky and bad, and it uses long-ass passwords.</p>

<p>I’mma have to do the set for Hydlide some day.</p>

<p>Anyways, the PC88 version is worse than the NES version. But it IS also 5 years younger than it. I AM looking at it objectively. But jeeze it was not very pleasant to play.</p>

<p>I should play Ys sometime, one of this game’s biggest followers. Never played Ys before.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="Hydlide" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/25/OOCY7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 7" /><published>2024-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/25/OOCY7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/25/OOCY7.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/d4yqo1v.png" alt="&quot;Oh, by lkike, did she mean she thinks I'm a good senpai? And by go out with, did she mean she wants us to meet the clients together?! Wow, that's super embarassing, I totally misunderstood her!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And when she said “I want to have wild lesbian sex with you” I bet she just meant she wanted to hang out, gosh, how embarrassing that I misunderstood her!</p>

<p>Source: The Marriage Partner of My Dreams Turned Out To Be… My Female Junior at Work?!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Marriage Partner of My Dreams Turned Out To Be… My Female Junior at Work?!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 109 - Telenet Music Box</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/25/RA109-TNMB.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 109 - Telenet Music Box" /><published>2024-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/25/RA109-TNMB</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/25/RA109-TNMB.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bVyQz24.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kuIKAvc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the weirder ones.</p>

<p>Okay, so Telenet Japan was a game company in the 80s, very influential at the time. They made a bunch of games that, at the time, were big deals. Nowadays, not so much. You’ve got stuff like Valis, XZR, a bunch of great shmups, they were a big publisher too, publishing Wolf Team’s magnum opus, Earnest Evans. LOTS of stuff on Sega consoles, too. But this is a very, very weird one of their’s.</p>

<p>This is a music program. It has a bunch of songs from their different games, all in one spot. This is FASCINATING to us today, the idea that Nintendo would be like “okay here’s a game on the Switch, it’s just 12 soundtracks from our most popular games”. But that’s how it was! Where the hell else were you gonna listen to all of these? The GAMES THEMSELVES? Fuck that noise.</p>

<p>So yeah, there’s not much to it. But it’s a cute and fascinating little thing, plus it has a lot of great music. XZR has some damn good music, I tell ya. And the art is really nice, too.</p>

<p>If you wanna hear some music, check it out:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h3zkOkBPrkw?si=JTD0dUcQr8-qynSR" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="Telenet" /><category term="Music" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/24/OOCY6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 6" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/24/OOCY6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/24/OOCY6.html"><![CDATA[<p>Me anytime I see two women so much as look each other in the eyes for any length of time</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pNCK9MO.png" alt="&quot;&quot;MOM! THOSE TWO GIRLS ARE FLIRTING!&quot;" class="center-block" />
Source: A Cute Guy</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Cute Guy" /><category term="not yuri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Me anytime I see two women so much as look each other in the eyes for any length of time]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 3 - McDonald’s Treasure Land Adventures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/24/RA3-McDs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 3 - McDonald’s Treasure Land Adventures" /><published>2024-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/24/RA3-McDs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/24/RA3-McDs.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ukd5y5O.png" alt="McDonalds" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/poBiSlD.png" alt="McDonalds" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/i5VmOXH.png" alt="McDonalds" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OZaQX1q.png" alt="McDonalds" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When I first started Retro Achievements, I went around the site hunting for games that were very important and special to me. And that usually means that I knew it extremely well, and I speedran it. That works for this game too. It’s another one I owned as a kid, and my… second speedgame? It’s up there, it was a really early one for me.</p>

<p>This is the first game ever made by a little company called Treasure, who you MAY have heard of, because they’re one of the best devs of all time. Konami alumni who got out early, they’d go on to make some AMAZING games, and were in fact working on Gunstar Heroes at the same time as this game. But this one released first. I can’t find information that this was done to fund Gunstar Heroes, but it probably was? Selling your soul early, huh Treasure?</p>

<p>I also can’t find information that this game wasn’t originally McDonalds related at all, though I wouldn’t doubt that. It has NOTHING to do with McDonalds. There’s no food here, at all… except for the tomato boss? The story is very simple. You find a piece of the treasure map, and want to find the other pieces to find some treasure. All of the pieces of the map lead to the other pieces of the map, which is not how treasure maps work but okay…. except for in Thousand Year Door, kinda. Anyway. there are four levels, each ending with a boss, through varied locations. And that’s it! The game is rather short, you could easily burst through it in 30 minutes on a first playthrough, though beginner difficulty also removes a room from levels 3 and 4, making it even shorter.</p>

<p>It’s also really easy. This is a kids game, through and through. But it’s still enjoyable to an adult, challenge just shouldn’t be a thing you’re hunting for. It looks really nice and colorful, sounds amazing, and the levels are goofy and fun, ranging from entering a monster’s stomach to traversing a sunken ship to going to space. The gameplay kicks it up a bit though. It’s a platformer, sure, though it’s a little more reminiscent of Ristar than a Mario or a Sonic. With a bit of run and gun in there, too. Ronald can shoot magic, jump, and extend his arm with some scarves up his sleeve (geddit? Cause clown?) to grab things and hang from them, like bionic commando. Though he’s static, he doesn’t swing. That’d be sick though.</p>

<p>All in all, while it isn’t anything transcendent or complex, it probably helped keep Treasure afloat long enough to make some of the best games ever made, so we have to give McDonald’s Treasure Land Adventures SOME credit for that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Genesis" /><category term="McDonald&apos;s Treasure Land Adventures" /><category term="Platformers" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 108 - Joshi Daisei Private</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/23/RA108-JDP.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 108 - Joshi Daisei Private" /><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/23/RA108-JDP</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/23/RA108-JDP.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q2wUP34.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G4rcjYO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I kinda like the idea of just, focusing on a console and playing a bunch of random games from that console. It’s a fun thing, gives you a snapshot into it. Plus, playing all the obscure random shit you can find in a console helps you find some real gems!</p>

<p>The PC88 is different. I was looking through the library on RA, trying to find things to play. Most of them are porn. Some of them are <strong>very bad</strong> porn, like 177. This is at least better than that. It’s just boring and bad.</p>

<p>Joshi Daisei Private, or Private Stripper, is a very simple sliding puzzle game from 1983 by Nihon Falcom. Yes, <strong>that Falcom</strong>. Before they made Ys, or Brandish, or Xanadu, or Popful Mail, or even Dragon Slayer, they made this. How does it work? Okay, you start the game, then select K for Kyoko, M for Miyuki, or Y for Yuko. Then you select Quadratic or Cubic. And then, depending on the girl you selected, you do three puzzles, sliding them in place as they get more risque, going from pinups to showing tits. Ooh, scandalous. The art is pretty bad, I’mma be real. Like they don’t have very many colors to show off, but it’s still pretty hideous.</p>

<p>In Cubic mode, all of the squares are there, and you slide an entire row or column along to slide things into the right spots. In Quadratic type, one of the tiles is missing, and you can only slide tiles into that spot. Someone in the comments said that quadratic type puzzles can be literally impossible, but that didn’t happen for me and I dunno how that’d happen. Either way, that’s just a traditional sliding puzzle alright!!</p>

<p>There’s really not much more to say. This is a VERY weird footnote in the storied history of Falcom, alright.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="Joshi Daisei Private" /><category term="Puzzle Games" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/23/OOCY5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 5" /><published>2024-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/23/OOCY5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/23/OOCY5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4GrJrps.png" alt="&quot;I want you to love me, and my boobs.&quot;" class="center-block" />
Source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 3" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dJF1W2N.png" alt="&quot;You didn't forget anything, did you? Take care! I'll have some side dishes to pick up once you get back!&quot; They gained another mom." class="center-block" />
Source: About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl]]></summary></entry></feed>