<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-23T13:14:53-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 179 - Jack Rabbit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/23/RA179-JackRabbit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 179 - Jack Rabbit" /><published>2025-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/23/RA179-JackRabbit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/23/RA179-JackRabbit.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/i8xA4Rc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Hi there! I’m Jack Rabbit! I love carrots, and I’m very hungry! Wuh.</p>

<p>These are the words said by Jack Rabbit, the titual character of 1984 arcade game Jack Rabbit, by Zaccaria. Zaccaria was an Italian pinball and arcade company, and they invented a voice synthesis technique, which they used in two arcade games. This one, and Money Money. Basically, Jack Rabbit talks between levels.</p>

<p>This game is kind of a meme in some circles, because he’s SUPPOSED to say “Will you help me?” after his “I’m very hungry” line. However, the speed of the synthesis was off in MAME when it was first put in mame, so he talked a bit slower and was cut off, so he just went “wuh”. Wuh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7DlHEOy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Jack Rabbit is kind of like a maze game mixed with some Qbert? You hop in an isometric space, with three different maps. Once you collect all of the carrots, you move to the next stage. You can hop one square, OR hold the button to do a twice as large hop so you can hop over pits and stuff. The first stage is a farm, the second is an auto scrolling desert that gets VERY fast in later loops, and the third is an island chain you have to jump between.</p>

<p>Jack Rabbit isn’t a complex game, but it’s just the right level of simple to fun. In my opinion, this is a fantastic little game that’s great to try and grind out high score to for 30 minutes every now and then. Plus it’s got a fun little story! Wuh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Arcade" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Jack Rabbit" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 146</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/22/OOCY146.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 146" /><published>2025-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/22/OOCY146</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/22/OOCY146.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sOWAx2D.png" alt="'I want to kiss her, that's for sure. But whether I like her... that much I still don't know.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Pinky Candy Kiss</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Pinky Candy Kiss" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 178 - Pokemon Red Version</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/22/RA178-PokemonRB.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 178 - Pokemon Red Version" /><published>2025-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/22/RA178-PokemonRB</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/22/RA178-PokemonRB.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BjseHzY.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is gonna be a different kind of review.</p>

<p>Allow me to tell you a story. It’s 1998, probably October or November, and I’m 5 years old. My parents have taken me to the local skating rink to ride around in circles, or more accurately for me, fall on my ass a bunch. After falling on my ass a bunch, I went to the break area and saw my neighbor playing on his Gameboy. I asked him what he was playing, and he showed me this new game he had recently rented called Pokemon. He described it as, and I’m not making this up, a game where you rent monsters to battle other monsters. Anyways I thought it looked like the sickest shit, so that night I went home and went to my brother and said “Jeff, I saw a new game we have to get! Pokemans!”</p>

<p>He will never let me live that down. Anyways, the rest, as they say, is history.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xTKA5pU.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Trying to review Pokemon Red/Blue is a fascinating task. This game is so etched into history at this point, but in a completely different way than other games. Let me peel back the veil for a bit. When I’m writing these, I usually grab an image or two from Google so it’s not just a wall of text. As an example, I’ll use a game I just beat, Dragon Quest 4. I go on Google, search “Dragon Quest 4 NES” and I get two box art images, and the rest are in game pictures. That’s cool. But if I search “Pokemon Red Gameboy” or anything like that, I do not get in game images. I get box art and cartridges. I have to scroll a LOT to get any in game pictures at all.</p>

<p>I think Pokemon has outgrown its video games. Pokemon isn’t really a game series anymore, it’s the largest multimedia franchise of all fucking time. To Google, the idea of Pokemon, and specifically owning one of the millions of shitty overpriced repro carts that are on marketplaces that everyone is still buying for some reason, is far more important than the actual game itself. Now, I don’t respect Google or its algorithms, at all, so I’m not about to say that’s reflective of all of culture. But it’s at least a small window into the realities of it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0noXNoi.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Pokemon story has evolved into a kind of mythos. You can find videos online talking about everything about the series, and I watch them all, because I’m a fan. Though I hate calling myself that, because in my personal opinion, there are NO fans worse than Pokemon fans. People will shit talk every Nintendo series fandon, but let me tell you, I didn’t get THREE SEPERATE EMAILS from those fan groups because I dared to showcase a woman runner on a speedrunning marathon.</p>

<p>The mythos of Pokemon Red/Blue also has a lot of discourse around it, too. Some will tell you this game is actually dogshit garbage, and has no business being played today. Just play FireRed/LeafGreen. I mean sure, those are good games too, but bugs and questional design decisions don’t ruin the enjoyment of a game. This game is pure nostalgia bait, and it makes me happy to play it, and really that’s what matters. I don’t care that you literally cannot play the game without running into some kind of bug, or that the balance is so fucked. Those poor, poor Bug/Dragon/Ghost types, jesus. And that’s not even getting started on the Fighting type. Yes, that’s all bad, but this game has grown so far beyond it and its own personal flaws that I really don’t care that much.</p>

<p>I go back every few years to play this one. This is actually my second time recently, I did a Prof Oak challenge last year. And I’ll probably play it again sometime soon in the future. It just makes me feel good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Pokemon" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 6-10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/18/LizstartrekVOY6-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 6-10" /><published>2025-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/18/LizstartrekVOY6-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/18/LizstartrekVOY6-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Qh1U7nT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Riddles</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L12TVW2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix and Tuvok are on the Delta Flyer, which is WAY fucking larger than I thought it was. Neelix is annoying Tuvok, who as usual, seems to detest everyone he’s ever met, but ESPECIALLY Neelix. Maybe it’s espcially weird between them considering The Episode That Must Not Be Mentioned. Anyways Tuvok gets grumpy after Neelix gives him a bad riddle, he goes back to the back to find that an alien is downloading some files from the computer. It attacks Neelix and he has a seizure.</p>

<p>They get some information from a nearby alien species. The ambasaddor to them believes it’s a species called The Ba’Neth, which his government claims does not actually exist. He’s basically a conspiracy theorist about these guys, adamant they DO exist, even though no one’s ever seen them, and there have only been 13 known attacks. Tuvok was the first attacked who survived! Lucky Tuvok.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wQljDTM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix feels guilty for what happened to Tuvok, so he does his best to make Tuvok comfy. The Doctor suggests that sometimes people wake from comas if they’re talked to or have smells, so Neelix goes ALL OUT. It works, and Tuvok wakes up, though his brain has been damaged, so he’s kind of running on instinct. He’s scared of the tricorder, for example. Neelix takes him on tours to try and jog his memory, and everyone is kind of worried and disturbed. They don’t know if he’ll ever recover.</p>

<p>They study the Ba’Neth and find out how to decloak them, using some fancy technology. THey use it and find out, whoopsies, there’s A FLEET OUT THERE WATCHING THEM. They attack and then scramble, running away.</p>

<p>Neli just asked “is this episode Tuvok’s brain”. Uh oh. Tuvok is talking again, but he’s kind of kid-like. He has emotions, he doesn’t much care for logic and meditation. He’s also kind of angsty about what happened to him, understandably. They know that he got a cloaking frequency before being attacked, and they need it to find the aliens. He doesn’t remember though. He, and everyone else, are kinda upset at the fact that Tuvok isn’t really Tuvok anymore, and might never be again. Seven puts it eloquently. She changed, quite a lot. And she was helped, not by trying to force her back to what she was.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1KZDkqM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I like this new Tuvok. He likes having fun. He likes smiling. He likes jazz. He ends up LOVING cooking, and specifically deserts. Why? Because “it tastes good”. Fair enough, man!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CNNCJIG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He still can’t remember the cloaking frequency. But he writes it out on a cake he’s making.</p>

<p>They find the aliens, and the investigator they’re with makes a good offer. His device he made to find them, in exchange for the weapon they attacked Tuvok with so they can help Tuvok. They do it, and make a way to fix Tuvok.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sp0hg9B.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tuvok is not happy about this. He likes who he is NOW. He can enjoy things, and be with his best friend Neelix! He knows if he goes back to the way he was, he’ll probably just avoid Neelix again. “How will you know how much I enjoy your company?” “Well, you just told me”. AWWWW. That really gave me feels. Can you imagine if Tuvok just stayed like this for the entire series??? No obviously not, though he’s gone, he’s not gone FOREVER. Tuvok has a little less logic in him. Just a little less.</p>

<p><strong>Dragon’s Teeth</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MWSH6y2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start IMMEDIATELY with a bombing of a city. Two aliens get in biopods to try and survive an attack. They’ll wake up 5 years later, and hopefully then the war will be over.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Voyager, they’re in some wormhole. By accident. An alien ship inside tells them to get the fuck out, which they’re like “We’d love to but how” so they push them out. The aliens then go “Prepare to be boarded, we’re going to wipe your computer so you don’t have records of our space”. Janeway obviously ain’t gonna allow that, so they’re attacked, and they flee to a nearby planet that’s highly irradiated to try and escape. It works, but the aliens are still hovering above. Scans show that the entire planet became nuclear dust 892 years ago. That’s a bit more than 5 years.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QoDpDnV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They awaken one of them. The other is dead, her machine not functioning. Horrifying. He explains he’s a Vaadwaur. Things have changed a LOT. He knows of the Talax-ilzay, the predecessors of the Talaxians. He knows of the Borg, back when they were a small group. In the old Talaxian language btw, Vaudwar means “foolish”. I’m sure that’ll mean nothing. This guy, Gedrin, makes a suggestion. Wake up his batallion, help them off the planet, and he’ll help them through “underspace”, some wormhole tunnels that can lead them closer to his own.</p>

<p>They wake them up and work with them. Looks like this alliance will go well! Well, the first cracks that come up are actually with Naomi. She doesn’t like the Vaudwar kids. They called Neelix stupid, like all his race. Jerks &gt;:(</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fB3ksWI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Yeah turns out the Vaudwaur are empiralistic and awful. They promised to help Voyager get home faster. Now they refuse to unless given weapons. They want what was once their’s, and they’ll do whatever they can to get it. And their new plan is to kill the people on Voyager and take the ship as their own, with its superior technology. Yeah that’s a GREAT idea, Voyager, the only thing keeping you alive right now from the violent race that hates you upstairs.</p>

<p>Neelix and Seven study the Vaudwar and find what they used to be like. Janeway confronts the leader, the original one they released, Gedrin. He’s like “Well yeah we USED to be aggressive but not anymore!” My man, YOU’RE THE SAME EXACT PEOPLE. Not just descendants, the same people.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BS77cbR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode has a BUDGET. Janeway is prepared for them to be betrayed, and sure enough they are. They contact the aliens in orbit, old enemies of the Vaudwar, who are willing to help if they blow up the Vaudwar. They need to access a satellite though. Gedrin offers to help, as “not all of [his] people are stuck in the past”. He sacrifices himself so Voyager can escape. The rest of the Vaudwar are stuck fighting the Turei, the other aliens. Some Vaudwar manage to escape though and survive, so they’re still out there, and might become a threat… in STAR WARS ONLINE! Which isn’t canon but that’s okay.</p>

<p><strong>One Small Step</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j0jejZB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Weird-ass image for this episode, but its literally the first thing we see. We watch a NASA ship above Mars in the 21st century, as its suddenly confronted with some super large thing coming at it.</p>

<p>Now back on Voyager, some things are malfunctioning. Turns out it’s Seven’s fault. She’s like “I’m just upgrading the systems, it’s causing minor malfunctions”. “Seven that’s not up to you” “I will do it anyway” Seven we’ve had this conversation like eight times, where the hell is your character development. THen they get close to a “Graviton Elipse”, which the last time that was detected, it was a Mars mission that ended up stranding some people on Mars for weeks.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2v3nXVQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They want to study it and get closer to it. Seven thinks they’re nuts. They think the NASA command center is in there, and find data from it, so they wanna go in and find it for themselves. Seven still thinks they’re nuts. She doesn’t understand this… “hero worship” or trying to make yourself a part of history. It’s highly illogical. Even TUVOK is into it. As he says, he IS a Starfleet officer. He’s here because he’s an explorer.</p>

<p>Tom, Seven, and Chakotay go into the Anomoly. Chakotay is so overwhelmed and excited by being in there, he wants to study everything they find in there. But they don’t have time, the anomaly is going to impact a dark matter asteroid and it’ll be Bad to be in there. But Chakotay is too up his own ass and doesn’t want to leave, so the impact happens and Chakotay gets shocked by a console in the Delta Flyer. The Flyer is damaged, they have two hours before it reaches subpsace, the engines are unsalvagable. That’s Bad.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0idQrsz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven is PISSED. Chakotay disobeyed orders and put everyone’s lives at risk. He SHOULD be court martialed, if he’s lucky. And by that I mean if WE’RE lucky. But nothing’s gonna happen to him, of course.</p>

<p>They send Seven over to the NASA shuttle to try and get some parts from it for salvage. They find some logs from the guy who disappeared into the anomaly. He did, in fact, survive. For a while. That’s fucking horrifying. This is a survival horror audio log. The rest of the episode is just them listening to this guy’s survival horror log as he dies. As he dies though, he makes a statement that it was right for them to come here, because he’s learned from all the debris out there that they’re not alone, and some day, someone might find the data he collected and learn from it.</p>

<p>They make it out, with his data and his corpse, and give him a proper sendoff. Seven now has a better appreciation of history and exploration.</p>

<p>So parts of this were great. All the stuff with the NASA survivor? Fantastic. Chakotay was annoying and bad as always, but we have a thing in our group called The Rule of Chakotay. Just cause Chakotay is in an episode and does something bad doesn’t make the entire episode bad, like how the Rule of Data means Data being good doesn’t mean the episode is neccesarily good.</p>

<p><strong>The Voyager Conspiracy</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/toBrgPO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven is setting up a machine that’ll download information into her brain as she sleeps so she doesn’t have to study it like the primitives. I’m sure this won’t go wrong in any way. Hey remember that episode where Barclay downloaded so much information he became super smart or whatever? Anyway.</p>

<p>She wakes up and immediately calls Torres. I imagine this happens a lot after this episode. “TORRES, I DOWNLOADED INFORMATION LAST NIGHT. HAVE YOU EVER HEARD OF SKA?” This episode then goes into what is basically a Sherlock Holmes jump through what happened six weeks ago. She theorizes from some base information some bugs are making their nest in the ship’s computers, and yes, they are. So clearly this thing works.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XABjX4v.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager comes across an alien named Tash. He was stranded here years ago, and has been building a Super Catapult to throw him across space, basically. What a coincidence, WE want to be thrown across space! Voyager offers to help him fix his catapult if they can use it after he does, and they see it’s safe. He’s 100% down, just excited to be able to finish his catapult. Seven wakes up, and warns them. She thinks this is a trap. She believes the technology from the catapult is the same as the one that the Caretaker used to bring them here in the first place.</p>

<p>What proceeds is what I can only describe as a clipshow. I made a joke during that earlier episode with the Vaudwar that the budget was so inflated with CGI battles and shit that we’d be getting a clipshow later this season to pay for it, AND BEHOLD. Seven explains that she believes there’s a conspiracy going on, and goes over events that happened years ago. We see scenes and information from SEASONS ago. It’s done as well as it can be, but there’s really only one reason to reuse scenes in a Trek show, and that’s to save money. It’s why we’ve seen that Klingon ship from one of the early movies explode like 12 times by now.</p>

<p>After all her studying and thoughts, she believes that Janeway and Tuvok intentionally stranded everyone here in order to set up a military presence in the Delta Quadrant. Which goes against all of Janeway’s ideals, not to mention any amount of logic. If you were going to send a ship to establish a military presence in a far off region of space, why would you send Voyager, a rinky dink science vessel that’s exploded like a million times in different timelines???? Neli theorizes that this is something the writers saw people talking about in early internet forums and decided to make fun of. I agree. Our conspiracy theory is much funnire than Seven’s.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FisaI1W.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Chakotay’s expression listening to Seven’s ludicrous screed. It’s fucking HILARIOUS. But the worst part is it seems he’s starting to fucking buy it??? Chakotay are you <strong><em>fucking kidding me????</em></strong> “Seven has some compelling evidence” NO SHE FUCKING DOES NOT. This is some “Photon torpedos won’t melt steel beams” shit.</p>

<p>Seven downloads more information, and then immediately calls Janeway. She believes now that Chakotay is planning a coup to restart the Maquis rebellion. Janeway is like “…..did Chakotay put you up to this what the fuck”. I think Seven’s just broken. Now Janeway and Chakotay assume each other, but they kind of ACCIDENTALLY let slip to each other they’re suspicious cause of stuff Seven has told them and then they’re like “wait this is stupid” just as Seven leaves in the Delta Flyer.</p>

<p>Janeway beams aboard to try and convince Seven to turn around, and she’s like “it’s no use, I know your TRUE REASON for being here! You came here to kidnap me!” She’s fucking broooooken. Janeway convinces her that she’s not here to hurt her, because she’s malfunctioning, and she cares about her. She gives examples of all the times she helped her and cared about her. It’s very straight.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Qh1U7nT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I don’t THINK there were any Seven/Janeway shippers making this show, but I wouldn’t be that surprised.</p>

<p>Seven comes back, they fix her, and everything is good. They also use the catapult to get 3 years closer to home! Chakotay and Janeway joke about it. “You didn’t poison the coffee, did you?” “No more than usual.” This episode was stupid as fuck but honestly really funny.</p>

<p><strong>Pathfinder</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/igVwUix.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy shit it’s Barclay. Holy FUCK, it’s Troi! She looks so good in the modern outfit. It’s nice to see her! She’s visiting Barclay as the Enterprise is docked at Earth. Barclay is his usual nervous weird self. He’s been working on something called the “Pathfinder Project”, but he’s stopped working on it. Hints at things going wrong happen quickly. He has a cat! The cat’s name is Neelix. That’s probably not a coincidence. Barclay is afraid he’s becoming obsessed with Voyager.</p>

<p>He tells the story to Troi. He believed he could establish two way communication with Voyager, but Rej’s theories are… far fetched. You know that meme about Human engineers in Trek trying to turn the sun into a Torus? That’s Rej. He’s alienating himself from his friends and coworkers by obsessing with this. It’s mostly cause he wants to help the Voyager crew so much. He couldn’t sleep, he couldn’t focus on work, he once again got addicted to the holodeck, using a Voyager simulation that he invented based on info about Voyager.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LreYzKV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s not ACCURATE information, and he’s practically using it as a second life MMO to live out a fantasy of helping these people and living on Voyager. Barclay is as uncomfortable and awkward to watch as he was on TNG. He makes an ass out of himself in front of Paris’ Admiral dad. He also tells Troi it’s totally NOT a relapse of his holo addiction, and she gives him a VERY funny “okay, sure” look. All of this gets him kicked off the project, and he wants Troi to tell the Admiral to put him back on the project, that he’s totally mentally fit to work. Troi refuses cause uh, he’s not. He’s unstable as fuck. He admits that a lot of this is because he’s no longer on the Enterprise. They were his family, now his family is Voyager. They’re all he has left.</p>

<p>He hacks his way into his work place later that night. He’s going to get the thing working so they can communicate with Voyager, if it’s the last thing he does. If he’s caught it WILL be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u874URw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look, the thing! Barclay’s boss comes in and tries to stop him before Barclay can do… whatever he’s doing. So uh, everything explained here shows what Barclay is doing isn’t DANGEROUS or BAD. It is something that his boss has been pushing back against mostly out of frustration with Barclay being the way he is. They could just let Barclay do this for 20 minutes but whatever. Then there’d be no episode I guess. Rej is caught, and the program ends, after he ends a few messages.</p>

<p>Back on board the ACTUAL Voyager, Seven is trying to teach Neelix to sing, much to her chagrin. But then they get a message! Well, send one back!!</p>

<p>Back in Starfleet, Rej is about to be arrested (ironically, Admiral Paris actually was about to give permission for Barclay to do this, buuuuut he was a bit too impatient), but they’re interrupted by Janeway pushing through a message. Finally, Voyager has direct voice contact for the first time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nRGFDcS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris hears that his son is there, and is an exemplary member of the crew. Not gonna mention he got demoted the other month, I guess. It looks like regular communication might happen. They also make Barclay, “whoever you are”, an honorary crew of Voyager. That’s cute.</p>

<p>Most of this episode was awkward and just okay, but the last bit was really good to see, after six seasons of build up, the emotional gut punch of them finally making voice contact.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 177 - Return to Zork</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/17/RA177-RTZ.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 177 - Return to Zork" /><published>2025-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/17/RA177-RTZ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/17/RA177-RTZ.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9r0Dxla.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I made this set! Return to Zork is one of my absolute favorite games of all time, one I know very very well. So I decided if anyone would make the set for it, it’d be me. There’s just one problem. There are three versions of Return to Zork I COULD make sets for, and none of them were the DOS version, the only one that’s in English. So I had three options. The Saturn version, which I futzed with but the RAM was a nightmare. The PS1 version, which was basically the same thing. Or the PC-FX.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NSs5QB9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You might be wondering what the hell a PC-FX even is. Understandable reaction. So, the TG16/PC-Engine was the 8/16-bit era NEC home console, right? This is their next generation console. Their answer to the PS1 and the Saturn and whatnot. And it fucking booooombed. Released in 1994, it technically limped on until 1998 when it was discontinued and NEC gave up on the home console market. It had a high price, no 3D graphics chip, and limited developer support. It didn’t stand a chance moving into the 5th generation of consoles.</p>

<p>So why the hell did I choose this damn thing over the other two? Well, for one, this port was made by another company, and it seems like a very good port! When I played the Saturn port, I got softlocked. Me. Softlocked in RTZ. I know this game better than the developers do, how the hell could I get softlocked? This version is rock solid in its programming, and well made. Two, when the fuck else am I going to make a PCFX set, or do ANYTHING with the console? The library has 62 games, which is not a lot, and most are anime bullshit I know nothing about. At least with RTZ, even though it’s entirely in Japanese, I know the game so well I don’t need to be able to speak its language.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PBoi2Sk.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, RTZ. Zork is the venerable adventure series dating back to the freaking 1970s, on big-ass terminal computers. The series started to fade a bit moving into the era of actually having graphics, but then RTZ came out and revitalized the series a bit. This is a weird entry in the series, made by none of the same developers, and the first to not have Steve Meretzky on it at all. The last Zork game was 5 years ago. Since then, Infocom had been devoured by Activision. Actually, fun story about this, in 1991 new owner of the company Bobby Kotick was looking over Activision’s back catalogue to determine what they should focus on. His decision? Zork. Quote, “Zork on a brick would sell 100,000 copies”. Bobby Kotick at one point believed fucking ZORK was their flagship series. That’s nuts to me now.</p>

<p>But could they make a Zork game moving into the new decade, with none of the same developers, and have it keep the vibe and style Zork fans know and love? AND move it into the age of actually having graphics for things?</p>

<p>Yes, they can. The way I’d describe Zork as a series is, imagine Discworld, but it’s midwest America instead if Britain. If you know anytihng about either series, you’re going “Holy shit, it IS that”. It’s irreverent, goofy, and funny, with loose rules and story that can be melded to fit whatever it wants. Especially for this entry, which takes place at the end of the timeline, long long LONG after any of the others. I’m talking like hundreds of years. There’s an event that took place like 500 years ago in this game that’s not in any other game, The Great Diffusion. As such, this game is pretty seperated from the rest of the Zork games.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pLRbhwe.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s also missing some of Zork’s classic tropes and ideas in places. Instead of it being an Elven sword, it’s a Dwarven sword here, and you meet the Dwarves too, who are in no other games. There’s only one mention of Flatheads, as an offhand joke. You could basically considering this completely seperate from the rest of the series and have no problems.</p>

<p>But how is it as a GAME? Well, it’s a bit rough. The FMV and acting are all fun and cheesy in that early 90s way, but the puzzles are hit and miss. It’s not as bad as people claim. Some people say the game soft locks you if you fuck up the bonding plant puzzle on the first screen, but no, you can fix that. The plant will regrow back if you destroy the old, dead one. There ARE ways to screw yourself though, many ways. It’s not a kind game. There’s also many too many mazes. Despite all this, I think its a fun experience. But maybe have a guide nearby if you get stuck.</p>

<p>Return to Zork is very near and dear to my heart, and hopefully one day DOS will come to Retro Achievements so I can make a set for the DOS version, so people will actually fucking play it. Because as it is now, you need to either know RTZ front to back, or speak Japanese to bother with this one. Not that anyone will, cause no one cares about the poor PC-FX.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PCFX" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Zork" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 176 - Pyramids of Ra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/17/RA176-Ra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 176 - Pyramids of Ra" /><published>2025-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/17/RA176-Ra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/17/RA176-Ra.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HWt2Uqo.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There’s a kind of puzzle that’s pretty common in games. You have a bunch of squares, and you can move along them squares. How do you fill in all those squares without stepping back over a square? What path do you take? It’s a puzzle I personally associate with the Zelda Oracle games, but it’s pretty common elsewhere too. Like here!</p>

<p>This is Pyramids of Ra, a 2018 homebrew Apple II game by Naspite Labs. Seems like a pretty simple homebrew, at least in gameplay. For music, they ported like, a lot of hard techno and keygen jams to Apple II. And considering the computer’s limited musical capabilities, it’s very crunchy and hurts the ears.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0nl3suN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Later on, it introduces different color tiles, which require you to clear them twice, or even three times. Simple progression. After 12-ish stages, the game is done. It’s pretty easy, even considering the concept, but I like a puzzle like this, and it doesn’t HAVE to be complex or wild to be enjoyable for 20 minutes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Pyramids of Ra" /><category term="Homebrew" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 145</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/17/OOCY145.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 145" /><published>2025-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/17/OOCY145</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/17/OOCY145.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fe0m042.png" alt="'Well, I can understand how the rain clouds feel now. We both want to see you get soaking wet.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Love Magnet</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Love Magnet" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 144</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/15/OOCY144.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 144" /><published>2025-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/15/OOCY144</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/15/OOCY144.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fymyyxn.png" alt="'It's so absurd but these stupid men get reeled in every time. Next, she'll lean her head on the man she's got her sights on, and say 'oh no, I'm soooo drunk &lt;3' or some crap.' LATER THAT NIGHT, the other girl leans her head on her shoulder. 'Woah, oh no, I'm soooo drunk &lt;3 I wonder if I can make it home on my own...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Amazaki Suika, https://dynasty-scans.com/images/33922?tag_id=21631, https://www.pixiv.net/en/artworks/102513101</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Amazaki Suika" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 175 - Newberry Winners - Bridge to Terabithia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/13/RA175-Terabithia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 175 - Newberry Winners - Bridge to Terabithia" /><published>2025-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/13/RA175-Terabithia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/13/RA175-Terabithia.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YPKvZoP.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I don’t know if this is so much a thing anymore, but when I was a kid, computers were JUST starting to become bigger and bigger, and used for things that weren’t like, landing shit on the moon. And that included in schools. My media center was getting new computers, and they were trying to find ways to use computers for education. One of those ways was for testing. I remember one of the first times I really used the computer at my school for things that weren’t like, teaching how to type or playing games, was a book test. I don’t know if they still do that anymore, but that’s all this program is. It’s a test on a book that you’d teach in schools.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VMBUV6L.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I have never read Bridge to Terabithia. Not once. I knew absolutely nothing about it going in, except that I’d heard the name before. It’s a popular book from like, the 60s or 70s that they taught in schools, never taught it to me though. Anyways, the test is several parts, very simple, ranging from answering basic plot questions to putting events in order.</p>

<p>Like I said, I’ve never read this book, but I managed to do very well on the test. Why, am I psychic? Well, I DID go to school for literature. I know how books work. And this is a basic test for babies on a simple kids book. It appears to be a fucking DARK kids book, like, wow. But it’s still for younger audiences. So I know how basic story structure works, and I used context clues and judgement to guess how the story went, and y’know what, I got it right, pretty much every time. And even if I missed a question I could just redo the test, cause what was stoppign me?</p>

<p>This is a weird review, cause like, it’s not a game. It’s not a game at ALL. It’s barely even educational, it’s just a test, it doesn’t teach anything, it tests you on what you’ve been taught elsewhere. But this was a thing back then, and this was how I first interracted with computers, so it’s important to me for that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Bridge to Terabithia" /><category term="Text Adventures" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/12/LizstartrekVOY6-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5" /><published>2025-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/12/LizstartrekVOY6-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/12/LizstartrekVOY6-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Tx1t43y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Equinox, Part II</strong> - VOY
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vhvdaMr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is still under attack by those nucleogenic aliens, after the Equinox ditched them. Chokie is hit by an alien and given a wild scar, but unfortunately he’s still alive. They kidnapped Seven, and also possibly the Doctor? They still have the Doctor’s emitter, but it’s filled with Evil Doctor instead.</p>

<p>Back on the Equinox, Captain Ransom talks to Seven, hoping that she’ll join them and help them. “You can be in the brig for a month until we get home, or join our crew. I’d prefer the latter.” “I would prefer the brig” “Janeway isn’t the ONLY person who can help you explore your humanity, you know”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fjMCKn9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>God DAMN, Seven. Anyways their stuff is locked by some codes, so they demand Seven do it. She refuses. So they bring the Doctor up and delete his ethical subroutines so he’ll do it. He agrees immediately. God, PLEASE make it so that he’s just faking. Sadly no, he doesn’t seem to be. But the thing about ripping out the memories would basically kill Seven.</p>

<p>Janeway wants to chase the Equinox to get Seven and the important Voyager parts they stole. Chokie wants to let it go and focus on Voyager, leaving Seven behind. Chokie, dude, they stole the part that makes you go vroom. He claims its all about revenge for Janeway, as it always is. What. “You’ve been known to hold a grudge” She has been?? THey focus way more on her want to stop Ransom than her want to save Seven, which disappoints the shit out of me. She has big Captain Ahab energy. Ugh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xbsBRPY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They chase after Equinox, but lose the fight. Which SEEMS stupid, but their systems are VERY taxed to hold off the aliens. Janeway feels really off this episode. They capture one of the members of the Equinox, and Janeway tries to get information out of him. When he refuses, she attempts to murder him by letting the aliens eat him. Chakotay comes in and saves him like “What the HELL Are you doing?!” This is REALLY fucked up of Janeway, and a very sudden 180. She’s doing the Ransom fall to darkness kind of thing, putting her morals away for a thing she feels she needs to do.</p>

<p>She ends up demoting Chokie and confining him to quarters, but follows his suggestion to meet the aliens who worship the extra dimensional aliens. She does, they’re like “we’ll stop attacking if you let us kill everyone on the Equinox” and she agrees, which disturbs Tuvok greatly. What the fuck is she doing?</p>

<p>And while Janeway has her 180, you know who else does? Ransom. He’s like “actually this is wrong and I need to do what’s right”. NOW? NOW YOU DECIDE THAT?! It’s too late though, when he tries to call them off and surrender to Voyager, he’s thrown in the brig by his second in command who takes control. The anxious ensign escorts him off. She’s just following orders, you understand. But actually she’s working with him and helps him break out to stop whatever the hell is going on.</p>

<p>Everything about this is stupid to me I’m ngl. What is it with Star Trek and not hitting the landing?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fvesr0m.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ransom shuts down their shields, and Max is now the bad guy. He refuses to go in Voyager’s brig, and would rather be stuck on a shuttle forever. So he fucking dies to the aliens, and the entire Equinox blows up, Ransom along with it. Everyone else is rescued. Everyone is sad about this. Janeway is like “He was still a Starfleet officer. He just forgot about it for a while.” YEAH, MY MAN. SO DID YOU??</p>

<p>They let the Equinox crew join them, but demoted and they’ll have to earn their trust. Janeway and Chokie are still tense. She acknowledged he probably should have mutinied against her. He says that would have been crossing a line. Then they hang the Voyager plaque back on the wall, which is poetic, I guess.</p>

<p>I want to quote one of the producer, Ronald Moore, about this episode: “The things that Janeway does in ‘Equinox’ don’t work, because it’s not about anything. She’s not really grappling with her inner demons. She’s not truly under the gun and suffering to the point where you can understand the decisions that she’s made. She just gets kind of cranky and bitchy. She’s having a bad day”. And it really just feel like that. This episode fucking blew. It RUINED what was an absolutely fantastic season finale and a great concept. Complete fuck up.</p>

<p><strong>Survival Instinct</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4y6pNHu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We have some scenes of Seven has a Borg with her unimatrix on a planet, then we jump back forward to the present. Voyager has docked at a pleasant location with a lot of alien traders, it’s nice! Seven is unhappy about this. Not cause it’s bad, just cause she’s bad with crowds. Her and Naomi try to eat quietly, but are accosted by a random guy who offers her some Borg implants he said he found for trade. They’re implants from her old unimatrix. She takes them then leaves to study it. The guy is then rude to Naomi, so clearly he’s not trustworthy.</p>

<p>We get more scenes of her and her unimatrix. They’re all acting a little weird. They’re y’know, talking, for one. But also they’re acting more like they’re already freed drones. Their vessel crashed, and they were the only survivors. The were seperated from the rest of the collective, and are now remembering who they were.</p>

<p>Back in the future, they’re trying to do SOMETHING to Seven as she sleeps. But are caught, and captured. But it’s pretty clear they’re not like, violent or evil in any way. They want to seperate the link between the three of them, as they are now seperate from the Borg fully not not each other. You’ve got three of them. The leader, some older guy, a Bajoran, and what looks like a stereotypical thug from a bad cyberpunk movie. Seven agrees to help them, but she’s concerned. She cannot remember what happened on the planet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LQw5BJk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They need to link Seven back up to the mini collective here to try and help them. There’s a chance she may get locked in the collective with them, turning it into a quartet, but she’s willing to do it. There’s a lot of stuff about family. They’re the closest thing she still has to family. Well, them, and Voyager. She has a moment with Naomi, telling her that she’s her family. It’s cute.</p>

<p>She hooks up, and we see more of what happened on that planet. They all became unique, their own people, but Seven was scared cause it’s basically all she knows. She ends up being the one who linked them all together, in fear of what would happen. When they find out Seven is the reason, they freak out and get pissed off, then go into neural shock.</p>

<p>The Doctor now announces they have a new problem. They’ll die like this. They can sever the link but they’ll live for a month. Or they could be returned to the Borg and live normal length lives, as drones. They also can’t be spoken to for their opinions.</p>

<p>It’s pretty clear what they’d want. They will happily live out shorter lives, as themselves, and Seven helps them with that. They accept Seven and don’t hold a grudge against her, wishing her well. Two of them leave to live out their days. But the Bajoran… stays on Voyager! She was Starfleet, and is happy to stay on Voyager, but she’s not able to forgive Seven. Things are tense, but she understands WHY Seven did it. She was a scared girl.</p>

<p>Seven spends some time with Naomi, her family. It’s a cute ending. Pretty good episode, good season premiere!</p>

<p><strong>Barge of the Dead</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sj9PaNX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Torres is trying a shuttle and crashes into the hangar bay, but she’s alive. Her hair is also all frizzy and curly! It’s cute. She risked her life to get a probe, but everyone is like “you are far more important than a probe. We care about you”. And she doesn’t try to bit their heads off!</p>

<p>Chokie shows her a thing that was lodged in her port nacelle. A shard of something Klingon. Some hunk of metal with the Klingon insignia on it, hundreds of years old. Neat. He gives it to her, and then it starts bleeding and screaming. That’s probably normal. It IS Klingon in origin.</p>

<p>She asks for scans of it, and they do, but find nothing. She orders more scans and Kim seems done with this shit. Usually I hate when people are like “come on you didn’t see the thign you saw, that’s wild” on Trek because Trek is finding new weird shit all the time. But in this instance, honestly I’m surprised Kim isn’t MORE done with everything. My mans gotta be exhausted.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nB4oHEi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At Tuvok’s weekly therapy, which is a thing Torres is doing now, he talks to her about her self hatred. She’s like “the hell are you talking about”. He then pulls out a batleth, wounds her, and tells her to leave, her and her dishonor. What the fuck</p>

<p>Neelix throws a party, a big Klingon inspired party. It’s partly cause they found that artifact, but also because it’s a piece of the Alpha quadrant so it’s a piece of home. She walks into the mess hall as they’re singing Klingon songs. It’s like a bunch of white people throwing a Diwali festival and the one Indian person walking in like “huh”. Anyways they celebrate, and then some Klingons come and murder everyone. Well then. Torres awakens on a bloody ship.</p>

<p>Turns out she’s on the Barge of the Dead. She’s dead. BEEN dead, in fact, and she’s being taken to Gre’thor, Klingon Hell. They just wanted to do a Klingon episode, and can you blame them?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QaKw9NJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They explain that she’s been in The Dream, something dying brains make up to think they’re still alive. The murderer was just waking her up. They can’t brand her though, apparently it is “still not her time”. She tries to fight the ferryman, Kortar, the First Klingon, and gets injured instead. And then her mother showsu p as another member of the dishonored dead, and suddenly she’s awoken in med bay. Apparently she almost died in that shuttle and was in a coma.</p>

<p>She’s now stuck on the memory of seeing her mother going to Hell, possibly for her sins and dishonor. She doesn’t believe in the afterlife, but a part of her still does, and she’s wondering, what if? This is a good “what’s real and whats not” episode.</p>

<p>She studies the Ancient Texts, and finds two things. One, her dishonor can in fact cause her mom to go to hell, cause of “the sins of the child”. Remember, Klingon Culture is fucked up and bad. And two, when people return from the dead, they have wounds that they got there come back. And she did keep the wounds given to her in the fight.</p>

<p>Torres is basically a born again Klingon. She has a plan. She’s going to simulate a near death experience and go back to the barge to try and bargain for her mother’s honor. Everyone is kind of belligerent about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MXjmTq9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Torres is really hot here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1ukH8tE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It works though. She finds herself back on the barge. She goes to find her mother, who’s kind of a bitch? Absolutely awful. She also refuses, she doesn’t WANT her to do this. “Cheat” her way into Sto-vo-kor. But in the moment, Torres ACTUALLY takes her place, and agrees to actually die. What’s her personal hell? Voyager. It’s just Klingonized Voyager. But no, actually she’s still on the Barge. No, she’s dying in the Med Bay. No, she’s on the Barge, arguing with her mother again, who is actually NOT in Sto-vo-kor, and refuses to tell her what she’s “supposed” to do, she has to find out herself.  What she’s “supposed” to be.</p>

<p>I’ll be honest, I also don’t know what she’s supposed to be. I don’t get this episode. I don’t follow the themes or what’s going on, exactly, but she throws away the Batleth while crying, and apparently that’s the right decision? Her mom says she’ll get into Sto-vo-kor. Maybe she’s just having an identity crisis and is suffering from a bad nightmare? I honestly have no fucking idea. Anyways she wakes up and is all good, and hugs Janeway first before her fucking boyfriend I guess. I have no idea.</p>

<p><strong>Tinker Tenor Doctor Spy</strong> - VOY
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/inhp8ll.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This might be the weirdest cold open in all of Star Trek. The Doctor is singing to a crowd, Tuvok has Ponfar, and the Doctor starts singing about him having Ponfar and needing a hypospray. He calms Tuvok down with it and ends his song to rapturous applause. We return to the REAL world to find out that the Doctor has invented a way for himself to daydream.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PTCcb3Z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Doctor why are you fantasizing about knocking out a horny Tuvok?</p>

<p>The doctor sends an official message to the Captain that he’s not being treated well enough by the crew, and that he wants a promotion, basically. She’s like “what the fuck” but hey, might as well draft a response. Meanwhile an alien ship is watching and scanning voyager.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sOLUAhe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They are the Onlookers, of the Hierarchy. They just spy on people and learn more about them so they can raid for supplies. Okay, sure. They view Voyager as an unacceptable risk, though. But one of them thinks they can hack into the computer to study them better. And it works! They get a live feed! But it’s a feed of… the doctor’s daydreaming. Oh my god what a FUNNY idea.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the doctor suggests for his promotion that he be given additional backup programming as a commander to help command when needed. The ECH: The Emergency Command Hologram. Janeway finds it interesting, but pushes it down the line, cause it’d be too much hassle for now. But that doesn’t mean he can’t be the hero commander in his own mind!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qWNLbL4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is all very exciting as he blows up a Borg Sphere by himself. The Onlookers are STUNNED, and are planning a raid, but only when he’s NOT in command. After all, the ship has riches upon riches inside!</p>

<p>The Doctor is walking down the hall, and is accosted by Chakotay, who congratulates him on blowing up the Borg. He’s confounded. Chakotay is in his quarters… uh oh. The daydreaming program is going off at all times. He tries to eject the core IRL, and they have to hold him back. They lock him in sick bay, but also hook him up to the holodeck so they can watch them. Everyone is excited, but Janeway is kinda disturbed. I mean, she promised him she’s treat him like any other member of the crew, and this is intruding.</p>

<p>Parts of this remind me of the first Barclay episode, but I like this a lot more. Some of the fantasies he has are a bit uncomfy, like romance fantasies, but like… a lot of us DO have those. We get it. He’d never act on them. Janeway sees one last fantasy where he’s so proud to be given the ECH program, because all he wants to do is reach his potential and help the people he loves. She feels a way about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BzAfzqc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The daydreams are fixed, but then they show back up. But it’s actually the Onlooker. His name is Phlox. He’s realized that what he’s been watching is NOT reality. And if his superior find out, he’ll be fired, or worse. He also wants to protect Voyager and the Doctor, because he’s formed a parasocial relationship over the past few days. I get it. I like the Doctor too. He offers to help them, but only if he ALSO pretends to actually be in command, so he doesn’t get fired. Oh boy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Tx1t43y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What commences is the ultimate bluff. The Doctor, anxious as fuck, talking to the Hierarchy leader, who demands surrender. The Hierarch actually could EASILY destroy Voyager, and take what they want, buuuut the Doctor has a secret weapon. The Photonic Cannon. A super weapon he built that blew up the Borg Sphere. And he WILL turn it on them. So they run the fuck away cause holy shit, they don’t wanna deal with THAT</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cPwF5ka.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor is given a promotion for his valor, and he will be given the ECH program after all. Wonderful, extremely enjoyable episode. I liked the Onlookers, they felt like Pacleds You Don’t Hate, and I love aliens learning about humanity from fiction. It was a combination of the Pacled episode and the Barclay episode, and it was way better than both.</p>

<p><strong>Alice</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kTF1XF9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is flying around when it detects a flotilla in front of them. Friendly or violent? Well, they get a hail, aaand it’s a junkyard. Abaddon’s Repository of Lost Treasures. They beam him on board, and he’s very interested to trade. He doesn’t have TOO much they need, but Paris sees a ship that looks VERY interesting. It has a “Neurogenic Interface”, which means it connects to the pilot through the brain, so you can control it directly. Seems weird, but sure. It needs a bit of fixing up! Good thing Kim is willing to help fix it up! “I am?”</p>

<p>Abaddon is sad to see it go, but is absolutely willing to trade. Paris names the new ship “Alice”, after a girl he had a crush on once at the Acadamy. He connects to it, but blows out some power relays and goes to bed. And theeen he hears voices in his head calling to him, calling him to the bay. Who is that? “It’s me, Alice”</p>

<p><em>cocks gun</em> ships haunted.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/svLwfyn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a montage of Paris fixing it up. He starts wearing a flight suit he found in her database. He gets REAL into it, missing hang outs with Kim. Stops shaving. Belanna and him have a date on there and she’s kinda weirded out by how he’s being. Aaaand then she starts manifesting as a thing he can see.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LEm4rhT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Alice. She has Overly Attached Girlfriend Eyes, she reminds me of Gifanny from Gravity Falls. She keeps wanting to leave and go elsewhere with him, tried to convince him to leave Voyager over and over. Also it seems like connecting with her is kind of… addicting? Brain washing? Bimbofying? One of those.</p>

<p>Everyone is watching Tom kinda become… less himself, and more distant as he’s working on this ship. It’s uncomfortable and kinda sad. He’s not SO far gone that he doesn’t at least try to save Torres when the ship literally tries to kill her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sX0gkAX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris at least realizes things are bad and tries to go to sickbay to get free of her influence, but it doesn’t go well. Alice causes him pain in his brain to force him to go back to the ship and fly away. He connects to the ship directly and they become “One”. It’s creepy. This entire episode is creepy. In a pretty entertaining way.</p>

<p>Paris and Alice manage to fly away. Voyager goes back to Abaddon to try and figure out what’s going on. He’s connected to Alice too, who tries to kill him for telling them anything. “I DID WHAT YOU ASKED I GOT YOU A PILOT-“ yeah, she’s nuts. They manage to save her, who tells them what we basically already know. She’s nuts, and wanted a pilot, for some reason. They find out where she’s going on scanners, a “Particle Fountain”, a kind of anomaly they know little about, because it ends up killing anyone who gets near it. Alice calls it “home”.</p>

<p>So either she’s an alien intelligence to some other universe, or she’s malfunctioning. Either way, Paris is probably dead. They can’t fire on the ship either, because he’s one with it, so hurting the ship will hurt him too. They need to shut down the ship by hacking it, while distracting Alice and Paris. So they hack into his neurogenic interface and hook Torres in there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XHzbPwN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s a Battle in the Mind, and he’s teleported out, just before Alice explodes. I guess she… got what she wanted? To explode in an anomaly???</p>

<p>Paris is extremely upset that he ever let it get that bad. “It was like I was sleepwalking. Thanks for being my alarm clock”. How romantic?? She also promises no more affairs with strange ships. But don’t worry about the Delta Flyer, they’re just friends.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>