<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-22T23:53:30-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 3" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dJF1W2N.png" alt="&quot;You didn't forget anything, did you? Take care! I'll have some side dishes to pick up once you get back!&quot; They gained another mom." class="center-block" />
Source: About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 2 - Daedalian Opus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA2-DaedalianOpus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 2 - Daedalian Opus" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA2-DaedalianOpus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA2-DaedalianOpus.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DyUJOpj.png" alt="Daedalian Opus" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rccW4Uw.png" alt="Daedalian Opus" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Look not every game I do has to be some big event.</p>

<p>I dunno why I discovered this game. Or why I fell in love with it. But I did. I speedran it way back in the day. It’s not a good speedrun. It’s barely a good game. It’s a 1990 puzzle game by Vik Tokai, and is very simple. You have some blocks, and you have a boaord. You can flip and rotate the blocks. Fill it in. It is a very simple pentomino jigsaw puzzle game, with a goofy silly name.</p>

<p>It’s nice pleasant little music that is nice for when you’re puzzling through a puzzle. The puzzles are all the same every time, and there are 36 of them. After puzzles you’re often given a new piece, which is then added to your pile, so it gets progressively more complex. It starts with just like simple rectangles, and then becomes almost  art pieces, things that look like rockets and shit.</p>

<p>The set was VERY simple, only progression. So I beat it in like 20 minutes. I don’t have much more to say. It’s Daedalian Opus, baybee. It’s not complex, but it doesn’t need to be. It’s just pleasant.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Game Boy" /><category term="Daedalian Opus" /><category term="puzzle games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 1 - Ristar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA1-Ristar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 1 - Ristar" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA1-Ristar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA1-Ristar.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2Lv7cF3.png" alt="Ristar title screen" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So a year ago, I started my journey on Retro Achievements. I’ve been posting about it a lot of Cohost, where every mastery, I talk about the game. But I started at like, game #40. So I have a lot of posts I just never made. Gonna fix that here. We’re starting from the start.</p>

<p>If you’re wondering what this series is, I basically play a game, and then do a review of it. Simple. Retro Achievements is a site where you can play a game, and it gives you achievements for it. Simple as well.</p>

<p>My first choice for a game to master was Ristar… Ristar is my favorite game of all time. I’m literally named after it. You may not have realized Lizstar is a Ristar pun, but now you do. This game is in my DNA. I know this game better than I know my own hands. I am way too close to this game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G6wYIQk.png" alt="Ristar " class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Ristar you play as uh, Ristar. He’s a 90s Sega mascot, so he’s cut from the same cloth as Sonic. He’s inspired by a pitch for Sonic, which was a bunny that grabbed things with its ears. That idea evolved all the way to this. Basically, Ristar was built with one core philosophy in mind. You experience most games with your sense of sight. Can we make a game where you use your other senses? This game is all about the sense of touch. You play as a child exploring the world, reaching out and touching things, or feeling them. This game’s working title was Feel for a reason.</p>

<p>Ristar can jump and strech his arms out, just for you. He’ll grab anything he can reach, which depending on what it is, will have different effects. He might swing around on a pole. He might hand on a thing, or climb ladders. He might turn switches. Or he’ll grab the enemy and slam his entire head into it. You’ve gotta figure out what everything does in the classic way. Grabbin’ it!</p>

<p>Ristar is slower paced than Sonic. He takes his time, sauntering through levels, exploring. It’s got a lot of that same DNA though, and is just as fun. The levels are colorful, well designed. And the music is, of course, fantastic. This might be the prettiest Genesis game. It was pretty late in the console’s life cycle, so it’s not a big surprise.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xujUvrt.png" alt="Ristar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The main time when Ristar speeds up is with the star poles. Ristar can grab these poles and spin around them, gaining increasingly more speed as he spins, before he releases and flies through the air. He’s hard to control, but you can explore and get to new areas this way. Again, all about that exploration!!</p>

<p>The story of the game depends on if you’re playing the JP version or not. This game actually changes a lot with the American release. In the JP release, the evil Kaiser Greedy is invading the solar system, and is taking over the planets and their leaders with his mind control magic! The people pray to their goddess Oruto for help, who sends her son Ristar. The US version keeps that kind of, except there’s no Oruto. Instead, his dad is the Galactic Hero who goes to stop Greedy, but is defeated, and Ristar has to save both the star system, and his dad. I guess they thought Americans would freak out about a non Christian God? Some of us would. There’s also other changes, like changing a cat monster to an ice monster, but both versions are fine to play.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WToUEKs.png" alt="Ristar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is not an easy game. But if you play it, you’ll find a LOT to enjoy about it. It is endlessly charming. Ristar is so cute, and he has so many fun idle animations, like making snowmen! It’s a good challenge, Greedy is one of the hardest Genesis boss fights. And of course, it’s just fun. The devs of this wanted to make a sequel, but Sega never cared about it much, and sent them all away to work on Nights into Dreams. Which y’know, is a good game. But I wish more had been done with my boy.</p>

<p>The actual set was good too btw. Though it had an achievement for grinding out points, which was kinda boring and annoying lol</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Genesis" /><category term="Ristar" /><category term="platformer" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 4" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HL0gfPl.png" alt="&quot;That girl and I just aren't on the same wavelength. We buy each other desserts on the same days. When I go to buy her a present, I stumble upon her. And the other day, we surprise proposed to each other at the exact same time. Can you believe that? It's like she's doing it on purpose! To think I have to share my life with her...&quot; &quot;Uh, okay. Happy marraige, I guess. Can I go now?&quot;" class="center-block" />
Source: UNOs 2</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="UNOs 2" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: UNOs 2]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/21/OOCY2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 2" /><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/21/OOCY2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/21/OOCY2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TecvJJ9.png" alt="&quot;W-w-we can't! If we do that, someone will die! Namely me! We shoul start with holding hands!&quot; &quot;We've already held hands many times!&quot; &quot;Why?!&quot; &quot;Because... we're girlfriends. Is something the matter with you, Mariya-san?!&quot;" class="center-block" />
Source: I Won 300 Million Yen in a Lottery so I Started Rasing a Freeloader Pretty Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Won 300 Million Yen in a Lottery so I Started Rasing a Freeloader Pretty Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: I Won 300 Million Yen in a Lottery so I Started Rasing a Freeloader Pretty Girl]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DO YOU REMEMBER?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shitpost/2024/09/21/DYR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DO YOU REMEMBER?" /><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shitpost/2024/09/21/DYR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shitpost/2024/09/21/DYR.html"><![CDATA[<p>NEVER WAS A CLOUDY DAY</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="shitpost" /><category term="shitpost" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NEVER WAS A CLOUDY DAY]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/20/OOCY.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 1" /><published>2024-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/20/OOCY</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/20/OOCY.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G0vNxhe.png" alt="A girl goodgling yuri" class="center-block" />
Source: Lily Love</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wl9KdWK.png" alt="A girl searching for girls dating online" class="center-block" />
Source: Nana Yuri</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I41pHIf.png" alt="A girl looking up what two girls do beyond kissing and being AMAZED" class="center-block" />
Source: Kase-san</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="Out Of Context Yuri" /><category term="Lily Love" /><category term="Nana Yuri" /><category term="Kase-san" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: Lily Love]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 45 - Faussette Amour</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/05/03/RA45-Faussete.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 45 - Faussette Amour" /><published>2024-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/05/03/RA45-Faussete</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/05/03/RA45-Faussete.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TajZokF.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yt0elDF.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KFsEeEk.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NDsUslN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Game #45 is done, Fausette Amour for the PC-Engine CD! I’m doing lots of PC-Engine stuff this month, because of a website-wide event. So expect some PCE masteries comin’ your way =w= This one took me about 4 and a half hours, and was mostly level-completion achievements, no-hit bosses, and a no-continues playthrough.</p>

<p>First is THIS… exciting experience. This is Fausette Amour, which if you can speak French, you’ll realize is extremely improper French. My friend Zandra came into stream and flinched a bunch at it lol. It’s a game released only in Japan, and it’s CLEARLY a knock off of the Valis games. Or, y’know, heavily inspired. The best way for me to describe it is it’s Valis meets Castlevania meets Bionic Commando meets uh… Ghosts n’ Goblins, mostly cause when you take a hit your clothes fly off, and you get two hits.</p>

<p>Story? I dunno, in Japanese. Fight a bunch of demons who are actually women, save your sister, stop a demon with big goat titties. This game is VERY tantalizing. Lots of tits and ass. Almost every one of the cutscenes involves your character, who’s name is Cork Lance btw, amazing name, standing in a bad ass action pose, with the camera focused REALLY CLOSE up on her ass, or thong. It’s a little much.</p>

<p>The gameplay is pretty jank, but honestly, the game itself is really not that bad. It’s a pretty hard game, but I’d give it a 6/10. Worth playing, maybe. But maybe just stick to Valis.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC-Engine" /><category term="TG16" /><category term="PC-Engine CD" /><category term="Faussette Amour" /><category term="Platformer" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 43 - Sid Meier’s Civilization for SNES</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/04/27/RA43-Civ.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 43 - Sid Meier’s Civilization for SNES" /><published>2024-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/04/27/RA43-Civ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/04/27/RA43-Civ.html"><![CDATA[<p>NOTE: These are posts I made on Cohost, and where I started talking about the games I mastered, as I mastered them. They are out of order for this reason. I’m going through and posting all my old content, so this is the oldest one even though it’s #43. Okay back to the review.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/U0Czf4X.png" alt="Civilization" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I said the other day I might start doing this. Well, I’m doing this. I’m on a website called Retro Achievements, which true to its name, puts achievements on old retro games. I’ve been working on “mastering” (read: getting all the achievements on) a bunch of games, and currently I’m at #43, Civilization 1 for the SNES.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/O7PiB56.png" alt="Civilization" class="center-block" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/BJxgz4j.png" alt="Civilization" class="center-block" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/ELbHcNx.png" alt="Civilization" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Now, I am a HUGE Civilization fan. I started playing the series in the early 2000s with an old copy of Civ 2 Gold on my windows 98 PC. That shit Whips. I did go back and play Civ 1, and played a few games of it to completion, but always saw it as generally inferior to Civ 2. Which tbf, it is. Civ 2 is essentially just Civ 1 with more features and a slightly better AI, it’s not like going from Civ 5 to Civ 6 where they changed a bunch of concepts around.</p>

<p>I did not know that Civ 1 got ported to the SNES though! And apparently neither did a LOT of people. I streamed this on my stream, and a bunch of people were like “this exists?!”, but I did have a few people go “YO I HAD THIS AS A KID, I LOVED THIS GAME”. I bet if I had had this, I’d have ADORED it.</p>

<p>It was made by Koei, who was THE company you’d want to hire for a port like this. Koei made a lot of strategy games on consoles, and I hate pretty much all of them. All of the games they made were really stupidly complex with lots of fiddly menus and IMO are NOT made for a console. You should not be playing Romance of the Three Kingdoms with a gamepad. Civ is different though. Yes, you can use a SNES mouse, but I actually did not. I used my gamepad, and it was perfectly enjoyable. A little slow paced, yes. It’d not the way I’d personally play this game, but there’s no DOS retro achievements (YET) so I had to do this version lol</p>

<p>This version is pretty great! Civ 1 is of course a fun game, though dated and a little primitive, and this version is faithful in almost every way. It adds a weird goddess to the beginning that reminds me of E.V.O., but that’s okay. And some systems feel like they just kinda don’t work. My cities were FILLED with pollution pips, but I never saw a single pollution tile, and I played through three games of this. But other than that, it works great.</p>

<p>As for the set itself, it was a LITTLE grindy. Get all of the wonders, that’s fine, you get so far ahead of the AI in this even playing on the hardest difficulty. Research some things before they were researched IRL, that’s fine too. I wish there was an achievement for “learn to fly before you learn what gravity is”, because that’s a thing I did. Researching Math before 3000BC was the only one that gave me trouble, cause math isn’t super useful early game so I had to do a specific game just for that. Then there’s the achievements for beating the game, on Earth, on an Ice Age Map, and on the hardest difficulty with 7 civilizations. Really easy, tbh. Just play as the Americans on the Earth map, you’re very isolated. The Aztecs did spawn, but I easily destroyed them by rushing them down, and could build up for a science victory without being hassled.</p>

<p>This game is also really succeptible to save scumming. Save scumming the villages, save scumming battles, it’s amazingly easy.</p>

<p>The only achievements that were actually a hassle were the ones for wiping out every tribe. All 14 of them. And you can only start a game with 7. However, in Civ 1, if a civilization is wiped out early enough, a new one will spawn. This is useful for these achievements but WOW was it annoying for the World Domination victory achievement, cause civs kept spawning in places I already found.</p>

<p>Over all though, a fun version of Civ, and a really fun game. Took me 14 hours of gameplay to master. I probably wouldn’t go back to this version, but I’m glad I checked it out. There’s no achievements for Civ 2 on the PS1 on RA yet. I’m considering maybe devving those myself, tbh. It seems like a challenge, but the game is so fine I don’t think I’d mind.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="Civilization" /><category term="strategy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NOTE: These are posts I made on Cohost, and where I started talking about the games I mastered, as I mastered them. They are out of order for this reason. I’m going through and posting all my old content, so this is the oldest one even though it’s #43. Okay back to the review.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 44 - Panzer Dragoon Saga</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/04/27/RA44-PDS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 44 - Panzer Dragoon Saga" /><published>2024-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/04/27/RA44-PDS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/04/27/RA44-PDS.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5dfxbkd.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AKXH0x2.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a1RNFjH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J7cun4q.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Took about 30 hours of gameplay, apparently.</p>

<p>The 44th game I’ve 100%’d on Retro Achievements, this is one of my favorite games of all time, one I’m SUPER into, and have wanted to do since starting RA. But it’s very intimidating. I’d never 100%’d PDS before, and uh, after doing it… I’m glad I did! But I’m probably not doing this again.</p>

<p>It was the most stressful mastery I’ve done, because 95% of this game is missable content, and you might find out 20 hours later that you missed something you can’t go back to from 3 hours into the game. I had a lot of backup saves set up to make sure I didn’t screw anything up. And I didn’t! I made it through with no problems! If you don’t know what 100% entails, imagine Castlevania’s 100% Map Hunting… But in 3D, on a dragon. And a lot of the map chunks are tiny slivers in a wall that you can barely see. But the game tracks it, so you gotta do it lol and it GRADES you at the end.</p>

<p>If you’ve not played this game, I won’t spoil anything, but it comes 200% recommended. Also I already did a review of it. One of the best RPGs of all time, and thus one of the best GAMES of all time, an absolute 10/10, I can replay this game every year or so happily. A fantastic time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Panzer Dragoon Saga" /><category term="RPG" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>