<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-03T09:58:56-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 170</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/03/OOCY170.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 170" /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/03/OOCY170</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/03/OOCY170.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KPD4752.png" alt="Yako-san is super thrilled. 'We've gotta have each other's backs for stuff like this!' Yako-san suddenly looks less thrilled, with KILL in her eyes, 'and the fact that we live in a society where gay partners have to expend this much effort simply because they want to live together never fails to stoke the smoldering rage in my soul! :D' 'The rage is showing in your eyes, Yako-san!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She Loves to Cook She Loves to Eat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 194 - Mario’s Point &amp;amp; Click</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/03/RA194-Mario'sPointandClick.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 194 - Mario’s Point &amp;amp; Click" /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/03/RA194-Mario&apos;sPointandClick</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/03/RA194-Mario&apos;sPointandClick.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eH8JnvO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the wildest things I’ve ever experienced. So, did you know the N64 had a mouse? It was made for the N64DD, and therefore has very little use, but it DOES exist. Well, someone took those protocols, and made a version of Mario 64 that uses mouse controls. Yes.</p>

<p>It’s literally just Mario 64, entirely, with no changes. Except when you click someowhere, Mario moves there. When you right click, a menu pops up, and you can select from a long list of commands. Things like jump, long jump, attack, etc, as well as a variety of effects you can turn on and off, like wallkicks or crouching.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t2oUzDW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It DOES have one unique area added for the hack, a tutorial area designed to teach you the mechanics. But other than that, nothing is changed. And it’s 100% completable. Not a single thing is impossible. You look at it, and immediately go “there’s no way”, but yes. Nothing is impossible. I did it all.</p>

<p>That’s not to say it’s easy. The slides are HELL, and any moving platform is the most evil thing on the planet, but you can overcome it. See, this hack turns Mario 64 from a 3D platformer collectathon to a puzzle game. And it’s WEIRDLY fun? I replayed Mario 64 the other year for the first time in a while. It was…. fine. Not as good as people say, but also not as aged as others say. It’s like, an 8/10, good game, but some of the later levels are so frustrating. But here? I had a WEIRDLY fun time trying to maneuver Tick Tock Clock. Playing it casually with normal controls, I was getting annoyed, but I died a BUNCH here and didn’t care at all, just hopped back into it.</p>

<p>I really recommend this, it looks intimidating and very much a “what the fuck” kinda thing, but it was a LOT of fun.</p>

<p>Oh also, I made this set. I guess I should mention that. I was given this as a Kusogrande match and loved it so much I had to make the set and then beat it lmfao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="N64" /><category term="Romhacks" /><category term="Mario" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 169</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/31/OOCY169.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 169" /><published>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/31/OOCY169</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/31/OOCY169.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fmUJpe6.png" alt="'Fufufu, I made you moan &lt;3' The other girl, Ritsuka, reacts by getting bashful and biting her. 'Wah! What the?! It hurts! It hurts!' Jump cut to the next day, with her dressed up in a heavy scarf. 'Why have you been wearing a scarf all this time, Kozuka-san?' 'Ah... well... a cat bit my neck...' 'Eh?! Are you okay?!' &quot;Eehehe...' then, internally, 'curse you, Ritsuka!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Even If It Was Just Once, I Regret It</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Even If It Was Just Once I Regret It" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 193 - Dragon Quest 1 &amp;amp; 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/31/RA193-DQ1+2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 193 - Dragon Quest 1 &amp;amp; 2" /><published>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/31/RA193-DQ1+2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/31/RA193-DQ1+2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jjlm4fx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So after playing Dragon Quest 4, I was in a bit of a Dragon Quest kick again. I decided to take advantage of this by playing one of the many, MANY re-releases of the games that exist, starting with Dragon Quest 1&amp;2 on the Gameboy. This is a combo package of… well, DQ1+2. Its what it says on the tin.</p>

<p>This came out in 2000, so over a decade after Dragon Quest originally did. Though it’s not actually the first re-release. DQ1 and 2 also got a release, as a single package, on the SNES. Obviously this is nothing like that, because that’s a major graphical overhaul. I’ll have to play it someday.</p>

<p>I played this off stream, because DQ1 is such a chill cozy game to me. It’s a nice grindy game to relax to while watching something, and I beat it in like 4-5 hours. I know it very well by this point. DQ2, on the other hand, was a bit more effort. I had only ever beaten DQ2 one other time before this, last year, so I didn’t know it NEARLY as well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R2g0vmi.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The games are MOSTLY the same, but there are some significant differences. The graphics, of course, but there’s some different equipment in 1, backported from 2, and it felt like the grind went even faster than it does on the NES, so maybe numbers were upped too. Oh also the translation is different, so she’s no longer Erdrick, she’s Loto now. I prefer Erdrick. In DQ2, numbers were upped a bit again, it’s still kinda hard and rude, but it’s a lot less rude feeling than it was on the NES. The most notably differences, however, is you can get puff puff in DQ1 now, and in DQ2, there’s a scene where the Prince, the 2nd character you meet, gets sick and you need to heal him to get him back in the party. Which is NOT needed to beat the game, so you  can beat the game with only two characters from that point on. As a challenge, I guess. I did not do that.</p>

<p>Dragon Quest, and many games from this point on, would begin re-releasing their older games adnauseum. But most of the time these days, it’s a super up to date version, or just the old version again with no differences. This was interesting. They could have made DQ1+2 on like, PS1 or something, but they didn’t. They used an 8-bit machine. So it’s really just DQ1 and 2 again, but with slightly different graphics, and slightly updated UI. Which hey, I like those games, so why not, right?</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievements Unmastered 4 - Digital Devil Story - Megami Tensei</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/30/RAUM4-MT1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievements Unmastered 4 - Digital Devil Story - Megami Tensei" /><published>2025-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/30/RAUM4-MT1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/30/RAUM4-MT1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/acCOcH6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I made the Unmastered series of posts to showcase games that I beat, did not master, but still wanted to review. This is a bit different. I actually did not beat this game. But I’m playing the sequel, and loving it, and expect to master it, so to talk about it, I wanted to talk about this one too, for context. There’s also a lot to talk about.</p>

<p>Megami Tensei is one of the most important RPG series of all time. Kind of. See, Megami Tensei was pretty popular, then it got a spinoff series called Shin Megami Tensei, which superceded the series and became so much more popular people forgot the original existed. And then that series got a spinoff series called Persona. And now some people don’t even know about SMT. And even LESS know about and remember MT. Even even LESS know about and remember the fucking book series that this game was based on. But is that fair? Let’s see where this series started, and determine if it’s unfairly forgotten…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rXevEMk.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Megami Tensei is a sequel to the novels. Basically, the idea is that Nakajima invented a computer program that let him summon Demons into this world. He used it to try and get back at and scare some bullies, but it went WAY too far, and now he’s trying to stop the Demons. There’s also stuff about him and his gf Yumiko being a reincarnated God, I dunno, I didn’t get to any part where that’s mentioned, if it is in this game. This game is VERY low on story, character, or plot, but the basic idea is you need to traverse this labyrinth and find and defeat Lucifer. Along the way you’ll explore different areas and defeat the generals there before finally fighting Lucifer. There aren’t really any smaller stories in this areas either, it’s pretty straight forward.</p>

<p>And now, the gameplay. Megami Tensei is a dungeon crawling RPG in the style of Wizardry. In fact, it’s basically just a Wizardry game. And, look… I like retro RPGs. A lot. I REALLY love NES era RPGs, ones people say “aged poorly”. I will happily play Dragon Quest 1 until the cows come home. But this… this feels like it goes beyond aged poorly. It’s missing so much shit that we take for granted today, and utilizes it in ways that fucking hate the player. This game is very, VERY rude. And it, like Dragon Quest, is almost completely a grind-fest. But it does NOT make that easy, or pleasant, to accomplish.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mtIcl6u.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You have stat allocation. Be sure to allocate it correctly, or you’re fucked. There’s a single place to save the game, heal, fuse monsters, and cure status effects. You can get spells to do some of these things, but if you get to the deeper areas, and Yumiko gets hit by a numb status effect, you gotta wander aaaalll the way back to undo it. While draining health, and being attacked by a ridiculous encounter rate. When you enter a door, the encounter rate is like, 60%. Also, the game crashes. A lot. A LOOOOOT.</p>

<p>But that pales in comparison to the #1 most fucked up thing I’ve ever seen in an RPG like this. Some enemies have attacks that drain your levels. Yes. ENTIRE LEVELS. Just, boom, hit by this enemy? Your levels are gone. You can run sure, but you’ll probably fail running at the worst time… and since you’re grinding like crazy, you’re probably on autopilot anyway, so you’ll miss that you’re fighting the level draining enemies, and suddenly whoops, 2 hours of effort is gone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dNFgWp5.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, what DOES Megaten bring to the table? It’s not just a rehash of Wizardry with really rude mechanics. It DOES have a lot of cool ideas, but they’re also implemented…. weirdly. This game has a monster catching mechanic! You can befriend monsters then summon them using your computer. They drain resources when they’re out, but you usually make back more than you drain if you’re just killing everything. They gain no levels, but are invaluable. You can also fuse them together to create new demons. Very useful, and neccesary to continue. It’s confusing and needs a guide for you to get anything done, but still, cool idea.</p>

<p>What ISN’T cool is the monster catching itself. In later games, you can influence it slightly. In this game, it’s all RNG baybee. Good fucking luck. And many demons just can’t be tamed, so you’d never fucking know, but they can and WILL take your bribes, just like all the ones that can, so you’ll just assume you’re VERY unlucky.</p>

<p>Megaten is… a rough game. It was cool for the time and had some good ideas, but frankly, there’s no reason to ever go back to play this now. Just play Megami Tensei 2.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Megami Tensei" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Unmastered" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 192 - Dragon Quest 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/29/RA192-DQ4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 192 - Dragon Quest 4" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/29/RA192-DQ4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/29/RA192-DQ4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jjlm4fx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Last year I played Dragon Quest 1-3. I’d only ever beaten DQ1 before, but I was a huge fan of it as a kid, so I was excited to finally sit down and beat DQ2 and 3. I’d played them, but never got very far. This one I had barely played at ALL, and put off until this year because it’s the start of a new series! Dragon Quest 4 is a new step for the series, and I’d heard it was good, but I REALLY liked 3, so I didn’t expect it to quite reach those heights.</p>

<p>Uh, I was fucking wrong. Dragon Quest 4 blew my fucking mind. This might actually just straight up be my favorite RPG on the NES now. Mother 1 is still holding on, but I’ll be real, it’s close.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xpJGjhl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Dragon Quest 4 tries for a new thing for the series: a plot! That’s a joke, but also kinda not. DQ1-3 had very mild plots. 3 had a bit more of it, but it was really about the scene to scene stuff. This game not only has a plot, but it also goes about it in a unique and interesting way. This game has like 7 heroes, and it introduces you to each of them by each chapter, as they’re doing their own things. Finally, after all their chapters, you’re introduced to YOU, the main character, the chosen hero, and the game fully opens up, with you collecting the crew and saving the world. Notably, you can also be a woman! And the game actually acknowledges that fact and doesn’t just fucking ignore it, like it did in DQ3!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g5aODwl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The different chapters range from your typical kinda fantasy story to very unique weird shit. Like, it starts with a knight trying to find kids who’ve been kidnapped by monsters. By the later chapters you’re a merchant trying to save up money for his own store, with unique mechanics exclusive to him about trying to get as much money as you can.</p>

<p>So, other than the story, what does this game have going for it? Well, it’s more Dragon Quest! And I really like NES Dragon Quest. It plays well, is well balanced, has fun progression, and has a LOT of extra content. This is the first game with little medals, for example. And they’re VERY well hidden, too, as they usually are.</p>

<p>Frankly, I don’t have that much more to add?? Like… it’s just an EXTREMELY high quality NES RPG. It’s still an NES RPG. You will have to grind. You will get confused about where to go on occasion, though it’s got a lot of QOL shit that earlier games REALLY did not have. Shout outs to the Return spell taking you to any town, yay. I’m excited to replay this someday with the DS version. But for now, it’s just fantastic, and I highly recommend it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 168</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 168" /><published>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/29/OOCY168.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PDdBpKW.png" alt="'Two girls look back at each other, one on a train that's about to move away. The train girl is pulling down her face mask to reveal her blushing face'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oJHRxce.png" alt="'Train girl leans her head down bashfully as the train rolls away'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n3Jgc2r.png" alt="The girl outside of the train starts blushing 'CUTE! OH MY GOD SO CUTE!! SHE'S SO CUUUUUUTE!!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: From Aiu Station on the Hiragana Line</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="From Aiu Station on the Hiragana Line" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 2" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekSNW3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/27/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Hegemony Part 2</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEvb4AL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Following directly after last season, the Enterprise is surrounded by Gorn, and some of their people are captured on the Gorn ship. The Enterprise is forced to retreat… but not before tagging the Gorn ship with a dud missile that’s actually a secret beacon.</p>

<p>Pike’s girlfriend, Batel, is infected with Gorn Babies and they might need to kill her, but to prolong things, they’re freezing her in a block of ice. Specifically SHE’S the one asking them to kill her if they need to. Well, at least that’s the PLAN, but turns out she’s allergic to being stuck in a block of ice, which I imagine I’d be too. Now Nurse Chapel is stuck trying to figure out how to cure Being A Gorn Mom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vvOBev.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Admiral April is like “we have to just ignore all this and let the Gorn capture neutral people” and Pike, being Pike, says fuck that shit, we’re being treated as Prey. And April agrees, unofficially, their rules are to punch the Gorn in the nose and show they’re not prey. Meanwhile, in Engineering, Scotty and Pelia the Warpcore Witch are trying to get a Gorn Cloaking Device up. Scotty says it’s impossible. Pelia is like “we’ll have it done in an hour sir”. Scotty is, one day, gonna be REAL good at doing the impossible on a deadline, and he’s gotta figure out how to get good at it real fucking fast.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Gorn ship, La’an wakes up and punches her way out of a Gorn sack. She rescues the other members of the crew captures, including Sam Kirk (Kirk’s brother), Doctor M’Benga, and Ortegas (who has had half her hand melted off). They want to get out… well, three of them do. La’an decides then and there, she’s going to save ALL the other colonists. Good luck.</p>

<p>Y’all remember Mitchell? She was a very minor background character in season 1, had some minor roles in 2, and now she’s on the bridge and refuses to leave until they can solve this. Yay, Mitchell!</p>

<p>They have some SMALL hope. Batel has a 14% chance of survival if they use Una’s blood. Yay! Also the Gorn seem to go to sleep when a certain kind of star flare happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jFp5msI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FkBzvR4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit is going way, WAY worse. Man this is tense. While exploring a weird binary star that seems to hide the Gorn homeworld because of radiation, they find a BUNCH of Gorn ships blasting out of the zone and going towards Federation space. Now Pike has a choice. He might lose the tag on the colonists and his crew if he leaves to warn Starfleet, but they are NOT prepared for an invasion. So he makes the impossible choice and leaves them.</p>

<p>Pike seems so fucking done. He’s EXHAUSTED, he’s worrying about every single little thing. And can you blame him? When he goes to Scotty and Pelia like “Hey can we make a solar flare” and Scotty is like “what the fuck no. Not without doing this this that and this which will blow up the ship” Pike is like “Sure just do it without the blowing up the ship part” and everyone just… stares at each other.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of “have faith” talk in this episode, which we keep making fun of by posting Star Wars memes. It doesn’t help when Ortegas takes over a Gorn ship and flies them out in a scene that is VERY Star Warsy. Also Ortegas becomes massively injured in the skirmish, but sticks too it. Poor Ortegas, she can’t catch a break ):</p>

<p>We get a fuzzy fisheye scene with them in the radiation, but it works. They use the flare to trigger a hibernation in the Gorn, as they come back to go eep. Ortegas raises her deathflag REALLY high but is saved just before dying, thank fucking God. <em>sees death flag in Ortegas’ mouth</em> WHAT DO YOU HAVE THERE? PUT THAT DOWN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/evmRMxM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Batel is saved, Spock and Chapel have a moment of acceptance, and the Enterprise is beat to fuck. But alive. It ends the “have faith” talk with Pike thanking God for some reason.</p>

<p>I thought it was alright! Not blowing me away, but good! Excited for more.</p>

<p>I’ll be editing this page every week and reposting it with the new episodes as they come out =w=</p>

<p><strong>Wedding Bell Blues</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9FnKzZH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s 3 months after the nightmare of the last two episodes, and the Enterprise is repaired and ready! Everyone is going to a gala to try and relax! I’m sure this’ll go exactly as expected! To try and get into the spirit, and to practice for getting things going well with Nurse Chapel, Spock is practicing dancing with La’an.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Yol3Cdf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>BUT NOT A BRAIN! :D</p>

<p>Anyways, Chapel comes on board with the doctor she’s been working with for three months, Roger Korby. He’s a very friendly guy, but a bit eccentric. Anyways Spock almost makes an ass out of himself before we find out Korby is, in fact, dating Chapel now. Whoops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AkPLZfu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy HELL, Uhura’s outfit is on point.</p>

<p>Ortegas is doing better. Physically, at least. We meet her brother, who is flirting a bit with Uhura, who seems reticent. Ortegas isn’t into it, though.</p>

<p>Everyone gets together to drink a bit. Spock is, as usual, awkward. He steps away for a drink at the bar, and we get this like, weird Mxptlk mother fucker who’s tending bar. He appears as a Vulcan to Spock, but to us, he’s a weird mother fucker. He gives Spock a drink, who…  wakes up later that night next to Chapel. They’re getting married! Oh boy! I’m sure Chapel will handle this very well!</p>

<p>This Mxptlk ass dude is basically acting as wedding planner and getting everything all right and dandy. Is he a… shipper? Of Nurse and Spock?? I will say, over all, I haven’t really… been into the Chapel and Spock thing? It’s not JUST cause I know it won’t go anywhere, but also cause of how they just… don’t go together lmfao which I think this episode is doing its best to try and show.</p>

<p>Korby is the ONLY person who seems to realize something is wrong. He can remember things how they SHOULD be, and is trying to subtly sabatoge the wedding. Spock catches him, and he explains that this is all wrong. Spock punches him out, but then for some reason remembers that yes, this IS wrong, and… well yes, feels bad, but most importantly is like “this needs to be fixed”. He and Korby work together, they’re both smart science boys, and though they love the same woman, they have to work together to figure out what’s wrong.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3XmlT3E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s kinda fun to watch these two try and wander around a changed reality, testing at the waters and touching the boundaries to find where they are. Spock tries to get others to realize something is wrong. He tries to get Kirk to punch him. He insults his mustache. It doesn’t work.</p>

<p>When they confront the Wedding Planner about this, he reveals he’s a giant fucking baby and this is all a game to him, which they’ll have to play, or he will wipe everyone from existence. Welp. Korby and Spock change up their plan and yeah, the only thing they can possibly do now really, is try to go along with it. When Korby DOES act up, he’s turned into a dog, and no one else seems to care. They’re really just his puppets.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JsdWJEP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually Chapel snaps out of it too, thanks to Spock, and when the Wedding Planner announces everyone is going to die. But he’s interrupted by his… dad. Who is, in fact, played by John de Lancie. Hmm. The bartender is just a kid, and he’s made to clean up his toys. Everyone is like “WELL THAT WAS WEIRD” and then tries to celebrate the actual reason they’re there, the Cenntenial. La’an dances with Spock, who has no regrets. We have one of the three armed aliens from TAS, who joins the crew as their bartender, yay! Aaaaand Ortegas has a PTSD episode. Yay!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 191 - Where in Hell is Carmen Santiago</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/27/RA191-WhereInHell.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 191 - Where in Hell is Carmen Santiago" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/27/RA191-WhereInHell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/27/RA191-WhereInHell.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fhqU3q3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is maybe one of the more interesting games I’ve ever played for this project. This is Where In Hell Is Carmen Santiago, and first we have to discuss what it is. Retro Achievements describes it as a “homebrew”, though notably, it came out in 1990. Japan has a word for games like these: Doujin. Self published games. But English really only has the term Homebrew, which is a newer term and doesn’t quite fit. It’s good enough.</p>

<p>This game was made by St. John M. Morrison in 1990, and that man is a MASSIVE nerd. You’ve got to be a huge dork to make an Apple II homebrew, but this guy really was a huge computer nerd. But let me first put you in the mind of a nerd paying attention to Apple II products in the late 80s.</p>

<p>Carmen Sandiego was a huge hit, and many jokes were made about it. I remember one I often heard: Where the hell is Carmen Sandiego? Well, Mr. Morrison took that joke and decided to run with it. This is both a Carmen Sandiego game, and an ecucational game, teaching you all about Dante’s Inferno! Well, it’s not actually very educational, but that’s okay. I actually studied Dante in college and wrote my thesis on him so like, I’m at least well versed in this shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FKpqezW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Where In The Hell, you must walk through Hell and interrogate V.I.L.E members, who are souls burning in Hell for historical crimes, in order to find where Carmen Santiago lies. Hell in Dante’s model is basically a straight line, going deeper, with each layer having the souls suffer for a different sin. You can move up and down, use items you find, look around to learn more about the layer, search for items, or call a name. When you call a name, you have a list of the V.I.L.E souls, and must theorize about whether that soul will be in that layer. If you guess right, they’ll come out, and you can interrogate them and ask them for items to help you on your quest. These items are things that let you get past later obstacles, basically.</p>

<p>It’s not actually that educational and is a lot of trial and error. But eventually you’ll find Carmen and she gives you an item to escape. And that’s it, right? Nope! This game has a second mode, known as “Pit of the Programs”. Remember how I told you Mr. Morrison was a MASSIVE computer nerd? We’re putting that to the test.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ITdhFlp.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kvjcyDW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All of the historical souls are replaced with characters that are references to popular edutainment games on the Apple II, like Stickybear or Reader Rabbit, turning into Stinkybear or Reaver Rabbit. Or, they’re referencing computer concepts, like vaporware. The map of Hell is the same, but its WAY more trial and error to try and find out where the hell anyone is and what they do. And it’s all just one big joke. It’s kind of a funny joke! One I like. But a joke.</p>

<p>This is a fascinating little program. It’s mostly making fun of a popular game of the time, and is… interesting, but I dunno if you need to play it? But you SHOULD know it exists.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Homebrew" /><category term="Carmen Sandiego" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 167</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/27/OOCY167.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 167" /><published>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/27/OOCY167</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/27/OOCY167.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WOmnhfP.png" alt="'I think two girls clinging onto each other is a wonderful thing! Or rather, I'd like to do so!!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Couple Drifting in the Wind</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Couple Drifting in the Wind" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>