<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-17T12:57:19-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 27</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/17/OOCY27.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 27" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/17/OOCY27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/17/OOCY27.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4l0vUGh.png" alt="&quot;I didn't even want to think about boobs!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="NSFW" /><category term="Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 34 - Overbold</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-34.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 34 - Overbold" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#34</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-34.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ZwiiG4.png" alt="Overbold" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Three years and 27 games after her introduction, the Space Pirate Alpha returns! Remember, she’s the Samus-esque character from Velgress. After her struggles in Velgress, she’s broke with no ship. Her only hope of getting the money for a new ship is to fight in the Red Arena, a blood sport arena where the more you fight, the more you win.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sROd9bJ.png" alt="Overbold" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Overbold is a Smash TV-esque arena fighter, where you choose how many enemies you fight each round. The more you add on, the more you make, in quantities of 100. You can then use that money to upgrade yourself, with random upgrades costing more or less each round. After like 8 or so rounds, you’ll fight a round that’s INSTANTLY at max difficulty, with a boss. Beat that, and boom, you win. In each battle, you can run around, avoiding enemy fire and lava pits. You have a gun that travels the whole distance of the arena, and bombs, which can and WILL kill you, but instantly kill almost everything.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2UCAcvX.png" alt="Overbold" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>As you may be able to tell from the fact I just described the entire game in a paragraph, and not a particularly large one, this game isn’t very complex. Honestly, to its detriment. I know a lot of people who really like Overbold, and I have no fucking idea why. It’s fine, yeah, but it feels MASSIVELY undercooked, like it just has no ideas. There’s a SINGLE arena, runs will take you like 10 minutes, and while it’s got some challenge to it, that’s not really enough to carry the game for me.</p>

<p>Sorry :/</p>

<p>6/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 33 - Fist Hell</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-33.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 33 - Fist Hell" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#33</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-33.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GbnEbcU.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s been a little bit, we’ve got another game in the Partyverse! You can tell, because Amy is here. She’s the protagonist of Party House, and is in Hot Foot. You can also see the gym from Hot Foot, along with “GO GATORS!” signs. It’s cute. Anyways, on to the game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UnHHM02.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Fist Hell is a belt scrolling beat em up, most clearly influenced by Double Dragon and Kunio-kun, ESPECIALLY with the sprite art for the latter. In Fist Hell, a zombie outbreak is occuring! The zombies have kidnapped Jay’s mom, who was running for mayor. The current mayor is on the case, but he clearly can’t be trusted, so Jay calls his friends up and goes on a rampage to save his mom!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fl0YzMK.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got four characters, as I said, Amy is here, but the only real character to play single player is Jay, IMO. Everyone else is just too weak. This is a BRUTAL beat em up, and any advantage you can have to tide the swarm faster is one you should take.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bDynNyv.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a simple two button beltscroller. You’ve got your jump, you’ve got your punch. If you walk into someone while punching them, you’ll grab them, and then with a direction and a punch you can throw them. This will be required for at least one boss. You’ve also got a jump slam you can do with the grab, I never found it super useful. There’s also food pickups, of course burgers and pizza and fries, and money pickups. After each level, you can buy either a full heal, or a powerup. Yes, you don’t heal inbetween levels. There aren’t many levels, but this makes the game even harder than it already is, and it’s hard. I know it took me a long time to get good enough to even beat level 2, I just kept bleeding health getting to that point. Learning tricks and strategies helps, though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jJ7Pf0p.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You have VERY classic hit stunning in Fisthell, where if you don’t finish your combo, just punch thrice, wait for a second, then continue, you don’t kick them away, and can just stun lock them down. This, on top with taking advantage of how you have more vertical range up than enemies do down, means that you can hit enemies safely and lock them down. This does apply to you, though. I found the safest thing was to just hug the bottom of the screen, most of the time.</p>

<p>I don’t like beat em ups. I find them pretty boring, honestly. You punch a guy, wait for them to get up, and then punch them again. Do this for 2 hours. Fist Hell isn’t 2 hours, and the enemies go down fast enough that there’s not much waiting. It’s constant action. It’s okay for what it is, a perfectly fine beat em up. Even if that’s not entirely my thing.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 32 - Mortol II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-32.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 32 - Mortol II" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#32</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-32.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SBqyDyd.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The long awaited sequel to Mortol 2 is here! And while Chun came up with the original idea, it was kind of changed to make the game more fun and pleasant. But now HE’S in control, that ol fuddy duddy Smolski is gone, so now Chun can do whatever he wants. And he wants to go back to his original idea, with MORTOL II!</p>

<p>The government is bringing back the evil to gain more power. Wow, how unrealistic. The people, upset that their sacrifice was forgotten, stand up once more to save Mortolia. This time, you have 100 lives. And no way to gain them. It’s a much differently designed game, but that original idea is there, and while it is kind of anxiety inducing to watch your lives drain away, the game isn’t too long once you know what to do.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vN91B9F.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The correct play is to explore, not give a shit about your lives, then route out a path after you know what you even need to do. It’s one giant open map, which changes as you effect it. Enemies stay dead, your sacrifices stay there, allowing you to tame this wilderness. You’ve got 5 different units: The warrior, who has strong melee strikes and can turn into stone platforms like in the first game, the Gunner who has long range guns and can spawn an ammo pack, the Scout who can double jump, throw a few ninja stars, and can create a teleporter, the Engineer who throws arced wrenches and can build 5-tall pipes through the ground, very useful if you know how to use her, and the Bomber, who is TOTALLY not a girl in a kink outfit, who explodes. That’s what she does. She explodes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DuiZKUL.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Using these fives units, you must explore Nilpis (which is VERY fun to say) and tame it, reaching into the castle to defeat the ancient evil inside. Feeling your lives drain away is painful and anxiety inducing, but I managed to do it with 52 lives left… the cherry is to do it in under 50, for the record, so I was VERY close. But my route got me there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BeMpKtk.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Each of the units has their own music, and the vibe and aesthetics are dark and spooky and weird, in the same way Mortol 1 is. It’s a good weird time that is just as good, if not possibly even better, than Mortol 1.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 31 - Pingolf</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-31.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 31 - Pingolf" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-31.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sZJYdkr.png" alt="Pingolf" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It is mid 1987, and UFO Soft has moved fully into its new offices! These new offices have a LOT of nice ammenities, including an indoor minigolf course, and a bunch of pinball machines. The new boss, Mr. Nemura, is really into collecting games it seems, so he has a bunch of old ones for the in-office arcade. Cool! Inspired by these, the team made Pingolf, a kind of combination of Pinball and Golf.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PPUgwXj.png" alt="Pingolf" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Pingolf is a cyber futuristic-esque golf game for a big tournament with a bunch of robo-people, but it’s also… a carnival? It’s weird, I don’t really like the vibe or aesthetic much. The music is fine though. It’s a side to side pinball game, just choose the angle and the power, and let her rip. You can also dunk the ball, which will SLAM the ball downwards, often at an angle if it’s moving forward. Do 18 holes and win the tournament!</p>

<p>It’s not very complex of a game. Compared to some of the recent games, in fact, it’s SHOCKINGLY simple. Very short, even, this can take you like, 10 minutes. Getting GOOD though, that will take you a while. The holes are the same every time, you learning a route, where and when to dunk, that’s gonna take you a bit longer. The cherry is to get under par. The AI is actually pretty damn bad at this, so like, just getting under par means you win handidly.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MQNta4a.png" alt="Pingolf" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s it! I didn’t like this game very much when I first played it tbh, but it’s… alright. I think it’s just okay. A little too simple for its own good, and a bit frustrating as you try and learn it, cause your ball bounces all over the mother fucking place, and dunking is hard to really grok. The best thing about this game is that using a code you can play as Waldorf. Hell yea, Waldorf.</p>

<p>6.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 30 - Rock On! Island</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-30.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 30 - Rock On! Island" /><published>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50#30</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-30.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K7lXGZx.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another game that feels less retro and more modern based on its genre and concept, Rock On! Island is a tower defense game from 1987. This genre basically wasn’t a thing until the early 2000s with flash games. But hey, whatever works, I’m here to review the games, not anochronistic issues.</p>

<p>Rock On! Island follows you as Ug, the young chief of a group of cavepeople, who are being attacked by dinosaurs, who are trying to wipe you out for good. Humans and dinosaurs got along for years, but now the Four Emperors have taken over and are trying to take the island for themselves! You must lead your people through wit and cunning to keep your caves safe.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9bAeN31.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It is, as I said, a tower defense. You have waves, and inbetween the waves you can set up cavemen to protect the lane leading to your cave. These cavemen can be upgrades to different forms: fire, spear, and rock. Then again, to fire 2, tar, spear 2, bow, rock 2, and wheel. Most of these can honestly be ignored, bow is what you need. Bow is EXTREMELY OP, and can carry you. But I’ll get to balance issues later. You can also buy chickens, which help increase the meat you get each turn, and can be cooked with fires to give a 3x price increase. Those fires can ALSO upgrade cavemen near them, so it’s about balancing and placing defenses, and economy. You can ALSO upgrade Ug, who has a stone axe, and you can increase the speed and power. On some stages, a fully upgraded Ug can straight up carry the entire stage by herself. She doesn’t even need cavemen, she’s EXTREMELY strong. Don’t get hit though, you’ll respawn after a few seconds and lose some health. Lose all the health, and that’s it, game over.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0N0KS19.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Okay, issues. This game has balance issues. The bow is OP, as I said, but all of the stages go the following way: The first 2/5ths of the stage are slow, shakey, and awkward, and you will lose constantly, or just BARELY not lose, if you’re trying to do it without taking any damage, which you are, cause that’s the good ending for the cherry. After that, after you have a bit of a starting defense, the game is piss easy and you barely have to pay attention. Repeat that for ten levels.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/op4aRcQ.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s FINE, but it’s really missing something to take it over the top. Also the lack of music in the planning stage is unfortunate.</p>

<p>I have nothing more to add, except for this little bit you can find in one of the side areas. Some animals have broken off to form a peaceful contingency, and this is what one of them says:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9pdmQCq.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/1p8Cg1Z.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/c1u02tx.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/bSOcV4X.png" alt="ROI" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Huh, I wonder what that’s about :)</p>

<p>7/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 29 - Vainger</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-29.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 29 - Vainger" /><published>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50#29</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-29.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KjFpk2I.png" alt="Vainger" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Vainger is one of those games that, when you see it, and you see the scope and what it is they’re actually trying here, you go “ohhh shit”. Cause this is a metroidvania, and yes, we’ve had those already, sure. But it’s REALLY a metroidvania. It’s UFO Soft’s Metroid.</p>

<p>In Vainger you play as a doctor who is tied to a robot combat suit, the Vainger. You re-awaken after an incident to find that the station you work at has become overrun, and that you were betrayed. Now you must explore the station, piece together the story from logs, collect items to travel deeper, and defeat the evil at the core of the station.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oubqAwE.png" alt="Vainger" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The best way I can describe Vainger is it’s Metal Storm meets Metroid. Metroid Storm. You run and gun and jump, with crouching included even, and then you can ALSO flip gravity so you run and jump on the ceiling. It’s extremely fun and fluid, and a lot of the gameplay and challenge comes from well timed flips to platform in tricky ways.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/12dsXL6.png" alt="Vainger" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Now, it IS a metroidvania, but it’s actually rather small, IMO. Porgy is maybe as small, but with Porgy, you travel much slower, and have to travel back over and over to the surface. In Vainger, there’s no such mechanic, so you can cover the entire station in only a few minutes. You could easily 100% this game in an hour and change. And in fact, I had to. This game has a glitch where it can eat your fucking power ups, which it did to me :) So I had to 100% it, again. This was very, very annoying, and honestly, I haven’t really forgiven it yet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jtNQ640.png" alt="Vainger" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another thing about Vainger is its powerup system. You find powers which allow you to explore deeper, like any Metroidvania, but then you must equip them to your grav system, your body, or your gun, each of which do different things. Having your items in different spots for different situations is important, and you need to backtrack sometimes to a save station to equip the right combo.</p>

<p>Vainger isn’t hard or anything, and while I’m very annoyed by it, I cannot deny it’s an extremely good metroidvania. It’s creative and cool and fun.</p>

<p>…now for some meta story. The buyout is fully complete, Gerry and his nephew Boby have left the company, and the rest of the team have to pick up the pieces and continue on. But it can’t be too hard, can it? …We’re already seeing some struggling. This game almost got cancelled due to arguments and problems within the company. Namely with its director, Chiffon Bola, who has been butting heads with the new management, especially Ian Spinzer, the new middle manager in the office. And them moving offices to a giant office across town isn’t helping. They’re a small team, they don’t NEED this giant new space, and the old space had so many memories. Now they’re seperated from the fun center, the burger joints. They’re seperated, and a bit isolated.</p>

<p>You can see Bola’s frustration with the situation as an easter egg in a hidden room in Vainger: Here’s a message, which makes no god damn sense…. unless you know who Ian Spinzer is.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/O4UQyZF.png" alt="Vainger" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>8.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 28 - Rail Heist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-28.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 28 - Rail Heist" /><published>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50#28</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-28.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y4zZNrP.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Lots to talk about with the backstory for this one. Rail Heist is the first game with credits since Tao Nemuru bought the company and became CEO and producer, and since Gerry Smolski left the company in the power struggle. In the credits of this game we see Tao Nemuru as producer, and the manager he brought into the company, Ian Spinzer. We now have middle management in the mix! Ian Spinzer will become someone VERY important to the story, but for now, we just know he’s middle management. Most of that doesn’t matter for this game, though. Rail Heist was already being made before the buyout even happened, so they didn’t have much of an effect on the creation of this game. Which might explain why it fucking kicks ass.</p>

<p>Taking place in the world of Lonestar, this game is the game that takes place, I BELIEVE, as a far flung sequel to the world in Devilition. There’s one other game that’ll take place here, Grimstone, which started production before Rail Heist but won’t come out for another year. So what is Rail Heist about?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jfq5pvu.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Rail Heist, you play three train robbers, led by Gran, an ol’ bank robber who’s retired by this point, but is still your guide, cause she knows this bidness better than anyone. This is a kind of… turn based action puzzle platformer? Your character is placed on this train, and you need to use the environment to your advantage. Once the lawmen are wary of your presence, they will begin patrolling, and now you only have 8 seconds before it swaps to their turn, where they move around, and if they see you, they’ll just fucking shoot you. If they see you, at ALL, they will fucking shoot you. The lawmen of this world have VERY twitchy fingers. You CAN use this to their advantage, throwing chickens to get them to unload their bullet and take a sec to reload, or have them shoot their fucking buddies. This game is PERFECT in its representation of how awful cops are at their jobs.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z0P4nd1.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You can use the environment to your advantage, hiding in barrels, throwing boxes, punching lawmen off trains, breaking the floor from under them and having them fall to their deaths. Sound isn’t a thing here, only if they have DIRECT eye sight with you will they know you’re there, so if you’re like, just above them, nope. They got laser eyes. But if you have your gun out, you ALSO have overwatch. Use THAT to your advantage!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2Ys3SkT.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is utter clownshoes, and is one of the most fun things I’ve played in ages. While the levels ARE always the same, things fall out of hand very, VERY quickly, and when you die you fucking bounce all over the god damn place between enemy bullets, or go SPLAT on the rail tracks, it’s so funny. It feels really rewarding and fun to FINALLY conquer a level. You can also get three medals on each level, one for killing all lawmen, one for beating a pre-set time, and one for killing no lawmen. It’s real fun learning each level and developing a route through each.</p>

<p>This is one of my personal favorite games in the collection, 4th place. Highly recommended.</p>

<p>10/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 27 - Divers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-27.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 27 - Divers" /><published>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50#27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/16/UFO50-27.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p9A46Fy.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I FUCKING love this game.</p>

<p>All that stuff about Nemuru and Smolski and the politics of the office, throw that out the window for this one. We have no idea who made this game. There are no credits. I can guess, though. You can find mooncat and Barbuta in here, and the game’s energy and vibe are…. deafening. And it’s one of the weirdest most creative fucking things I’ve played. I love this god damn game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Kk5I4Fp.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Divers is a game that makes no sense the second you open it up. You are IMMEDIATELY thrust in it, with three options, none labeled. Nothing about this game will be explained, so don’t bother. You’ve got a shop, and equip screen, and a button that I will just call “dive”. So you get your items, some sticks and lids, and equip your Bois. You’ve got three Bois: Dylan, Orlok, and Thyme. These three lizard men are a polycule, and they are your bois for the remainder of this game. 
Cherish them. Every day they dive into the murky depths in search of treasure, knowledge, and whatever the fuck it is they’re hunting for.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MFIvqqd.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The best way I can describe this game is that it’s Dragon Quest 2 meets the TMNT Dam Level. I call it that and all the other sickos like me who love this go “oh yeah, that is kinda what this is”. You explore a big open map, diving deeper, trying to find anything in the murky darkness. You have a small radius around you that you can see, and you need to find treasure chests and other goodies in the deep, while either avoiding enemies that float around and try to chase you, or fight them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kc5v8gX.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When you do fight them, you’ll find the combat is very early NES RPG, very Dragon Quest 2. The items you equipped to your bois can be used a limited number of times, and you select them as you fight, either to hit the enemy, or to defend one of your boyfriends. The combat is pretty rough at first, this game is a big grind game. You are weak as fuck at first, and after almost every fight, you need to step back and flee to the safety of the light above, where your bois will eat and rest and return rejuvinated for the following day. Every time a boi falls, it says in full caps that they DIED, but like, it’s fine. Food and sleep cures all.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CmC0z3a.png" alt="Divers" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Divers is large, and will take you over ten hours, most likely. You’ve got a large cavern system to explore and find secrets in. But by the end, I wanted more. I want a game that’s literally this but 3x as long, and I am not joking. The vibes of this game are immaculate. This game has one of my favorite OSTs in the entire pack, and 70% of the game is LITERALLY PLAYED IN SILENCE. Just the feeling and energy of the unsettling deep fills me with an emotion I cannot describe. I love this game. It is perfect in every way, and I absolutely cannot recommend it enough, but it is… a little difficult to get into. It’s a large undertaking, but if you like NES RPGs, you’ll probably adore this.</p>

<p>It’s also worth noting that somewhere in the depths is The Green Room, a giant room which is one of two rooms in the entire game where music plays, and there’s literally nothing in it. …Nothing that we’ve found. There might be a hidden boss, or meta progression, or it was a dummied out thing that was left in, we don’t know. But that music haunts me. I take naps to it :)</p>

<p>10/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 115 - Arkista’s Ring</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/16/RA115-Arkista.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 115 - Arkista’s Ring" /><published>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/16/RA115-Arkista</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/16/RA115-Arkista.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vH72BTs.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I felt like absolute garbage today, massive migraine day, so I decided to take the day off from doing anything actually important and I kinda just played games while watching Todd in the Shadows and videos about Archie Sonic. I decided to pick up and play this game, which I had played earlier this week on stream and decided after an hour that it was a “play by myself” kinda game. Because it’s kinda boring.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p7dgwvB.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Arkista’s Ring is a 1990 NES game by NMK and published by American Sammy. NMK made a bunch of games that I have not heard of at all, though Wikipedia tells me their most popular one is Zed Blade for Neo Geo. Sure. I had never heard of this game, but recently I’d been wanting to play more NES stuff, cause I love my NES and I hadn’t explored some of the more obscure depths of it, or even the less obscure depths. I pulled up the NES games list on RA and noticed quite early on (in the As in fact, funny that) this game, Arkista’s Ring. I was immediately drawn in by the 80s as fuck anime elf girl. Hell yeah, elf girls. I’m on board, let’s go.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dN6SCqh.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a top down action game that was compared to Zelda a lot on its release and I’ll be real I have no idea why because they have very little in common. They’re both top down games where you are and elf and you fight enemies that kinda walk around on a grid-base, but uh, that’s about it. Zelda is a big ass adventure where you explore and discover secrets. Arkista’s Ring is level based and very samey. You have an open area where you need to kill all enemies, and then a key spawns in a little stand thing, grab that, go through the door, boom next level. There are like 40 or so levels, and they’re all the same every time, there’s no randomization here. The enemies are deterministic based on your movement, so you can outsmart them pretty easily. You play as Christine, a cute little elf who’s trying to get back Arkista’s Ring, an Elven ring stolen by the evil Shogun that has caused shadows to fall over the land or some shit, typical fantasy stuff. The game can be split into three different parts, where you go into dungeons and fight a manticore, go into crypts and fight a vampire, and then go into the shogun’s castle and fight the shogun.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dN6SCqh.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There are a bunch of enemy types, that can kinda be split into a few different types. Enemies that wander and run into you, enemies that throw shit when you cross their line of sight, enemies that wave back and forth and fly over walls, and ninjas. Ninjas are the fucking worst. They’re basically just the enemies that run into you but they’re fast as shit, some have way too much health, and they can jump over walls. Literally, if you fight these things like normal, they will out damage you at full health. Thankfully you can sometimes cheese their wall jump to get them stuck.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fh67ybC.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If you press select at the start of a level, you get to see your character, and it’s laid out like an RPG’s stat sheet, as if Christine isn’t the only character you can play. Sex: Female. Yes please. Anyways, you also have loads of items and weapons you can pick up from enemies. You’ll get a full loadout by the end of the game… probably. Two items, the Elf Mirror and the Wealth Amulet are like, .5% drops, and even though this game is very long and you pick up a lot of items, I did 1.5 playthroughs of it and only found it on my third real attempt, on level 35. I played this game halfway through, gamed over, and had to start again. You DO get 10 continues, VERY generous, but the set required a 1cc so I started over. And this is a rough game for that. You need a route and plan to deal with those fucking ninjas, and though the game is short, kind of, it’s also long as fuck. You see, there are 31 levels, but after you beat the Shogun on level 31, the game loops. Oh so it’s endless? No. There is an end. After loop 4 the game goes “yo good job” and just ends on the character screen unceremoneously. So it DOES have an ending but you literally have to beat it all 4 times. It’s a bit of a slog. Put on a podcast like I did and veg out.</p>

<p>All in all, Arkista’s Ring isn’t anything special, but it does have an 80s anime elf girl, which is what I came to it for, I guess. It’s really not BAD, but there’s a reason it’s been kind of forgotten over the years.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Arkista&apos;s Ring" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>