<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-11T11:35:40-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 71</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/11/OOCY71.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 71" /><published>2024-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/11/OOCY71</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/11/OOCY71.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eZcpZ4s.png" alt="&quot;&quot;How many times do I have to tell you I'm the dirtier one?!&quot; &quot;B-but I'm constantly thinking about @!$#ing you and stuff!&quot; &quot;S-so? I wouldn't stop there-&quot; &quot;What the heck are you guys talking about?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Heartbeat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Heartbeat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 129 - Magnet Girl</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/11/RA129-MagnetGirl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 129 - Magnet Girl" /><published>2024-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/11/RA129-MagnetGirl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/11/RA129-MagnetGirl.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qzGMdoO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Some PC88 sets came out so I played a few of them. The first is Magnet Girl by Lotus Roots, a doujin game! I think I’ve explained doujin games before, but they’re basically the same as doujin manga. Just uh, games. Doujin is usually used to refer to like, fanworks of things in America, but it basically means self published works. Nerds would make games on PCs of the day, namely NEC’s PC88, and would sell copies of it at local stores and conventions. They were pretty much as indie as you possibly could have gotten back in the 80s.</p>

<p>Though this game is 90s. This lasted for a while, well into the modern day. The most famous doujin game is, in fact, Touhou. All the early Touhous were PC98 games released as doujin games! But I digress, let’s talk about Magnet Girl.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OrMSEr8.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Lotus Roots made a few of these “Magnet World” games, but I’ve only played this one so far. It’s a rather short puzzle game with a unique mechanic. You platform around, pretty much on a grid, and you can swap your polarity from red to blue. There are magnets about, and they need to be pushed onto the opposite color, so they’re annihilated. Once all magnets are clear, you win. You push magnets by using your polarity. Like repels, opposites attracts. Turn on the same color to push a magnet around. You can’t pull, however, so turn on opposites instead to climb on top of magnets and use them to platform around and position yourself better. You can also repel yourself while on top of a magnet to reach greater heights!</p>

<p>It’s a little janky and a little clunky, but it’s a cute and clever concept. It’s got Sokoban energy, though I’ve never seen something quiiiite like this before. The game is not very long, and not super hard, but it’s a nice brain tickler, and I’d have loved to pick this up for 600 yen back in 1991.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Magnet Girl" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 70</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/10/OOCY70.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 70" /><published>2024-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/10/OOCY70</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/10/OOCY70.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qNdoEmg.png" alt="&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yy7R3Px.png" alt="&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: 4:30am at the coin laundromat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="4:30am at the coin laundromat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 128 - The Final Fantasy Legend</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/10/RA128-Saga1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 128 - The Final Fantasy Legend" /><published>2024-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/10/RA128-Saga1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/10/RA128-Saga1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/guShBYa.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Keeping with the Final Fantasy energy lately, I did The Final Fantasy Legend! Well, it KINDA fits, at least. The Final Fantasy Legend was known in Japan was Makai Toushi Sa・Ga, and is the first game in the SaGa series, which is its own distintive series that is not actually connected to Final Fantasy at all, except that a lot of the ideas in it are built off of Final Fantasy 2. But when it was translated for Western audiences, RPGs didn’t sell super well, so to try and boost sales, they connected it to Final Fantasy. This was a thing Square did a lot. Final Fantasy was at least KNOWN to some people here, so let’s just make this game a FF game even though it has little to do with it. At least this has more to do with Final Fantasy than Mystic Quest does.</p>

<p>This game is the first ever RPG for the Gameboy, released December 1989. As such, it’s pretty simple, but honestly it’s shockingly complex for that era, and for the Gameboy. Compare this to like… Mario Land. This shit looks like it at LEAST came out a few years later, if you compare them. The plot is simple: There’s a tower, and it’s said that the top of the tower holds a paradise. This tower connects many different worlds, and your characters are just one of countless adventurers who are tackling the tower. Simple, and actually quite commonly spoofed these days, ESPECIALLY the ending, which I WILL spoil, you’ve been warned.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4HqUZFq.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Like in Final Fantasy, you build your units out of different classes. There are three classes, and also two of which can be gendered, which is neat. You’ve got humans, mutants/espers, and monsters. Yes, monsters in this game can be friendly, and even fight alongside you! Humans don’t level up traditionally, instead they level up by using stat up items you can only buy in town. Mutants level up by fighting, getting random stat ups as they fight. And monsters level up by eating other monsters. As monsters are defeated, they can drop meat, which can be eaten to transform your monster. It’s fascinating. The humans are totally the best, though, if you’re okay with a bit of grinding.</p>

<p>The game is split into a few chapters, basically. You have the Continent World, then after you do all the stuff there and get The Orb that unlocks the tower, you climb 1/4th of the tower to reach the next world. Do the quests there, get the next orb, climb five floors, get to the next level. Repeat until you get all four orbs and reach the top to fight ASHURA. After defeating her, you need to climb the tower, AGAIN, and find God at the top, who’s like “Yeah this is just a game. You’re just my toys, I wanted to see if y’all could defeat real evil”, and your characters, disgusted at this behavior, KILL GOD. It’s sick as fuck.</p>

<p>The story is simple, but the little stories you encounter in the different worlds can get really interesting. They’re pretty impressive for a 1989 gameboy RPG! I recommend the game almost for these stories alone, but the gameplay is fun too.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TsJUNc7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I had to play the game as a solo run, actually. Which SOUNDS hard but like, it’s not, at all. If you pick Human Female, you get a really good item, which you immediately sell for a money boost, spending it on power ups to be able to handle the early areas easier. And the first floor’s whole thing if you’re collecting King Equipment, which makes you essentially invincible. You then just farm. I farmed for about 40 minutes before getting enough money to get my stats up to 140-ish each, and I was good. I just cruised through the game, occasionally upgrading my stats further. Your stats can go to 255 before overflowing back to zero, but it only shows to 99, which CAN be annoying.</p>

<p>Anyways, this is a really good game that I’d have loved back in the day. I can see why it’s beloved, and I’m glad I finally got to it!</p>

<p>Also one more fun thing, from Wikipedia: “Square’s concept for the game was a title that could be completed in six to eight hours, based on the duration of an airplane flight between Narita, Japan and Honolulu, Hawaii.” Thats cute.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="SaGa" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 69 - NSFW</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/09/OOCY69.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 69 - NSFW" /><published>2024-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/09/OOCY69</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/09/OOCY69.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jww0sT1.png" alt="&quot;Hey, you can still keep going, right? You fucking slut.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Nobody but You</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nobody but You" /><category term="NSFW" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 68</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/08/OOCY68.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 68" /><published>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/08/OOCY68</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/08/OOCY68.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UHndcCZ.png" alt="A girl sending a text to the girl she's holding hands with that says &quot;I love you&quot;, which causes the other girl to explode into steam" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Unforgettable Flowers and Rainbows</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Unforgettable Flowers and Rainbows" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 21 - 25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/08/LizstartrekDS96-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 21 - 25" /><published>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/08/LizstartrekDS96-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/08/LizstartrekDS96-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zdayXgW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>So, there’s only one more episode left in DS9 season 6. We’re going to watch it next week, where I’ll repost this with the additional episode.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>The Reckoning</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fiK79p8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The war is going bad, though a BIT better with the Romulans entering. That’s good! Odo and Kira are cute and lovey dovey now which will take some getting used to.</p>

<p>Anyways, Sisko, Kira, and Jake go down to Bajor, cause apparently some monks found a thing that might be important for the Emissary. Jake is being a weird little bitch about it like “Why is my dad okay with being Jesus now, why are we here, isn’t there more important stuff to worry about”. Jake. You’re an adult now. You’re like, 20. You don’t need to tag along when your dad goes away. As they see some old door that says “Welcome Emissary”, Sisko gets a vision that tells him that THE RECKONING APPROACHES.</p>

<p>They bring the stone door up to the station and give it to Dax, who has one of my favorite lines. “Yep, I know what this was the moment I laid eyes on it. It’s a hunk of stone with some writing on it.”</p>

<p>Sisko: “The prophets are never clear in their messages”</p>

<p>Kai Winn: “Ah, I wouldn’t know. They’ve never spoken to me.”</p>

<p>WHY IS THIS WOMAN POPE?? Anyways Kai Winn is a bitch like she always is, and demands the stone tablet back, just cause she’s a weirdo xenophobe. And then they translate the tablet and it says, very clearly: “DS9 is going to blow up”. Uh oh. And then the wormhole gets unstable and it starts fucking up Bajor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ulIDbN.png" alt="trek" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/x5XQf56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then Sisko gets fed up with it all and throws the fucking tablet against the wall. We then see Things release from it. I’m sure that’s fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yPjAwhq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We then find out what’s happening. Some Prophets and some Pah-Wraiths were released. The Prophet takes Kira, who it says is willing so that’s fine, and says that it is going to fight a Pah-Wraith here once it takes its own body to fight with. Kai Winn is like “FINALLY, A PROPHET” and begs it to give her something to do, she wants to help, and its basically like “who are you” by just, ignoring her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KBoEKlv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They call for an evacuation, and everyone leaves, except Winn who’s being annoying as always, and we see the Pah Wraith’s choice of body: Jake. There’s a lot of body horror in his face, it’s extremely upsetting to watch. There’s a fucking DBZ-ass battle, with energy beams, and it’s unsure who’s going to win, and who might die… Until Kai Wrinn uses a button that hurts Prophets, and knocks them out of their body. Why? We don’t know. She goes “Prophets forgive me…” but uh, I dunno if they will.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that everything that follows is probably her fault. The prophets said everything would be good if they win, which wasn’t guaranteed, but it looked like it was. So yeah, she just killed a LOT of people, and Space Satan is still out there. Kira calls her out on it, and blames it on her pride, which y’know, makes sense. It’s what the whole episode was about.</p>

<p>Interestng lore, just alright episode.</p>

<p><strong>Valiant</strong> - DS9
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JLpcQmR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While Jake and Nog are going to Ferenginar to deliver a thing to the Grand Nagus, they’re attacked by some Jem’Hadar, oh no! They’re rescued by… the Defiant! Nope, not the Defiant, it’s a ship called The Valiant, which is clearled based on the Defiant. So they’re trying to mass produced the Defiant now. That’s… gonna go well I’m sure. The people on the ship are all cadets… kind of. Turns out they’re RED SQUADRON! You may not remember them. They were the Elite of the Elite cadets at the Acadamy. They ALSO tried to help set up a coup a season or two ago. They explain that they were supposed to just be on a training exercise (the same one they were sent on in that episode actually), and then all the senior crew died in an attack, and one of them, Shepard, took command and now they’re stuck behind enemy lines and basically doing run and hide tactics to hit at the Dominion.</p>

<p>They invite Nog in to join them, and Nog’s always looked up to Red Squad, so he’s on board, and they need an engineer. But Nog is a little suspicious… because this captain seems to be doing this under the radar, and all the missions are sent to the dead captain instead of him, and they don’t know he’s just assumed command. But everything is on the level so far. So far.</p>

<p>Jake befriends the doctor on board, and asks her about home. This gets her kinda emotional and missing home. Y’know, normal human stuff. But this is a WAR and we are a MILITARY. Please ignore the fact that Starfleet is not, in fact, military. They are a MILITARY. They bring her and Jake in and are like “You are not allowed to be friends because you’ll DISTRACT THEM”. Also, the captain appears to be addicted to pills, and is kinda wigging out in a very sussy way. Jake is side eying all of this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOB1m6S.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re all just kids. They’re kids who are thrust into a situation they aren’t ready to handle, and they are kids who are basically being used to play out the captain’s Captain Fantasies.</p>

<p>Jake is thrown in the brig because he’s questioning this guy’s bullshit. Everyone else has kinda swallowed the poison. The captain has them go attack a destroyer. It’s basically like the Millenium Falcon trying to blow up a Star Destroyer. It does not go well. It predictably does not go well, and everyone starts dying as the Explodium goes off. It’s now just Nog and the girl Jake befriended, and then they rescue Jake from the brig and escape in a pod, barely making it out. The girl is like “the captain was a good man, and if he failed that means we failed him.” She’s STILL drinking the coolaid, but Nog makes the episode’s message clear: He may have been a good man. But he was a bad captain. And he killed a lot of innocent people with his arrogance.</p>

<p><strong>Profit And Lace</strong> - DS9
1.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zdayXgW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Here it is. One of the big ones. This is often considered the worst episode of DS9 of all time. And as a woman myself, I am sure I will have a LOT of opinions about it. But who knows? Maybe it’ll surprise us, and be good!</p>

<p>The episode starts with Quark sexually harassing one of his workers by demanding she sleep with him or he’ll fire her.</p>

<p>Well, that didn’t last long!</p>

<p>Anywayst the REAL episode starts when Grand Nagus Zek shows up on DS9 with Quark and Rom’s mom, Moogie. She’s wearing clothes! and in PUBLIC! Zek explains that he recently passed a law that allows women to wear clothes. And if they can wear clothes, they can go out in public. And if they do that, they can make profit. Yay! Unfortunately, this caused societal upheaval, and all the men in power banded together to depose Zek, and now Brunt is acting Grand Nagus, to be sworn in in only a few days. Zek drags the other main character Ferengi in trying to get people on his side. It doesn’t go well. Everyone is sexist. Fuck, even Zek is. He’s progressive… for a Ferengi. Anyways they get ONE person on their side, ready to see a female to prove females can interface with society</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gk5PrgF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Brunt continues to be the most punchable man in the galaxy.</p>

<p>Quark and Moogie get in an argument and she has a heart attack. That’s not good. They need a woman to show to this guy, but where are they going to get one?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AHWrcp5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Good thing Bashir does gender reassignment surgeries like every other day. It IS the 24th century.</p>

<p>Yes. That’s right. This is the transgender episode. Kind of. It’s actually the Gender Bender episode, but like, this hits a lot of trans energy. And not in a good way. Quark is now a woman, MEDICALLY, like he’s filled with estrogen. And it’s making her emotional. Ha ha, you know them women. ALWAYS emotional. They have a lot of things to grill Quark on, she has to be presentable in like, 12 hours. She needs to work on her walk. And her voice. And she needs to smile more! They don’t literally have that last one, but god, they might as well.</p>

<p>This is one of those feminist episodes that…. fails in almost every way, but god, is it insulting. I mean, I guess it’s trying. Kind of. The original concept was to make it a kind of comical farce, like a Shakespearean farce, but the director, Bashir’s actor, and Quark’s actor decided to play this DEAD serious. As such, the writing and the visual intent clash in a way that is very, VERY uncomfortable.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1Pgnw9l.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We literally get three straight minutes of this guy they invited chasing Quark around her room, trying to sexually assault her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cDnTSaX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Brunt bursts it and is like “THAT’S NOT WOMAN, THAT’S A MAN, BABY” but when Quark shows her tits to this guy, he doesn’t care. Well at least he’s a chaser, I guess. Anyway alls well that ends well, and he backs Zek to put him back in office. Quark’s experience with being a woman makes him more sympathetic, at least for a bit, and he apologizes to the woman he sexually assaulted, and she’s like “oh but I was looking forward to fucking you :(“. Ha ha, what… fun.</p>

<p>Yeah, this blows a lot. To be fair, Armin Shimmerman, Quark’s actor, also agrees. He thinks the half-serious half-joke idea failed horribly, I agree, and he actually toned down some of it, because the script wanted him to cry a lot, and he felt it was a bad stereotype, and went against the feminist angle of the episode. Yea, that’s true. It could have been even worse. Also, Quark really learns nothing by the end, and yeah. THey LITERALLY go “You’ll be back to your old self soon~”</p>

<p>And obviously, this episode wasn’t built with trans stuff in mind, but as trans stuff is VERY in the public conscious these days, it’s hard to ignore that reading. And that voice outing scene made me want to gag. I hated this episode, but I can’t give it a 1. It’s at least TRYING to be good, it’s trying, but fucking god.</p>

<p><strong>Time’s Orphan</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dVWHBeg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>O’Brien is back! We haven’t seen him in a few episodes. And KEIKO IS BACK! We haven’t seen her in AGES! They’re back from Bajor, and O’Brien doesn’t want them to ever part again. The bad news is, they are immediately parted. O’BRIEN MUST SUFFER! They’re playing on a Bajoran colony on vacation, and Molly finds a weird gate thing in a cave and falls into it, disappearing as the gate closes.</p>

<p>They find out it’s a TIME PORTAL that was just sitting around I guess, and it sent her hundreds of years in the past. She’s now somewhere in the past, when the planet was uninhabited. They reactivate the portal, and get her back… but 10 years too late. She’s now 18, and is a wild child. She bites O’Brien before she’s sedated. She’s VERY unga bunga. Now they need to re-integrate her into society, and good luck with that,.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the B-plot is that Worf needs to baby sit Yoshi, and he is VERY bad with kids. At least the A and B plots fit. It’s also a fun concept.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4fCwdwq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode then becomes Keiko and O’Brien trying to rehabilitate Molly, who seems to have repressed all her childhood memories and remembers nothing. It’s actually REALLY heartwarming and sweet to watch, tinged, with some sadness.</p>

<p>Eventually she becomes a little unstable. She’s improving, but she wants to go “home”. They take her home, but no, not THAT home. HOME. They can’t go back to the planet though, so they take her to the holosuite. But they can’t keep her there forever, and when other customers want it, Molly goes…. feral, and freaks out, and then runs through the bar and STABS A MAN IN THE STOMACH WITH A BROKEN BOTTLE. Oh. Oh that’s very bad. The man presses charges and wants her incacerated, because she’s dangerous. I mean, she kind of is… it’s a very unfortunate situation. She needs wide open spaces, but they can’t really give her that on the station. And they’re going to send her to a therapy center, which is PROBABLY not going to be good for her either. And imagine her being on a transport for a few days.</p>

<p>So what are they going to do? Time for O’Brien to do crimes.</p>

<p>They kidnap Molly and drag her, sedated, back to the planet. She’s not safe there, she’s not really safe anywhere… so they try to steal a runabout, and are caught. Odo’s like “Come on Chief, I thought if ANYONE could steal a runabout without getting caught, it’d be you. On your way”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oABXZlr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They send Molly back through the portal, planning to destroy it after. It’s a tearful goodbye, but Molly goes through, to his home… and then finds out she’s been transported not to her time, but to the exact time she went through the first time, finding herself as a 7 year old. She sends her back through, and fades away due to temporal shenanigans.</p>

<p>Well, that KINDA negates the gut punch. That’s a real shame. Like, I liked everything about this episode, it was cute and heartrending, and then it meant nothing! Hmmrf. Good, but didn’t hit the landing.</p>

<p><strong>The Sound of Her Voice</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4HcpJvs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On the way home from a long tiring mission, the Defiant gets a distress call from a woman who’s apparently a star fleet officer asking for help. They head over to help her. They can’t get any messages back through the planet, and O’Brien is on the case. He leaves her SOS message on as she rambles, basically. She’s just rambling about her life, because she has no one to talk to and is scared she’s going to die. Everyone is like “why are you doing that”. And he’s like “I dunno, it just feels right, like someone HAS to listen, otherwise she’s falling on deaf ears, and that’s sad”</p>

<p>Also the B-plot is Quark is distracting Odo by reminding him of his love for Kira in order to do illegal stuff, and Jake is researching him. It doesn’t fit.</p>

<p>Anyways they connect and can communicate with her now. She’s a captain who was returning to the Alpha Quadrant after an 8 year exploration of the Beta Quadrant. She’s the only one in her squad left, and she’s dying on an L-Class planet, so they’d better get there fast, but they keep her company. Most of the crew find her boring as fuck. Especially Bashir. She tortures him for ignoring him by pretending that something got her and ate her. It wakes him up and makes him realize he was being shitty. She’s his patient.</p>

<p>It’s kinda interesting seeing this. Everyone talks to her in a different way. O’Brien practically uses her as a friend and therapist. She tries to give advise to Sisko. And she and Bashir jab at each other. But things take a bad turn; the medicine she’s using runs out faster than expected, as her last dose was tainted. She’ll die in two days of CO2 poisoning. And they’re still 3 days away.</p>

<p>The b-plot ends in a cute way. Quark gets outplayed by Odo, who hears Quark like “and after I helped him with with Kira, tsk tsk”, and Odo decides to… let him have one. JUST this one. It’s cute. Odo’s been pretty good these episodes, he’s really grown as a person.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HvaIkGS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tried taking a picture and caught this picture instead that looks like Sisko just heard someone on the bridge make a racist joke</p>

<p>They have to risk their lives in a few ways to make it in time, but they do it, to save her life.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lxajUtY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways they go, and find out she’s been dead for years. The anomaly that they had to get through caused her SOS to go forward in time. They couldn’t have EVER made it in time. She had no chance ):</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sW6ycOK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They couldn’t save her, but they have a funeral for her, because over those six days, she had become a friend. And not only that, but she taught them all that they needed to talk, that they were holding things inside. It’s really touching. A very good scene. And a good episode! The Quark B plot was alright but mostly unrelated and didn’t fit in, but it ended quite nicely.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 67</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/05/OOCY67.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 67" /><published>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/05/OOCY67</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/05/OOCY67.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hisVuNe.png" alt="&quot;Hello! Right now I am playing basketball. Basketball is a sport where you try to put a hard ball that hurts when it hits you into a net.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Subtraction Tautology</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Subtraction Tautology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 127 - Final Fantasy 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/05/RA127-FF5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 127 - Final Fantasy 5" /><published>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/05/RA127-FF5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/05/RA127-FF5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P7X5pt9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I played all the NES FF games recently, and decided to keep it going with some SNES, but after playing FF3, I decided I wanted to play FF5 next. This game is basically the sequel to FF3 in many ways, and also, I’d played it once before, but never beaten it. And I remember ABSOLUTELY loving it. I had played the GBA version though, and this is the original SNES version. Which isn’t too different, tbh, it just has a few less bonus features. But how does it hold up? Is it as good as I remember it?</p>

<p>Final Fantasy 3 is, in my opinion, the best Final Fantasy game. In terms of its mechanics, that is. FF6 still wins out over all, though if you told me FF5 is your favorite, I’d go “that is 100% fair”. FF5 builds on what FF3 does in such a way that ESSENTIALLY perfects it. I have a single problem with the game and it’s not even really a problem. I’ll get into it.</p>

<p>Let’s start with one of the things people tends to complain about with this game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nZIElFz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, the story. FF5 is nestled between FF4 and FF6, which have large complex stories with lots of characters. FF5 has four characters, and then you swap one of those out for another later down the way. That’s it. And the story isn’t some major political intrigue with FF6 or a game with major twists about the characters like FF4. Like I said in FF3, it seems that even FF games are story-based, and odd ones are mechanics based. And yeah, this story is simple. An evil force is trying to break the four crystals to free himself. But I think people who say the story is simple and boring are frankly, wrong. This story DOES have twists, and it has a LOT of fantastic moments. A FF game that suddenly has a surprise second world map isn’t anything new, but this has THREE.</p>

<p>And of course, the Galuf Fighting Exdeath scene is, frankly, one of the best scenes in all of Final Fantasy. I felt EXTREMELY invested watching that scene, which is more than you’d expect from a “childish” story, as people say. It’s not FF6 or Chrono Trigger, sure, but all the characters are likable and interesting (Lenna is maybe the least, but hey, it’s fun to make fun of the fact that she poisons herself like four times), the plot is good enough, and the writing is goofy and fun. FF2, 4, and 6 are kinda serious games. FF1, 3, and 5 are a little goofy. And it’s goofy in a GOOD way. That’s not to say EVERYTHING lands, but I like the story. It also has a lot of themes about old generations and new generations coming along to fix the pasts’ mistakes, and that’s a theme that I like.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ypGDh71.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Now for the best part of the game: The mechanics. FF5, like FF3, is a job system. You have characters, who are Freelancers to start, who can swap to different jobs, after unlocking those jobs from the crystals you find. These jobs have their own levels you can gain and their own EXP, on top of your normal levels and EXP. This unlocks new abilities you can slot into your ability slot, but notably, you can ALSO slot those abilities in for OTHER jobs too. So for example, get enough levels in Thief, you gain the steal ability. Now when you swap over to Dragoon, you can also slot in Steal, so your Dragoon can steal as well!</p>

<p>The jobs are balanced by the fact that most of them are fucking busted. A lot of them have VERY strong abilities you can use. Time magic, for example, has a spell that just lets you use two actions in a turn. Nuts. And dual wield + X-Factor is SO powerful that they literally made it Bartz’s super finisher in the Final Fantasy fighting series. So yeah, a lot of things are busted. But not everything is busted, sadly, and some jobs, like Dragoon or Berserker fall by the wayside. At least Red Mage KINDA has a chance to shine… kinda. Red Mage sucks-ass, but if you get 999 job points, you get dual cast, which you immediately put on someone OTHER than Red Mage, because by that point not having tier 3 magic bloooows.</p>

<p>I essentially cannot sing the praises of FF5 enough, but if there was one thing that bugged me…. So, in FF2, when characters died, they were put in the back. That was a fiddly thing I kept forgetting. In FF3, when back attacks happened and I had to swap rows, it didn’t automatically swap them back, so that was a thing I kept forgetting. The tradition continues here, too. This game’s Fiddly Nonsense I Kept Forgetting was the auto-equip system. In FF3, you had to manually unequip everything to change jobs. That was annoying. Luckily this game has an auto-equip feature that chooses the best equipment! Good! Unfortunately, it only cares about stats. So if you say, have the Bone Mail, which has KILLER stats but turns you undead, and then forget to take it off… Oh hey, Faris is low on health, let’s cast cure and- oh she’s dead.</p>

<p>This gets worse if and when you have cursed equipment. I ended up getting so fed up I ritualistically killed the equipment (and by that I mean, sold it)</p>

<p>But other than that, I seriously have no complaints. This is one of the best RPGs I’ve ever played, extremely fun, and highly worth your time if you haven’t played it. Unfortunately it’s pretty forgotten these days, and never got its due here in the west, since it took until the GBA era to come out here.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 66</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/04/OOCY66.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 66" /><published>2024-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/04/OOCY66</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/04/OOCY66.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/riPCwhP.png" alt="&quot;Whether I think of her as a friend or my wife, I love her. I love her more than anything else...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>