<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-08T00:14:37-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 1 - 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekEnt1-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 1 - 5" /><published>2025-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekEnt1-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekEnt1-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>STARTING ENTERPRISE NOW! I know NOTHING about this, other than it takes place very early in the timeline, has a guy named ARcher and a guy named Phlox, people smother gel on each other naked a lot, and a lot of people get a lot of opinions.</p>

<p><strong>Broken Bow</strong> - SNW
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vgoPgE9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with a kid being racist towards Vulcans, complaining that if the Vulcans were actually helping them, they’d be going at Warp 5 by now. We then jump cut 30 years later, and it’s now the opening of Star Trek. Some aliens drop down, a Klingon blows them up, and then a farmer blows him away with a blaster shotgun.</p>

<p>Then we get the opening theme song. If you were wondering, this is was my watch club’s reaction to it:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6ZMdhOd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So apparently the plan for Enterprise was that Voyager’s rating were falling by the end, so they’re trying to make a new kind of Star Trek. Something Modern. By modern, we mean dated as fuck, and kind of boring, I guess? Also the CGI is very, VERY dated too.</p>

<p>Anyways, the Vulcans are here. The Klingons are upset a Klingon got shot. He’s still alive, but the Vulcans are ready to just kill him. Their logic is nonsense. Then we’re introducd to our ‘hero’.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/c9gbUUj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Captain Archer’s ship is ready to be launched, but the Vulcans are like “Don’t launch yet and go out and meet other people in space, you’re not ready”. They’re all kind of dicks about it. Whoever wrote this doesn’t know how to write Vulcans. A Vulcan woman tries telling him to wait until he’s ready, and he threatens to beat her. Captain “Would beat a woman” Archer. The Earth Admiral is like “alright fuck these guys, we’re launching after all”.</p>

<p>We then get scenes of all the crew. It’s kinda hard to tell who is and is not important in these scnees, but I’ll try and explain them all. We’ve got Archer, he’s kinda smug and I’m not sure how much I like him so far. Then Phlox, the doctor working on the Klingon who seems like a friendly guy, Reed, the Armory Officer. I can’t tell what his deal is. Mayweather, the resident Black Guy. We’ll see how he is. So far he seems young and friendly. He’s also really horny for aliens. Sato, a Linguist who’s really excited to learn Klingon, she’s kinda cool so far. Tucker, the Engineer, who’s kinda belligerent and rude. He yells a lot. I cannot tell Tucker or Reed apart.</p>

<p>And then we meet T’Pol.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0rhsVB0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s assigned to the ship, the Enterprise, by their Vulcan superiors. No one is happy about this. When she entered in, I was like “is Archer gonna be racist in this?” and then he opened his fucking mouth, and yes, he is. AND Sexist! I think the idea is that he’s annoyed at the Vulcans cause of history and personal things, and the idea is that we’ll eventually grow as people and our cultures and civilizations will grow closer. That’s the idea. But it’s not pleasant to watch the start of that!!</p>

<p>We also get a scene where an alien talks to the Emperor from Star Wars about the Klingon being takne by the Humans. This guy’s alien species then comes and steals the Klingon away. The alien’s species is the… Suliban. Which is inspired by the Taliban. Yeah. <em>sigh</em>. The Suliban is genetically enhanced, which is strange for their species. T’Pol tries to tell them to go back home. She’s told to shut up. They go to the last known place the Klingon, Klaang, was known to be. A planet called Rigel. Everyone is pretty much immediately kidnapped. T’Pol gives a “told you so” look. Alright.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episode 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episode 6" /><published>2025-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekSNW3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Through the Lens of Time</strong> - SNW
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N8mQara.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This season is going really hard on the romance drama, which is starting to get mostly tiring for me. But it’s ALSO pushing this new nurse guy, Dana. He’s SO excited and happy to be here. This guy is SO fucking dead. He’s got the voice over and it’s really pushing him, he’s so fucked. It also seems like he was brought in secretly as a third wheel so that thigns aren’t TOO awkward between Spock and Korby as they do some kind of dig.</p>

<p>Ortegas’ brother is also here! He’s recording stuff for a documentary, it seems, and is also invited to this mission, which SEEMS to be an archaeological dig on a sacred site. He’s also getting romance vibes with Uhura. They’re really trying to hook EVERYONE up this season aren’t they? Though Pelia the Warpcore Witch also seems to be real into him. And I like that, cause it’s funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5JfYBa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They all enter some kind of temple, after Chapel does some kind of thing to gain entry. They IMMEDIATELY find corpses and Spock is like “okay, protocol tells is we need to leave now”. Korby gets pissy and refuses, and Chapel, who’s in charge of the mission, sides with him cause he’s her girlfriend. There’s also a lot of tension cause of the whole Spock x Chapel thing. See, this is why everyone shouldn’t just fuck. Use the holodeck to fuck- wait. We already had an episode about how that’s a bad idea at this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ypNSSmn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>New Kid, who’s name is Gamble, acts like a TOS red shirt and randomly touches shit. Anyways, woah, New Kid gets his fucking eyes exploded cause things are actually super dangerous in here! Looks like Spock was right, what a mother fucking shock! The native living with them sees something else, freaks the fuck out, and tries to run away, and is vaporized. But we have so many things we could learn here!!! Korby was ABSOLUTELY going to just fucking die because he wasn’t being careful enough if others didn’t die before him, frankly. Why was he SO SURE that he had to do this dig RIGHT THE FUCK NOW? “I’ve waited all my life for this!” Yeah dude, but you’re like, 33. This temple isn’t going anywhere. Put down that fucking idiot ball, right now, mister!</p>

<p>They get split up, as if it couldnt’ get any worse, and are in different rooms, but able to communicate. This now turns into a split room puzzle game escape room. Seems to be the same room but also not, seperate dimensions. They can still communicate though. Why? I dunno, bad writing?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x4jYCCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Eyeball Regenerator, which apparently exists, is not working. New Kid’s brain is also registering as braindead. New episode name: Gamble’s Brain. Gamble is also acting Kinda Sus now. Hmm.</p>

<p>Ten minutes ago, Gamble’s eyes exploded. Now, Spock is saying how Korby is not being safe enough and not taking any precautions, and then he TAKES A FUCKING VISOR OFF OF A DEAD ALIEN AND PUTS IT ON HIS EYEBALLS AND USES IT TO LOOK AT THINGS. WHAT THE FUCK, SPOCK? I’m starting to think this episode might just not be well written.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLyV7Ze.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel, who I remind you is now half Gorn, meets Gamble, and starts speaking in tongues. Gamble does the same, and they proceed to beat the shit out of each other. Gamble also murders someone in the scuffle. After he’s captured, he just breaks through the force fields and kills more red shirts. Damn, this episode has a body count.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hp0x8tF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Pelia shoots Gamble in the back, releasing the ancient dimensional alien inside of him. Scotty then captures it in a Pokeball and tosses it up into the transporter. He locks it in the transport buffer, until they can figure out what to do with it. There’s no WAY that’ll backfire!!!</p>

<p>Pelia has a big discussion about ancient evil, which turns out to be her mugging for the documentary. Okay, that was funny. I was like “wow that’s very on the nose- oh okay, that’s good”. I do like Pelia. As M’Benga calls Gamble’s parents to tell them about their son, the Enterprise computer screens flash alien text. Wow, I knew it’d backfire but THAT fast.</p>

<p>I think my judgement of this will depend on if and when it goes anywhere, but I feel it was poorly written. Something was off and the pacing was bad.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 180</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/04/OOCY180.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 180" /><published>2025-09-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/04/OOCY180</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/04/OOCY180.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FdKvpAg.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KkfHLOf.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class’s Green Tea Bitch</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class&apos;s Green Tea Bitch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 179</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 179" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UYb48Ag.png" alt="Out of context yuri, panels are from 'Keeping a Jewel' by Sachi Miyabe. Two women are on a bed, looking at each other, with a soft filter effect going on. Their hands are almost touching. One thinks, as she looks longingly into the other, 'I'm sure the reason my heart races even though she's a girl is because I have social anxiety...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Sorry for no yuri in a bit, got distracted</p>

<p>source: Keeping a Jewel</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Keeping a Jewel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 203 - Link’s Awakening DX</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 203 - Link’s Awakening DX" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TMF9nVH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I apparently never moved my Link’s Awakening review over here. God, what do I say about Link’s Awakening? Well, it’s my all time favorite  Zelda game, which means it’s one of my favorite games ever. I replay it once every few years. I own like six copies for some reason. It’s utter Zelda perfection.</p>

<p>Coming out in the middle of the Gameboy’s life-cycle, it got a port to the Gameboy Color six years later. It’s pretty similar, with only a few minor changes, and is more of the same. I mastered the original last year, and put this one off cause some of the challenges annoyed me.</p>

<p>This set has a lot of missables. No hit challenges, don’t do this in this order, etc etc. I actually had to play this game through twice to do this because it glitched out. If you kill like 80 enemies in a row or something (I was trying to farm for acorns, forgetting how that worked) it will change your tunic color, and might glitch out other things. It gave me a photograph and I couldn’t get the achievement for getting that photograph later. Oops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8hZucB7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Link’s Awakening started as a remake of LTTP, but I’m so glad it became this in the end. It’s a weird, unique Zelda game. Lots of things that are just… It. And the story! Oh man. I think it’s fitting that my two favorite  Zeldas are Majora’s Mask and this, the two games with the most melancholy and sad stories.</p>

<p>I don’t think I need to go into a full deep dive of Link’s Awakening. All I need to tell you is that it’s fantastic, and this is a good version. Not DEFINITIVE. It adds an additional dungeon, which is an okay dungeon, and the photos system, which is cute.</p>

<p>If you’ve never played Link’s Awakening, I highly recommend it. It’s not too long compared to other Zelda games, but it’s a solid thing for a Gameboy title. Do yourself a favor and check it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Zelda" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Musical Transients - Review and analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/27/MusicalTransients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Musical Transients - Review and analysis" /><published>2025-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/27/MusicalTransients</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/27/MusicalTransients.html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MAW84RRNw84?si=bgv44V_IhUrtScs2" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>I don’t usually review music. Music is one of those things that’s hard to recommend or review on the internet. When you try to share music, I find people are very likely to just turn their brains off and ignore your suggestions. I’m not sure why this is, but I think it’s cause everyone has specific musical tastes, just to them. Everyone but me, I guess. I love all kinds of music. Every genre, I can find something in it I like. But you know what I ESPECIALLY love? Mashup albums.</p>

<p>At AGDQ2025, my girlfriend asked me if I’d heard of Musical Transients before. She knows I love mashup albums. I had not, so we went back to our room and she showed it to me. Now, that was actually my Nap Time. I would sleep for like an hour or two, because I had to be awake until 5AM. But I’d put this album on, listen to a bit, and fall asleep to it. I do it all the time. That did not happen. I put it on, and it was so interesting, I listened to all of it, then researched the meanings of the songs. I did not take a nap that day, and I was STRUGGLING at 4AM.</p>

<p>Since then I’ve probably listened to the album 100 times. I’m not joking. This is one of my favorite albums of all time now. It’s art.</p>

<p>Musical Transients is made by Psynwave, a British musician and mashup artist who made another album a few years ago, Musical Tangents. Now, I do like Musical Tangents, but not as much. That doesn’t matter much, though. Musical Tangents was advertised as having no real theme or anything, it’s a collection of mashups. Good, well constructed mashups, with the idea of taking the original songs, and completing twisting their meanings and vibes. But still, no meaning. Musical Transients, the follow up album, was advertised the same way.</p>

<p>When I show people Musical Transients, which I do often, I tell them it has no theme for a few songs, before admitting, actually, there’s a VERY central theme to the album. Can you guess what it is? Most people can guess it by the end. I guessed it immediately, but I cheated.</p>

<p>IF YOU’RE INTERESTED IN THIS ALBUM, DO NOT READ AHEAD. This is both a review and a full total analysis of the ENTIRE album. This album is very, very dense with meaning, and I want to take it apart right in front of you. If you’re interested, watch the album, then come back to me. Yes, watch. The album has a lot of fun things in the video, and the video also has subtitles for the songs, which are very useful. Okay, we good? Let’s go.</p>

<p><strong>I BELIEVE IN THE GREEN PARADE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BdAyctj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The album starts with a song called “I Believe in the Green Parade”. It’s a mashup of Black Parade and Rainbow Connection. This album is the opening thesis of the album. It sets the theme and asks a question, basically. But it also feels slightly disconnected to the rest of the album to me. This album is a story of someone’s life, but this album is setting the tone, and is this person basically looking back. It was also designed around a meme post on Twitter from years ago that went “When Black Parade talks about the broken and the beaten and Kermit talks about the lovers and the dreamers, they’re talking about the same people”. It’s a funny post. Why not make a song about it?</p>

<p>After a bit of simple mashupping, where we get the banjo with the lyrics, it bursts into Black Parade’s backing track, and some muppet Show shenanigans. And then we get this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3k8OsSY.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WxOEN4j.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I want you to read these lyrics.</p>

<p>ITs time to put on makeup, it’s time to dress up right. It’s time to raise the curtain on the muppet show tonight.</p>

<p>And then I saw her face, now I’m a believer. Not a trace of doubt in my mind. I’m in love, I’m a believer, I couldn’t leave her, if I tried.</p>

<p>And I don’t really care if no one else believes.</p>

<p>So she said, what’s the problem baby? What’s the problem, I dunno, well maybe I’m in love, love, think about it, everytime I think about it, maybe I’m in love with <em>your body</em>. How much longer will it take to cure this? Just to cure it cause I can’t ignore it if it’s love, love, think about it, maybe I’m in love <em>with the shape of you</em></p>

<p>This sets up the thesis of the album. What’s this album about? Like I said, I cheated. And I mean, come on. The album is called Musical Transients and the cover is in the trans pride flag colors. This is a song about gender discovery, and being a trans woman. This song sets it up pretty well. It shows that the feelings are there, like with the first line about putting on makeup, moving into “and then I saw her face”. Then it makes it clear, “I don’t care if anyone else believes”. This will be a happy story with a happy end. Then the last line, they change the lyrics a bit. “Maybe I’m in love <em>with your body</em>” and “<em>the shape of you</em>”. Not you. Just the shape of your body. I love the feminine body. I sure do wish I had it. Can’t stop thinking about it.</p>

<p>This WILL be a story with a happy end, though it might take a bit to get there, as shown by the next few lines. Black Parade comes back in, with:</p>

<p>“On and on we carry through the fears. Disappointed faces of our peers”</p>

<p>“Another turning point, a fork stuck in the road”, cue the rest of Time of Your Life. Followed immediately by…</p>

<p>“This is my fight! Take back my life! Prove I’m alright!”</p>

<p>Being trans in this world is a dangerous thing. Literally dangerous in many cases. Outsiders will judge and hate you for the rest of your life. It’s a turning point, do we ignore this call, or do we go through with it? The song makes it quite clear: This is YOUR life. Take it back. Don’t let others control what and who you are, through their personal fears and delusions. Be who you want to be.</p>

<p>It ends with one more “I don’t relaly care if nobody else believes in me”, with a fade out of the Rainbow Connection. It’s an uplifting song, and a good thesis statement to the entire album.</p>

<p><strong>I WANNA BE A ROCK</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tnn0g3m.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The rest of the album is a story. Its the story of our narrator as they go through their life. It starts with them, as a young boy. This song is a combination of a lot of hard scrabbled masculine songs, rip snortin’ masculine songs. We’ve got We Will Rock You, with the Ramones Blitzkrieg Bop, and then Kenny Loggins comes in with Danger Zone, and finally Nickelback’s Rockstar. A lot of masculine manly man songs. But when Nickelback’s Rockstar gets to the chorus, it’s not “I wanna be a Rockstar”, it comically cuts off with “I wanna be a rock”, as the other character in the song goes “….what??”</p>

<p>I think this song has multiple interpretations. I’ve heard someone say that wanting to be a rock is gender identity, a gender neutral “I don’t wanna be a man like you all think I should be, I’ll be gender neutral, like this rock”, but I don’t think so. I think rocks are manly. That’s a weird thing to say, but like, it’s tough and course, LIKE A MAN. It’s stupid, and intentionally so, IMO. It’s a joke. It’s one big giant joke about masculinity and toxic masculinity.</p>

<p>There’s also one other thing. Rockstar’s lyrics are SLIGHTLY changed elsewhere too. The original lyric is “I’m gonna cut my hair and change my name”. It’s now “I’m gonna <em>grow</em> my hair and change my name”. Ha ha, wouldn’t it be REALLY funny if I grew my hair out? Like, as a joke? This is a very real early gender thing, to me.</p>

<p>Anyways this continues for a while until…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/D7V00GW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>These manly man songs are interrupted by t.A.T.u.’s All The Things She Said. Which is maybe one of the most feminine centric songs I can think of. And even when the masculine songs begin to break back in, with the drum line, and then lyrics, t.A.T.u. is still there, in the background. It won’t go away, ever again. It keeps breaking through, always reminding you of that inkling at the back of your brain. And even now, the lyrics to the other songs are changed slightly.</p>

<p>“I wanna be a-“ with static, and a face behind the static. That don’t look like a rock. Or even a man’s face. Hmm, what could that be?</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z4nA3K7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This song starts with one of the best parts on the album. Lizzo’s Truth Hurts is basically unchanged. “I just took a DNA test, turns out, I’m- <strong><em>AUTISTIC</em></strong>”, with the song suddenly being interrupted by Live and Learn from Sonic Adventure 2. The artist said they were scared about putting in this joke, that it’d offend people, but are you kidding? Autistic people love Sonic. So do trans people. Autistic trans people go FERAL for Sonic.</p>

<p>This song uses Live and Learn’s backing track, with some songs over the mix, namely Green Day’s Basket Case. This album has a lot of Green Day. It also has a section right at the start, with the Avalanche’s Frontier Psychiatrist, where they say, plainly, “That boy needs therapy!”</p>

<p>This song is a therapy session. Our protagonist is at the therapist, discussing the things they’ve been hyper focusing on.</p>

<p>“Do you have the time to listen to me whine? About nothing, and everything all at once. I am one of those melodramatic fools, neurotic to the bone, no doubt about it. Sometimes I give myself the creeps. Sometimes my mind plays tricks on me. It all keeps adding up. I think I’m cracking up. Sometimes <strong>I wanna throw it all away</strong>.”</p>

<p>People with Gender Dysphoria USUALLY fear ever acting on those feelings, because society tells us it’s creepy. They’re just tricking themselves into thinking they’re a girl, anyway. They’re cracking up. Like an egg, perhaps! And then the final line is Goldfinger’s Superman, throwing in that this is all so much, it might genuinely end with self harm. This is not an easy transition to go through.</p>

<p>Then we get the chorus. Live and Learn is replaced with the very comical:</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“Always something there to remind me”</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“Cause you’re amazing, I can’t believe it”</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“I really don’t think I’m strong enough, no”</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“It’ll never be enough for me.”</p>

<p>This is our protagonist reacting to the idea that they could possibly be trans. They can’t go through with it. How could they? They’d always be reminded they’re not a “real” woman. They’re amazed by other trans women, that they could do this, but not them. They’re not strong enough. All the procedures and estrogen in the world wouldn’t be enough, they’d know what they “really” are.</p>

<p>The song continues like this for a bit, though there are a few changed lyrics. “She says my lack of sex is bringing me down” changes to “She says my <strong>sex</strong> is bringing me down”. Our protagonist gets diagnosed with gender dysphoria. But it’s not like they could really go through with this… right?</p>

<p>I’m not 100% sure what LIVE LAUGH LOVE means. Like, I know it’s a painfully optimistic phrase that helps nothing. I think that’s the idea here, that people are supplying our protagonist with platitudes that do nothing, while they have to struggle through this, practically alone, and take a giant lunge. But eventually, they do. Cue more Goldfinger.</p>

<p>“So here I am, doing everything I can, holding on to what I am, pretending I’m <strong>a man</strong>.”</p>

<p>“Danger, look behind you, there’s a stranger out to find you”.</p>

<p>The protagonist admits they’re a trans woman, but they can’t be out about it. After all, if you’re trans, there are people in this world who are practically HUNTING you. Always keeping an eye out, strangers, out to find you. Duck Tale’s “Whoo hoo!” is interspersed in the mix, more parts of the song where the vibe seems to not fit the actual theme and message of the song. On purpose, mind. This album is FANTASTIC at taking the original meanings of songs and twisting them on their heads. The next song, IMO, is the best at that.</p>

<p><strong>SHRIMPING POOL</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6IVYv6c.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If someone did not get the meaning of the album yet, if they’re paying attention, this is about where they usually get it. This song has a Katamari Damacy backing track, Lonely Rolling Star specifically, with the Kero Kero Bonito Song comically asking the question:</p>

<p>“How many shrimps do you have to eat, before you make your skin turn pinl? Eat too much and you’ll get sick, shrimps are pretty rich.”</p>

<p>Then we get Eiffel 65 bursting in with “Blue”, which is mostly unchanged. Yo listen up, here’s the story. He’s a blue guy, living in a blue world. etc etc. We then get one of my favorite parts of the album: Kendrick Lamar’s Swimming Pools, mixed up with Drowning Pool’s Bodies.</p>

<p>“Pour up” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Head shot” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Sit down” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Stand up” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Pass out” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Wake up” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Faded” “NOTHING WRONG WITH ME”
“Faded” “NOTHING WRONG WITH ME”</p>

<p>This turns the meanings of both songs on their heads, ESPECIALLY Drowning. What was once a song about an insane man refusing to accept it, here it’s a personal screed. Every day, they go about their life. It’s exhausting. This blue life, with these blue corvette, is exhausting. They’re faded. And all the time, inside, they know, these feelings they have? There’s nothing actually wrong with them. No matter what society says, there’s NOTHING wrong with them.</p>

<p>Then we get the chorus. Kendrick Lamar comes in with:</p>

<p>“Then somebody said, why you babysittin’ only two or three <em>shrimp</em>? I’mma show you got to turn it up an inch. First you get a swimming pool fool of <em>shrimp</em>, then you dive in it. pool full of <em>shrimp</em>, then you dive in it.”</p>

<p>This, alongside the question of “how many shrimp do you have to eat before it makes you skin turn pink”, tells you what shrimp is. It’s a metaphor for estrogen. This is a song about our protagonist getting on HRT for the first time. They’re alone and trying to go through it alone, in this blue world, but there’s a promise of pink in the future. And there are people out there willing to help him. Later additions to the chorus include:</p>

<p>“All the girls wanna play baywatch”</p>

<p>The girls in this case are other trans women, who know correctly how to dose HRT, probably more than any fucking doctor, let’s be real, and are willing to help younger trans women with advice. They’re watching the pool, so people can swim responsibly.</p>

<p>In the end, the song makes it clear.</p>

<p>“Yo listen up, here’s the story. About a little guy who lives in a blue world. <strong>CAN’T TAKE MUCH MORE</strong>. And all day, and all night, and all he wants to do is <em>turn pink</em>.</p>

<p>Our hero takes the plunge. On the advice, our protagonist begins taking shrimp.</p>

<p>I REALLY love how this song twists every single song on its head. It makes Flamingo and Blue actually HAVE meanings, Bodies is about self affirmation instead of insanity, and Swimming Pools, a song about public pressure and societal alcoholism, is now about responsibly teaching others how to take care of themselves through medical substances. It’s nuts.</p>

<p>The song also ends with Jimmy Eat World’s “The Middle” which is one of the most trans songs ever made.</p>

<p><strong>FACTS AND LODGING</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GnZjLYa.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is the down point of the entire album. And it’s very, VERY heavy. The first time I heard it, I had to pause the song and stare at the wall for a second. It was nuts.</p>

<p>This is a combination of two Gorillaz songs, 19-2000 and Clint Eastwood, alongside Flobot’s Handlebars, with The Eagles’ Hotel California in the background. Most people have heard Handlebars’ first line, but not the later lines. The song goes places, so I knew it’d get… dark.</p>

<p>“The world is spinning too fast, I’m buying lead nike shoes. To keep myself tethered to the days I’ve tried to lose”</p>

<p>These Gorillaz lyrics makes it clear what the song is about. The news, the world, and society is… a lot. It’s exhausting. You need to try and keep yourself tethered.</p>

<p>We also get Supertramp’s The Logical Song hitting in with our protagonist’s internal dialogue.</p>

<p>“When I was young, it seemed that life was so wonderful
Oh, it was beautiful, magical
And all the birds in the trees, well, they’d be singing so happily
Oh, playfully watching me
But then they sent me away to teach me how to be sensible
Oh, responsible, practical
And then they showed me a world where I could be so dependable
Oh, intellectual, cynical”</p>

<p>Things used to be better when we were kids. Not cause they WERE better, but we could ignore them. Now it’s impossible to ignore them. Especially when you’re the target now, to a lot of society. There’s also this part I like a lot, where it jumps between Clint Eastwood and Handlebars in a way that makes it feel like these lyrics were designed to go together.</p>

<p>“Allow me to make this childlike in nature
I can ride my bike with no handlebars
Rhythm, you have it or you don’t; that’s a fallacy
I can keep rhythm with no metronome
Y’all can’t see me now ‘cause you don’t see with your eye
I can see your face on the telephone
Intangible, bet you didn’t think so I command you to
‘Cause I can lead a nation with a microphone”</p>

<p>Eventually, Supertramps begs to ask, “Please tell me who I am”, as the rest of the song explodes around them. Handlebars reaches its end, “AND I CAN END THE PLANET IN A HOLOCAUST”, and Del the Funky Homosapiens says “I SEE THE DESTRUCTION AND DEMISE, CORRUPTION IN DISGUISE”. Supertramp cries out:</p>

<p>“I said, watch what you say, or they’ll be calling you a radical. A liberal. Oh, fanatical, criminal. Ooh, it’s getting unbelievable”.</p>

<p>The world is getting to be too much. WAY too much. We can’t live like this, we can’t live our lives while all this noise happens. So, suddenly, the song COMPLETELY changes. It turns into the theme from Balatro. The only way to escape the heaviness and exhaustion of the world is escapism, games and things. But even with that, the drums from Hotel California are in the background. You can check out anytime you like, but you can never leave.</p>

<p>This is a dark, and cynical, look on society, and how we can’t really escape it. There’s no positive message here. It’s just dark.</p>

<p><strong>PINK LION CLUB</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cQJh1cG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If the previous song is the down point of the album, this is where it lifts upwards again. I’ve heard a lot of interpretations on this song, but I’ve changed mine recently, thanks to suggestions by my friends on the meaning. This is a song that seems like it should be a downer. It’s Linkin Park’s Numb and Porter Robinson’s Lionhearted. Those are kinda darker songs. But they’re over the backing track of Pink Pony Club, and then as they’re going throguh with their darker lyrics, they’re interrupted by Lebo M’s He Lives in You.</p>

<p>“Wait
There’s no mountain too great
Hear the words and have faith
Havе faith
He lives in you
<em>We’ll be the lionhearted</em>
He lives in me
<em>For we don’t care about it</em>
He watches over
<em>We’ll finish what we started</em>
Everything we see
<em>So promise me that they’ll fall</em>
Into the water
<em>They broke the walls we guarded</em>
Into the truth
<em>But we don’t care about it</em>
In your reflection
<em>We’ll finish what we started</em>
He lives in you
<em>So promise me that</em>
<strong>I’ll be less like you”</strong></p>

<p>This is in contrast to the lyrics of Numb and Lionhearted. Numb is about losing faith in someone who wanted them to be a way, he can’t feel you. But Lebo M makes it clear: He’s still here. He watches over. He lives in you.</p>

<p>This song is about who we used to be, and who we will become. To a lot of trans women, they regret who they once were. They can’t feel the man they once were or might have been. But this song makes it clear. He’s still there. And that’s not a bad thing. It’s about reconnecting with yourself. You might have hated what you once were, but we can move on. After all, the man you once were is a lot like you now, with someone disappointed in you.</p>

<p>This is made clear with a break in the middle, with Bastille’s Pompei:</p>

<p>“But if you close your eyes
Does it almost feel like nothing changed at all?
And if you close your eyes
Does it almost feel like you’ve been here before?
<em>So promise me that</em>
<strong>I’m gonna be an optimist about this</strong>
<em>So promise me that</em>
<strong>I’m gonna be an optimist about this”</strong></p>

<p>A lot has changed. But also not much has changed. In spite of everything, it’s still you. Pompei’s lyrics are changed to, from “How am I gonna be an optimist about this” to “I’m gonna be an optimist about this”. Things will get better. They’ve already started.</p>

<p>This song is genuinely beautiful to me, and is my favorite on the album by far. Which means it’s probably one of my favorite songs of all time. I love this song to death.</p>

<p><strong>I’ve Had It With This Name</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y3nQkQT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The early songs are a little harder to get the theme of. The album is VERY blunt fron this point on. It’s not hiding <strong>anything</strong>.</p>

<p>This is a song about self discovery. Who are you, now? Literally, what are you changing your name to? But also, what are you, who are you, and what do you want to be?</p>

<p>There’s a lot of songs here, but the main one that matters is “Somebody Told Me” by The Killer. Lyrics are shifted and changed to say things like:</p>

<p>“Breakin’ my back just to know my name
Seven tracks and I’ve had it with this name (That’s not my name! That’s not my name!)”</p>

<p>This is the seventh track.</p>

<p>“‘Cause heaven ain’t close in a place like this
I said, oh, heaven ain’t close in a place like this”</p>

<p>Whoever our protagonist was before, that’s not who they want to be. That’s not heaven. They’ll find heaven their own way.</p>

<p>Other songs move in, like REM’s End of the World. The meanings are really clear, IMO, they’re basically the original song’s meanings, but then we get a great breakdown, with Radiohead’s Creep, Coldplay’s Fix You, and Keala’ Settle’s This is Me.</p>

<p>“When you try your best, but you don’t succeed
<em>I wish I was special</em>
When you get what you want, but not what you need
<em>I want a perfect body</em>
And the tears come streamin’ down your face
<em>I don’t belong here</em>
Could it be worse?
When the sharpest words wanna cut me down
<em>I don’t care if it hurts</em>
I’m gonna send a flood, gonna drown ‘em out
<em>I wanna have control</em>
But if you never try, you’ll never know
<em>What the hell am I doing here?</em>
Just what you’re worth
So tell me who are you?”</p>

<p>I’mma be real, if I didn’t know better, I’d say Creep is about a trans woman. Like, those fucking lyrics, holy hell. They’re not even changed.</p>

<p>The song ends the only way it could. With Slim Shady breaking in with “MY NAME IS-“ before getting cut off. We don’t need to know her name. We just know she’s decided who she is.</p>

<p><strong>FINALE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HsBsHsF.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Then we get the finale, which like the intro, is less a part of the story, and more outside it. A wrap up. It sets the stage and clears it up, with Gwen Stefani’s “Just a Girl”.</p>

<p>“Take this pink ribbon off my eyes
I’m exposed, and it’s no big surprise
Don’t you think I know exactly where I stand?
This world is forcing me to hold your hand
The moment that I step outside
So many reasons for me to run and hide
I can’t do the little things I hold so dear
‘Cause it’s all those little things that I fear”</p>

<p>Again, if I didn’t know better, I’d say that song is about being a trans woman. It’s uncanny.</p>

<p>The song goes through a bit of each song, as they’re all a part of our hero, and her journey. But we they come in, eventually, they’re all wiped away. What matters is the future, and what she is. We also get Gwen Stefani’s part replaced by a trans woman who covers it, quite fittingly.</p>

<p>At the very end of the song, the album is mocking you, asking you if you know the theme. Different parts from every song come in, starting with a part from THIS song, Hey Ya asking “You think you got it? Ooh, you think you got it?” It’s fucking MOCKING you. Those parts from the earlier songs move back in, repeating over and over, caucophinously, but they’re all wiped away by Gwen Stefani, making one thing clear:</p>

<p>“I’m just a girl”.</p>

<p>Then, after four repititions, it says:</p>

<p>“I’m just a girl. Can I make it any more obvious?”</p>

<p>Four more repitions, and the song ends, making it just the tiniest bit more obvious, with a scene from Celeste showing on the screen. Any more obvious, indeed.</p>

<p>So yeah, this album is fantastic. Essentially perfect, to me. A great look into gender identity and the journey to finding and being trans. This album made me feel gender euphoria. It made me feel the gender euphoria of coming out for the first time, which I haven’t felt for <strong>ten fucking years</strong>. I can never thank it enough for that. Please, please listen to it. Thanks for reading.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Music" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 178</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/24/OOCY178.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 178" /><published>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/24/OOCY178</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/24/OOCY178.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rKY83SY.png" alt="A page from 'Black and White'. One woman kabedon's another by putting her leg up over her and against the wall behind her. The other woman is sitting in a chair, looking kind of stunned." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Black and White</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="black and white" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 202 - Panic!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/24/RA202-Panic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 202 - Panic!" /><published>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/24/RA202-Panic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/24/RA202-Panic.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GVD2uv9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Panic!, also known as Switch in Japan, is one of the games that, to those in the know, is a MUST get for the Sega CD. It’s a cult classic that sold like shit at the time, and reviewed about as well. Developed by Sega, it was not released here by Sega. Instead, Data East did the work to translate it, which is interesting to me.</p>

<p>The story is that all machines on the planet are infected by a virus. They are all literally sick. They do random things, often just throwing up. A program, called “Panic!”, was designed to fix the situation and return things to normal. You play as Slap and his dog Stick, very fun names, who must travel to the center of the madness and turn on Panic!.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IHJUDag.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In order to do this, as you enter a room, you are met with what’s going on in that room, then shown some buttons. Each button does something different. Some transport you to other rooms, some do gags. Some do both!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XxGAkmn.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There are 20 levels in Panic, and most of the traveling moves you from right to left, looping around. The map balloons out in the middle, before going back into a point near the end. And that’s it! What, you might say? That’s it? Where’s the gameplay? Well that’s the thing. There isn’t any. This game is literally just… you press buttons, and watch things happen.</p>

<p>There are 964 gags, though you don’t NEARLY have to watch all of them, and in order to watch all of them you basically need to game over upwards of like, 7 times, due to the way the game works. You CAN game over. Either by just beating the game, or by going to the SKULL ROOMS where a member of your family tells you to stop playing games and bullies you, or by blowing up all the monuments. Some buttons are “booby trapped”, and you get to watch famous monuments blow up and collapse. Collapse em all and it’s game over, which you’d need to do to get 100% gags anyway. Also, exits are considered gags, and some are one way. So that throws complications in too.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TLj1oJg.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I worry I’m being reductive when I say “that’s all” to Panic. This is an EXTREMELY interesting, and fun, game. And there’s barely any game here. The humor and style is off the charts, the animation is quite good for the Sega CD, it’s smooth and flows well, and it’s very, VERY Terry Gilliam. You can tell that the devs of this LOVES Monty Python.</p>

<p>Occasionally you’ll also see scenes with these little creatures, and a voice over. The US voice over is kinda rough, but it’s not TERRIBLE. They didn’t really have to change that much, honestly. There’s even a Mega CD Bios room, which they didn’t change, at all, for the Sega CD version, even though the Sega CD Bios are NOTHING like that. There is a SINGLE room they changed, and by changed I mean literally just removed, and it was killed with kanji and would be hard to bring over here, so fair.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cxo3K3D.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Oh, one other thing I forgot to mention, the game’s sound effects are <strong>fucking fantastic</strong>. It’s literally just one dude making all the sounds with his mouth. Gun sounds? Mouth. Explosions? Mouth. Twisting moving things? Mouth. Zippy zaps? You better believe its mouth time.</p>

<p>There are so many fun and creative rooms here, and yes, not all the jokes or humor land. There’s a lot of vomit and grossy kinda stuff, but it’s for kids, who cares. A lot of it is REALLY fun, or cute, or clever. I think my favorite room is the Mona Lisa room, though there are other great contendors.</p>

<p>I don’t recommend 100%ing this game, but frankly, even if you do, it’s just 8 hours of watching funny animations. Pace yourself. Without that, it’s an hour or two and well worth your time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Panic" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 201 - Iron Helix</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 201 - Iron Helix" /><published>2025-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wF4by86.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This could double as an Obscure Games You Probably Haven’t Heard Of post. I’m a huge fan of Iron Helix, and have been for a long time, but it’s completely forgotten by this point. This game is extremely important, for a few reasons I’ll get into. But first, this is the second of the two Sega CD games I made sets for! I made one for Kids on Site, and this. Someone might have made a Kids on Site set without my help, but no one would have ever made this, and that’s a promise.</p>

<p>Iron Helix is an early 90s PC-ROM survival horror game by Drew Pictures and Spectrum HoloByte. It’s possibly one of the FIRST modern survival horror games. It’s no Sweet Home or anything, but it has a lot of that Survival Horror style. You’re exploring a dangerous place, alone, and being hunted by an impossible to overcome force, while trying to solve mysteries and find clues to what happened here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IjMTg5G.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Iron Helix starts with an intro that tells the story. Some Earth Force ships are doing military training on the edge of the neutral zone, essentially. But one of them, the Obrian (it’s gonnna be SO hard not to type O’Brien) suddenly veers off, losing control. It targets a peaceful neutral world of the other super power in the galaxy, the Thanatosians. We’re in a cold war with them, but this will make it run hot, and kill an entire planet of innocent civilians too. A message from the ship’s captain explains: They’ve been infected by an unknown virus that’s weakened their immune systems and changed their DNA. The ship’s AI Defender no longer recognizes them as Human, and assumes they’re invaders, killing them. Believing they’re at war, the ship goes to blow up some Thanatosians. Nothing can be donw.</p>

<p>Except… you’re the only ship in the sector! But you’re just a scientist, onboard the exploration ship Indiana. And it’s not like you can board the ship, you’ll get infected and killed too. You’re contacted by Earth’s Forces and asked to stop it, by sending drones into the ship, and blowing it up before it can reach the Thanatosians.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/92gXUmAWv24?si=U5ehhNHeqwmiuG39" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>I think it’s a rather compelling plot. Then you’re hit with the sickest fuckin’ title theme of the early 90s, and you begin. Choose your difficulty level and dive right in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xPMWjBU.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Iron Helix plays like you’re controlling a little drone through a computer screen, which you are. It’s clunky and awkward, because it would be. You move up and down the pathways of the ship, which you can see through surveillance maps that you’ve hacked into. You always know where the Defender is, though when you interract with things on the ship, it knows where you are too, and will hunt you down. You gotta dodge it by running through access tubes and running away, though you can also use battery life to jam the Defender and stun it for a time. The Sega CD version is quite clunky about this and slow paced, the PC version is much faster.</p>

<p>Your goal is split into chunks. First, collect DNA. The Humans were killed, but the ship responds to their DNA still, and not all of it has become changed. You can find hair follicles, chunks of skin, etc, all over the place. Scanning an area, you can release your access arm and pick up DNA, which will allow you through doors to deeper parts of the ship. Once you have all the DNA you need, usually by collecting the captain’s DNA, you can access everywhere, including the information terminals.</p>

<p>The Humans on the ship were trying to stop this before it began, but couldn’t. But they left breadcrumbs for you. They have access codes that they’ve set up to do different things, like blowing up the warp manifolds, or shutting down the Defender. You need to find a code for blowing up the ship, and a code for stopping the Defender, before proceeding. Then you shut down the Defender, then blow up the ship, in that order. Otherwise the Defender will just stop you. And once that’s done, you win!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dBUaPvC.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You can beat Iron Helix in like 9 minutes on this version. Way less than that on PC. If you know what you’re doing and where you’re going, it’s easy every time. Buuuut it’s not easy the first time. If you’ve been reading this review, you’re probably picturing the game in your head and going “woah that sounds sick as fuck???” and it is! On paper. But the Sega CD version is very flawed. The PC version shows you when DNA is nearby. The Sega CD version does not, you have to scan every single square of the ship. It’s also direction sensitive, so you need to check all four sides. It’s AWFUL.</p>

<p>And it’s not very replayable. Once you beat all three difficulties, that’s it. All the difficulties do is shift the DNA and codes around. The codes are different for each difficulty, too. In the first one there’s a code for just turning off the defender. But after that, you need to use yourself as bait to bait the Defender into the cargo bay, and then vent the whole thing into space.</p>

<p>Iron Helix is also built around an FMV base, which at the time was cutting edge, but is now MASSIVELY funny and outdated. You can barely make out these characters, the quality is so low. And their acting is Rather Rough. The best part is Commander Arbok though, your advisor, who after you succeed, rewards you with a job well done by… torturing you for information and killing you. Uh oh, we’re actually the bad guys.</p>

<p>Yes, there’s a hidden thread of information in Iron Helix. I’m telling you this because I doubt you will ever actually play it. You can find logs about destroying the ship, yes, but also ones about the Iron Helix, which is a secret weapon Earth is developing with the capacity to blow up entire planets. It’s highly dangerous, and highly illegal. So to keep their information a secret… they’ll need to silence you. It’s a downer ending! Yay!</p>

<p>Iron Helix is an extremely interesting game for the time, but all of its ideas will be done better down the road, and it’s pretty rough to play these days. I still love it though, it’s very special to me.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pzkFXilM4ls?si=M5tqcRRnh33VzRtO" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Before I forget though, here’s the PC installer for Iron Helix. Absolutely beautiful. It has a lot of charm to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Iron Helix" /><category term="Horror" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - JJ Trek Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - JJ Trek Movies" /><published>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>Note: This isn’t complete yet! We’re watching the first one for now. We’ll watch the others after a few Enterprise seasons.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Star Trek</strong> - 4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YHsmYFt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>As we discuss this movie, I want you to forget about it being a Trek movie. Don’t think of it as that. Think of it as JJ Abram’s demo reel for Star Wars, the thing he actually wanted to do.</p>

<p>We start with a ship in the middle of nowhere under attack. The captain is called to the enemy ship, which EASILY defeats them, and he gives command to his SO, a man named George Kirk. The captain is asked a few questions, where is Ambassador Spock, what is the stardate. And when he answers, he’s then impaled. Kirk then needs to stay on board, distracting the enemy ship as escape pods launch. We get a VERY drawn out scene of him sacrificing the ship as his wife gives birth on the escape pods. As George is about to die, he agrees to name him “Jim”. And then his ship explodes. Hell of a gender reveal party.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iaRqICf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1nd5ibe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then we get the scene made for the trailers. A young James T. Kirk steals his shitty abusive father’s car, as the Beastie Boys blasts out of the car. He’s chased by the cops and drives the car off of uh… whatever the fuck this thing is. The great gorge in the middle of Iowa. You know, what one. Then he says “MY NAME IS JAMES TIBERIUS KIRK.” End trailer! Boom!</p>

<p>On Vulcan, we see a young Spock getting bullied by some very unvulcan vulcans, and he’s beat up by them. He then gets in trouble with his dad for reacting to their bullying, as if them bullying isn’t the problem, it’s the fact that you reacted to it. I fucking HATE shit like this.</p>

<p>Time jump. We get Adult Spock. And if there’s one thing I can say about this movie, it has some AMAZING casting. My only major issue is that the Spock they get is VERY smirky. He’s in front of a board of ministers accepting him into the Vulcan Acadamy of Sciences. He ALSO applied to Starfleet, but they’re like “unneccesary” and deem it dumb to even conside going to Starfleet. Yeah cause Vulcans NEVER join Star Fleet???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oNKfx2w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Kirk being a very uh… “suave” little shithead? He meets Uhura and flirts with her cause of course he does. That alien in the middle should have been one of Morn’s species, tbh. Some Cadets beat the shit out of him for being a little shit, and then he’s saved by… CAPTAIN PIKE! He begs Kirk to enlist in Starfleet, and in 8 years he can captain his own ship. Pretty sure the enlisted don’t… do that. Aren’t they like, O’Brien?</p>

<p>That’s a major thing about this movie. If you peel back the layers and look at it under the hood, even for a fucking MINUTE, it’s stupid and makes no sense. Because JJ Abrahms doesn’t know anything about Star Trek and doesn’t care to make Science Fiction, just Science Fantasy. I could easily whine about shit like… George Kirk’s shitty little ship has the same crew retinue as the fucking Enterprise E. Or “why is the villain’s ship screaming, and why does he not look ANYTHING like a Romulan”. also “Why is his ship FUCKING HUMONGOUS AND POWERFUL BUT A MINING SHIP”. (it’s like if a bulldozer went back in time and blew up the British navy). But it doesn’t matter. This is a late 2000s action movie. Who the hell cares.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Z0y6HAq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We jump through a lot of scenes. Hello, Bones. Karl Urban is good casting. We get more of the villain, Nero, who wants to “make him watch”. Kinky, dog. We also get Kirk fucking a green space babe, and he wins the Kobayashi Maru by hacking the test. It’s like someone read a wikipedia article about Captain Kirk and tried to distill him down in 4 minutes. Keep in mind that, IMO, that’s impossible, because Kirk in the original series is a mad man with four distinct personalities that depend on who writes him through the episode. You either remake Kirk with SOME of his traits, or make him a madman. They kinda went with madman.</p>

<p>While Kirk is getting yelled at for cheating at the Kobayashi Maru by Spock, the maker of the test, they get a distress call from Vulcan. And apparently the only ships in the sector who can reach Vulcan are…. the fucking Cadets at Earth? WHERE ARE ANY OF THE OTHER SHIPS?! Everyone is split off into different ships. Kirk is left at home cause he cheated, but Bones is a bro and basically sneaks him on board. While the ages don’t really fit for making them all be cadets together, I kinda like the Bones and Kirk “roommate buddies from college” energy. Not ALL the characters are perfect here. I don’t like overly confident Uhura here, SNW self doubt but very good at her job Uhura feels more believable to me. Sulu is also here, piloting the Enterprise, but he’s young and inexperienced. And also Chekov is here, again, age problems. And his whole thing is he talks weird. Nurse Chapel also gets mentioned, cool.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t4SwLxG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nero, the villain, is attacking and blowing up Vulcan. They think it’s something natural, but they’re being attacked, and Kirk knows this because its the same thing that happened when he was born. If he can coem to that conclusion anyone should, because it’s not like it was a small problem, lots of people died. We get Kirk, having an allergic reaction, running through the Enterprise screaming and trying to communicate in a funny way to Uhura that they’re about to witness an actual genocide. This movie has a tone problem. Trek has always toed the line between humor and seriousness. It does that well. But it usually doesn’t involve ACTUAL PLANETARY genocide.</p>

<p>Pike leaves Chekov in control of the bridge to go be a hostage. What the fuck? Why him? Chekov is only like, 6 years old. He was just born yesterday, and you’re putting him in command? He also promotes Spock to Captain and Kirk to first officer. Why? Who the fuck knows. Bones is also now chief medical officer cause all the doctors fucking died. Pike sends Kirk Sulu and some shmuck to do an orbital fall to Vulcan to try and destroy this thing they’re using to destroy the planet.</p>

<p>Oh no, one of the people Kirk is going with on this mission is wearing a red shirt. Dude, I’m so sorry for you. There’s like 6 things JJ knows about Star Trek, and that’s one of the top ones. He died because he’s being a fucking idiot. It’s okay, I saw his parachute. Like, literally.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fYI07oO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a fight scene on this orbital platform that’s moving to the planet’s code. Sulu apparently brought a MOTHER FUCKING KATANA to this fight. Why? Because he’s Japanese of course!! This is the scene I remember from this movie most of all. I remember thinking it was sick as hell.</p>

<p>This movie is very loud.</p>

<p>The Romulans are making a black hole at the center of Vulcan, which is of course, destroying the planet. He goes to the planet and evacuates his parents, though his mom dies in the process. The temple they’re all in appears to be a Sith Templ- I mean uh, the Katric Chamber. Yeah. Holy shit we finally get silence in this movie, and it’s to mourn Spock’s mom’s death. For like 20 seconds, then it’ll be loud again.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3K7nSIa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A whole hell of a lot of people are dead now. Also Uhura makes out with Spock. It’s literally a student fucking their instructor, don’t worry about it. We all consume questionable stuff. But it wouldn’t be MY ship. Spock needs his lips ready for Kirk.</p>

<p>We find out Nero’s purpose here. He’s from a future, and his super ship nothing can beat is a fucking mining vessel. In the future, Romulus blew up, and he blames the Federation for not helping, especially Spock, so he decides to go back in time and get revenge.</p>

<p>Spock and Kirk get in an argument so Spock literally jettisons him off his ship to an ice planet (that claims is M class, it’s not) onto a fucking ice floe. Was Spock trying to literally murder Kirk? Because he nearly succeeded. Kirk is freezing to death and gets hunted by some alien beasts. What the FUCK, Spock??? You’re the good guy?! Also for some reason there’s an M Class ice planet that’s right next to Vulcan. Okay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vZ8FxrJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Congrats Kirk, you were saved by a 150 year old Vulcan. Kirk just RANDOMLY runs into Spock on this fucking planet. Why? I dunno, JJ Abrahms wanted to make a part of this movie that’s very reminiscent of Star Wars Episode 5. Old!Spock teaches Kirk what happened in the past/future. This part is canon. This movie? Not canon, it’s an alternate universe. But a supernova happening to Romulus DID happen. This causes a lot of awful prime timeline shenanigans. Also there’s a Federation outpost nearby. Why wasn’t Spock ALREADY THERE???? WHY WAS HE JUST LIVING IN A CAVE?!</p>

<p>Sorry, I am TRYING to ignore the stupid bullshit in this movie but it is very, very hard.</p>

<p>Anyways we’re about to get to the best casting of this movie. Karl Urban is #2. This is #1.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sJ7HOOB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Scotty’s actor is the only person here, other than Nimoy of course, who knew fucking ANYTHING about Star Trek before joining this crew. And he fits this perfectly. He’s pretty great.</p>

<p>Old!Spock demands that Kirk not tell Young!Spock that he exists. Because it’s his Destiny. WHAT DOES THAT MEAN? WHY DOES THAT MEAN? Whhyyy? Spock also claims he learned how to cheat from an old friend. I bet he’s gonna teach Kirk about Fizbin sometime.</p>

<p>Oh you know what, it’s been a while since we’ve had some scene where people run around with slapstick! We get a scene where Scott is beamed into Enterprise’s water tubes, and there’s some giant chopping blades that the water flows to. Good thing there’s no one currently in Engineering???????</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AInxFB5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Under Old!Spock’s suggestion, Kirk just pisses Young!Spock off enough to make him attack him, which will make it obvious he’s not fit to lead. He relinquishes command and now NO one is in command. Why are the only people on the best ship in the fleet Cadets? Well, we DO have a captain now. Kirk WAS made the acting first officer, so now he’s captain. You know, Spock was removed from captaincy cause he was emotional compromised, but this Kirk is ABSOLUTELY not emotionally compromised.</p>

<p>Spock comes to because his dad said he loved his wife, and sets himself as the new first officer. Status quo achieved!</p>

<p>Loud flicky pew pew action scene, oh boy. Scotty beams them to what he thinks is an unoccupied part of the ship. It’s not. Fight time. Luckily all these enemies are very bad. They’re attacking JUST as the ship starts to bore a hole in Earth like it did for Vulcan, almost blowing up the Golden Gate Bridge. Been a while since we saw it blow up! Also now that Spock and Kirk have fought together in a SINGLE fight, Spock is on a first name basis with Kirk and calls him Jim. This movie has some problems with pacing.</p>

<p>Nero: “I WILL DEPRIVE YOU OF YOUR LIFE, JUST LIKE I DID YOUR FATHER”</p>

<p>How the shit did you know that you killed his dad, you never interracted with him. Okay, man. It’s not like I’ve never made writing plothole mistakes before but whoof. This villain isn’t TERRIBLE, but I don’t like him that much. This is what everyone thinks Shinzon from Nemesis is.</p>

<p>Spock is going to sacrifice himself and blow up the red matter, but the Enterprise comes in like Big Damn Heroes to save the day. He crashes the ship with the red matter into Nero’s ship, creating a black hole, just as Kirk saves Pike and Spock is warped away. Was Spock trying to kill Kirk again while doing this? Yes. Yes, he was straight up going to kill him.</p>

<p>Wow this movie has a lot of flashing effects.</p>

<p>THey eject the warp core, and by that I mean like 8 of them, I dunno why they have 8 of them, and let the blast carry them away from the singularity. What if we had more flashing and more shaking effects? Lovely. And then they surfed the wave while listening to rock music. Wait, wrong movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9KjYFUy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a goodbye to Old!Spock as he meets Young!Spock. He explains he lied about it, because it’d make Kirk and Spock be friends. Fair enough.</p>

<p>All the cadets are still there, despite the fact that ALL of the ships they were all put in were blown the fuck up earlier in the movie, sure, okay, that’s fine. They make Kirk captain, give him a medal, and all cheer him on. Also Pike is in a wheelchair now! All is right in the fucking world.</p>

<p>The movie ends with them blasting off. Punch it chewie, etc. And then we get Old!Spock doing the voice over. These are the missions of etc etc. That’s pretty emotional. And we get a reprise of the original theme! Cool.</p>

<p>Obviously this movie is like, not great. It’s kinda bad, in many ways. But it’s not unenjoyable? My friend Elle in my group watch said it best. “This movie is a 40 minute carnival ride that lasts for two hours”. It is shlocky action that is poorly directed, because JJ Abrahms is not a good director. Also we all make fun of the lens flares and weird scaling but the REAL problem is that it was loud, too fast, and the fucking flashing was nuts. This movie is so bright, and so loud. It’s like getting flashbanged by a mediocre book.</p>

<p>At least the soundtrack is pretty good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="JJTrek" /><category term="Movies" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!]]></summary></entry></feed>