<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-12-28T22:53:28-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 18-24</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/28/LizstartrekEnt3-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 18-24" /><published>2025-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/28/LizstartrekEnt3-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/28/LizstartrekEnt3-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RLrV1Ug.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Azati Prime</strong> - ENT
4.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JwbzXvq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise finally reaches Azati Prime, the planet they gaslit Degra to learn its location. Guess who’s already there? Degra! Dun dun dun! The other members of the Xindi Council are here, too. I love how one of them is just CLEARLY evil, the others are like “Yo good job, you’ve accomplished so much so soon!” “LET US NOT SPEAK OF ACCOMPLISHMENTS YET, NOT UNTIL THE HUMANS ARE EXTERMINATED.” Like, if I was on a political council and one of my coworkers talked like that, I’d do… SOMETHING about it, cause jesus.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/T2peAlp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer is about to sacrifice himself for a suicide run to blow up the weapon before he’s dragged to the future by Daniels. Daniels is like “look, this is all being run by the Sphere Builders who are using the Xindi to make the future better for them. If you sacrifice yourself, they’ll just build another weapon and nothing will change, AND we’ll never get the Federation, which btw, has Xindi in it. This beautiful future could be your’s if you just try diplomacy for once in your life.”</p>

<p>And what does Archer say?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g3hJT0x.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>“No.”</p>

<p>Straight up, Archer is the worst Star Trek captain? He often gets to the right spot in the end, but for some fucking reason he always has to start at the WORST FUCKING SPOT and then be FORCED there. He’s told “You can do diplomacy to stop this peacefully” and he goes “No, I want to kill people”. WHY IS THIS OUR HERO? Like, this is the culmination of the ENTIRE season. He later says he’s sacrificing himself cause he’s done a lot of horrible shit this season but MAYBE YOU SHOULDN’T HAVE DONE THAT, AND MAYBE THERE ARE BETTER WAYS TO MOVE FORWARD. If it’s trying to do a survivor guilt “I must get my penance” kinda story, it’s NOT telling it well, at all, because his violent aggressive war crimey bullshit he’s done the entire season has been the right choice in the story. He wouldn’t be here if he didn’t fucking kidnap and gaslight a scientist.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BssPyBn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What a fucking surprise, Archer gets captured. What a wild twist. Fucking idiot.</p>

<p>On Enterprise, they’re suffering with possibly losing their captain cause he’s a fucking idiot. T’Pol is acting VERY weird.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6jJ9oDt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>After harassing some reptiles beating him up for a while, Archer decides to try the diplomacy route. Better late than never I guess. He asks for Degra, who shows up, and he makes it clear to Degra he knows a lot about him, saying “I know the name of your unborn dead third child”. “How do you know that?” “That’s not important right now” OH, ARCHER? NOT GONNA TELL HIM YOU KIDNAPPED HIM AND WIPED HIS MEMORY?? SEE, THIS IS WHAT I MEAN. That was a fucked up way to gather information, but WITHOUT IT, he would NOT be able to do this. Warcrimes are okay as long as you need to do them to succeed in stopping terrorism. Anyways he tells Degra about the Sphere Builders, the future, and that the Humans need to survive or the Xindi will die. He goes to his superiors, and while they don’t BELIEVE him, it puts some dents in their armor.</p>

<p>Anyways sudden jump cut, Enterprise is being blown up. It really was jarringly sudden. When Degra and the other non-Reptilian Xindi find out they’re like “But you said you’d hold off?” and he OBVIOUSLY EVIL REPTILIAN IS LIKE “I grew tired of waiting. And no, I won’t stop.” WHY ARE WE WORKING WITH THIS GUY? God, good thing there are no psychopathic manchildren in the real life government.</p>

<p>It’s actually funny because this Reptilian Xindi is a great example of what Republican politicians were like in 2003.</p>

<p>Meh.</p>

<p><strong>Damage</strong> - ENT
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P7jAKS2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise stops being blown up, only because they just decide not to kill them. The other Council Members have overruled the Reptilian one and are ordering him to give them Archer. He is NOT happy. The Aquatic are going to deliver Archer to the Council so they can talk to him.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Enterprise is dangerously on fire, and T’Pol is still not doing well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/99orzP5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ey, the Aquatic vessel is good. I dunno if we’ve EVER seen aquatic-based alien life in this series in this way? Anyways, he’s knocked out by gas, and then… is sent in an escape pod back to Enterprise. Weird. T’Pol is STILL acting weird. Her hands are shaking and she’s viewing the world warped and slowed. Ohhh NO, SHE HAS RADICAL SIX!!!</p>

<p>There’s a random shower sex scene with T’Pol and Trip in the middle of the episode and I hate it. But it’s just a dream. Hmm. I think Berman just wanted more horniness in his Trek again for his OC.</p>

<p>Some aliens show up, their ship hurt by this region of space. Archer is willing to help them, if they help too, because his ship is fuuuuucked. These are the Illyrians! They’re friendly and chill. Archer asks them for their warp coil, and they’re like “uh no, without that it’ll take us 3 years to get back home”. Okay, that’s off limits then :)</p>

<p>T’Pol risks her life to get some Trellium D, then crushes is up and injects it into herself. What in the fuck is this episode? Why is it like this? Why did they decide it was supposed to be like this? I thought for a second that her disease was getting out of hand, remember she does still have Vulcan AIDs, but no, it’s a drug metaphor. What the fuck?!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B71tF8p.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer has a conversation with Phlox. It’s well framed and dark, but like… Archer is like “I’m about to cross a line. One I never wanted to cross. But I have to, if the mission is to succeed.” OH, JUST NOW? YOU’VE BEEN DOING THIS ALL FUCKING SEASON, WHY STOP NOW?!</p>

<p>“In response to Archer saying (later in the scene) that a line he intended to cross would probably not be the last one, Phlox replied, “Sometimes you have to draw a line… sometimes you have to step over one… ethics are not the only consideration,” instead of merely responding, as he does in the final version of the scene, “Probably not.””</p>

<p>FUCKING CHRIST.</p>

<p>Archer makes his plan clear. He’s going to steal the Illyrians warp coil. What the fuck?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pqi4BIG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back in the Council, we learn of their benefactor, the Female Changeli- I’m sorry, the Female Sphere Builder. She’s been guiding them and helping them, and admits to helping the Reptilians and Insectoids go back in the past to kill all Humans. But she was just doing it so that the council would stay stable, cause they were going to leave the council if they can’t do a genocide, she just wanted to help :) They CLEARLY do not trust her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UgUCq2w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol confronts Archer about his plan. She even <em>QUOTES THE QUOTE I OFTEN QUOTE TO MAKE FUN OF HIM</em>. But it turns out, she’s only getting emotional and angry about it BECAUSE SHE’S A FUCKING DRUG ADDICT AND ISN’T IN HER RIGHT MIND, NOT BECAUSE IT’S ACTUALLY WRONG TO DO. After this, she relents and goes to the doctor to get help for her drug habits.</p>

<p>This is bullshit and terrible in a way that most bad Trek isn’t. It’s really, REALLY rough. Like, okay… this isn’t bad on paper? Some of this could be handled well. The crew having to do evil things but then realizing in the end that they can go the higher route or something, but we KNOW that’s not how this is going to end. And then the drug stuff? She could be out of her mind because of her Vulcan AIDs, or from residual Trellium poisoning, not because of the ACTUAL reason she gives, which is “I was finally able to access emotions and it became addicting”. THAT’S NOT HOW VULCANS WORK. Also it’s implied it’s because she wanted to fuck Trip more. That is SO UPSETTING TO ME I WANT TO FUCKING VOMIT.</p>

<p>This is just reminding me of how they fucked up the Equinox storyline. They realize shit is evil, Archer is admitting he’s doing evil, and it’s not framed heroically. But it doesn’t actually handle it well, because of the way the characters handle it. This is not going to dwell on them, their hypocrisy doesn’t effect them, they will get over it next week. When Sisko did this, he had to repeat to himself over and over “I can get over this” BECAUSE HE COULDN’T. AND THEN HE NEVER DID ANYTHING LIKE IT AGAIN, BECAUSE IT WAS A ONE TIME I HAVE TO DO THIS THING. ARCHER’S BEEN DOING THIS ALL FUCKING SEASON WITH NO PROBLEMS.</p>

<p>Anyways they steal the fucking warp coil and strand the Illyrians 3 years from home in a region of space with dangerous anomalies that kills 90% of the people who enter it.</p>

<p>This fucking sucked.</p>

<p>This episode sucked SO BAD that we decided to watch movies instead. See you next week for the end of Season 3. Thank god.</p>

<p>Okay its next week. Let’s get this over with.</p>

<p><strong>The Forgotten</strong> - ENT
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zr0vcM4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>18 people died over the nonsense that happened in the last two episodes. The episode REALLY hammers this in. You know, inbetween THIS.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IdW7drM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol being a drug addict is not a thing that’ll that’ll be ending any time soon. She’s just… emotional now. Well, she wasn’t really acting like a Vulcan anyway.</p>

<p>Enterprise meets up with Degra and the Arboreal council member who’s backing Archer. They arranged for Archer to be returned to his ship, and want him to prove that he can time travel. That’s gonna be… hard, but he offers to show them proof if they come aboard his ship.</p>

<p>You know, I was told something about this season before I watched it. They described it as “the most submarine coded season of Star Trek”. I was looking forward to that. A crummy ship in a dangerous area where they can only kinda pop out occasionally and gotta patch up holes. But now that we’re here, uh, it sucks. They use it to justify straight up killing hte Illyrians, and Tucker’s reaction to this is to not sleep for 2 days as he gets crabbier and crabbier. I’m not sure why I was ever looking forward to that to begin with.</p>

<p>Seth Macfarlane has a cameo in this. He says two sentences to Trip and looks about as excited to talk to him as I would be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aN63lrs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Trip meets with Degra and yells at him about how his weapon blew up Florida. And also Cuba, Venezuala, prolly some of Jamaica… But those don’t matter. Only Florida matters, cause that’s ‘Murica. This’d be like if 9/11 happened and also a bunch of other countries got attacked, but everything was treated exactly the same. I fucking HATE how America-centric this show is.</p>

<p>There’s a plasma leak, and an eepy Tucker needs to go out with Reed to fix it. God, imagine if we had ANY ENGINEERS THAT AREN’T TRIP who could help him?! Well we did, one of them died, we had never seen her before, and Trip has been spending the episode complaining about needing to write to her parents.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7TqcRuB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Despite all of Trip’s being a shithead, and all of the lack of evidence Archer is giving (just show him the fucking future shit that Daniels left), Degra is throwing his hat in with the Humans, and wants to help them. Though when a Reptilian warship shows up to finish the job extrajudicially, he’s not exactly ready or willing to join the Humans and attack the Reptilians… at first, but just a LITTLE convincing and he joins them to fight. Good thing Degra’s one of the good one- oh, he went WAY too far and just straight up KILLED those Reptilians. Welp, whatever, they would have hurt our alliance, so it’s GOOD that they died!</p>

<p>Degra convinces Archer go to in front of the council and show his evidence (what fucking evidence?!), but it’ll take three days via a subspace corridor, which some kind of beings use as hunting grounds. I’m sure that won’t be a problem.</p>

<p>Trip finally writes that letter to the dead crewman’s parents. He makes it about himself and his dead sister. I am going to become the joker.</p>

<p><strong>E²</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DDadCxG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode starts with Old T’Pol with Land of Confusion-style makeup talking to some Vulcan like “we could not stop the 7 million people from dying, so you must find Jonathan Archer”. Interesting.</p>

<p>As they approach the corridor, they are approached by another Starfleet ship. It’s Enterprise, looking EXTREMELY shitty and awful. They tell Archer to hold back and not enter the nebula… they come over and the Vulcan guy introduces himself as Lorian. He tells a story, which is shown in like 5FPS shitty cam footage. Why?? I dunno. Anyways when Enterprise goes through the corridor, it’ll send them back 120 years. In the past, they have a plan, to stop the first Xindi attack. They obviously failed, and now they want to help team up to stop the second.</p>

<p>This is YET ANOTHER case of this show just taking a previous episode I like, and almost certainly doing it worse. This is just the DS9 episode where they go down to a planet with time shit, and find their descendants. The writer actually had an original plan of it being the Columbia, Enterprise’s sister ship, who got sent back instead, but was overruled by executives who were like “eh, it’s been long enough since DS9 aired”. I don’t like THAT, but I don’t mind it that much so far. And I love this kind of “AU who pares off with who” storyline.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/akSOH5k.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>You know the Hot Lady Marine that we see every now and then? Her name is Amanda, and Phlox apparently shacks up with her. Phlox can GET IT. Phlox won Enterprise, hell yeah.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7GhvVme.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Aaaand the twist, The Future Enteprise is actually evil. Lorian makes plans to steal some Enterprise tech so that they can go and meet the Xindi and stop them. I was thinking they’d do this so that they can justify their own existence and cause themselves to exist, like the DS9 episode, but no, they’re just kinda doing it because they think this is the best chance of stopping the Xindi. That’s a LOT less interesting.</p>

<p>Also, it’s bad and evil that they’re stealing engineering hardware. Piracy is bad again!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aKiaZye.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Lorian is stopped. His crew won’t let him just KILL the others when he wants to. In jail, he explains why he did what he “had to do”. Because he’s guilty he couldn’t stop the weapon. Dog, SO MANY people could have stopped this weapon, there’s time travel in this storyline.</p>

<p>Old T’Pol tells Young T’Pol the best way to handle her emotions. Use Trip as a fucktoy to get all the emotions out. I am only BARELY exaggerating.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xxqZ7VF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shout outs to Twinborne in my chat for this nonsense.</p>

<p>The Enterprises work together, and they basically tow the Current Enterprise out of the corridor, while sacrificing themselves. The Future Enterprise’s fate is not shown, but the Current Enterprise made it through, into the right century. That problem solved itself I guess.</p>

<p>Enteprise meets with Degra, the end. At least this episode shows Phlox has the most game on Enterprise.</p>

<p><strong>The Council</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CRUqxer.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode starts with a council of Sphere Builders yelling at each other about KILLING ALL HUMANS, floating in a white void. Damn bitch, y’all live like this? No wonder you wanna enter the Beta Quadrant.</p>

<p>Hoshi and Archer go to the council. Holy SHIT, Hoshi gets to DO SOMETHING? MEanwhile, T’Pol, Mayweather, Reed, and a Redshirt are doing…. SOMETHING at a sphere. Degra and Archer are nearly stopped by Dolim, the Reptilian councilmember, but they make through after all.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fZE50Zm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>REALLY good Archer, amazing diplomacy skills. You start your talking before the council to make your case that they’re being lied to by going “You killed 7 million Humans, I fucking hate you”. Very good.</p>

<p>VERY American worldview, frankly.</p>

<p>It doesn’t go well. What a fucking surprise. The Reptilians and the Insectoids are NEVER going to side with the Humans, but maybe the Aquatics will. They need to focus on convincing them, and they respond best to hard visual evidence. Meanwhile, the Sphere Builder woman, or “The Guardian” as they call her, is behind the Reptilian telling him to make sure the weapon launches so that the Reptilians rule over a unified Xindi empire. Yeah, an empire of One species.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZP1ELGV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, the B team are in a Sphere, prolly intending to get something that proves their case. The Red Shirt is waving his death flags all over the fuckin’ place. Oh shit he died, no way.</p>

<p>After showing the dead Sphere Builder, the council is a liiiittle more reticent to learning more. And then, they get their three votes to postpone the launching of the weapon… Not the Aquatics! The Reptilians! Glad they’re finally coming around :D Dolim comes around to have a peaceful meeting with Degra- oh, nope.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/62rUoRC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>RIP Degra.</p>

<p>Obviously this pissed off EVERYONE on the council, except the Insectoids, who are ontologically evil. I do kinda wish it was JUST one group, the Reptilian leader and his yesmen, pushing for this after all the evidence. The Insectoids and Reptilians leave the council, launch the weapon, and they can’t stop it as it leaves to Earth. But not before stealing THE FEMALE (Hoshi). Oh no! Time for I AM LOCUTUS OF THE REPTILIANS, RESISTANCE IS- no, prolly not.</p>

<p>Pacing is a little off but pretty alright actually.</p>

<p><strong>Countdown</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mvHSd7g.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Hoshi being tied to a chair and tortured. They intend to use her to hack the code so they can activate The Weapon. Poor fucking Hoshi. FINALLY taken out of mothballs just to be tortured.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gqlMRvn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone on Enterprise is like “I sure with Hoshi was here to help us with this thing”. Y’all made do without her this entire fucking season, why is it a problem now?</p>

<p>They need the Aquatics help to go after The Weapon, but the Aquatics are fine with being neutral in this new civil war. Archer tries to diplomacy them to their side, but is VERY bad at diplomacy, so instead he says they know how to disable the Spheres, and will teach them if they help him. They cannot do that. So now Trip and T’Pol need to find out how to shut down the Spheres. Whoops.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A7C7bkZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Aquatics agree. Now, after eight months in the Expanse, it’s time to leave and stop that weapon. The battle begins. The aquatics smuggle Enterprise in a giant carrier, which is kinda neat, and then there’s a big battle. Even the MACO get their chance to FINALLY do SOMETHING. They board a Xindi vessel to try and save Hoshi and stop the weapon from launching. This looking VERY good for our heroes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2HZsFuc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Sphere Builders use the spheres to create MASSIVE anomalies that destroy a lot of the attacking fleet. Shit Gets Bad real fast. The giant Aquatic ship falls apart, kinda sad. And then the MACO struggle to survive against the Reptilians, and the leader is killed in action, after everyone else is teleported out. They can’t stop them. The weapon is launched.</p>

<p>Also the Reptilians betray the Insectoids, who are like “Yo actually that anomaly shows the Guardians DID build the spheres”. Oh no, the leopards!</p>

<p>Plans are made to chase it and send a team inside to stop it. Hoshi is EXTREMELY injured, and moving her might kill her, but Archer demands she be moved anyway. Come on, man. Also, the rest of Enterprise head to a Sphere to blow it up, which should blow up the entirety of them.</p>

<p>Eh, it’s okay.</p>

<p><strong>Zero Hour</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VM35iXY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the FINAL episode where Brennan and Braga will be writing…. until the VERY end of the series. We’re almost free of them. But their shadow remains.</p>

<p>We have to watch the Reptilian eat some mice. Everyone hated that. I guess they’re Snake People now.</p>

<p>Wow, what a surprise, Archer is REALLY handling the Hoshi thing wrong. She’s not sure where she is, because she has BRAIN DAMAGE, and he’s yelling at her and shaking her to JUST STOP BEING HYSTERICAL, WOMAN. Bitches just need a bit of Percusive Maintenence. He also intends to TAKE HER BACK ONTO THE WEAPON. Dude.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RpQlKgJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Daniels shows up one more time to tell Archer he’s The Very Special Boy who needs to live so the Federation can happen, so just sacrifice one of the others, Reed or Hoshi, they aren’t important. The more this guy shows up the more I hate him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ceGwTz2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>HE’S HERE! The Andorians are here to help hold the Reptilians off so that Archer can sneak on board. God, I love Shran. Thanks for being the only good part of Enterprise, Shran. “AND TELL ARCHER WE’RE NOT EVEN ANYMORE. HE OWES ME.” God, you’re great.</p>

<p>We have two tense moments here. Archer is hacking into the weapon from the inside, using Hoshi’s plans, while Enterprise is sitting in intense radiation and trying to blow up a sphere while the Builders try to stop them. Shit just keeps getting worse and worse. Hoshi loses her notes, people continue to die.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w6nt6VS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Christ, the special effects are horrifying.</p>

<p>They disable the weapon, but Archer stays behind to blow it up. He HAS to scratch his savior complex!! But I’m sure it’s important, because this raging war criminal is the ONLY person from this time period that actually matters.</p>

<p>Yes I am still hung up on that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/U9PFJB9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Well, we NEED Archer to stay behind so that we can get one last one on one battle! He and Dolim have an epic battle with the typical “holding him over the edge and trying to push him over” thing. But Archer wins, blowing him the fuck up. IT’s gruesome.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pVeh6yQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Wow, they really went for it, huh? This looks MEATY.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UE78ZvV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are you fucking <strong>kidding me</strong></p>

<p>T’Pol FINALLY tells Trip her age, because he’s insufferable and still on this. This series has a tone problem. Everyone else makes it back to tell them the weapon is destroyed, but Archer didn’t make it.</p>

<p>The Xindi transport the Enterprise to earth, and then leave. And they are literally never seen again, ever. Neither are the Sphere Builders. Star Trek Online does not count.</p>

<p>Enterprise returns to Earth and hears no response. They go down, and are attacked by fucking P52s. Somewhere, Archer wakes up in a fucking war tent, as NAZIS COME AROUND HIM, ONE OF THEM BEING AN ALIEN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kbyYa65.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What the <strong>fuck</strong>.</p>

<p>This was legit Berman’s last laugh. He had no plans, and no goals. He knew he wasn’t going to work on season 4’s writing. So he just put up nazis and went “GOOD LUCK!” There are theories that it was a ploy to make it so that if the network cancelled Enterprise, it’d make people yell SO LOUDLY that “YOU CAN’T JUST END WITH A FUCKING NAZI CLIFFHANGER” that it’d make exec’s lives miserable. The one good thing Berman ever did, try to make Exec’s lives miserable.</p>

<p>It’s still really fucking stupid though.</p>

<p>This season legit sucked. It’s the worst. At least it’s pretty much entirely skippable? The FIRST season in the best season somehow so far, how the FUCK did that happened? I hear from a lot of people I trust, season 4 gets actually good. So… WE’LL FUCKING SEE.</p>

<p>Gonna take a 2 or 3 week break for GDQ. Enterprise returns then.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 13-17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/14/LizstartrekEnt3-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 13-17" /><published>2025-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/14/LizstartrekEnt3-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/14/LizstartrekEnt3-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F5SkyLE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Proving Ground</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XzAjCcQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>SHRAN IS BACK! I know we shut down ALL plotlines that we were building in order to force this Xindi shit down our throats, but thank GOD we’re bringing back the best, actually GOOD part, of seasons 1 and 2. Shran is here!! And he’s hunting for the Pink Skins, for some reason.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/odoUW2u.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>God, Andorian Women are hot as fuck. Do you think there are half-human half-Andorians out there? If not, I can help.</p>

<p>Shran shows up and rescues Enterprise from getting its shit kicked in by an anomaly way. Everyone is grateful, but why? Shran is very clear: He’s here to help. Nothing more, nothing less. After all, they helped him multiple times. Pluuuuus, the Vulcans couldn’t even spare a SINGLE officer, she had to RESIGN in order to help. So if the Andorians help out, well, that makes them better, doesn’t it?~</p>

<p>It IS a morally correct thing to do but they clearly have reasons for it. The chance to formally make an ally, and seperate them from the Vulcans in one fell swoop, why not? Everyone on the Human ship is… extremely dodgy about this. Archer is in his ANGY ARCHER mode, so he’s growling at people for no fucking reason. I guess his favorite Water Polo team lost recently. But really, both sides don’t quite trust each other.</p>

<p>See, I love the Andorian plotline in this show. The Andorians, and Shran himself, are xenophobic, militaristic, and distrusting. They are essentially the opposite of Starfleet. But as we know via lore, they will be Earth’s first allies, and the founding members of the Federation. This makes it clear: Even when things are stacked against you, you can always find common ground and make friends to better everyone. It is VERY Star Trek, and I totally believe it was a fucking accident, cause all of the other choices in this show are absolute garbage and are not at ALL Trek. But it’s a very good thing. Please do not fuck it up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/29uGPNj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The entire episode is little things, bit by bit, to show that they’re not so different and they can be friends. I liked the scene where Shran talks to Trip about his dead sister, and is like “I lost a brother in an earlier war with the Vulcans. We have common ground. You’re SURE you don’t want vengeance?” “No, I just want to make sure they don’t hurt anyone else.” and Shran clearly finds it admirable.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, things can’t be so good forever. Shran is going to use his ship to swoop in and steal the Xindi Weapon. Archer is like “Oh thats a great idea, your ship can handle the radiation better”. But its very, VERY obvious that Shran is going to JUST steal it and leave the Humans. He is NOT happy about this though. He makes a plea to his superior officer to let them ACTUALLY make allies of the Humans, but the General is like “no killing Vulcans is more important”. Ahh, the people in charge for EVERYONE is imcompetent!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HcG1b6n.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shran is very unhappy, but it works. He also had his people handicap Enterprise so they could run away… but Enterprise ALSO handicapped THEM and catch back up. No one actually trusted anyone at any point, and it was always a handshake with knives behind backs. Well that puts a damper on everything :/ But they turned the Xindi Weapon into a bomb, so that they can’t use it to kill Vulcans. It blows up, damaging the Andorians, who limp back home… but not before Shran sends a coded message with scans and details of the Xindi Weapon.</p>

<p>I still liked it, but that plot twist kinda felt like it ruined the themes of it.</p>

<p><strong>Stratagem</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gV3X07I.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Degra, the Xindi scientist making the superweapon, wakes up to find himself on a strange unknown ship. Archer, older and disheveled, is like “oh good you’re up, help me we’re being attacked”. They manage to escape, and Archer explains: He’s Archer, they’ve been roommates in prison for three years, and they JUST escaped. But the Insectoids did a thing, a bloodworm apparently, that makes memory go wonky.</p>

<p>Okay so, is this episode going to just be “We gaslight this guy”? I mean he IS building a planet killer weapon but still.</p>

<p>Archer takes the Bloodworm out of Degra in a scene that’s like 25 seconds of Archer carving into this dude’s arm in a very gruesome and graphic way, it is MASSIVELY uncomfortable and I’m STUNNED they showed it all on screen. Anyways through this and all the talking, ARcher manages to get Degra to trust him. aaaand then its revealed…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UAx2uR3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>it’s all a simulation. They’re watching through cameras and trying to get him to hint at things so they can find out where he weapon is being built. This seems EXTREMELY elaborate, why not just… torture him or something? You CLEARLY don’t care about the ethics, Archer, so why bother??</p>

<p>What then proceeds is a 3 day flashback where we see Enterprise kidnapping Degra. He won’t give any info through just asking, so PHLOX OF ALL FUCKING PEOPLE suggests a serum that’ll erase his recent memories so they can do this to him. Remember when Phlox was super ethical?? What the fuck were they doing with Phlox this season?</p>

<p>So I think it’s important to discuss Ethical Nonsense this season. Everyone on this ship has basically wanted to or DONE torture and other fucked up things. And I’m not against characters in Trek doing bad things. Remember DS9? One of the best fucking episodes of ALL TIME is about the captain deciding that he can do unethical, even evil acts, if it means saving people. But he doesn’t rope everyone into it. He JUST ropes Garak. He doesn’t go to Bashir and Bashir is like “oh hell yeah”, no, Bashir is PISSED about the fucking gel and refuses to have anything to do with it. But none of the characters here are like that, none of them will do that, because these characters aren’t here as characters with ideals and thoughts, they’re here to fit into the story that they already planned with these Xindi.</p>

<p>And I can’t tell you how silly this whole premise is. It’s actually the exact same thing that the Romulans did in that one episode to Riker, except in that one, they were bad guys, and this time it’s good guys. It’s LITERALLY just that episode reversed. Enterprise CONSTANTLY reuses ideas, but usually not this ineptly.</p>

<p>Anyways eventually Degra realizes its all fake, but not before giving them coordiantes that seem like they COULD be for the facility where the weapon is being made. Degra is like “Wow you Humans ARE ruthless just like I was told.” YEAH ARCHER, GREAT JOB MAKING TRUST YOU EVEN LESS.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YjugsoK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They manage to trick Degra, AGAIN, to admitting that the coordinates they give are actually the right ones. They then wipe all their fucking memories, again, and plant them back on their ship, before heading to the coordinates.</p>

<p>This was just kinda dumb, and the moral and ethical ramifications are nuts. I can’t really say anything more than “they sure did reuse an older idea but make the bad guys the good guys because we gotta stop 9/11-2”.</p>

<p><strong>Harbinger</strong> - ENT
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FCi09oE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode starts with Trip massaging some marine woman’s feet.</p>

<p>Can you believe this episode was written by Berman?? Why does everyone on this ship want to fuck Trip, he’s so extremely repellant to me, I feel myself become dryer every single time he’s on screen, I fear my nethers are going to become a new biome with NEGATIVE humidity. Anyways she kisses him because there’s some kind of radiation here that makes things melt the decision center of the brain.</p>

<p>No, it’s cause Berman wanted his OC to kiss a hot woman cause he can’t fucking get any.</p>

<p>Okay so this episode has A, B, AND C plots. The C plot is that Trip is doing meditation with this random marine girl, and T’Pol is getting jealous. Great. The B-plot is that Reed is butting heads with the head marine because he’s moving in on his territory as the security leader on the ship. GREAT. And the A plot is actually interesting shit about aliens, so it will get the least screen time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XBLbMTH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I’m beginning to straight up hate Reed. I literally cannot think of a SINGLE scene where he’s added to it in a positive way off the top of my head. His character is two things: 1) boring, he’s a boring dude with no hobbies who just wants to do his job and 2) a fucking pissant grumpy baby who is angry that no one else is taking this seriously, and that people came to space to be peaceful and friendly. And here, that pissant baby energy is at its largest, because he keeps having a dick measuring contest with the marines.</p>

<p>The marines, if you remember, are here because SOMEONE should be trained in combat when we’re in dangerous territory and basically at war with the Xindi. Reed is having a dick measuring contest because HE was the dude for security here and now he has to actually work with someone else. I don’t need a dick measuring contest to know that Reed loses, because he’s a piss baby who’s MASSIVELY incompetent at his job.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wDb7oWx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, ACTUAL TREK SHIT. They find an alien with a ship with failing life support and pick him up. He appears to be in some kind of suspended animation. They revive him and he’s like “FUCK YOU PUT ME BACK ON MY SHIP YOU PIECES OF GARBAGE”. Oh, okay. He’s suffering from extremely cellular degredation and looks like he’s LITERALLY falling apart.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F5SkyLE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are you <strong>mother fucking kidding me</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UpM0XV3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh shit how did this get here</p>

<p>So the A plot is shit too. But this episode 2/3rds BAD CONCEPTS JUST AT THE START. This fucking episode is a bottle episode of Enterprise concepts I really hate. This episode was already fighting an uphill battle, but let me tell you, if something is good, and I’m predisposed to dislike it, I can get over that. I can see the good in things. I saw the good in <strong>Spock’s Fucking Brain</strong>, I can find the good in things that I don’t like.</p>

<p>I cannot find the good in this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kmQ51fZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways THIS happens after an extremely awkward and poorly acted scene, like the actors were internally rebelling at the idea of doing it. Then we see T’Pol’s bare ass. Which SHOULD make me happier but doesn’t. That was apparently very controversial btw. Which is funny cause I know we’ve seen lots of men asses on American TV, but we can’t have no female asses, that’d be gay.</p>

<p>Speaking of gay, we get more of Reed and the marine being catty and snapping at each other. If that previous scene is any indication, these two should make out now.</p>

<p>Anyways the alien is a Sphere Builder, they built the Spheres. You can tell from their name. His people cannot exist in our dimension without THIS happening to them, and this guy was sent into this dimension as a canary in the mine, so see if they could live in this dimension yet. He can not. When he learns they’re from Earth though, he phases through the ship for some reason, after attacking poor Phlox. He beelines to the engine and tries to blow it up.</p>

<p>They manage to stop him, but not before he gives a cryptic message that when the Xindi kill them all, his people will prevail. See, it’s okay because They’re Out To Get Us.</p>

<p>Also T’Pol shrugs off the sex she and Trip did in a really bitchy way, back to the status quo I guess.</p>

<p>I seriously cannot stress how terrible this was.</p>

<p><strong>Doctor’s Orders</strong> - ENT
 7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b6e1br0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone on the crew has been put in a deep sleep…. except for Phlox. He’s alone while everyone else is in a medically forced eep. Well, he DOES have Porthos! They’re moving through a spot in space that makes everyone’s brains die unless they shut down their brains and force themselves into comas. Also, Phlox is immune.</p>

<p>So yeah, it’s just Phlox for 4 days. He’s writing a message to his friends during it.</p>

<p>You MAY remember this as that one episode in Voyager where they did the same thing but with Seven of Nine. That was a RECENT episode too, that was the last season of Voyager, so only a few years before this!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Pgz5F5v.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy <strong>shit</strong> they gave him an Austin Powers-ass nude scene. Okay, forget all the negative shit I just said, this is worth it.</p>

<p>Anyways things are going smoothly only a few days in, but then there’s some clanking… spoooooky, ooooh, ship’s haunted!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qmHOEfQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>JUMP SCARE, IT’S T’POL! Yes she’s actually awake too, they didn’t mention it at all. She asks the doctor if he’s okay, he explains he has a slightly headache but should be fine. He’s clearly agitated and anxious. The silence of three days is getting to him. He also says he watched the Exorcist right before this which is really funny.</p>

<p>There are hints something is amiss though. He keeps seeing shadows. Things aren’t exactly how they should be. And also… T’Pol isn’t actually eating. They have dinner and she doesn’t pick up her spoon once. Hmm.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/anZ11QB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit keeps getting worse. He sees something outside crawling on the hull. He sees a Xindi Insect inside, skulking around some sleeping crewmates. T’Pol keeps telling him there’s nothing and he should rest. He does not. He gets more and more stressed and then THIS almost happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QYiFve5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is very funny out of context.</p>

<p>He FINALLY realizes shit has gotten out of hand and he IS hallucinating things when he sees a mutated Hoshi telling him “YOU DID THIS TO US”. He scans himself and realizes yes, he’s hallucinating. It’ll be fine and there are only 6 hours left, but he asks T’Pol to look over everything and then he’ll put himself under. She begs him not to, and he finally relents… until 6 hours later, when they SHOULD have been out of the anomaly, they find out they won’t actually be out for ten weeks at this speed. They need to go to warp.</p>

<p>Phlox has no fucking clue how to turn on the warp engines. And then he gets Trip yelling at him about it. It’s funny cause none of the hallucinations have been anything like the actual people so far, except Trip is very accurate.</p>

<p>He manages to start up the ship and they get through with no problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KMPrB5z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE T’POL WAS COMING FROM INSIDE THE HOUSE</p>

<p>Obvious twist but still fun.</p>

<p><strong>Hatchery</strong> - ENT
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PZRcQYF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While on route to the weapon, Enterprise finds a derelict Xindi vessel crashed on an planet. Why are they sending Trip on this fucking away mission, DON’T WE HAVE MARINES?</p>

<p>On the ship, they find the entire thing lost atmosphere, except for one part that appears to be a hatchery, with 31 eggs still intact. They made that part handle total ship failures, makes sense. One of the eggs sprays Archer with some kinda acid.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lB0hRad.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Phlox makes it clear the acid is just a simple defense mechanism, but then Archer starts being like “Okay we need to protect the eggs now, collect them so we can save them. He’s like “How would we react if we found a nursery of 31 primates? We’d save them. We should save the insectoids, even if their parents want us dead.”</p>

<p>Now, I know how this show works. So my guess is that he’s only doing this cause of a side effectof the acid. If that’s the case that is… bad. You need to be mind controlled to do the ethical thing? Great. Lovely.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zrj6rYC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some of the babies die due to a fuck up, cause Trip is bad at his job. Archer is taking this hard. Everyone is acting like he’s being fucking nuts, cause he’s upset some sapient creatures just died. I mean he also clearly hasn’t showered or changed his clothes in two days, he’s slimey and gross. But the issue is he cares about sapient creatures. And it’s clear something is wrong with him, cause he’s treating these creatures with respect, but they don’t go to Phlox about relieving him, they go about it in the dumbest ways. By questioning him loudly in public. So he has T’Pol assigned to quarters.</p>

<p>Trip is like “Better lock me up too, cause we’re not doing the right thing here. They wouldn’t do the same for us.”</p>

<p>OUR ENEMY IS ONTOLOGICALLY EVIL AND IS DOING TERRORISM AGAINST US, SO WE DON’T NEED TO TREAT THEM WITH RESPECT. GOD THIS SHOW FUCKING <strong><em>REEKS OF 9/11 XENOPHOBIA</em></strong> AND I FUCKING <strong>HATE ITTTTT</strong></p>

<p>The marines literally go “I’m not happy I locked her up but I have to follow all orders, even if they’re unlawful.” NO. YOU DO NOT. THAT’S NOT HOW ANY OF THIS WORKS.</p>

<p>IT’s also a problem because Archer is basically putting the Xindi Babies first and will kill his entire crew by using up all their antimatter to save them.</p>

<p>I’m so checked out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ipNfhhZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They do a coup. The marines refuse to cooperate and are overwhelmed. Trip goes down and shoots Archer, who was NOT threatening but was instead petting babies and treating them nicely. Turns out yes, the acid was a neurochemical that made him reverse imprint on the babies and subconsciously feel like their caretaker. They clean out his brain and leave the babies behind and move on. The end.</p>

<p>Awful. I hope I don’t need to explain why.</p>

<p>Neli asked if we’re being unfair to Enterprise, but I don’t think so. I just think we’re Trek fans who are not moderates and are 24 years out from the absolute batshit lunacy that was the 9/11 era. It’s fundamentally just… morally reprehensible to me, and that’s not what Trek has EVER been.</p>

<p>This show is literally just propaganda.</p>

<p>And I can’t fucking <strong>stand</strong> Bush-era propaganda.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 8-12</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/07/LizstartrekEnt3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 8-12" /><published>2025-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/07/LizstartrekEnt3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/12/07/LizstartrekEnt3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F4XFBRW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Twilight</strong> - ENT
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wD6bF8W.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Christ, look at that. It looks like a Myst village.</p>

<p>Archer wakes up to shit exploding, is confused when told the captain ordered him to stay in his room, and goes to the bridge to find T’Pol in charge, as they all watch the Earth explode. I… I think this is the first time Earth has exploded in Star Trek? They don’t usually do that.</p>

<p>Archer wakes up to find himself Old. He kinda looks like Serak.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nD68pYS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out that Archer was hit by an anomaly, after saving T’Pol from it, that put parasites in his brainmeats. These parasites make it so he can’t form new memories. What we then see is a flashback of them trying to handle having a captain who is now mentally impaired. It’s kind of sad, and not poorly done, tbh. Things go worse and worse for the mission, until they’re damaged, and can’t really assist as the Xindi blow up Earth. There are now like 6000 Humans left. Oh, also Mayweather is killed.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/16WTPIn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At least T’Pol was promoted, given a commission, and a suit. She looks great in it.</p>

<p>Now, a decade later, there’s a procedure that Phlox has developed that SHOULD fix the brain parasites. Oh fuck, this also means Porthos is dead. Jesus christ. This is the worst timeline.</p>

<p>Man, all this just to fix Archer. Archer is our golden boy. He’s our very important super boy. Phlox also thinks that T’Pol is in love with Archer. T’Pol of course denies it. Wow, I thought they completely killed this ship so that Trip could romance T’Pol.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jZCv9Gt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Angry yelly Trip with lighter hair looks more like Kirk.</p>

<p>Anyways, turns out the parasites, which are in another dimension, if they’re killed, will cease to exist in the past as well. So Phlox and T’Pol think this might save Earth. Trip, however, needs those weapons to protect them from the Xindi who are showing up. Archer goes running off to help, like he can do anything, while T’Pol chases after him. But they’re too late, the Bridge is exploded, and everyone dies. Archer commands everyone else to leave, while he sets up a subspace implosion to blow up the rest of the parasites. T’Pol is like “with all due respect, you were relieved of command”, and they stay behind. Archer keeps getting shot, but eventually it works, and we get to watch the Enterprise blow up, and then ARcher wakes up back in the past.</p>

<p>Over all, actually a good episode. Very Trekky concept, well handled.</p>

<p><strong>North Star</strong> - ENT
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7e8G8MS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode starts with the first lynching I’ve ever seen in a Trek episode. It’s not quite Earth blowing up, is it? It’s some kind of western town, and a human woman is pissed off about the lynching. The sherriff says he wish he could have given him a fair trial instead, and the woman is like “Yeah, and then those same people would be on the jury”. The sherriff is like “Well, he killed a man in defense. That’s a death sentence for Skags.” I wonder if this is inspired by anything at all.</p>

<p>Trip, T’Pol, and Archer are investigating the town, wondering why Humans are on a planet in the middle of the expanse. Trip trades a gun and a harmonica for a horse for a few hours. Where the fuck did they get a gun??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u1AiAqB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a scene with the deputy mistreating a “skag”, some lower class citizen working at the bar, while Archer sits and listens. He interrupts the bullying, and is told, very subtly, to get the fuck out of town.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CBVKpYB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer meets the teacher, the only person who was agaisnt the lynching, to learn more about these Skagarans (skag is a slur). They’re taken to a broken ship, where Trip and T’Pol are getting data chips from it. ARcher stay behind to learn more from the teacher while they leave, and he learns that the Skagarans took Humans from Earth as slaves for this colony here. Understandably, not good. But uh, yeah. Might be going a bit far here.</p>

<p>There’s some good lines here. Archer is arrested and brought to the sherriff. “How about a shave, Mr. Archer? Nothing like a shave to keep a man civilized” “I feel civilized enough already.”</p>

<p>Before Archer leaves, he fucking decks the deputy and breaks the teacher out of prison. She’s shot, and Archer beams them both out. Right in front of everyone. So now the deputy thinks the Skagarans have come back, and so it’s time to just fucking kill all of them. This guy might be one of the least sympathetic Humans in the ENTIRETY of Star Trek. Not quite as much as the guy who decided the height of Human civilization was Nazi Germany, but he’s up there. The Sheriff is like “Nope, none of that, not while you work under me” and then the deputy just quits so he can lynch them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7wqVJvq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer just takes the shuttle down and makes it CLEAR that he’s from Earth, b ut the Ex-Deputy starts a fucking shootout. It’s a CLASSIC western-style shootout, and is quite fun. Archer is shot in the shoulder, very bloodyt squib, and then gets into a fist fight with the racist asshole anyway.</p>

<p>T’Pol is taken hostage cause woman weak I guess, god this fucking series, and Reed just fucking shoots her. In the lyncher’s shock, he shoots him too. Smart move. Kinda funny.</p>

<p>Enterprise can’t just take these people back to Earth yet. And even if they could, these people couldn’t really integrate. But clearly, they can improve. The sheriff agrees to change some laws, and they give the teacher a padd to teach with. It’s adorable.</p>

<p>Straight up a good episode.</p>

<p><strong>Similitude</strong> - ENT
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EvyN6Ww.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode starts with Trip’s funeral. YAY. THE EVIL HAS BEEN DEFEATED. Everyone in chat fucking CHEERED.</p>

<p>Flashback, Trip thinks he has a plan that can make the ride smoother and help the engine last longer. It works for a second, then the engine has Problems and there’s explosions. Oh, Trip, you continue to be bad at your job. Trip is thrown and falls, and he falls into a coma. He might not survive. But Phlox has an idea.</p>

<p>He has a creature that, when given DNA of something else, will duplicate that creature’s life cycle at a very fast rate. If they inject it with Trip DNA, it will become Trip and age and die in 15 days. Phlox believes they can use it to make a new Trip and then harvest his neural matter to save Phlox. Dude, Phlox. You are the most humanitarian doctor in this fucking universe. And you’re thinking this is okay? T’Pol is like “that’s really ethically fucked up”, but it’s NOT ethically fucked up to Phlox???? Phlox has a VERY strict ethical code. This is weird.</p>

<p>I seriously cannot get over this. This is a FUCKED UP CONCEPT. This is unambiguously the darkest thing a Federation captain has done. You all think Tuvix was a moral conundrum? Check THIS shit out. He feels he has to though, cause Trip is apparently their ONLY ENGINEER. HE’S NOT EVEN COMPETENT AT HIS MOTHER FUCKING JOB. They’re stuck in a place that’s killing them slowly, but ONLY Trip can fix this fucking engine? Archer, YOU HELPED BUILD IT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9kTqtZJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They name the clone Sim. He’s also remembering things from Trip’s actual childhood. Creepy. DNA memory or something.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P6b4Bn8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s told when he’s 4 days old that he’s here as a clone to save Trip. He takes it SHOCKINGLY well. He integrates well into the crew. He also develops some strategies to help them get out. I’m surprised I’m saying this, but I dunno if they made this angsty enough. It’s like they didn’t think about the morality of it, at all.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1HML2dJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sim declares his love for T’Pol. Officially sending THAT ship out. He basically confesses for Trip. Okay. I still don’t care about this romance.</p>

<p>Sim’s plan works, and they might be able to escape. At the same time, Archer is told by Phlox that oh, in order to harvest his brain, they need to kill Sim. That wasn’t orginally the plan, but turns out it has to be done. Sim is like “why shouldn’t I just die?” but then they find out there’s a way to maybe stop the aging. An enzyme MIGHT make him not age and die in ten days. But by the time it’d take to synthesize it, Trip would die, prolly.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q8bFero.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer is like “no, you should die to save Trip”. He handles this VERY poorly and awfully. Sim is like “I’m my own person, and I’m basically Trip, I even have his memories. Why don’t I deserve to live? Why am I not Trip?” and Archer goes “YOU’RE NOT TRIP, HE’S LYING IN A COMA IN MEDBAY”. Archer. Give him some fucking dignity. But Archer is like “NO I WILL KILL YOU TO SAVE TRIP. DON’T FORCE ME TO KILL YOU MYSELF, TAKE THE DECISION TO DIE INSTEAD.” DUDE, ARCHER THAT’S KILLING HIM.</p>

<p>“I need Trip to finish this mission, Trip himself.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EAvHo56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh fuck, shit, how did this image ge here?</p>

<p>Okay when I said this needed to be angstier, I didn’t mean at the expense of Archer’s fucking character.</p>

<p>Eventually Sim decides to die, and T’Pol gives him a kiss. Everyone in chat either laughed or yelled angrily. This episode is dumb.</p>

<p>Sim says that Phlox and Archer made good fathers, wishes them good luck, then dies. Why are we making this a triumphant thing? Anyways then we move to the intro, where, ha ha, it was SIM’S funeral all along! Trip is there watching, like “this is the wierdest day of my life”. The end.</p>

<p>I really hated that. This does not meet its concept in a good way at all.</p>

<p><strong>Carpenter Street</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cBGwwsP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s 2004 Detroit. Some shlub enters his apartment, grabs left over pizza sitting on his bathroom sink, and then gets a call. We’re supposed to relate to this guy btw according to the background info, so get ready. His name is Loomis, and he’s called to be told to bring another one, and do the sedetive right this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bZzd0LY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are… are these the first prostitutes seen in a Trek episode? I mean, technically there’s lots of dancers and stuff, but they seem to be dancing for the love of the game, there’s no capitalism. Anyways, Loomis kidnaps and drugs a hooker. This might shock you, this is one of the last episodes we have left written by Berman. Rick Fucking Berman over here like “yeah, who hasn’t related to a shlub living like a fucking neanderthal and drugging prostitutes?” The man should be on a list.</p>

<p>Back in the right fucking show, Enterprise, Daniels shows up again! He’s the future dude who keeps trying to help Archer. He says “it takes time for time changes to ripple through the timeline”. Then what the fuck was that episode where the future ended?? Anyways, he wants Archer and T’Pol to go back in time and find otu about it. Why the fuck doesn’t he go himself? “Because it took him long enough to get the clearance for this, it’d take too long to get clearance to go back himself”. WHY DIDN’T HE DO THAT FIRST???</p>

<p>Also this is maybe the first time I’d say we should send Trip on an away mission. He’s a loud belligerant asshole. He’d fit right into 2004 Detroit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Na7PH9H.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re given a Sonic Screwdriver that lets them do whatever they want, which is very boring. Rememebr when Data fit right in and hustled? “I am a Frenchman”. Archer carjacks a car, and T’Pol is skeptical he can drive it</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b9tH5pH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sorry, I keep getting reminded of better shows.</p>

<p>They find where the Lizard Xindi are stationed, but dunno how to sneak in. They see Loomis leaving though, and follow him, capturing him. They learn that he’s been kidnapping people, doesn’t know why, but he gets paid, so. Archer beats the shit out of him. T’Pol is openly, clearly disgusted by him. He thinks they’re cops. They get him to agree to sneak Archer in my pretending he’s one of the people he’s kidnapping.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F4XFBRW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This scene is one of the writers getting his anger about drive throughs out, clearly. Also he tries to get T’Pol to touch his dick by dropping food on it.</p>

<p>Archer sneaks in, and does his best to sneak around, though he ends up getting into a laser fight, while T’Pol is stuck with Loomis, and fucking HATING him. I do too. Loomis tries to blow their cover and warn the fucking Xindi, the piece of garbage.</p>

<p>Raptor in my chat gave a good thought. They could just be doing this on the Western planet, which is near them, cause they just need Human blood types. But whatever. This might not be the worst time travel episode but it ain’t great.</p>

<p>They manage to stop the Xindi and send everyone back to it proper time. Loomis is then arrested, the end.</p>

<p>meh.</p>

<p><strong>Chosen Realm</strong> - ENT
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/c8FHgjD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A shuttle returns from a Sphere after studying it, and some aliens watching them are like “ah, this is what we were waiting for”. The aliens send out a distress signal and Enterprise goes to help them. They’re the Triannon, and they worship the Spheres. They’re religious zealots, very clearly, (and look like bargain bin Bajorans) though the Humans aren’t gonna call out anyone for religious fundamentalism, that’s rude.</p>

<p>We’re really doing this. Remember this is just post 9/11 as I tell you what happens.</p>

<p>The leader, D’Jamat, puts some of his people around the ship, including next to the warp core, and they all have organic explosives inside themselves. So he’ll blow the ship up unless they do what he wants and takes him where he wants, which is back to his home planet so they can kill all the enemy heretics. It’s a fucking 9/11 planejacking episode.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ShvLiMo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We see a suicide bomber activate his bomb, it’s very gross looking. A crewman dies.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b283zpf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I want to say, I am not against a Trek episode about religious fundamentalism. I’m pretty sure we’ve had plenty. But uh, we know this was made right after 9/11, and we know exactly what religion they’re thinking about when they wrote this.</p>

<p>This gets even worse when we also throw abortion into this, as one of the fanatics’ wives wants an abortion so that her kid isn’t grown up in this cult. Holy fucking shit. Let’s just go right up and piss on the third rail.</p>

<p>D’Jamat is a calm seeming guy, rather amicable and pleasant, but every fucking word out of his mouth makes it clear he’s evil. We fucking get it. He doesn’t need to also tell a story about how he killed a child. We get it, he’s fucking evil.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XVdzy62.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>D’Jamat tells Archer that people need to die for scanning the spheres. But because he’s generous and likes Archer, he’ll only kill ONE person, and Archer gets to choose. Gee, how generous. Archer chooses himself, and he says his choice of death is the teleporter, a humane technology they use for executions. Okay, that’s genius. That’s like, a Kirkian gambit. Love that actually.</p>

<p>Archer works with Phlox to try and disable the bombs. He also gets the abortion guy to join him, cause he’s pretty unhappy about what’s happening. He also explains what makes his sect different and better than the other sect. They believe the Makers made the spheres in 9 days. They think it took 10.</p>

<p>That feels like a fucking shitpost. It’s a little TOO on the nose. It’s the same kinda corny that the black and white face guys in TOS give off.</p>

<p>Archer and Reed take the ship back by just shooting everyone. Isn’t it great that so many problems in Enterprise can be solved by just shooting everyone? This really is the 9/11 Star Trek.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TwUsMaq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer drops them off on their planet. Just like they wanted. They were gonna kill all the heretics and bring peace. Well, here’s the peace. His planet was blown up in religious war 8 months ago. The end.</p>

<p>This ended up being way better than I expected, but it’s still not very good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Talk About Metroid Prime 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/12/07/Prime4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Talk About Metroid Prime 4" /><published>2025-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/12/07/Prime4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/12/07/Prime4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ujF8y8J.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I have been a fan of the Metroid series for my entire life. Honestly, saying that is an understatement. I used to write Samus fanfic. On any given day, my favorite Nintendo franchise is either Metroid or Pikmin, which frankly means that on any given day, my favorite franchise of all time is Metroid. I own every single game (except Federation Force, cause why would I), and replay them constantly. And it all started when, as a little child, I played Metroid Prime for the first time.</p>

<p>The Prime games are some of the best that the Metroid series has to offer, if not THE best. My personal favorite is Prime 2, and while I wasn’t as big a fan of Prime 3, I’ve nonetheless been extremely excited for Prime 4. I tried to temper my expectations, but I could not beat down that little girl in me, so excited to finally play a new Metroid Prime game. Because y’all, the last time a Prime game came out was 18 years ago. Prime 3 can <strong>vote</strong>. But that length of time should also send a shiver down your spine, because a lot happens in 18 years.</p>

<p>Hello, I’m Lizstar, a humongous Metroid fan, and this is my review of Metroid Prime 4. What will follow is a very indepth review, giving some spoilers of things in the game, so if you don’t want to hear that, this is my pithy little statement about the score: In the first two hours, I was excited for more but there were a few things that bugged me. 8/10. I started the stream back up the following day, and after 3 more hours, ended at a 7.5. Started stream back up two days later, and a few hours later, it was a 7/10… and finally, by the end of a huge ten hour stream, it had reached a 6/10. It was sliding. I could not ignore the problems after 15+ hours.</p>

<p>Also before I get into this review, warning that I am an annoying feminist, and it WILL come up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sS77EEB.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But what problems could those be? Well, to set the scene, let’s talk about the development of Metroid Prime 4, which is fucking <em>nuts</em>. The game was first teased by Kensuke Tanabe in 2015, who had produced the previous games, with him saying that the game would possibly be made for the NX, which is 2015 talk for the Nintendo Switch. When it was finally announced, two years later at E3 2017, we were all super excited. But there was a murmur underneath. Prime 4 was being made not by Retro Studios, but by Bandai Namco, mainly their Singapore branch. Different, but interesting! Aaaand that was all we heard, for two years.</p>

<p>In 2019, Nintendo announced that Prime 4 was cancelled. Kind of. Apparently Bamco had not “met their standards”, and the entire thing was scrapped, and then given back to Retro, who got to work. But hey, Retro were the original devs, so if anyone could do it, it’s them, right? :D Well, 2019 Retro was a very different company from 2000s Retro, and honestly it’d only change more. I’ve looked into some of the people who came and went during this period from Retro, including someone named Megan Fausti who worked as a writer for a time on it (they are non-binary and pro-trans Samus, so GOD I wish they had stuck around), but EVENTUALLY we can narrow down the team that worked on this to a lot of people who worked at another company.</p>

<p>343 Industries was a Microsoft-owned development team mostly known for making the Halo games. God. Remember when Halo and Metroid were compared a bunch in the mid 2000s?? I haven’t thought of that in YEARS, but it’s going to come up a LOT today, so buckle the fuck up. A lot of the people working at 343 left to join Retro and work on Metroid. So as I enter into this review proper, and compare things to Halo, know that’s not a mistake. A LOT of Halo people made this. Of course, it might be important to ask, do I like Halo?</p>

<p>Not really, no! I played Halo 2 back in the day, read some books, and watched people play the other games. And my take on the game is the same take I have on every rah rah military shooter from the 2000s, like COD or Gears of War, which is that they really do not think hard enough about anything, because that’s not the point. Halo is a story about a Human military that got to where it is by creating child soldier projects that killed a LOT of children and sending them against farmers who wanted to be paid more, and that’s all in the lore, but the games are only RAH RAH MILITARY GOOD. It’s very post 9/11 to me, where the obvious atrocities of an American-inspired military are front and center, but never addressed because what REALLY matters is killing some people who don’t look like us. Gears of War does the same thing, where the whole plot is that the humans are colonizing another planet for its oil and polluting the aliens who were already on it. But that’s not what anyone who plays the games knows it for. Instead they know it for RAH RAH MARINES KILL THINGS WITH CHAINSAWS.</p>

<p>So yeah, I was a bit worried about Halo people working on Metroid. And I was probably right to be, because there’s a lot of Halo in this. There’s a LOT to cover, so let’s get started by splitting it down into smaller chunks… starting with maybe the BIG one most people are complaining about.</p>

<p><strong>CHARACTERS AND WRITING</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/12zEiI9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>About a month before the game came out, early reviews were pouring in, and one caught everyone’s attention. While almost every review went “it’s good”, one review focused ENTIRELY on a new character for this game, that it called Samus’ comic relief sidekick, Miles McKenzie. He’s a dorky Galfed engineer who won’t shut the fuck up. He’s an anxious nervous wreck. Honestly, same. A LOT of people went “oh no Prime 4 is going to suck”, but I decided to wait to play it… and my conclusion is, McKenzie is the 2nd best character in the entire game.</p>

<p>That is not a great thing.</p>

<p>Yes, when he’s following you, McKenzie is kind of obnoxious. “Hey, we should check that out, Samus” kinda stuff. Which obviously isn’t great. And even after he leaves your party, yes there’s a party system in this game, he’s your base command and gives you suggestions on where to go next. But it is, at worst, just the same thing as the computer from Prime 1 and 2 telling you “there are abnormal readings here”, pointing at the next items to obtain on your map. It’s handholdy, but Prime has always been like that. It is, however, a LOT more annoying here because the game is so fucking linear. We’ll get to that.</p>

<p>McKenzie isn’t nearly the worst character part of this game. Let’s introduce the entire cast. Samus gets stranded on this planet due to an alien teleporter gone awry, along with five other Galfed people, and Sylux, who’s the big bad of this game. Sylux was always built up as Retro’s cool OC they wanted to be the big bad. I’d have preferred Trace TBH. I just don’t find him very interesting. Anyways, you have five Galfeds. You’ve got the dorky engineer McKenzie, the rah rah no nonsense sargeant Ezra Duke, his subordinate private Nora Armstrong, a badass loner sniper Reger Tokabi, and a big android robot named VUE-995. You find them all in the different areas and after you’re done in each of their areas they go back to base camp. And may I say, I AM annoyed that they introduce five new characters, and four are men and one is a woman. Even the robot is given he/him pronouns.</p>

<p>For a series that is well known for having the most famous heroine in video games, Metroid is fucking awful with how it handles gender. My friend counted up the amount of named characters in Metroid, which frankly most of them are very minor, but 8 are women. 40+ are men. And we don’t need to get into how anti-feminist Metroid Other: M is again, we are all WELL aware of that. This game is not much better. But it doesn’t feel intentional or anything, it just feels… uninspired and like no thought went into it.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ovFIdNfraMk?si=uPDKtWd52O08Nb3P" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Of all the characters, my favorite is Armstrong, but there’s a lot of caveats here. When she’s introduced, she’s basically a squeeing fangirl for Samus, and it takes her grumpy superior to stop her from gushing about all the Reader x Samus fanfiction she’s clearly written. I like that. But this character of hers is toned down when she and Duke accompany you in the fifth area of the game, the mines. Let’s talk about this part, because it really exemplifies what I think the problem is with the writing in this game.</p>

<p>Duke and Armstrong go with you into the mines to find the fifth teleporter key that will let you leave the planet. The mine is swarming with Grievers, which are the alien inhabitants of this planet, mutated into basically living zombies. These grievers live in the caves, so they’re blind but can dig through rock and are attracted to loud sounds, so a lot of the puzzles in the mines involve making a loud sound using missles or things, and then fending off a horde that pour out of the floor. Good enough concept.</p>

<p>You have to hold off a horde while a drill mines through the floor to allow you access. You do it easily cause you’re Samus Fucking Aran and they all die to one charge shot. Then you and Armstrong drop down, and Duke goes “CHANGE OF PLANS” and uses the drill to block the path forward, going “IT’S UP TO YOU NOW, SAMUS”. His comms then go silent as he’s torn apart by zombies.</p>

<p>Now, you may notice that this gutrending sacrifice is <strong>fucking stupid</strong>, because THESE THINGS DIG THROUGH ROCK. YOU’RE NOT BLOCKING JACK SHIT. Also I didn’t like Duke that much anyway, so it just feels more stupid than emotional, like they intended. But it gets so much worse. Fangirl Armstrong, destraught over her superior’s death, becomes despondant and morose, until finally she has her OWN heroic sacrifice, using a digging machine to cause a cave in to block the Grievers from reaching Samus, giving a “it has been an honor to serve with you” speech before you hear her scream in pain on the other side as she’s eaten alive.</p>

<p>WHAT THE FUCK?</p>

<p>The robot comes down after this too, and he has his own sacrifice, but I didn’t mind that as much, because that one involves him literally not being able to get across a giant chasm as some Grievers approach, so he tosses you to the other side as he’s taken down. That’s fine. But Armstrong and Duke’s heroic sacrifices have all the emotional weight of… well, Halo 5’s writing, frankly. And then, guess what?</p>

<p>They’re actually fine.</p>

<p>On your way out of the mines after getting the keys, you get to the elevator and Duke and Armstrong are there like “Hey what took you”. They then go “what, you didn’t think those things could take us down, could you? ;)” and then that’s it, that’s all the explanation we get. Straight from the Anthony Higgs school of survival. YES, YOU CAN TELL I’M A METROID FAN BECAUSE I REMEMBER “REMEMBER ME’S” ACTUAL FUCKING NAME.</p>

<p>What the fuck was the point of this entire situation if A) the entire thing was a waste of time cause they weren’t blocking shit with their sacrifices and B) it just didn’t happen in the first place? It legit angered me. And that, dear reader, is the thesis of what is wrong with this writing.</p>

<p>They don’t fucking think anything through.</p>

<p>This isn’t even the worst story thing, though. The worst part legit made me ANGRY, and maybe even more clearly shows that they don’t actually think hard enough about what they’re doing and saying.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0pKv8mr.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Samus enters the ice area, going towards a frozen research center. She walks out onto the ice as a storm awakens. Deep in the storm, ice wolves begin to stalk her, circling around her, and occasionally coming out of the wind and pack to attack. It’s actually a kind of cool scene, nice set piece. They die to one fire shot, and I had 50 ammo, so I killed them, easily. And then I killed more. And more.</p>

<p>They occasionally drop ammo too, so SIXTY WOLVES LATER they were still coming, more and more aggressive, until I finally fell… but I didn’t die. Forced death! That’s a thing in Metroid games but uh, usually its the final battle, not the start of the 3rd area in the game. I digress… the cutscene starts up, and a turret spins up from the facility, and shoots at the wolf pack. Two wolves die, and the rest freak out and run away. When we reach the facility we find that our hero who rescued us was a cool badass loner sniper type character.</p>

<p>IT SURE IS GOOD THAT A BIG STRONG MAN WAS AROUND TO SAVE SAMUS ARAN, WOMEN CAN’T DO ANYTHING.</p>

<p>Obviously they didn’t intend it that way, but DUDE. Even if it was another woman who saved her and we were completely ignoring gender dynamics, it’s STILL BAD, because I KILLED SIXTY OF THESE FUCKING THINGS. Its like the wolves were trying to wingman for this guy and make him look good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wVIvz4H.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So yeah, your hanger-on characters aren’t anything special, they’re kinda cookie cutter Halo soldiers, except for Armstrong who I’m gonna commission art of Samus fingerbanging. How about the villain? The villain in this game is Sylux, who was Retro’s poster child baby for a long-ass time. He was introduced in Prime Hunters as Samus’ rival, and then they weren’t allowed to use him in a game as the bad guy until finally just now. We’ve been waiting for 20 fucking years for this guy to be the big bad, and after all that build up, he kinda fucking sucks.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qRRZQjh.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>His backstory is he was a galfed soldier who ignored orders and got his entire squad killed. Samus showed up and offered him a hand, and he slapped it away. He now hates Samus and the Galfed with a burning passion. This is a bad and stupid backstory for your big bad villain. Ridley just wanting to kill things is more engaging.</p>

<p>Anyways, Sylux has taken over a group of Space Pirates and is raiding the Galactic Federation, who are researching an alien artifact they found. Sylux has cloned some Metroids and is using them to mind control people. This barely comes up at all. Most of the bosses are metroid mind control’d, but we find out at the end Sylux has actually not actually been around, he’s been in a vat of psychic liquid the entire game, so I guess the metroids just did that for fun. Anyways, Sylux shoots the artifact like an idiot, it overloads, and everyone is teleported to a planet. Samus is then told by the psychic ghost of an alien she’s the chosen one, his entire race is dead, turned into those zombies I mentioned earlier, and he wants her to grow a Memory Fruit from a sacred tree, which contains the memories and history of his people. That plot point is kinda cool I guess, though we never learn what causes the zombification, and we do not fix it, so that feels like a story deadend there.</p>

<p>The ending straight up sucks, though. After a two phase boss fight with Sylux in teleporter space, Sylux is defeated and falls down. Samus goes back to her friends and starts up the teleporter, but oh no Sylux comes back. They can’t stop him AND use the teleporter, it’ll short circuit! So all her friends sacrifice themselves to hold Sylux back so she can leave.</p>

<p>This is straight up a Halo ending. You lead a group of plucky soldiers, and they all sacrifice themselves so Master Chief can Finish the Fight. It sucks. This is not what Metroid is, or should be.</p>

<p>But all this pales in what might be the worst writing in this game, the worst character of them all… SAMUS HERSELF.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PF4yiS3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Samus as a character is something we take for granted. She almost never speaks, she usually doesn’t interract with others, and she just goes in, kills things, blows up planets, and then leaves. She’s a cool quiet badass. And that’s fine. But the people around her ARE characters who DO speak. So they’re speaking to Samus, and then it shows Samus’s reaction, which is always… nothing. Just standing there like a brick fucking wall. No thumbs ups, no body language, no ball curled into a fist as people die around her. Nothing.</p>

<p>There are TWO good character moments, and of course they’re both with Armstrong. When Armstrong first nerds out over her, she kinda moves away slightly like “woah, what the fuck” and then later when she defeats Sylux and comes out of the portal dimension, she hugs her and Samus just awkwardly pats her on the back. That’s fine! Samus being an awkward dunno how to interract with people character is fine, but it’s not even that for 90% of the game.</p>

<p>It also doesn’t help that McKenzie’s job makes Samus even less of a character. Allow me to explain. You find chips that give you shot upgrades. But unlike every other item, it’s not just integrated into your suit, it needs to be put in “by a Galfed engineer level 4 or higher”. That’s Miles. You go aaalll the way back to base camp, he nerds out over the chip, puts it in your suit, and you move on.</p>

<p>Samus can’t work on her own fucking suit? If we NEEDED this kinda thing, I think Samus could fucking do it herself. Show her out of her suit, grease on her face, as she works with the internals of her suit. You KNOW people would go fucking feral.</p>

<p>All in all, the writing and character in this game is just straight up bad. I ONLY liked Armstrong, and that’s because like sees like. And I know a lot of people will react to this like “well of course, Metroid shouldn’t ever have any writing. There should be no characters, no writing. Metroid should be a game where a silent badass bounty hunter goes to a planet, kills people, then blows it up”. But I disagree. Metroid COULD do writing well. Case in point, Dread. Dread had some writing in it. And added two new characters. AND those characters are BOTH MEN, so I should HATE it, right? But no, I didn’t. I thought Dread’s story was actually handled fantastically. I love Bird Daddy, as I call him, as a villain. Samus fighting her father figure is cool, and the Chozo are awesome. So it obviously CAN BE DONE. It just hasn’t been.</p>

<p><strong>LEVEL DESIGN</strong></p>

<p>Oh my fucking god.</p>

<p>This is the worst part. Honestly, if the only flaw was the writing, I’d barely care. But no, it’s not, not by a long shot. Allow me to set the picture. This game has five areas, each of them seperated by a giant circular desert, so it’s kind of open world. Lots of people have complained about the open worldness of it already. The desert is large and not very interesting to navigate. Music for the desert is hidden behind amiibo, which is fucking nuts. It’d be like if you had to buy DLC for the ocean music in Windwaker.</p>

<p>Out in the desert, there are a few little mini dungeons with one or two puzzles in them to explore. Six over all. There are a few upgrades littered around. And there’s a lot of green energy. I’ll get to that later. I’ve seen a LOT of complaints about the desert. And you know what? It’d not terrible. Not great, but like, I don’t care. The enemies that attack you suck ass though. They’re boring and spawn over and over. It’s not nearly the worst part of the design, though.</p>

<p>Here, let me show you a map of the first area. Maybe you can tell me the problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/euvc2bY.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Getting the picture yet? Here’s another area.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sGqF2R3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>How about now?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Vsrydur.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s right. EVERY FUCKING AREA IN THIS GAME IS A CORRIDOR.</p>

<p>This is not a metroidvania. This is a fucking low effort FPS. There’s no exploration. THough there IS a lot of fucking backtracking. In that last one, the volt forge, you can’t go to the very bottom of that middle tower until later in the game, so you gotta come back to back track. This isn’t like a “where do I do” kinda thing cause it’s hidden behind an obvious upgrade, just come back once you get the upgrade.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oW3CJax.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Compare that first map I showed you to the first real area in Prime 1. You’ll see the difference IMMEDIATELY. Lots of loops, lots of exploration. Metroid Prime 4 is like you’re playing Metroid Prime, but every single area in the game is Magmoor Caverns.</p>

<p>All the actual rooms and puzzles are good, though. That’s the worst part. It still plays okay and is fun that way, but it’s just NOT engaging or interesting. Oh, and the enemies suck-ass too. Like, imagine Prime 2. You’ve got only 3 areas, but each area has unique monsters and enemies. AND that game has the dark world, so there’s new enemy types there too, even if they’re similar to the light variants. In this game, there ARE some unique monsters… like, maybe 1 for each area. But every area instead uses the same 4 drone and 2 tank enemy designs, over, and over, and over. It’d be like if you were playing Metroid Prime 1, but 90% of the enemies in EVERY area were Space Pirates. It’s extremely fucking boring.</p>

<p>I cannot stress enough that all this is SO much worse than the story and writing being bad. Metroid has never been about the writing. It’s about the vibes and the level design. Our vibes are hurting, and our level design is dead. I was NOT surprised to hear that the Halo team worked on this, because it really does feel like Halo 6. It’s a corridor shooter, but occasionally you scan things and do a Metroid puzzle.</p>

<p>Oh, all the items are kinda uninspired too. It’s all your typical MEtroid Prime upgrades, but with “Psychic” tacked onto it. The ONLY new item is basically the Stinger Missiles from Metal Gear Solid, and they’re there for me to constantly forget that I can use them. This isn’t like, a BAD thing. The Metroid collectables are all good. Though for most of the game, missiles are useless, so there’s no real excitement from getting missile packs, cause you can’t just spam them like in Prime 1.</p>

<p>Let’s talk about one more bad thing about the game design. So, remember how in all the Prime games, you get all the items, complete the areas, and then you need to collect some items in order to get to the final boss? Well, that’s here too. There’s a kind of energy here called uh… green energy. Creative. It’s in the form of green crystals scattered around the desert. There’s also some in the mini dungeons, and some in rocks you can power bomb. You need to get at least half in order to beat the game. I was collecting crystals the entire game. The ENTIRE time I was in the desert, I was driving over green crystals, as I went from one spot to the next. I did everything in the game, until I got to the point where I needed the crystals. And I had less than 25% of what was required. It took me two hours of driving around specifically to harvest crystals to get what I needed.</p>

<p>This sucks ass. I know a lot of people dislike the Prime 1 and 2 artifacts, but uh, they’re not NEARLY this bad. It was annoying and boring, in the worst way. At least with Prime 1 and 2, it involved exploration. There was no strategy or excitement here.</p>

<p><strong>ART AND STYLE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A0EbQLv.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>We’ve been doing a LOT of negatives, let’s talk about a positive. This game looks great. Samus’ suit is gorgeous, especially the new suit designs. Some of the background art is a little… Avatar, but it still looks good. The music is quite good too, when it plays (GREAT DESERT, HELLO). Though the vibe isn’t quite there, since the game is so chatty and so Halo, it really doesn’t feel like Metroid.</p>

<p>Though a lot of it is very uh, well it lends itself to Metroids of the past. I got into a fight once where the Prime 1 theme started playing. No real reason for it, but my brain lit up cause I like that song.</p>

<p>Also, there’s a bike! I haven’t mentioned it yet cause it really isn’t a big thing. It’s there to get you across the desert faster. But there are a few bosses with it as the primary weapon. It’s cool. Giving Samus a lesbian bike is a good idea. Though I imagined it’d grow from her suit. Instead, it… appears. Alright.</p>

<p>Oh right, on more thing. This is a door in the game. Does this remind you of anything?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ySSa6l3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is maybe the most yonic Nintendo game I’ve ever played. All the doors are like this. And some of them require you to play with a fucking circle at the top of it to open it, I am NOT fucking kidding. I can tell that the people in charge of this game were straight cis men, but I can also REALLY tell that there were some lesbians working on this and sneaking things in cause fucking look at this.</p>

<p>….Don’t have much more to add. It’s good.</p>

<p><strong>Gameplay</strong></p>

<p>It’s pretty much just Metroid Prime! Gameplay is good! It’s fun to kill and dodge things, and the bosses are nicely designed. I will note, this game changes the gameplay ever so slightly. You can aim while being locked on, moving the aim around while just the camera follows the thing you’re locked on. A lot of the bosses are basically this: They have a big glowing weak point, and you can’t lock on it, instead you have to aim a bit more to hit it while locking on the center of the monster. This is technically more complex and interesting but I kinda find it more annoying, cause I am bad at aiming.</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>In conclusion, Prime 4 gets like, a 6/10. And I am being very, very generous. Gameplay wise it really is fine, but every other thing about it… it’s barely a Metroid game, honestly. And you can tell, the Development Hell it was in REALLY did a number on it. Going through multiple teams, an entire remake, I’m frankly stunned it exists at all. But I’m worried.</p>

<p>Metroid exists in a very nebulous spot in the Nintendo arsenal. Nintendo has never liked Metroid, and have basically only been making the games out of spite for a very long time. They’ve tried to kill the series multiple times, only to stop when fans yelled (rest in peace Chibi Robo, which was not saved by fans). And any time a Metroid game comes out, I PRAY for it to be good even more than any other game, because if it’s NOT good, that might be the last fucking Metroid game I EVER play.</p>

<p>This was not very good. But it also was barely a Metroid game. Metroidvanias aren’t easy to design of course, and especially 3D ones, but you can clearly do it. Prime 1 and 2 are some of the best games ever made. I’m not saying do those again, of course. But you can create a really cool metroivania work to explore in a 3D space.And even the story can be done well, I’m sure! Like I said, I think writing and character and story is a thing Metroid could do, and do well.</p>

<p>You just need to hire women.</p>

<p>Once again, my annoying feminism rears its ugly head, but really, if you gave Samus to the lesbians, we would write the best fucking thing ever.</p>

<p>While I do hope we get more Metroid Prime, if it’s from this team, I might sit it out, honestly. Games are expensive. This cost me 70 dollars. <strong>I bought a Switch 2 for this game,</strong> so that’s even more on top of that (though obviously I use the Switch 2 for more than just this). I dunno if I can justify 70 dollars for more 6/10 Metroids. No one else is making Prime clones, sadly… but maybe we’ll get that eventually.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading my LONG-ASS review of this. I had a lot of thoughts. And I’m sure I’ll keep thinking about it. For the day after that fucking wolf thing, I was that one grumpy Homer in bed meme. I might play some Prime 2 to cheer myself up. At least we’ll always have that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Modern games" /><category term="Metroid" /><category term="Metroid Prime" /><category term="Switch" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 202</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/05/OOCY201-Copy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 202" /><published>2025-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/05/OOCY201%20-%20Copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/05/OOCY201-Copy.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GIlnGdo.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: #Gal and Gal Yuri</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Gal and Gal Yuri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 201</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/05/OOCY201.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 201" /><published>2025-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/05/OOCY201</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/05/OOCY201.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CaQzmPr.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gS3bTh2.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Warning! Beware of the Dog</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Warning! Beware of the Dog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 200</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/02/OOCY200.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 200" /><published>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/02/OOCY200</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/02/OOCY200.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/10COSBw.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Unaware His Majesty Is a Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Unaware His Majesty Is a Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 199</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/01/OOCY199.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 199" /><published>2025-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/01/OOCY199</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/12/01/OOCY199.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VgdQD72.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Nevermore</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nevermore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 1-7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/30/LizstartrekEnt3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 3 episodes 1-7" /><published>2025-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/30/LizstartrekEnt3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/30/LizstartrekEnt3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EAvHo56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p>Welcome to season 3. Berman and Braga will be taking the backseat… but not yet, sadly.</p>

<p><strong>The Xindi</strong> - ENT
2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/s8Vjp6y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a scene to start with a council of a bunch of aliens, many very different designs. I like em! They’re like WE MUST FIND AND STOP THE HUMANS.</p>

<p>And then we get the theme song and what the fuck?? They completely changed the instrumentation. It was apparently made more upbeat and chipper. It’s a weird guitar, and the voicework sounds like they isolated it from the original recording so it’s weird as shit, almost like it’s missing some tones. But either way, why the FUCK would you want to make this more upbeat and chipper? It’s a fucking 9/11 allergory, what the shit are you doing</p>

<p>Okay, a few important notes. 1) Archer is weirdly grumpy and angry. Joy. And 2) There are some new characters!! MARINES. Yep, Archer asked for some marines to come on board. They’re fine enough for now, but god. This shit is 9/11 vibes, isn’t it?? Military, oh boy. That goes so well with Starfleet. They’re members of MACO, the Military Assault Command Operations.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8XlGfpY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get a meeting with some miner foreman. He appears to snort liquid platinum, and wants it in exchange to talk to a Xindi that works in the mines. The Xindi comes up and is like “Yeah uh, we’re treated like slaves here. Get me out of here, and I’ll tell you my planet’s coordinates.” Trip attacks him. I am very much not looking forward to a season of angsty angry Trip and Archer. Anyways the Foreman betrays them and locks them down there, but the Xindi works with them to help them get out.</p>

<p>He explains that there are five distinct species of Xindi, which all look different. And none are dominant over the others, but there are arguments. Phlox mentioned that the DNA was weird. His DNA, this human-like one, is related to the lizard corpse they found, but not 100%. Weird. I don’t think thats how that works.</p>

<p>The escape plan fails, but they’re rescued by THE MARINE! RAH RAH! LOTS of people die in the process. We even get a girl marine fighting someone! Holy shit what? Anyways the Xindi is shot just outside the ship, which Neli called and got VERY angry that she was right about.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6SImuPd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They treat this guy like shit, go “WE’RE GONNA LEAVE YOU BEHIND” after he’s annoying and tries to throw them under the bus to save his own skin. Dude he’s your only lead. Anyways, he gives the coordinates before he dies. Okay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/C2IHTqX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh no. Ohhh no. Oh no oh no oh no. They’re gonna push this romance aren’t they? She uh, teaches him some Klingon Neuropressure… in order to try and help him sleep. But it’s clearly sexual and romantic and I am going to fucking scream. Why <strong><em>DOES EVERY WOMAN IN SPACE WANT TO FUCK THIS FUCKING GUY</em></strong></p>

<p>JUST PUT T’POL AND ARCHER TOGETHER FOR GOD’S SAKE. IF YOU’RE NOT GOING TO DO THE CORRECT THING AND PUT HER AND HOSHI TOGETHER.</p>

<p>The episode ends with the Insect Xindi being overly aggressive. Of course they’re the aggressive ones.</p>

<p>I don’t like this. A very, VERY bad omen.</p>

<p><strong>Anomaly</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uGLEJmu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise suddenly gets the shit beat out of it by some anomalies. Apparently there are some weird anomalies in the expanse that break the laws of physics. Are they ever gonna be explained? I highly doubt it. They limp along and find an alien ship that has no atmosphere and no biosigns. Archer, Reed, and some nameless marines go aboard. They find corpses. Two days ago. Whatever killed them is still nearby.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Eso9rv0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Aliens come aboard and attack. It then becomes a  bunch of action sequences, of Enterprise characters trying to stop the pirates who are attacking. The pirates steal a bunch of cargo before teleporting out, though one of them is stunned and captured.</p>

<p>Archer is still a weirdly angy little pissant, acting kinda pissy towards T’Pol. He goes down to talk to the pirate they captured. He’s like “you can’t torture me for the info, you’re too soft. You have too much morals” and Archer goes “There’s too much at stake. I don’t have time for morals.” Don’t like that. Really do not like that. This ain’t gonna be no In The Pale Moonlight.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z6rK2fC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise chases the pirates, and finds a weird anomaly. Inside of it, they find some kind of giant manmade object. A giant sphere in space. They take a shuttle inside, finding a big door, and find some tubes moving large energy through, as well as some ports with breathable atmosphere inside. They find the pirate’s stash inside, with all the stolen shit and a bunch of other stuff which they take.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JQlR7T4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer continues to be EXTREMELY fucking angry. He realizes the prisoner might know anything about the Xindi, and fucking screams at him, drags him to the airlock, and almost kills him. The prisoner then gives him all the info he wants about his pirate friends and the Xindi. Torture! It works!</p>

<p>Do you all like those episodes where the captain you know and love gets really angry and become Ahab-y? How about a whole mother fucking season of that? Now, since the show has really constant continuity, this MIGHT turn out to be something good in the long run, as Archer realizes he can’t lose his humanity for this. But uh, I fucking hate this. I didn’t even like Archer that much to be honest? He’s already my least favorite captain, I think, but this is pretty bad, frankly.</p>

<p>The codes and info he gets works, and they defeat the pirate, so they let the captive go. The captive mocks them about it. Alright dude. The episode ends with data they downloaded from the pirates flashing across Archer’s face as he looks at a screen. How the fuck could you get ANY information from that?</p>

<p>This is not making me confident about the season.</p>

<p><strong>Extinction</strong> - ENT
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fvJopqt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start the episode with an alien running through a jungle, persued by Firebats from Starcraft, who light him on fire, and he dies screaming. What the fuck?</p>

<p>Hey, I know what you wanted more of! Trip x T’Pol romance! Oh fucking boy!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N6fj5Qx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Trip gets a foot massage from T’Pol. I’m sure SOMEONE is turned on by this, but its not me.</p>

<p>Anyways they find some readings that maybe some Xindi are on a planet nearby, and they go down to check. They find a crashed ship and some corpses, but none of them are xindi that they’re aware of.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4CB01py.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone immediately starts mutating, becomes super aggressive, and yelling in some alien tongue. Everyone but T’Pol, who is mutating KIND OF but not fully. Vulcans sure are resiliant. You know how Vulcans are super strong and powerful, right? Yeah, well that’s why she immediately runs away when they attack her, trips over a fucking root and immediately knocks herself out. We’ve NEVER had strong T’Pol this entire time. Even when she was horny. What ever happened to They Have Great Strength When Aroused?</p>

<p>Rick Berman should be sent to the Hague. He wasn’t one of the people who wrote this episode, but he should be anyway, it would make me feel better.</p>

<p>All the mutated Humans swarm her, hissing and chittering like they’re season 1 Ferengi. That’s a very bad thing to be compared to. Except its <em>even worse</em>, because Mutated Archer is horny and wants to fuck T’Pol. Also the pacing is bad, it just keeps showing them being weird and creepy. People go down in suits, grab Reed, and take him back. He’s apparently infected by a Mutagenic virus. At the same time, an alien ship shows up thats like “You are now under quarantine, prepare to be boarded”. Trip stands his ground. The aliens say they’ve been combating this virus for 60 years and the only way to deal with it is to kill the infected so it doesn’t spread.</p>

<p>So we know how this is going to end. The white saviors are going to swoop in and solve it in two days, what these aliens couldn’t do in 60 years. BTW the alien is played by a black guy. I don’t think that was intentional subtext, but it IS fucking subtext.</p>

<p>There’s some weird shit with a dead city and genetic memory of it. The aliens come down to kill people, and T’Pol is once again thrown around like a sack of potatos, but Trip saves her. I want to scream. They warp back up, the aliens are like “WE’RE GOING TO KILL YOU” and then Archer walks out of the fucking door, fully fine. Holy SHIT they solved it off screen. What the fuck? That’s just… incompetent.</p>

<p>Archer decides to keep the last vial of the virus. He claims that the virus was a last ditch attempt by a species to keep the species alive. If he killed the virus, those people would be gone, and he refuses to cause the extinction of a people. Dude. That’s not how this works.</p>

<p>Remember that Voyager episode with the beacon that made people relive the last days of a civilization being war crimed to death? And they were like “we can’t destroy this, that’d be like erasing history”. This is like that, but instead they just shove the beacon in a drawer and forget about it forever.</p>

<p>This was just bad. Incompetently written. Even Braga thought it was bad, and Braga has VERY bad taste.</p>

<p><strong>Raijin</strong> - ENT
2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rVNhsCH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>First we get a Xindi Council scene where a guy is like “I NEED MORE TIME TO CREATE THE DEATH STAR”, then it goes to more naked Trip and T’Pol time where Trip’s first words are “You can go harder” and I want to throw something through my window.</p>

<p>They go down to a planet looking to get some Trellium-D, which is a thing that can help negate the anomalies in this region of space. They get specifications on how to synthesize it in its liquid state, though its apparently highly unstable like that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XBQkHWw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They meet and get info from a slave trader who trades in hot women, and then one of the hot women, a lady named Raijin, is like “omfg please take me with you” and they beat the slave trader up and free her. Okay, the right thing to do, for once.</p>

<p>Archer, no. No, Archer. No no no. Do not romance the slave girl you just freed. Do not fall for and romance the slave girl you just freed from slavery, Archer NO, NO ARCHER, YOU’LL BE CANCELLED ON TWITTER ARCHER, DO YOU WANT THAT ARCHER?!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kNc20Sb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She starts wandering the ship and is IMMEDIATELY a sussy baka. She’s very flirty with everyone… and then she comes onto T’Pol. She apparently has some mind control sexy powers. Oh boy, time for more SEXUAL ASSAULT. She overwhelms T’Pol mentally, which is the ONLY THING Y’ALL ALLOW HER TO BE STRONG WITH, and then when she breaks free with Trip’s help (OF COURSE), she overwhelms her physically too. WHAT THE FUCK IS WRONG WITH Y’ALL? She then goes on a fucking firefight through the ship, trying to escape as she calls for evac. Eventually she’s captured.</p>

<p>She says the words “She shouldn’t have resisted”. I need a drink.</p>

<p>ARCHER ANGY. GIRL WAS HOT AT ME, NOW SHE’S BAD, SO IT’S TIME TO BE ANGY &gt;:(</p>

<p>She explains that she was sent to collect genetics data to help the Reptilian Xindi build a bioweapon to wipe out Humanity.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZfV6c3M.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some Xindi board the ship and rescue Rajin. Two Reptiles and an Insectoid. They succeed, but not before the Humans scan their ship, their warp capabilities, AND capture one, who dies via suicide pill, basically.</p>

<p>Back to the Xindi council, everyone is PISSED the Lizards and Insects went above board and risked teaching the Humans more about them. Rajin tries to defend the Humans, but is thrown out before she can. The end.</p>

<p><strong>Impulse</strong> - ENT
2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v5SfvLU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a cold open with them trying to shove T’Pol in a scanner thing, strapping her in as she screams bloody murder, screaming she’ll kill them, screaming her HEART OUT, fade to black.</p>

<p>…
…</p>

<p><em>soft strings play</em> It’s been a loooong roaaad~</p>

<p>Jump cut back, they all get into a shuttle and fly through an asteroid belt towards the Soleil, a Vulcan ship that had been lost in the expanse and is sending out an automated distress call. THey hope they fared better than the other Vulcan ship we learned about, where everyone died violently like it was a horror movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jyE0F1X.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The horror movie continues. The Vulcans are basically zombies. This turns into Alien, but with zombie Vulcans, and LOT of flashing lights for some reasons. It also seems to be affecting T’Pol. She’s getting more and more emotional. Why do we keep doing this to T’Pol??</p>

<p>Also there’s a B-plot of Trip and mining asteroids. Okay.</p>

<p>Hey, wounded redshirt, stay behind with the Vulcan who might be losing her mind. Holy <strong>SHIT EVERYONE HERE IS SO INCOMPETENT</strong></p>

<p>There is a LOT of flashing in this episode. It’s legit really hard to even look at.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QzmenR1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Remember the season 1 episode where everyone was getting suspicious and racist, except for T’Pol, who was immune? This is just the opposite of that. And I didn’t like that episode very much either. T’Pol pulls a gun on them but is overpowerd, because she woman.</p>

<p>Phlox finds out that Trellium D is toxic to Vulcans, and breaks their brains. T’Pol can be saved but the other Vulcans are past saving, so they blow up the ship and escape. Oh good, it’s still flashing during the explosion.</p>

<p>The pacing in this episode fucking blows, I’mma be real with you. This escape takes like 5 fucking minutes and nothing happens but then running, things flashing, and shit exploding.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EAvHo56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Remember that recent episode where Archer was five seconds away from killing that guy with the airlock? And he only stopped cause the guy gave him the info he wanted? I think we’ll be returning to this image a lot this season.</p>

<p>Anyways, T’Pol is rescued, and all is well… but now she’s having nightmares about the ship. Understandable tbh. And she wakes up, Phlox coddles her, the end.</p>

<p><strong>Impulse</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zcnvRPf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh BOY, it’s a Hoshi episode! Holy SHIT, they actualyl are writing things for Hoshi? But lower your expectations. It seems to be an episode where a psychic alien fucks with a woman aboard the crew, cause let’s retread THAT TNG plotpoint, not any of the fucking good ones. Anyways she sees an alien who’s like “Hoshi, can you hear me?” and then disappears. Okay.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, T’Pol thinks she has a breakthrough. The weird things here in the expanse APPEAR to be coming from the Spheres. That means they can predict where they are. They make their way to another sphere that seems to be nearby.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tz3magI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hoshi starts seeing things again. She dreams she’s teleported to that castle from Batman Begins. When she comes to, she tells everyone, AGAIN, of what she saw, and AGAIN, they go “don’t be silly Hoshi. What a dumb woman she is” and walk away. Hey, remember how in EVERY OTHER STAR TREK PROPERTY TO EVER EXIST, when weird shit happens to a single person, they go “Okay, let’s figure this out” and don’t immediately ignore that person and tell them they’re crazy?? Yeah, I FUCKING MISS THAT. AND IT ONLY EVER HAPPENS TO WOMEN IN THIS SHOW. They only finally come around on it when Hoshi gives them imperical data and evidence. Fucking christ. They make their way to this alien’s Batman Begins castle.</p>

<p>They meet this telepath, he’s a weird ugly alien. His name is Tarquin. He’s been here on this planet alone for a very long time and is very lonely. He also has a super power. He can touch things made by people and learn things about them, like where they’re from or who they were. …Wait a fucking minute.</p>

<p>THAT’S THE POWER OF THE MAIN CHARACTER OF MY NOVELS. What the fuck?! I swear, I did not steal that idea from fucking Enterprise. Anyways, Tarquin offers to help them find info on the Xindi if he can hang out with Hoshi cause he’s lonely. He makes her pizza. The thing is, this guy actually has some pathos. I feel for him. He’s a good character. If he ends up JUST being a sad lonely dude who wants a friend, but doesn’t know how to communicate with people other than through his telepathy, that’d be really good tbh. But uh, it’s Enterprise. So it’s not going to be like that. Instead he’ll be a creepy sex pervert who’s trying to isolate Hoshi from the others so she can be his hot mistress.</p>

<p>It doesn’t help that Hoshi can only ever really give off the energy that she really does not want to be here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wCDKZFs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tarquin teaches Hoshi some psychic stuff. Woah, Hoshi Psychic Arc??? No, absolutely not. This will probably never come up again. Hoshi also finds some graves, and is extremely freaked out. He’s like “oh they’re just my exes, I live a lot longer than people so they passed away. Hey, wanna be mine? No one can understand you like I can.” Aaaaand there it is. Ahhh man.</p>

<p>Trip and Archer land on another sphere, and Trip’s incompetence almost strands then. Why the FUCK is this guy in Starfleet</p>

<p>Tarquin apologizes for trying to force Hoshi to marry him, and wishes her well. And theeen tries tricking her into staying with him by impersonating Archer telepathically. Then when she realizes it, he tries to hold Enterprise hostage. This is awful, and I do not like it. She ends up winning in a way I DO like though. By putting her fucking foot down, and being kinda badass. Like “I WILL DESTROY YOUR ONLY WAY TO COMMUNICATE WITH PEOPLE, AND THEN DIE HERE AND YOU’LL BE ALL ALONE.” Good on her. It doesn’t save the episode though!</p>

<p>He sends Hoshi one last psychic message, giving her more info about the Xindi, and some coordinates. Of course he does it in a creepy incel way, saying “I don’t want you harmed. You might change your mind about me some day~” Gross, dude.</p>

<p><strong>Impulse</strong> - ENT
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AlMSzWw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise heads for the coordinates Tarquin sent them to, which appears to be where they’re building some of the doomsday weapon. They find some Xindi, these weird furry ones. They’re mining Kemocite and shipping it off somewhere… Archer and his team attack a scientist in his home, and Archer is fucking PISSSSSED. The Xindi, Garlik, for what its worth, seems to not even know what this thing is being used for. He doesn’t know anything about a weapon.</p>

<p>Reed: “Congralations, sir. We’ve only been here 3 months, and we’re already about to destroy one of their weapons facilities.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EAvHo56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Why is Reed so unlikable. Also, wow, where did this image come from?</p>

<p>Also there’s a subplot about Trip and Phlox and T’Pol trying to learn more about the Xindi weaponry.</p>

<p>Archer continued to harass this fucking guy, who keeps denying he did any warcrimes. Eventually he pushes the bomb piece in his face enough for him to realize that yes, it was because of him and his Kemocite that his people mined. He was TOLD it was just for research. Whoops. Sometimes Archer is understanding here, sometimes he gets pissy and angry. But eventually he seems to calm down about this. Gralik explains the Xindi history. There were six Xindi species, though one is extinct now, the Avians. The Reptilians and the Insects are violent, and aggressive, and are the ones who blew up the planet during a civil war.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K0sKmr8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gralik is a calm guy, but he’s like, QUIET angry about this whole thing. At first it was at Archer pointing a gun in his face, but now that he knows he indirectly killed seven million innocents, he wants to do what he can to stop this from ever happening again. When Reptilians show up 3 days early for the final shipment, they go with Gralik’s plan. He doesn’t really mention what it is, but they’re basically just hiding him now. All the while the Reptilian leader is a Star Trek villain so he’s aggressive and unrelenting in a “HOW DARE YOU NOT BE READY WHEN I SHOWED UP 3 DAYS EARLY” kind of way, just to add the ticking clock.</p>

<p>Actual good moment for Archer. Gralik asks if he intends to blow up their livelihood and kill them, and he’s like “The attack on our planet was not your fault. And I won’t make you pay for it.” Imagine that. Reed is like “IT’S A BAD IDEA TO TRUST HIM, WE SHOULD KILL THEM ALL” cause Reed is actually kind of awful. Wow, I like Archer when he’s thoughtful and not angy, but he’s angy like 90% of the time now.</p>

<p>omfg, Gralik was chill this entire time. He was amicable. But in the end, the thing that makes him angry. The Reptilian rushing him. He’s like “FUCK YOU, I TAKE PRIDE IN MY WORK”. Go, buddy, go.</p>

<p>They end up poisoning the shipment. The Xindi taking the kemocite are like “you’re doing this to help stop a RUTHLESS ALIEN SPECIES, DON’T WORRY”. He’s a LITTLE worried, but is like “Fuck it, I trust these Humans” and helps them anyway. He wishes them luck with finding the weapon. This will delay it, but not forever.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t3XQlth.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Maybe this will end the Angy Archer Arc? Please god.</p>

<p>Actually kind of a good episode, holy shit. Imagine that. Thank god.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 25-27</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/23/LizstartrekEnt2-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 25-27" /><published>2025-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/23/LizstartrekEnt2-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/23/LizstartrekEnt2-6.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dGpcohL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>First Flight</strong> - ENT
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/s8Vjp6y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer is lookin’ at some cool Dark Matter, and then gets a call from Admiral Forrest about some guy named A.G. who died climbing Mount McKinley. Archer is super bummed about it and wants to go on the Dark Matter mission by himself, some alone time, but T’Pol forces her way on. She’s just worried about him, it’s sweet. Archer tells her about him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0Won53j.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a flashback to something called the NX-Project, a warp engine. It seems like a long while ago (seven years apparently), but uh, Archer is old as hell still, even though he’s trying to act the part of a younger man. A.G. isn’t much better. Archer is called in and told that A.G, another captain, is being given the assignment to pilot Enterprise instead. A.G. is pretty boastful about it. Turns out they weren’t really ‘friends’ per se, more rivals.</p>

<p>The test flight goes… poorly. A.G. claims he got the job because he doesn’t play by the book, and he decides to push the engine way past where it should be while everyone is like “Uh dog, your ship is gonna collapse if you do this”. It fucking does. It explodes alongside Jupiter. Everyone assumes he dies, which like… this would be more suspensful if we didn’t know he already survived this.</p>

<p>Oh of COURSE Trip is here. He claims he’s working under Captain Jeffries. Eh, a little nod. They get A.G. back, and he tells off the Vulcans, of course. Oh my GOD they explain Trip’s nickname. He’s the third Charles Tucker, so he’s the triple one. Trip. They fucking Han Solo’d Trip, but like, in series. I dunno if that really counts actually.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tC0y5nz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A.G. and Archer get in a scuffle cause A.G. claims it was his father’s shitty engine that caused the problems, and not him refusing to listen to others. He’s kinda clearly in the wrong here, ESPECIALLY cause we know the engine is fine <strong>because we’re watching a show right now where the engine is letting them move at warp 5</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5ed07F2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer concedes to A.G. about this for some reason, I don’t get it. Especially cause he proves through some telemetry that they can easily fix this problem, but the Vulcans want the Humans grounded. They just needed to prove it. So A.G. convinces Archer to steal the second test ship and fly it himself. He also promises Trip that he’ll put him on his ship if he gets a big one. Thanks for that, Archer. The flight works, proving the ship can fly. The Vulcans can’t dispute that. Though this stunt pisses everyone off, and they’re grounded for months. Got off SHOCKINGLY light. I think the higher ups agreed, prolly.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/S5HpbFX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways Archer finishes his story and we get a conclusion to the Dark Matter story, where they make the dark matter explode and light up all pretty. They name it after A.G. and move on.</p>

<p>The framing story is kinda poorly paced, but it was cute, I liked it. Also its nice to have actual world building for Enterprise.</p>

<p><strong>Bounty</strong> - ENT
2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1HIoxjj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy SHIT a Tellerite. This is the first time we’re seeing them in a very, VERY long time. One episode of TOS.</p>

<p>A Tellerite finds Enterprise above a planet, and is super friendly. Offers to come over and show them some things he’s found about the planet. He IMMEDIATELY shoots Trip and Archer and abducts the captain.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dGpcohL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>You know what this episode where our captain is kidnapped needed? A long, sensual scene where we get T’Pol and Phlox in decon rubbing gel on each other. Holy SHIT, Berman. This is by far the most egregious decon scene we’ve seen. I knew there’d be lots of these, but was expecting more tbh. There haven’t been many lately. I know they’re supposed to stop soon but we get one last one… and worst of all? T’Pol is acting…. weird.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Archer tries talking to the Tellerite about this. Apparently he’s been abducted by a bounty hunter working for the Klingons. Archer DID escape from prison, after all. The Tellerite isn’t a HUGE asshole. He’s like “Look, I’m sure you’re not a bad person, just an unlucky one. But I need the money. Sorry.”</p>

<p>T’Pol is getting VERY emotional. God please don’t be what I think it is.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0z36wbb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Fucking christ on the cross, it is.</p>

<p>Hey, remember when Spock and Tuvok underwent pon’far on screen and started acting like sexy little kittens, trying to seduce and mewl?</p>

<p>I’d watch that episode actually. Hmm.</p>

<p>Credit where its due, T’Pol’s actor is putting everything she has into it. She’s not like Troi’s actress, where if she gets something sexist and dumb she just kinda shuts down. She’s playing the horny Sex Kitten very effectively, but it fucking sucks. At least it’s with Phlox and not Trip. Can you fucking imagine? I’d have given this a 1 and left the room. Phlox is VERY professional about all of this.</p>

<p>The painful thing is the Tellerite storyline is actually quite good. This Tellerite captain’s got pathos. He made a small mistake, which is only a crime to the Klingons, and his ship was impounded by the Klingons and he was lucky to escape with his life. Gee, does that sound like anyone? It’s a good story. And even when it’s clear that things aren’t going to go well, and he’s never gonna get his ship that was stolen from him back from the Klingons, if he helps Archer he’ll just be killed. And of course they only give him 2/3rds of what he was told he’d get. Of course. I know Klingons are often dickheads but wow. Before Archer is taken though, the Tellerite gives him a lockpick so he can try to escape, and then tells the Enteprise where to find Archer.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2T3HSZd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The conclusion to the T’Pol storyline is she breaks out and runs around trying to fuck anyone she can while sweating and screaming. She’s shot and knocked out. Rick Berman should be in jail.</p>

<p>Oh, Archer shot some people with a stolen Klingon gun. Those don’t have a stun setting. Add that to his list of Klingon Crimes. Anyways he escapes. The Tellerite tells him to be safe, and it ends.</p>

<p>The A plot had a great setup but not a very good payoff, and the B plot was absolutely fucking awful.</p>

<p><strong>The Expanse</strong> - ENT
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kfX6jvN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Apparently this episode will completely toneshift the show and setup the third season, is is supposedly VERY different. I’m ready. God, I’m ready for ANYTHING different.</p>

<p>Our episode starts with an unknown probe blowing up Florida. I was cheering. Then the probe hit Cuba, and I was like “NO NO, SHIT”. Meanwhile, the Klingons go “WE NEED TO STOP THAT DASTARDLY ARCHER” and send Duras after him. When Archer learns of the attack, he’s recalled back to Earth. Trip is DEVESTATED. He IS from Florida, after all. His sister might have been among the 3 million casualties. And then suddenly, the Suliban attack and Archer is suddenly kidnapped. Wow this episode is paced REALLY fast.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u7B4XY2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Shadowy Figure is here! Remember him? He’s the Palpatine-ass mother fucker who’s a player in the Temporal Cold War, and has the Suliban working for him. He’s surely going to be important, right? Nope! This is his last appearance! :D But even though we never learn who he is, we know who he was SUPPOSED to be. Guess! It’s fucking Archer, from the future, apparently. That’s dumb, but it’s dropped so who cares.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/T61jd9o.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways Palpatine tells Archer that the attack was by the Xindi. They are aliens who learned that their planet will be destroyed by Earth in 400 years, so they’re trying to kill the Humans now to stop it. Archer returns home and is attacked by Duras, but he’s pushed off. Man this episode REALLY has a bad pacing problem. They’re trying to cram so much in so quickly. When he returns home, they learn where the Xindi are. The Xindi are apparently in an area called The Delphic Expanse, a giant region in the beta quadrant that is dangerous and barely explored.</p>

<p>The Vulcans are as awful as usual, sending some weirdo to try and declare Archer mentally unwell cause he’s talking about time travel. He lies about who he is and why he’s there to do this. Phlox is PISSED. “Where is your sense of medical ethics?!” “I’m just doing what I’m told.” YEAH DUDE THAT’S ALWAYS A GOOD EXCUSE.</p>

<p>Trip finds out his sister was killed in the attack, and becomes super pissy about it. I get it, but 2 seasons of Trip being the worst character, now him becoming a super angsty angry mother fucker… I don’t appreciate it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6cCTSIl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone gets to decide if they can stay on Enterprise… except for one person. T’Pol doesn’t get a choice. She WANTS to stay on board, and is kind of pissed. No one is happy to see her go. Except maybe Trip. Also everyone gets a scene about if they should stay, except for Mayweather and Hoshi. Hoshi HAD one but it was removed from the episode. Of course. Who cares about her, right??</p>

<p>Oh good. Trip is like “It’s a good thing she’s leaving, she’s push for noninterference, and we need to kill all of the Xindi” OKAY DUDE. YEAH, WE SHOULD KEEP HIM ON BOARD, THAT’S A GREAT FUCKING IDEA. He’s VERY Starfleet!</p>

<p>Enterprise is retrofitted and heads out, and is immediately attacked by Duras again. But Enterprise took a level up and easily kicks their asses.</p>

<p>T’Pol announces she’s resigning her commission and quitting the High Command to stay on Enterprise. Ey, first Vulcan in Starfleet? :o The Vulcans are NOT gonna like that.</p>

<p>You know what we need? A THIRD FIGHT WITH THE KLINGONS. Duras gets other Klingons to chase Archer with him, but they flee from the Expanse cause it’s scawy. Duras chases after him, cause I mean clearly nothing’s deterring him from this… I dunno why he’s even still here, the Klingons at teh start said “YOU HAVE ONE MORE CHANCE DURAS” and then gave him three fucking chances in this episode. Well, Archer FINALLY decides to kill Duras, blowing up his ship. Bout time.</p>

<p>And then they move into the Expanse, the end.</p>

<p>This episode’s pacing was bad. Hopefully this is not an omen of things to come.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>