<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-15T16:01:18-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/15/OOCY25.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 25" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/15/OOCY25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/15/OOCY25.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MBy0N0H.png" alt="&quot;Yep, cats.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>cats</p>

<p>source: laundry cat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="laundry cat" /><category term="handholding" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 26 - Hot Foot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-26.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 26 - Hot Foot" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50#26</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-26.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FGcwjAZ.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Hot Foot is one of the most important games in the entire UFO Soft canon, which is very funny, cause when I first played it, I got none of that, and it felt like the most nothing game I’d ever played. Let’s start with what the game is, then I’ll go into the very deep lore around its creation, its existence, and Gerry Smolski.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DipnogS.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Hot Foot is another sports game, which I’ve already said isn’t really my thing. It’s based on a game Smolski and Chun played in their school as kids, and it’s a kind of variant of dodge ball. You have hacky sacks, which you are trying to skid across the ground to hit the opponent. You can charge your throw, which can leave you open to be hit. You need to jump over the enemy’s sacks as they throw them at you. Each jump will charge up your star meter, which can be used for two Super Moves. Either double tap jump fior one, or charge the strongest throw for the other. These moves should NOT be ignored, they are very strong. Hot Foot is all about paying attention to your opponent’s moves, and trying to react to them, hitting them when you’re charging, or grabbing a hacky sack, or grabbing a drink, which gives you star points.</p>

<p>It’s a lot to pay attention to, especially since you’re controlling two people at once! This IS doubles. You both jump at the same time, though you need to press the swap button to move the other player around. You can also hold the button to pass hacky sacks. This is a very complex double button game, and it’s kind of a lot to learn, which is a bit of its learning curve. Once you get past that point, it’s actually kinda fun? This game ended up growing on me, and even though the cherry requirement is hard, I ended up liking it quite a bit by the end. It’s nothing SPECTACULAR or AMAZING, but y’know, it’s an alright sports game. It’s got charm. You’ve also got cute things all the characters can say to each other too, like uh, this one guy telling a one eyed kid named Jerry that he’ll take his other eye too…. huh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gzKWQFg.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>…Jerry, that name sounds familiar.</p>

<p>That concludes the review portion of the review. Now let’s talk about meta story.</p>

<p>Hotfoot is made by Gerry Smolski, and is the final game that he made with UFO Soft. after this game, Gerry Smolski, remember, one of the two founders alongside Benedikt Chun, would leave the company, in a move that is sliiiightly fishy, as the company came under new management. This was his final game, a kind of send off, and a look into both Gerry Smolski as a person, and his childhood, because this game is EXPLICITELY about Smolski and Chun’s childhood, the history says that directly. This is their school as kids, that’s their coach, these are their classmates. Jerry is Gerry Smolski, and Benji is Benedikt Chun.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AQhGAzz.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Quick side tangent, but this game ALSO takes place in the Partyverse, introduced in the previous game. The Monkey from that game appears here, and Amy, one of the playable characters, is the party thrower from Party House, as shown later down the road. She’s implied to be based on an IRL person from Chun and Smolski’s childhood, which is interesting. But that’s not what’s important here.</p>

<p>It’s 1986, and for the past year, something has been brewing in LX Systems. Or, as it’s called now, UFO Soft. They had been having financial problems for quite a while, with no big hits and not a large user base, but in 1985, they had their big breakaway hit! Campanella was a massive success, and with it, they got… attention. Introducing Tao Nemuru.</p>

<p>Tao Nemuru is the antagonist of our story. If you just look at the credits without piecing together who enters and leaves and what times, and how they work, he might almost seem like a protagonist. And HE certainly views himself that way. And in 1986, a lot of people in the company probably view him that way, too. Tao Nemuru is a rich man, and he’s entering into the company, offering to buy it and support the company with his money. He wants to be their CEO and producer, so they can keep creating the games that they love making. Sounds like a great idea, right? Benedikt Chun seems to think so. He’s on board with it, and is working directly with Nemuru, in an attempt to keep the company afloat. After all, without him, they’ll jsut shut down.</p>

<p>But Gerry Smolski seems to think otherwise… If you bring big money into the equation, if you have someone holding that kind of power and influence over you, it’ll influence the art. It’ll break what made us swap to games in the first place. The love of the game. So for the past year, there’s been conflicting power struggles in the company, but following Hot Foot, Gerry Smolski will leave the company, and Tao Nemuru will officially become the lead producer of every game after that point, and known as “the boss” around the office. Whether this will be a good thing or a bad thing in the end, only time will show.</p>

<p>Wanna know how I know all this? Gerry says it himself to Chun, and in Party House, his previous game he worked on.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sqeGhHc.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/7zNit1I.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a classic case of developers hiding their feelings about company bullshit in their games. And it’s also it’s a rather classic struggle in the industry. The struggle of money, and of letting money control us. But the story motivations of Tao Nemuru are actually far, FAR more complex and interesting than they first appear, and while we won’t really see them reflect on the company JUST yet, rest assured that I will get to them, eventually. Stay tuned.</p>

<p>Oh, yeah, Hot foot. It’s alright.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Qtb7sHF.png" alt="Hotfoot" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Bye, G.S.</p>

<p>6/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 25 - Party House</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-25.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 25 - Party House" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50#25</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-25.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RsGV6rJ.png" alt="Party" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One of the best, and most popular games, in the entire collection, Party House is one of two games that in my opinion kind of breaks that retro vibe. Because this is NOT a retro game. It is a modern game with modern sensibilities in a modern genre, with a slap of retro paint on it. This game is a deck builder, something that maybe existed at the time, but EXTREMELY not in video game form. It is a very unique experience for this kind of era, and in my opinion, absolutely whips, and is popular for a reason.</p>

<p>This is ALSO the start of a major part of UFO Soft lore: The Partyverse, as I call it. This universe, its characters, and the settings, all return over and over again, as cameos, or main characters. This is the first example of it, but I will harken back to the Partyverse a LOT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YRdPYXl.png" alt="Party" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Party House, you play the part of a party thrower trying to throw the PERFECT party. Every night, you throw a party, and as you open the door, a different guest from your rolodex will show up. Once the party concludes, you get two resources based on who showed up to the party: Popularity, used for adding new party goers to your rolodex, and money, used to upgrades how many party goers can fit in your house at once.</p>

<p>At the start you start with three different goers, or cards as I may call them, because yeah this is totally just a deckbuilder with a video game coat of paint. These three are old friends, who just give 1 popularity, rich friends, who give 1 dollar, and Wild Buddies, who give 2 popularity, but introduce the Trouble mechanic. If you have three or more trouble in your party, the cops will show up. You’re warned about how much trouble you have as it grows, and also Roof Cat is there to freak the hell out if there’s too many drunkards screaming in your house. If the cops show up, the party is busted, and you don’t get ANYTHING for that night. You can also get busted if a party goer has like, an effect that brings in another card, and your party is already full. That’ll drag in the fire guard.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JAZ4qjc.png" alt="Party" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The goal of every game is to throw the ultimate party, which requires getting 4 Stars in one party. Stars are the final resource, and are only given by expensive units that usually don’t do much other than just sit there. So yeah, fill up your deck with useless cards to win. It’s an interesting mechanic, but it works out! Once you get four stars, boom, you win! Now try to beat that scenario in a lower amount of days. There’s also randomize mode, which can give you some MEAN combos, or really easy ones. Some party goers are just straight up better than others. The climber is really just the best.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YQAKat0.png" alt="Party" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is VERY RNG heavy, and with no ways to remove any cards, it can feel like the game just fucking hates you after you open the second party in a row with three wild buddies, when you <strong>ONLY HAVE FOUR, AND YOU HAVE TWENTY PEOPLE IN YOUR ROLODEX THAT DON’T GIVE TROUBLE</strong>. Sorry. That happened a few too many times for me. Anyway, this game is extremely fun and creative and very much a “one more go” kinda game, but I cannot deny something I feel about it… it feels like it could be more. Something is missing, maybe there’s not enough here. Maybe I just want an expansion pack or something, I dunno. But I feel it could be EVEN more to become a PERFECT version of itself. But what is here is already extremely fun, and well loved for a reason.</p>

<p>Huh, interesting thing about this. Tao Nemuru is not credited in the special thanks for this game! :) That’s interesting! Well, Gerry Smolski did an amazing job with this game. It’s also cute cause it’s said that a lot of the party goer designs are IRL people that they knew. There’s a bit more I wanna say bout this and how it fits into the party verse, but I’ll leave that for next time….</p>

<p>9.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 24 - Caramel Caramel</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-24.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 24 - Caramel Caramel" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50#24</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-24.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RsGV6rJ.png" alt="Caramel" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another Chun concept, even though Petters directs and programs it, Caramel Caramel is an early shmup, very akin to something like Gradius, but with a twist, as a lot of UFO Soft games are like. It’s a side scrolling shmup where you control a cute little spaceship and her friend as they explore the galaxy, checking out all the different touristy attractions, with her new CAMERA! She got a camera, and now she wants to take pictures and go on a vacation. That’s it, that’s the concept.</p>

<p>It’s very Gradius, but without the Option system or power up system. Instead, you’re JUST your ship, no power ups to be found here at all. You instead have your camera, which you can snap a photo with to stun and weaken enemies. Most normal enemies you can kill in one hit with this, as a big clump. You can also take pictures of weird background phenomina to make crystals spawn for points. Your camera has a battery, which charges slowly, though you can also pick up green crystals to recharge it. The crystals will fly towards you, but fly VERY fast if you’re not shooting, so there’s quite a lot to focus on if you want to play at a really high level. Which is cool! High level shmup stuff is neat. The game is very challenging though, with lots of enemies, and you move soooo sloooowly. Your ship is slow as fuck, and it makes it very hard to shoot and also dodge shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Sov6fQp.png" alt="Caramel" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You have a few other tools, too. As you hold shoot, you also have a charge shot, with throws disks up and down, useful for getting some hard to reach turrets. And of course, you have your friend. This is a thing that REALLY confused me. When you die, you immediately respawn, as your friend. Then, when you die again, that uses a life, and you restart the entire stage, no matter where you’re from. It felt like, to me, the game was doing both isntant respawns AND checkpoint respawns, which confounded me, but if you think of the lives as just continues, it changes everything, cause that’s how the game treats them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/armX7LC.png" alt="Caramel" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is hard as fuck. Like an ol fashioned Gradius! But at least it doesn’t have the power up problem of dying loses your powerups and makes it almost impossible. No, it’s just ALWAYS hard, no matter what. It is fun, and very cute and charming, and the music is legit amazing, but I cannot deny that this game is a pretty hardcore not for everyone shmup. If you like shmups of this day, and this energy, you’ll prolly have some good to find here, but I think compared to other shmups, even in this collection, it’s just okay.</p>

<p>Tao Nemuru appearing again as a special thanks. We’ll get to him soon :)</p>

<p>6/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 23 - Onion Delivery</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-23.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 23 - Onion Delivery" /><published>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50#23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/15/UFO50-23.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/srNyVWL.png" alt="Onion" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Ahhh, Onion Delivery. This is one of the big ones in the collection. And by that I mean, usually considered one of the worst. People do not like this game. I’m people, in this instance. It WAS my absolute bottom of the barrel least favorite when I did my first two tier lists, but after cherrying everything, it’s now like… bottom 5. But why is Onion Delivery so maligned? It’s the directorial debut of Chiffon Bola, who used to work as a delivery driver, and I LOVE Bola, so this SHOULD be good, right??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KRbQWMG.png" alt="Onion" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Onion Delivery you play as Woogy, an alien who lives in Zorrg City, in the seedy and dangerous occupation as ONION DELIVERER. You work for Onion and Sons and your job is to drive around the city, going to randomly selected drop off points on the map, and dropping off onions. It can be described as like Grand Theft Auto 1 or 2, with some Crazy Taxi thrown in. It’s really that simple. Drive around, going to the different drop off points that it assigns you, for five drop offs. Once you drop off five, it will allow you to either clock in for the day, or do some more deliveries. You have a limited time, but after finishing your alloted five, it gives you more time for overtime. Get through the week to win, get 50 deliveries (an average of 7 a day, plus one 8 day) to retire early and live out a life of vacay. The cherry win.</p>

<p>The game starts out normal, but every day a random Day Event is rolled, shown on the television at the start of the day. These events can range from incliment weather, backed up slime pipes, roving street gangs, or aliens trying to shoot you. Everyone in this city <strong>fucking hates onion delivery people</strong>, and if a gang is driving around and sees you, they will do <strong>everything they can to make sure you are fucking dead</strong>. It’s annoying as hell! Some events are worse than others, but the worst ones are prrrobably the chasing onion mom, and the two that make the game harder to control, backed up slime and rainy weather, because…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dbrroPp.png" alt="Onion" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game controls. Like. Shit. This game feels awful to control, and even once you start getting better and better, it doesn’t get THAT much easier to control. It legit feels like you taped a rocket to some ice and are trying to race around on butter. You cannot make sharp turns to save your fucking life from a stand still, you need some speed, which is really awkward in a lot of setups, ESPECIALLY because this city is FILLED with dead ends and wrong turns, and the arrow pointing you to your next destination do NOT help. You NEED to memorize this city. I looked at a map and kept pausing over and over to figure out my route to each area. EVENTUALLY I KINDA figured out some of the map, but it was… rough.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iVCQYlI.png" alt="Onion" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I seriously cannot over exaggerate how agonizing this game feels to control. You eventually learn strategies that will help. You can hold the brake and accelerate and turn for good 180 turns. You need to let up on gas for sharper turns. You learn the routes, where to pick up extra time, the shortcuts. But nothing will prepare you for just being fucking thrown around by random events and shit. You have three health, and you regain it easily by driving fast with no accidents, or delivering an onion, which is good cause otherwise I do not doubt this would be impossible.</p>

<p>In conclusion, Onion Delivery is a game that seriously grew on me as I got better at it, and I still don’t actually like it. The style and vibe is good weird space shit, and it’s goofy as hell, but god. It just isn’t very fun to play.</p>

<p>3.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 22 - Porgy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-22.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 22 - Porgy" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50#22</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-22.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jWrJaab.png" alt="Porgy" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is another big grower. In my mind, I compare this extremely heavily to Golfaria, as they’re both very similar. Both are metroidvania-esque games. Both involve exploring out, but with a limited resource for exploration so you have to go back to base a lot. And exploration is EXTREMELY unpelasant, until get a few powerups and have some leeway in case of mess ups.</p>

<p>In Porgy, you play as Rashmi, a marine biologist exploring the ocean in her submarine, the Porgy. The fish in the ocean have recently grown aggressive, and she wants to figure out why! This is a far more traditional metroidvania, or as I assume they call them in this universe, “porg-em-ups”, or “porglikes”. Your sub floats around, and can shoot torpedos to stun fish. You have fuel, which is also your health, and if it runs out, boom you splode. Your goal is to spread out, try and find fuel and weapon upgrades, and other power ups that can make your exploration easier. Like I said, exploration fucking sucks ass at the start, but it was immediately better than Golfaria, because while they both have that painful exploration is required bit, at least Porgy is a simple like, run and shoot kinda thing, and not a weird-ass golf game where you also need to learn new controls. Porgy is much easier to pick up and play.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cCyoADq.png" alt="Porgy" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Once you get past that opening hump, Porgy is actually very pleasant and fun to explore. It’s quite large, took me five hours to 100%, and I resorted to a map for the last bit, and it STILL took me a while. It doesn’t help that you need to return to the surface every single time you get anything, which slows things down a lot. And combat really, really does suck at the start. Your weapons are weak and awful and awkward to use, and there’s no real need for it. So you have three things you can do. 1) Take a hit, which prolly means you’ll waste your time and fail this exploration dive. 2) Take a long time trying to avoid it, which wastes time, and you’ll prolly get hit anyway. 3) Kill it, which takes a long time for no reward, but at least it’s dead for the way back now. But after you refuel, everything respawns.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/k357Qnr.png" alt="Porgy" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is rather huge, and a lot of the stuff is extremely well hidden. It really was fun by the end, but I won’t deny when I first palyed it I legit kind of hated it. I got ANGRY. Especially since big bosses just roam each area, and if they appear in your path on your way back with that fuel you so desperately need, you’re pretty much fucked, do it again, slut.</p>

<p>The ending is also fucking confounding, in a way I really don’t want to spoil, but also what the actual fuck??</p>

<p>Also, there’s Tao Nemuru in the credits again! Huh, I wonder what that’s all about :) Also worth noting that this is the first game that has the UFO Soft name right there in the title. It’s official, no more LX Systems.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 21 - Waldorf’s Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 21 - Waldorf’s Journey" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50#21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OvtkuAx.png" alt="Waldorf's Journey" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is maybe the weirdest game in the entire pack, which is saying something considering the pack has Barbuta, Mooncat, and Divers.</p>

<p>I want you to imagine something, for a minute. Imagine it is alternate universe 1986. You go to Blockbuster and see a game on the shelf called “Waldorf’s Journey”, which has a cute walrus on the front. Oh boy! You love Walruses, this looks like a cute little adventure game! You bring it come, plug it in… you’re greeted with a shattered world with floating platforms and music that, while beautiful, is kind of… haunting, uncomfortable, dreamlike… You’re a little walrus, and there’s a sign near you. You move over to the sign, and read it, and it say’s the following:</p>

<p><strong><em>“THEY’RE COMING FOR YOUR TEETH”</em></strong></p>

<p>You’d be under your bed crying all night. That’s this game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FHC9MBq.png" alt="Waldorf's Journey" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is a creepy pasta. Someone concepted this game as a fucking creepy pasta. This game wasn’t made, it spawned in a garage sale sold by a creepy old man who disappeared immediately after you bought it, and no one remembers him living there.</p>

<p>In Waldorf’s Journey you play… Waldorf, a cute Walrus who’s just a normal-ass Walrus. And he’s having a dream. The closest thing I can compare this to is a “Getting Over It” style game. You can control Waldorf’s angle and his jump, as he jumps between platforms, trying to get to the end of the dream. You can flap a bit to control yourself in the air. It’s almost golf-like. Yopu have a meter to control your flapping, which when it runs out, you’re flying blind, but you can regain power by eating fish. You’ve also got shells you can pick up, which you can spend on items from shops. There’s also puffins, which will save you if you fall. Your goal is to get to the end. The game is NOT long. It’s literally like a minute long as its shortest. I won’t spoil it, because it’s quite goofy in a way I love, and it’s one of my favorite games.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B886f61.png" alt="Waldorf's Journey" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Waldorf’s Journey is very simple, and that CAN be bad. To some people it might feel like this is almost a nothing of a game. But to me, it’s weird-ass energy SELLS it, and I fucking LOVE it. God bless Waldorf.</p>

<p>There’s one other interesting thing to mention about this game…</p>

<p>This game gives special thanks in the credits to “Tao Nemuru”. This is the first time he’s ever mentioned, and while he currently is not affiliated with the company, Tao Nemuru is about to become EXTREMELY important to the story of UFO Soft. I’ll get into him later, once it becomes explicitely relevant.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 20 - Warptank</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-20.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 20 - Warptank" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50#20</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-20.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z0bw7EP.png" alt="Warptank" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Warptank is mayb ethe MOST like an NES game to me. It feels EXTREMELY like an NES game you’d play from like 1987. For 1985 it feels really ahead of its time, but it’s a damn good game.</p>

<p>In Warptank, you must save the world from the evils of Big Tank. You do this by going into the different parts of a space station, and sever its ties to “Capsule World”. There are several different levels you can go into from a big central connecting map. It’s not a complex setup, though it’s actually SHOCKINGLY big. This game is WAY larger than I expected. There are over 25 levels. That is a lot of god damn levels.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hrF9HO3.png" alt="Warptank" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You play as a little tank. The warp tank! You move along, and can press B to shoot and A to warp between the ceiling and the floor. If you warp successfully (the floor is actually there, or nothing is in the way), you’ll appear on the ceiling. So you’ve got to move along, dealing with enemies and hazards as you find a way to proceed, using slopes to move between floor/ceiling and wall/wall. It’s a good puzzly action… platformer, kind of? It’s EXTREMELY creative and enjoyable.</p>

<p>In each level there’s also, what else, COFFEE to collect! Collect them all for a bonus level. It’s very similar to Campanella in that regard, the coffee is in little hidden nooks.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DMwUInq.png" alt="Warptank" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The music and aesthetics are on point, though after my friend told me “the music can be sung to the cadence of the Mr. Bucket jingle”, it was COMPLETELY RUINED for me. 100% fucking ruined. Still good, though.</p>

<p>This game is long, and can be a little challenging at points, but it’s never unfair with unlimited lives and constant forward movement. One of the best games in the pack.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 19 - Big Bell Race</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-19.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 19 - Big Bell Race" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50#19</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/14/UFO50-19.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SHVgRIN.png" alt="BellRace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Every game company needs a Mario Kart, right? Well it’s not really Mario Kart-ish. It’s a very 80s feeling racing game, to me.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pyefDKN.png" alt="BellRace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Made in literally two weeks, using the same system from Campanella to try and cash in on the success, this game expands the Campanella universe by introducing some new characters! Most aren’t important, except for Pilot’s sister, Isabell, who will become more important later on. All of the characters are exactly the same, there’s no difference other than their color and the ending screen they get, which is the same for everyone except that it has your character on it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WQgnc9y.png" alt="BellRace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Big Bell Race is a very simple racing game that FEELS like it was made in 2 weeks. Using Campanella’s controls, you zoom through a level while smacking opponents and avoiding getting smacked. You have three health, and if you die, you start your lap over, which can basically ruin chances of getting first, unless you are VERY far ahead. And you probably will be. The AI is dumb and bad at their job. They’re just straight up slower than you. There’s also power ups you can find which increase your attack power or make you spawn bombs, stuff like that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eRRUTwF.png" alt="BellRace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a VERY simple racing game. Too simple, honestly. I do like Campanella’s controls, they’re smooth and silky, but there’s literally zero reason to play this after you get 1st in every race.</p>

<p>5.5/10. It sure is a game. One of the more interesting things about it is that it still uses LX Systems, but in the credits, says it was made by UFO Soft. They were starting to move over to that name.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 113 - Lunacy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/14/RA113-Lunacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 113 - Lunacy" /><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/14/RA113-Lunacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/14/RA113-Lunacy.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B2qAowb.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I finally got around to playing Lunacy/Torico, the final game in the Mansion series. Kinda. So, there was a game called Mansion of Hidden Souls, and then it got a sequel, called The Mansion of Hidden Souls, which was… worse, and much more poorly named. And then only a year or so later we get this, Lunacy/Torico, the final game, not technically related, but similar, same kinda thing, and built on the same themes and energies.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xxMOex2.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I call it horror, but Lunacy isn’t really horror. It’s more of a suspense thriller with an unsettling energy to it. In it you play Fred. Or at least, “people call him Fred”, because Fred has no idea who he is. He’s a wanderer, going from place to place, but he just woke up four years ago and now doesn’t know who he is. He wanders into the Misty Village one day, and is immediately accosted by the local lord, who is interested in him because of the tattoo on his forehead. He’s got a weird-ass tramp stamp on his forehead that apparently means that he was once in The City of Moons, and since escaped. The City of Moons is another world, its inhabitants immortal, where everything is cared for. It’s paradise, basically. The lord of this town, Gordon, has condemned Fred to death, but if he can find the entrance to the City of Moons, he will spare his life. Simple, right?</p>

<p>The game takes place in two parts, on two disks. You’ve got the first half, where you’re collecting items needed for a ritual to enter the City of Moons. Once you do that, spoilers I guess, the second half takes place in the City of Moons, with all the inhabitants you met dragged in as well. Things are off balance with so many newcomers, and they’re all going to fucking die, so you need to save their lives, going around and solving puzzles to save them. You can also let them die, technically. But that’s kinda fucked up. One of them is an asshole, but the rest of them are innocent regular people.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vD27Bdc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game is a first person point and clicky-esque game, though it’s less a point and click and more a… walk and walk. You can turn, and move forward towards things to interact with whatever is there. You go around, walking forward to grab items, and you need to solve puzzles. Pretty basic puzzles. Hey, the doctor wants an item, and has a pocket watch the clockmaker wants. Get the item, do a simple trade. Ah, the way to get this item is to cook paint in a silver cup? Yeah let’s just, do that, using the matches on this silver cup. Very simple stuff.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RRpenaT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The biggest thing about Lunacy is the amazing mid 90s CGI, and the absolutely amazing voice acting, which is god awful in the best way.</p>

<p>It’s not as good as the first Mansion game IMO, but Lunacy was an enjoyable time. I’d recommend watching someone play it over playing it, though. And if you do, use a guide, because the game is very samey looking and you will probably get lost, so you’ll want a map. ESPECIALLY in the second half, the City of Moons is confounding in its layout.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="point and click" /><category term="Lunacy" /><category term="Mansion of Hidden Souls Horror" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>