<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-22T23:31:18-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/22/LizstartrekVOY7-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 1 - 5" /><published>2025-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/22/LizstartrekVOY7-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/22/LizstartrekVOY7-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YNBLMoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Unimatrix Zero Part 2</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HDpKDmG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We return to find out heroes Borgified. But it’s okay, they’re still themselves! Mostly. Torres has a broken voice box, and Tuvok is slowly starting to hear voices. They’re trying to sneak a virus in, but things aren’t going immediately as planned, but at least they’re unknown for now. It’s interesting that the person most at risk of losing themselves is TUVOK of all of them.</p>

<p>Also it’s kinda nuts that Voyager just has anti-assimilation medicine, will this EVER come back cause that’s super useful</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iCiBXgb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Seven goes back into Unimatrix Zero and tries to help out from inside. We’ve basically got a three-part war here, as Voyager is also chasing the borg cube. There’s also some stuff inside, Chokie is acting captain, Paris is acting first officer, and Paris is unhappy they’re several hours too late and wants to pull them out, their lives aren’t worth the risk. They’re KINDA doing a Riker in Best of Both Worlds thing with Chokie here, but uh, the difference is Riker is likable.</p>

<p>The Borg Queen is still a Saturday Morning Cartoon Villain and I do not like her. She IS attacked by a Borg who’s disconnected himself from the hivemind somehow, though sadly it fails.</p>

<p>She also looks like she’s on the verge of crying at all times for some reason.</p>

<p>Tuvok betrays them, and Janeway is taken before the Queen. The Queen realizes some are being released due to the virus, and blows up entire cubes and spheres in front of her because ONE person there is free.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J664jw3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She eventually enters Unimatrix Zero herself, at Janeway’s suggestion. Janeway thinks she’s afraid to go in cause she’ll realize how good being an individual is, but that’s weird cause she’s THE ONLY ACTUAL INDIVIDUAL THERE. Anyways she goes in with a more diplomatic approach and tries to befriend children. “Oh it’s lovely in the collective, you’ll love it”. And that’s why you’re forcing people into it, yeah. And why all of the deaths that you’re doing are Janeway’s fault, of course. She suggests Janeway compromise.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GLiWD58.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately this seems to work on Janeway? She sends a message to Voyager and is like “Demand their surrender. Unimatrix Zero can no longer exist. I won’t be responsible for more deaths.” Chakotay somehow sees this as a coded message. I don’t see it but I guess I’m not the most shipped person with Janeway, ALTHOUGH I SHOULD BE <em>sob sob</em></p>

<p>Yeah so they shut down Unimatrix Zero so that they can’t find them there anymore, and they’ll be seperated and safe. Janeway flatly goes “I don’t compromise with Borg”, which is pretty badass, and some newly released Borg show up to help Voyager save their away team.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3vG9rBG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven goes into the collapsing Unimatrix Zero and has an undying declaration of love with this guy. It’s been my least favorite part of these episodes other than the Borg Queen shit. But my favorite thing is that, canonically, they do NOT find each other, and Seven falls in love with women instead. Hell yeah.</p>

<p>And then it ends, alls well that ends well, maybe this will effect the Borg in a good way. Maybe not. Who can say?</p>

<p><strong>Imperfection</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RcmK0Iq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get rid of the Borg Kids in the cold open. All of them but Icheb, who I’m sure will have a nice long life with us. Seven and Icheb are genuinely sad to see them go, but happy they’ll live lives with their people, and together. Icheb is also looking to apply for Starfleet, which is cool. Again, I’m sure that’ll go well for him.</p>

<p>Seven is having some problems, unfortunately. She’s hiding things from the Doctor, and her alcove is refusing to let her regenerate, saying her parts are not working. She goes to the mess hall and passes out, having a weird attack. Her skin begins to rip apart and its very unpleasant to watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rV6fQao.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Her cortical implant is exploding, and needs to be replaced, it can’t be fixed. So they need to go get a new one from a Borg debris field. Seven is also being a grumpy pissy puss about this. I mean, it’s a common response with serious illness, as the doctor says, but I dunno. Janeway is going herself, to try and save Seven, because uh, they are very good friends, yes. She’s taking the Flyer… Wait, the Flyer??? It blew the fuck up last season, and they bring attention to it too. I guess it got better in the Sickbay between episodes.</p>

<p>They go to a broken up Borg Sphere, and surgically remove a node from a dead drone, but are attacked by some scavengers. They get out pretty easily, with no problems. We then get a surgery scene with Seven dying, buuuut it’s just a simulation. Clearly the node won’t work. Seven does not take this news well, understandably.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9jV2QCb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She breaks out of Sick Bay, and where does she go? Back to work. Work is what makes her feel better. She literally says “What I want is to be useful”. And Torres, who has ALWAYS been grumpy and shitty to Seven (Seven doesn’t make it easy), is the one to stand up for her and stick with her. I actually like that a lot.</p>

<p>Icheb refuses to give up on Seven, and offers his own node. The Doctor refuses, that’s suicide, but Icheb has done a LOT of research on this. He thinks he can survive cause he’s younger and not as connected to his cortical node. Seven, of course, doesn’t give a shit. ANY chance Icheb won’t survive is enough for her to say no.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GL0Lh8U.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Icheb turns off his node in defiance. Holy shit. It shows that it can, actually, work, and there’s a very emotional scene with him BEGGING Seven to open up and rely on others for once, so they can help her, like she’s helped everyone else.</p>

<p>It works out well, there’s some more emotional scenes. I like this episode, it was a good powerful one.</p>

<p><strong>Drive</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/twPMezp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This was apparently supposed to be the next episode after Unimatrix Zero Part 2, but for some reason they aired the previous episode before this. Oh well.</p>

<p>While running some tests on the new Delta Flyer, Tom and Harry run into an open world side mission with an alien ship coming up and challenging them to a race through an asteroid field. Something something Kessel Run. I like the idea of this being a racing episode, because we’ve never HAD anything like that with Star Trek.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MwzEWyc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They beat her, and get invited to join a big race, the Antarian Trans-Stellar Rally, which they offer to join. Janeway is down, and is ready to win. And now it’s time for a ROMANTIC COMEDY, because the race was scheduled on the same fucking day Torres and Paris were planned to have their first date in a long time.</p>

<p>Actually, Torres is SURPRISINGLY chill about it. For now. It’s hinted she won’t be eventually. That eventually comes VERY soon. She’s not like, angry. She just decides they don’t belong together because he’s always too busy and they’re not right for each other. Silly me, hoping they’d be adults about something.</p>

<p>The straights are writing relationships again. I just wanted my damn racing episode.</p>

<p>Voyager becomes the host of the race, because of neutrality being needed cause some of the racing participants hate each other. Fair ‘nough.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vgJKQyl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Belanna decides to stop being a doofus and support Paris. Not just support, but SUPPORT. She takes Kims’ place as his co-pilot, which is cute.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CBsPAvQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What results is a fun little race, but also with some big political maneuverings. There’s some attacks and sabatoge that ends up knocking out one of the co-pilots, the co-pilot of the girl who started all this. Kim teams up with her to make things fair. Paris and Torres are rocky in how they’re handling this co-pilot thing. She’s trying. Paris isn’t.</p>

<p>Everyone on Voyager is REAL into this race, keeping a close eye on it.</p>

<p>Turns out the girl Kim is crushing on and working with in this race is a terrorist who wants to blow things up to destroy peace. Wow what a fucker. He figure sit out cause Kim is actually quite smart, and holds her at gunpoint, figuring out through easy deduction that she rigged a bomb to the Delta Flyer. He sends a message to the Delta Flyer just as they’re talking out their feelings. There’s a race going on here, y’all.</p>

<p>Harry sends them a message using morse code, and they need to eject the core. They have 30 seconds to warp core breach, and htey need to get away from everyone to contain the blast. While the explosion is counting down, Paris asks her to marry him. “YOU’RE ASKING THIS NOW?!”</p>

<p>They survive the explosion, and obviously don’t win the race.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u2DiA3L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kinky.</p>

<p>They get saved, and we get a cute ending with them flying off in the delta flyer with JUST MARRIED written on it and shit tied to the back. Adorable.</p>

<p>This one was alright.</p>

<p><strong>Repression</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xNot6Lr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are you ready for a MAQUIS EPISODE?! Yes, the Maquis may be all fucking dead and long gone, but not ENOUGH. We get some Bajoran nonsense from this guy, and then we see he’s talking about Chokie’s ship which is… CALLED THE FUCKING VAL JEAN. ARE YOU MOTHER FUCKERING KIDDING ME???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JJecrLv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>If you all don’t remember Eddington and his WEIRD god damn exception with Les Mis, it’s a HUGE meme in my friend group, and this DROVE US NUTS.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in a date at the holodeck, Tom and Torres find a Maquis member who’s in a coma. Apparently attacked in some way. Tuvok is put on the case. His first and only suspect is Tabor, the injured crewmember’s, best friend. Chokie is like “That’s ridiculous, I’ve known her for years!” Dude. You are, in fact, the WORST at spies and judging people, it is WELL documented.</p>

<p>More Maquis are knocked out in this way, and now the Maquis are getting jumpy. They also don’t trust Tuvok about this, because he’s betrayed them too. A Bolian is like “Could be Janeway. Could be Seven. Could be-“</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dm8o830.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tuvok is getting VERY antsy about this. He has “a hunch” and feels this all is extremely unlogical. He even starts suggesting HARRY is a suspect, cause he had a friend who was killed by the Maquis once. Harry is like “Dude are you for fucking REAL?” I like burned out Kim.</p>

<p>Also the injured are starting to wake up. They’re fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FhS2uDm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Wow no way, it’s TUVOK? Yeah obviously. He’s forcing people into mind melds. “It’s a holy time”, he says before attacking Torres and Chakotay. He’s clearly not fully in charge of his mind. He actually ends up realizing it and IMMEDIATELY turns himself in. He’s seeing a Bajoran be command him to kill and hurt.</p>

<p>We then get what is the FIRST time Tim Russ has been allowed to really super act in a while. He’s getting EMOTIONAL over this. He’s lashing out. They find out there was an awakening word in a letter to Tuvok recently, hacked by this guy, Teero. Chakotay, waking up, recognizes him. He was kicked out of the Maquis for being an extremist.</p>

<p>DUDE. YOU ALL BOMBED CIVILIANS. YOU WERE ALL EXTREMISTS.</p>

<p>Tuvok sends out a message to Chakotay and awakens all the sleeper agents now. They then fully take over the ship. I’m not super engaged in this, because I’ve NEVER liked Maquis stuff, I find it so fucking stupid. And also I find Janeway is being SO dumb here, she just does not understand wtf is happening here until Chakotay points a gun at her. “What is going on here?” GIRL. YOU KNOW WHAT’S GOING ON BY NOW, DO YOU HAVE ANY AMOUNT OF AWARENESS</p>

<p>Also after taking over and putting on Maquis clothing they’re sTILL wearing the insignia.</p>

<p>Tuvok convinces them he’s on their side by almost killing the captain. I don’t really get the scene. Chakotay tests his mettle by giving him a defective phaser, telling him its set to kill, and telling him to kill Janeway. He tried to, and then IMMEDIATELY mind melds with Chakotay after. I don’t get it. Okay, we explain it later. Tuvok had been in his senses, and knew that it wasn’t charged because he wouldn’t give someone he doesn’t trust a loaded weapon. Fair.</p>

<p>Anyways they fix things VERY easily, turning everyone back to normal, and nothing happens ever again? This was meh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YNBLMoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At least we get this fantastic image.</p>

<p><strong>Critical Care</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TQ5W0ay.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a scene of a really awful hospital situation. Some smarmy con artist schmoozes his way through and offers a head doctor something he found. The Doctor, in his holoemitter. Uh oh. He’s VERY unhappy about this but immediately starts treating people. The ship here is VERY low tech and he doesn’t have all the ammenities he wants, but he dives in anyway, while complaining, mind</p>

<p>This shit is just the American healthcare system.</p>

<p>Meanwhile on Voyager they find out they got a fake, IMMEDIATELY realize who did it, and go hunting after him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YJlnR3B.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They take the Doctor from the horrible triage conditions to “Level Blue”, which has rich patients with boo-boos. His absolutely priority. It really, REALLY is just the American Healthcare system. Apparently their computer, the Allocator, assigns who gets the care around here. And for SOME reason its assigning it to the rich and powerful. Gee. The Doctor IMMEDIATELY tries to sneak helping other people. The computer won’t let him. So he begins stealing medicine for them instead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aWuCdYe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile Voyager is on a wild goose chase to find this thief. It’s just a Stembolts plot again.</p>

<p>The Doctor is eventually caught. The kid he was treating is basically killed by restricting him medicine. But he tries sneaking around AGAIN. When his boss finds him, AGAIN…. he fucking INFECTS HIM WITH A VIRUS.</p>

<p>HOLY SHIT.</p>

<p>Note that the Doctor has ethical subroutines. He’s not allowed to do unethical things. So this is the most ethical solution he could find. Intentional poisining people. And the administrator isn’t getting ANY help for his disease from any of the other doctors there cause they’re ALL unhappy with how shitty the system is.</p>

<p>After the Doctor fixes this garbage, Voyager shows up and saves him, and he IMMEDIATELY goes to Seven and is like “My ethical subroutines are broken, please fix them”. Hah, they call it out. But yeah, they’re working fine. He did the right thing, which is almost more fucked up.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 155</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/21/OOCY155.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 155" /><published>2025-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/21/OOCY155</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/21/OOCY155.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zknkOM1.png" alt="'Boy or girl, it doesn't matter. Because you're still cute.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Madoka no Himitsu</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="not yuri" /><category term="Madoka no Himitsu" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 153</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY153.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 153" /><published>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY153</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY153.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/POzDWkx.png" alt="'But there is one thing... you confessed to me in a department store's toilet. What's up with that?' 'Ah... yes... you know... sorry.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: It’s a Secret</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="It&apos;s a Secret" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 154</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY154.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 154" /><published>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY154</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/19/OOCY154.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6ruJXLF.png" alt="'Babe...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jsiwztt.png" alt="'Babe!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 152</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/17/OOCY152.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 152" /><published>2025-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/17/OOCY152</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/17/OOCY152.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/l1VH6w1.png" alt="'You guys really are too close.' 'Yeah, we're going out.' 'Ah, I see.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: It’s a Secret</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="It&apos;s a Secret" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 6 episodes 21 - 26</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/15/LizstartrekVOY6-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 6 episodes 21 - 26" /><published>2025-06-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/15/LizstartrekVOY6-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/06/15/LizstartrekVOY6-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/s1q86nz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Collective</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Hh1jPt5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some miners are excited to meet Voyager and make a deal with them. Apparently Voyager needs some Dolomite to save sick kids, so they’ll trade some dilithium for it. The away team beams down and uh, uh oh. That don’t look like Tuvok.</p>

<p>So yeah, some people are impersonating Voyager. They steal the Dolomite and get the fuck out. Meanwhile, ACTUAL Voyager is dealing with some nonsense. Janeway tries to shower and her shower screams at her and breaks the mirror. Imagine how horrifying that’d be. They find the problem, and it’s a thing given to them by some monks who were raising money for sick orphans. Ahh, I see.</p>

<p>We find out that Neelix and Tom got cheated by this group. The girl of the group was VERY excited to hear a WOMAN was in charge of the Voyager. Also there’s a B plot about how Tom and Neelix are grumpy that they got marked. Can you imagine a B plot that’s fun, AND fits the actual episode and builds from the A plot?</p>

<p>After Voyager gets yelled at by some angry miners, it’s time for a hunt. They find them being attacked by another mark, who then turns on them thinking they’re the Voyager protecting the Delta Flyer. The “Delta Flyer” gets away, but they get “Captain Janeway”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lXVVrLP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get some fun shit with Janeway trying to con this conwoman. She makes Tuvok lie. Tuvok is not good at lying. Neelix goes to the conwoman, Dala, and tries to be nice at her. He gets his ass kicked and she escapes with his gun. Neelix, why did you bring a gun in??? OH it’s cause they were intentionally letting her escape so she’d lead them to them.</p>

<p>The episode from this point off is like the old ball and cup game that Neelix and Tom are playing. Lots of deception and hand offs. Turns out Tom snuck aboard the delta flier that Dala stole. They then do a teleporter switcheroo and replace her with the Doctor, who “betrays” them as Dala.</p>

<p>Also one of the impersonators has been REALLY getting into the character of Tuvok. When he meets Tuvok he’s so excited and is like “logic dictates neither of us have the advantage in this fight” and Tuvok goes “Your logic is flawed” and beats his ass, it’s good.</p>

<p>This episode is goofy and fun.</p>

<p><strong>Muse</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/krN9CLf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On a primitive, Ancient Greek-like planet, a play is put on about some a Voyager story, where Torres crashes onto their shores after sending Kim out an escape pod. The patron of the play loved it, and is excited to hear more stories about this Torres. The Poet, Kelis, is apprehensive, but can’t resist his patron. He then goes off to his muse… who happened to be a captured Belanna Torres in a crashed Delta Flyer not far from there.</p>

<p>Torres comes to, and is like “wtf is going on also why did you cut me up” “Oh I was releasing the heat from your body, that’s how you treat fever :D” “Oh god.” While she was out, he listened to her audio logs and wrote about it. He believes she’s an “Eternal”, a god basically. But she’s a new Eternal they’ve never heard of, from a new clan. It’s got some Steven King Misery energy. Torres agrees that if he lets her go, she’ll give him some more stories. She kinda leans into the “I’m a god” thing by saying they have rules, and then almost shoots him to get him to leave. But when things aren’t going so well, she can’t fix her ship, and is hungry, so he feeds her in exchange for stories.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bBaVfwi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They make a new deal. Some dilithium, which is only on his patron’s lands, or no more stories about Voyager. Don’t get caught :). Their partnership is VERY strenuous. He’s not unfriendly, but Torres is Torres.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/H0cRd8b.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>LOL this dude trying to teach his actors how to play his parts, and getting REAL into the specifics. No no NO, a Borg wouldn’t act like that!! No no no, LOGICAL Klingons do not CRY!!</p>

<p>His Patron is going to war soon, which will cause famine and kill a lot of people. But Kelis has a plan… a SHOCKINGLY progressive one. Her magic cannot stop a war or change minds, sure, how you know what can? Culture. Writing. Words. We can write a play to try and convince the world of peace. He convinces her to come and help him directly. But no one but the players can know she’s an Eternal, or the patron might try and capture her to get her to help him declare war.</p>

<p>It doesn’t go well at first. The most he can think to do to bring passion to the play is make everyone kiss. Torres and him talk it through, and he decides a good idea is to instead have an enemy, the Borg, and the Borg Queen. . Captain Janeway goes on a mission of vengeance, but finds instead the desire to bring peace. That’s a good ending!</p>

<p>There’s also a thing with the poet’s lover being jealous. She claims if Torres shows up she’ll expose her as an Eternal. Ah, the woms be cray cray. And Harry Kim finding Torres. He explains that he landed 100km away and walked. Holy SHIT, Harry. With Harry’s help they contact Voyager. They’re gonna be alright! But what about the play? :o Torres finds she’s REALLY gotten into this play. So she teleports in to save the play.</p>

<p>The lead actress, in a fit of jealousy does in fact cry out that Torres is really an Eternal, but he’s like “Oooh it’s part of the show :D”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A1Zsgal.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nice cute scene with her in the end as she beams away, saying that they don’t need her, as long as they do what’s right. It’s a cute episode in all!</p>

<p><strong>Fury</strong> - VOY
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rTp11NS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway is grumpy that Tuvok has been hiding something from her… Oh, it’s his birthday! Aww. He blows out the candle, but only cause it’s a fire hazard. Anyways then Kes shows up, demands to be let on board, beams on board just before ramming her ship into Voyager, and walks down the hall as it explodes like its a fucking action movie. Huh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ujcT4Ey.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s causing bulkhead explosions and harming people as she walks down the halls, using magic mind powers to do it. So many people are PROBABLY dead. Torres at the very least is dead, but probably so many more. Kes touches the warp core then vorps out of our reality and into the past.</p>

<p>Back in the past, she’s sneaking around the ship, morphing herself into a young version of herself. She captures her younger self in the hydroponics bay, which I don’t actually think we’ve seen since Kes left Voyager a few seasons ago.</p>

<p>It’s fun to see a Voyager that’s pretending to be season 1. Janeway has her bun. Doctor can’t just wander everywhere. Kes and Neelix are dating. We even see Naomi’s mom!! I wanted to find ANYTHING they fucked up, but the only thing I could find is that they were still using that weird dead lipstick that they’ve been using for Janeway this entire season.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wFTzYHz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back in the past, they’re trying to avoid some Vidiians, which Kes is taking some real interest in. Also Tuvok is getting confused. He’s talking about the Delta Flyer, staring at Kes like “I sense a disturbance in the Logic”, and sees Naomi Wildman in the elevator. He then wanders into a Borg infested cargo bay. Weird. He goes to explain it to the Captain, explaining what happened. Which sets in to motion that they know something is up.</p>

<p>She scans Tuvok to see what’s up as he has a seizure, and they realize it’s Tachyons. Those mother fuckers again!! Just as the Vidiians show up and attack on Kes’ suggestion and orders. Ey, the first continuity error, they’re using the wrong phaser rifles! Janeway confronts Kes who’s like “I was corrupted by your ideas, a CHILD! You took me from my home! I BELIEVED YOU!” Okay Kes, whatever. Janeway ends up having to murder Kes, and they manage to hold off the Vidiians. Everything is alright. For now. She needs to stop this from happening again. Time to cause a temporal paradox!! Or y’know, multiverse theory shenanigans.</p>

<p>In the future, everything happens as usual. JAneway had ALMOST forgotten, but once Kes shows back up, she evacuates Deck 11 and puts on shields, avoids her from blowing up most of the ship. Most of the damage is reduced, but not entirely. At least there’s no deaths.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5yzoY7j.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kes’s hologram shows up and talks to older Kes, begging her to not do this. Trying to get her to remember who she was. She eventually seems to come to a weird understanding, she had kinda forgotten somehow?? She comes to her senses and is no longer violent, and decides to go home. Back 30,000 light years I guess. It’ll only take her six fucking years.</p>

<p>I feel this episode didn’t explain or show the reason why Kes would suddenly be evil. Ocampan Dementia??? I dunno. IT’s not explained well at all, and so it kinda falls flat. The novels apparently make this even worse, cause Kes merges with another Ocampan who’s pregnant with a caretaker and makes an evil Kes clone, it sounds stupid as fuck.</p>

<p><strong>Life Line</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WBELKzi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>More than just an infuriating but weirdly fun PS2 game, it’s another episode about the Alpha Quadrant! Barclay has gotten in contact with Voyager and the Pathfinder project is going amazingly. What ISN’T going well is his mentor’s health. Dr. Zimmerman, the man who invented the EMH, is sick and dying and no one knows why. Last time we saw this guy he was a horrible dickhead to Bashir.</p>

<p>Back on Voyager, they get good news. The Pathfinder Project has found a way to send information! A datastream. It uses a quaser, but only works once a month. They can send info back up to 16 hours later. Letters from home. Sounds nice. Everyone gets letters, including the Doctor! It’s from Barclay, who wanted to let him know that Zimmerman has only a few months to live. They never “met” really, but the Doctor views him as a kind of doctor, and thinks he can cure him using some Vidiian and Borg technology! He asks to be sent in the datastream, which no one is SUPER happy about, but they allow him to cause he’s VERY adamant about this. It doesn’t go well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tBvYykk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Zimmerman is, as usual, the absolute worst. He looks down on the doctor cause he’s a lowly mark 1. He intentionally sabatoges the doctor’s attempts to scan him. He’s just a general nuisance. The Doctor can’t leave for another month, so he just has to put up with it. Also, the actor is AMAZING with this, Zimmer man has such a different way of talking as Zimmerman, it stands out. Reg wants to help, so he also calls the only person who MIGHT be able to help. Troi is here! She wants to try and counsel Zimmerman. Good luck, girl.</p>

<p>Obviously it doesn’t go well. Zimmerman is very bad at dealing with people, and frankly so is the doctor. But EVENTUALLY they get through to him because Zimmerman is only good with one thing, and thats holograms. He has two friends. One is Reg, and the other is his assistant, who is a hologram. Older than the mark 1, even. And when the Doctor’s program is in danger, he DOES step up to fix him. THough he also tries to “make him better”, which the doctor does NOT want.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eK4bLo6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually they come to an understanding. Zimmerman is pissed at the EMH and hates it, because it was his biggest failure. And it’s a failure BECAUSE of him. He made it just like him, and no one fucking likes him. They’re all literally scrubbing barges now, all with his face.</p>

<p>Also it turns out Reg set up a thing to cause the degredation in the Doctor’s program and almost destroy him. All to try and push for this to happen. And it worked! Zimmerman FINALLY allows the doctor to work on him, and it works out. Cute episode. I hope the Doctor doesn’t return to find that everyone is dead cause of Tom being the surgeon on call.</p>

<p><strong>The Haunting of Deck Twelve</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0r5GCuU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Something is happening, and they need to turn off the power as they move through a nebula. All of the power is shut off and they float through. As it turns off, the kids wake up from their regeneration, and Neelix is there as their chaperone! He has stories and games! But they’re interested in one thing in particular. Naomi has told them there’s a GHOST on their deck… so Neelix has them gather around, and tells them a ghost story. It’s time for an episode of ARE YOU AFRAID OF THE TREK!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Q3p69Yf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Several months ago, before the kids had come aboard, they were in a nebula, sucking up Deuterium from it, when they were ZAPPED by something! Something had boarded Voyager… ooooh, ghosties! Things start malfunctioning. Anything they try to figure out why it’s happening isn’t working. Chakotay almost dies as the elevator breaks. Seven is trapped by force fields and poisoned by the creation of a micro nebula.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/s1q86nz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The kids are very into the story.</p>

<p>More problems happen. All of them seem to relate to the idea of re-creating the nebula they were in before. Also that Bajoran from the lower decks episode is here! I liked her, even if the episode was kinda meh. She’ll never appear again. Anyways all the banter on this is REALLY good. Voyager suffered in the early days from a Lack of Banter, which is SUCH a Trek thing. Good Trek Needs Banter. The episode is KINDA like that episode of TNG where everyone is split up into groups as the Enterprise is broken down. We’ve got Neelix and Tuvok, Tuvok trying to calm Neelix as he has panic attacks. Kim and the Bajoran trying to find others. And the Captain trying to communicate with this thing taking over her ship, which is communicating through the computer’s syntax. “Captain Janeway, please report” kinda stuff.</p>

<p>THey learn it joined by accident during the nebula destabelizing, and when they go to try and return it, they find it gone, fully. Its home is gone, so it decides to blow up Voyager. Everyone has to evacuate.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Dcyco3b.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The creature won’t let Janeway go though, and almost kills her, but she convinces it to let them take back control of their ship. This was of course, just them delivering the lifeform. Unless of course, everything Neelix made up was fake. The powe rcomes back on, and Neelix packs up. Of course it WAS true, and he hopes it lives happily ever after as they leave the nebula behind.</p>

<p><strong>Unimatrix Zero</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n1yRfwl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with the Borg Queen harassing some drone and being overly evil mustache twirlingly villainy about dismantling him because he has a disease. I really, really dislike the Borg Queen. Always have. They needed a villain for people to latch onto but she makes NO sense for the Borg and she’s SO human-y in her evilness, like, she’s NOT Borg, at all. It’s annoying. She even uses contractions! What kind of a Borg uses contractions?!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Seven is dreaming. She hates it. Of course she does.</p>

<p>Tom comes to work and everyone is grumpy with him. He finds a box on his chair, and what’s in it? Oh, why it’s a pip! He’s being promoted back up to Lieutenant! :D Good for you, Mr. Paris. I guess they got tired of writing around it. Also this happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JC4uvlW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh Harry, you know you’re never getting promoted.</p>

<p>Someone in Seven’s dream contacts her. He explains this isn’t a real dream, it’s a a shared dream amongst the borg, specifically ones with a genetic mutation. They’ve been here in the dream for years. They all know each other and interract each night. Seven did this every night for 16 years, and made lots of friends there, as she’s told. This seems like it was just written up now, and not quite fits in. Anyways they call it Unimatrix Zero, and some of the people there want Seven to help them break them out doing some technobabble and making the entirety of Borg join Unimatrix Zero.</p>

<p>Tuvok uses Vulcan Magic to link Janeway with Seven’s mind and send them both into Unimatrix Zero. At the same time, the Queen is being stupid and I hate her, and she’s like “It is time to PAY THEM A VISIT, MUAHAHAHA”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6MjouqL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They invade the dream and assimilate them in the dream so they can find where exactly they are. Janeway fights them off with a fucking Batleth that she picks up from a fallen Klingon. When the Borg Queen sees her….</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nke07r9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Apparently they’re rivals or something. I guess she DID ruin her plans for Locutus 2.0.</p>

<p>They develop a virus that will not only protect the dreamers from being found like that, while also making sure they wake up with memories. They need to do a dangerous thing to try and spread it through the Borg, but they gotta do it. They get a message, though. Kim does the whole “Captain, I think it’s for you” thing that makes this feel like a TNG movie more than a Trek episode.</p>

<p>She offers them transwarp if they fuck off. That’s honestly the funniest thing. “You’re such a god damn hassle, please leave”. Janeway refuses, she’d prolly be betrayed anyway tbf. They begin the operation, infiltrating a Borg Cube, with the Queen watching like “Ohhh I expected more from you” like she’s a fucking Batman villain watching Batman sneak around her hideout. The Borg also blow up the Delta Flyer. Rip Delta Flyer.</p>

<p>They’re all caught and injected with nanoprobes, assimilating them. “So far so good,” Chokie says, leaving, and we get a scene of Janeway and the others as drones</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5cRYkgC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>To be continued!</p>

<p>One more season, so only like five more weeks of Voyager. This was a GOOD season? Like, the best Voyager season by far. Some stinkers, but a LOT of good episodes. Very worth watching.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 151</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/13/OOCY151.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 151" /><published>2025-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/13/OOCY151</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/13/OOCY151.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7yBCJie.png" alt="A panel from some Yuri Manga. Two women are by the ocean. 'Huh? What did you say? I couldn't hear you clearly over the waves' One asks. The other responds. 'I wouldn't mind falling... even to hell. As long as I'm with you, Takara-chan'." class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gT5tAWd.png" alt="'It would be heaven to me.' She finishes, as the first woman looks at her with the gayest God damn expression kiss already do i look like I care that you're married to some dude" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Pinky Candy Kiss</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Pinky Candy Kiss" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 183 - Cranston Manor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/13/RA183-Cranston.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 183 - Cranston Manor" /><published>2025-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/13/RA183-Cranston</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/13/RA183-Cranston.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qoPCT7u.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I got on a bit of a text adventure kick. We’ll be seeing a lot of them in the coming bit. This is a 1981 graphical text adventure by none other than Sierra Entertainment, who’d go on to be fucking humongous in the 80s. But this is still pretty dman early in their career. Hell, they’re still just called “On-Line” at this point, they’re not even Sierra yet.</p>

<p>This is one of the games in the “Hi-Res Adventure” series, a series of games for the Apple II that are text adventures, but with graphical images to show a general idea of where you are. A cute idea for the time, though the art is usually pretty…. rough. There’s this vibe that early Apple II art has that just tells me it was made by people who never actually learned how to make art. Perspective is wrong, things are just off, and god forbid if we get humanoid shapes. You don’t NEED to have the graphics on if they’re distracting though.</p>

<p>One of the weirder things about this is it’s actually a port. This was made by someone named Larry Ledden for Atari 8-bit computers. Sierra acquired the rights to port it and make a graphical version, which they did, though Ledden isn’t even given credit in this version.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HTFEVVB.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Cranston Manor is a simple game with a lot of the trappings of other text adventures of the day. In it, you just sneak into the manor of a dead millionaire and steal the 16 treasures that are kept inside. That’s very Zork. In Zork, your goal is to wander around, solve simple puzzles, explore, and find treasures to bring back to a central location. This is basically just that, but with a manor.</p>

<p>As a text adventure, it’s perfectly fine. A little confusing at times? But the puzzles aren’t overly complex. Like for example, uh, there’s a robot that follows you to make sure you don’t steal anything. But he’s afraid of mice, so you take some cheese and mice start following you, so he runs away from you. Simple, right?</p>

<p>Over all, this isn’t a text adventure anyone remembers or talks about, but it’s an interesting blip in Sierra’s history!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Sierra" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 150</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/09/OOCY150.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 150" /><published>2025-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/09/OOCY150</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/06/09/OOCY150.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wVAfhxR.png" alt="'The feeling of a nipple! I've lived my whole life unaware of the feeling of a nipple...!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Young Lady Wants to be the Protagonist of a Love Comedy!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Young Lady Wants to be the Protagonist of a Love Comedy!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 182 - Zork I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/08/RA182-Zork.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 182 - Zork I" /><published>2025-06-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/08/RA182-Zork</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/06/08/RA182-Zork.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wcR0ZN7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I recently played Return to Zork, and talked a bit about the later Zork series, but I cannot stress enough how big Zork really was. Like, it was HUGE. One of the first big smash video games. Originally released in 1977 for mainframe computers, it had to be split into three parts with later home computer releases cause they couldn’t even handle it. Only one of these actually has achievements so far, so I’m just playing Zork 1 for now.</p>

<p>Zork is not the first text adventure. It was inspired by Colossal Cave Adventure, which also wasn’t the first, but was probably the first well known one. Well, well known among nerds. The creators of Zork all worked at MIT and were huge nerds. Zork itself is based on a Huge Nerd terminology. It was slang around the office. The word “Zork” was just the file name MIT nerds in the 70s used for programs they hadn’t named yet, and then it stuck and they didn’t want to change it to anything else.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lsTo4hy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Zork is weird and irreverent. It’s built on fantasy games like D&amp;D and whatnot, but it’s also got a lot of American energy to it. The way I always describe it is, Zork is Midwest America’s Discworld. A lot of that is still here in the first one, but to a lesser degree. The lore of Flatheads is kinda here, we have the Dam here, you can visit it.</p>

<p>Zork is really just a giant maze, with some smaller mazes thrown in, and a lot of really weird “puzzles” that usually involve bringing an item from one far off room to another. Once you break it down into its constituent parts, it really isn’t that complex and doesn’t take a long time. Fuck, you can turn the entire winning playthrough into a song. Here you go: https://debsanderrol.bandcamp.com/track/walkthrough</p>

<p>Is Zork GOOD to play these days? Eh. It’s more interesting than anything, and I have a deep love for it, but like, there are much better text adventures to play, even. Just play Zork Zero.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Zork" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>