<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-09T12:12:37-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 133</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/09/OOCY133.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 133" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/09/OOCY133</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/09/OOCY133.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BiBaHwe.png" alt="'You wanted to become a girl and be loved by girls, huh?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Manga About a Hero who Pulled Out the Holy Sword and Became a Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Manga About a Hero who Pulled Out the Holy Sword and Became a Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/06/LizstartrekVOY5-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5" /><published>2025-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/06/LizstartrekVOY5-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/06/LizstartrekVOY5-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lEMFojx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Night</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w6YtUOn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with a cheesy B-movie with big Flash Gordon energy. Both Kim and Paris are super into it. All the special effects look like shit and its black and white, I genuinely love that. Paris claims it’s sociology, cause they’re studying how the 20th century viewed the future. Thats really cute. I love seeing each group love a different kind of classic shlocky story (Detective Noire, James Bond, and then this.)</p>

<p>Also, they FINALLY have Seven out of that fucking corset. They realized they didn’t need to try and force her to be hot, she was just… naturally hot.</p>

<p>Anyways the ACTUAL plot is that they’re two months into an expanse, and there’s no signs of any stars anywhere near them. For two fucking years of travel. It’s only been two months, and they’re all feeling kind of stir crazy. There’s been no exploration, nothing. They’re doing FINE, they’re able to survive, but it’s making everyone grumpy… and freaking out others. Poor Neelix has a panic attack while trying to calm down others who are angry. And all the while, they’re picking up some theta radiation…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eJluwa6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway seems depressed as hell. She’s secluded herself in her room, beating herself up about making everyone stuck in the Delta Quadrant for years. It’s kind of a bad time for this, considering everyone likes her and are feeling restless. Like, she’s upset that she chose to save people she didn’t even know in episode 1, rather than her own people. This will probably be a theme for the episode.</p>

<p>The silence and boredom gives way to sudden massive panic as Voyager turns off. No thrust. No power. Nothing. This does NOT help poor fucking Neelix. I hate watching Neelix have panic attacks. We’ve got everyone split up in different groups. And then it turns out we’re not alone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zd9OaXb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some aliens, cloaked in the blackness of space, have shut down the power of Voyager and boarded. They’re aggressive, and do not react to diplomacy. Seven IMMEDIATELY knocks one out because of course she does. And then they’re saved by a ship coming in to save the day.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MIE2K3T.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Emck, of the Malon. They’re the Druuj. They’re just STRAIGHT UP the Druuj from Star Control 2. He’s a sleezy little fucker who demands compensation for saving them, says he’s just here to transport some stuff. Oh I’m sure. But he DOES offer them a way out of this space, a vortex that takes them to the other side. Well that’s helpful! Let’s get the other side, though… the Night Alien explains that his people have been there for a long-ass time, peacefully living, but then the Malon showed up and are killing them with some kind of radiation they don’t understand. That’s the theta radiation. They look into what Emck is doing, and yep, he’s just dumping a shit ton of toxic waste into the expanse. They offer him a way to teach how to recycle, and he’s like “Nah that’d put me out of business, I make LOADS of dosh off of polluting this space, I’m good”. He’s a sleezy fuck.</p>

<p>Well, the MORAL thing would be to destroy this vortex they use to hop here, and save the Night Aliens. But they can only blow it up from this end, which would strand them here for two whole years. The crew claims they can live with that, but Janeway can’t. So she goes and declares what’s going to happen, stepping onto the bridge for the first time in two months. She’s going to commit suicide, allowing them to go on ahead and then blow up the vortex, leaving her behind in the Void. So she tells them to go on ahead as she uses a shuttle, aaand everyone refuses.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XJHXqnH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s a sweet reaction. Everyone cares about her, and no one blames her like she blames herself.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u5cIkIH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They do a dangerous maneuver to blow it up with torpedos thrown behind them, and ride the shockwave to the other side. The Malon ship is stronger, but the Night Aliens show up to save the day, and they blast forward through the vortex, which was destroyed behind them. That maneuver didn’t take them ALL the way through the expanse, they still have a bit left. But they’re close. And then they see the first star at the end of the expanse, and make it through to a bright new day.</p>

<p><strong>Drone</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K5u1Bgv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Seven practicing smiling in the mirror. I hate it. To be fair, so does Seven.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nJx1nET.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, Paris, Torres, the Doctor, and Seven are on a shuttle watching a thing explode, but it explodes too well, and they need to be teleported out. This new dude, Ensign Mulchaey, is like “I can’t seperate their patterns”, so we’re threatened with a DOUBLE Tuvix, but thankfully that’s avoided and it all seems fine. Uh, except that the Doctor’s holo emitter is on the fritz. They take it off him and set it aside to work on it, and then Borg tubules splorp out of it.</p>

<p>Anyways, after a day, Seven detects some Borg on the ship. But no scans show up anything. And then the tubules Splorp into the Ensign, extract some tissue from him, and she detects Borg one more time. They go to investigate, and find that the thing had turned an entire station into an incubation chamber for some fucking reason.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VfNRA7w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is Voyager’s answer to that fucking Troi Gets Gregnant episode from TNG. This is a new kind of Borg, growing in there. They don’t want to literally abort this fucking thing, but it’s growing FAST. It’s also connected to 29th century technology in the holo emitter, so it’s a VERY advanced Borg. It’s dangerous, but without connecting to the Borg, it has no real direction yet. So Janeway wants to give IT a direction.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1R50d2Z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s not immediately reticent of… anything, really. It’s like an empty computer. Seven has to basically handhold him learning things, putting info into his brain, and he’s IMMEDIATELY more friendly and pleasant. He’s also like a little puppy, following Seven around. Neelix also kind of adopts him. I love that they needed to have Neelix and Seven take care of this guy, because everyone else is fucking afraid of him, and they’re the people most likely to not be racist.</p>

<p>Neelix says he needs a name, and tells him to name himself. He chooses “One”.</p>

<p>One is very smart. He’s a bit awkward, in that Borg way, but he’s very, VERY observant. He immediately sees ways to make the engine better and do Torres job for her. She’s at first angry at him even EXISTING, but once she spends time with him, she doesn’t seem to mind. He’s valuable, but above that, he’s also becoming a personality. He’s being his own self. He is also very much wants to learn more about the Borg. They decide not to tell him anything, in case he wants to go after the Borg. When he sleeps though, he accidentally contacts the collective… who are VERY excited to meet him, and send a sphere to collect him. Obviously can’t let THAT happen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GpbDZQw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They show One what the Borg is all about. At first he’s kind of into the idea, but when they explain it a bit further, he actually feels anxiety. In that Borg Way. “I am experiencing cardiovascular increases” and whatnot.</p>

<p>This is the first time they’ve gone up against the Borg since Seven joined them. She doesn’t want to go back. As she says, “Voyager is my collective”. One does what he can to improve their weapons, but it’s not enough… so he teleports onto the sphere and does a fucking Musou against a horde of Borg, interfacing with them to blow it up from the inside out.</p>

<p>Everyone is STUNNED, but then they get a life sign in the debris. One survived.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HoqiZ1v.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But not for long. The doctor needs to do surgery ASAP, but One has come to a conclusion. As long as he exists, Voyager is in danger. He cannot let that happen. He erects a forcefield around himself, as Seven BEGS him to let them save his life. But he refuses, making his decision. It’s actually a really powerful scene, in a nerdy Borg kinda way. Though maybe it’s more funny than it needs to be, with the way they’re talking</p>

<p>The episode ends as Seven tries her best to adapt, the new emotions moving through her.</p>

<p>I dunno WHY I feel like this isn’t a 10. Maybe it’s too close to the Lal episode, beat for beat?</p>

<p><strong>Extreme Risk</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xgIOjj5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Torres jumping out of a shuttle and skydiving onto a planet from space altitudes. She deactivates some safety and hops into space. Then she’s called the Engineering. Yep, holodeck. She’s a bit grumpy about it, and calls out, asking Seven to take over for her.</p>

<p>Anyways, a Malon freighter is harassing a probe of theirs, and so they hide it in a gas giant. The Malon try to chase it down there and fucking explode. Now the probe is stuck down there and they can’t get it back. I dunno why they need that probe that fucking bad.</p>

<p>Paris has a suggestion. One he’s apparently made a dozen times. Just build a better shuttle. Oh, just a better shuttle? Easy peezy. He’s already planned out some stuff for it, and is VERY excited to work on it more. He gets a team together, Seven, Kim, Tuvok, and of course Torres who is uh, not really there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/34eMGvf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris asks her about it. They’d gushed for years about how it’d be great to actually work together to make something, and now she doesn’t give a shit. She seems tired. EXISTENTIALLY tired. She refuses to explain, then goes back to the holodeck, turns off safeties, and beats the shit out of a Cardassian.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Malon are still anxious to get a hold of that Probe. I like how apparently the Malon are our new threat this season. Just a bunch of capitalists who want to dump garbage everywhere.</p>

<p>Tuvok: “These dials you are installing are illogical.”
Paris: “Look, I am tired of just TAPPING PANELS. I need something physical!”</p>

<p>GOD, PARIS, SAME. THANK YOU FOR SAYING IT. I CAN’T BELIEVE I’M AGREEING WITH PARIS.</p>

<p>Torres does more suicide attempts in the holodeck, almost dying, but Chokie saves her in time.</p>

<p>Janeway stages an intervention. She KNOWS something’s wrong, and kicks her off the shuttle project. She doesn’t seem to care, so Janeway KNOWS something is wrong now. No one wants to dig into her personal life or her files, but she’s a danger to herself. They HAVE to.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sR3tdB4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s diangosed with depression. As someone with depression, especially depression that’s been really bad lately, I’m NGL I’m seeing a lot of myself in her, and I’m unhappy. Anyways Chokie gets an in by pretending to be a friend who’s here to restore her holodeck privileges. And then he activates a SPECIFIC program and forces her into the holodeck. She demands that it gets shut off. He drags her through it. Chokie that’s uh, that’s not the right way to do this, I don’t think.</p>

<p>This episode has been pretty good at handling depression. So far. But this is a terrible, TERRIBLE way of handling it. Yes, Chokie, go ahead and re-traumatize the person in crisis. That’s a great fucking idea. STUPID fucking Chokie, jesus christ.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8rGGf0L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She doesn’t feel anything. Not about her friends, about her job, about Tom. She’s depressed. That’s just the definition of depression. She’s getting herself hurt not to die, or for suicide, but just so she can feel ANYTHING. This is good. This is a good subject, powerful, worthy of being shown, and being shown well. Chakotay is just handling it in the WORST WAY I COULD EVER FUCKING IMAGINE. Intervention is good. But NOT LIKE THIS. Shut the FUCK UP, CHAKOTAY.</p>

<p>And then when Torres decides that she DOES want to work, she wants to help, because she’s the best they’ve got and she wants to help her family now so nothing bad happens again, Chakotay’s like “NO, YOU’VE HAD YOUR CHANCES” before FINALLY letting her go on. Holy shit, SPACE HIM.</p>

<p>They launch the new shuttle, trying to reach the probe first. With some quick thinking and work by Torres, they manage to survive without the shuttle imploding. Seeing her do quick thinking engineering in a tanktop is cool. And hot as hell. She macguivers some phasers into a handheld shield generator. Hot.</p>

<p>She thanks Chakotay for being a shitty therapist, and then threatens to break his neck if he ever tries it again. She should have just said that second part. Then she eats some banana pancakes, and tries to let herself feel again.</p>

<p>Part of this episode is really good, but holy FUCK that Chakotay part was bad. It’s like 80% good. They were originally going to let Paris be the confidant for Torres’ problems, but they made it Chakotay to avoid melodrama. Terrible decision, but tbh if Paris had done EXACTLY what Chakotay would have done, I wouldn’t have liked it! It still would have been bad!</p>

<p><strong>In the Flesh</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zd2gdEO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got a scene on Earth, at Starfleet Command. Boothby is there! There’s also a bunch of Ferengi. How pleasant. Uhhhh and also Chakotay is there, examining it, confounded. Yeah, me too dude.</p>

<p>Boothby has a pleasant conversation with Chakotay. Well, Boothby is pleasant. Chakotay’s charisma stat is like, a 7. And then a woman comes up to him and starts flirting. Again, charisma stat of 7. And then a dude in the corner has a VFX attack.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zd2gdEO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The girl is like “Oh that’s his third time reverting this week. You know how hard it is to keep pretending to be Human. Breathing is so weird. Sleeping is even weirder. Anyways, we’re not supposed to be talking about this. How about a date? :D”</p>

<p>Chakotay and Tuvok try to leave… wherever this is, and then a guy catches them, so they knock him out and drag him up to Voyager too. Yeah, so these are some kind of aliens who recreated Earth. For what reason, who knows. When the alien wakes up, he freaks the hell out, refuses to let anyone touch him, and yells “DISEASE! HUMAN!” before releasing a toxin into his bloodstream and killing him. The Doctor finds a way to revert him back to his original species, whatever that is…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uBxoLeb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Species 11 million and 2!!!</p>

<p>Okay, so they know WHO they are. But why??? Chakotay has an in, at least. Valerie Archer, that girl who was hitting on him. He can try and infiltrate. God I can’t wait for this episode to end with Chakotay fucking a Species 8472.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tBxAUdW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Me too, Kim. Me too.</p>

<p>Neli described this as “when an anime does an episode in America”, which is very funny. Chakotay has to pretend to be at least slightly ignorant of Earth stuff, but it’s hard to tell, because he can’t act, so it just looks like he’s ignorant.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6fHmSIB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>TRANS SPECIES 8888! LFG! I’m IMMEDIATELY imagining a better version of this series, that version of the series where they add new characters on. Y’know, the one where Janeway’s girlfriend Amelia Earheart went into space with them. In this version, this girl realizes she’s wrong about how Humans are, and that Humans are cool and she likes being a Human, so she joins Voyager. Oh well. We’ll never get that reality, sadly.</p>

<p>We get a burlesque scene, basically. She strips in the bathroom, we see her naked body as a silhouette on the wall. She walks back out in a nightrobe, explains she needs an injection, and injects herself as her body blorp borps around the injection. H-hot.</p>

<p>They make out, she seems to kinda like it, and then she tells Boothby that they were right, she tested his DNA. Chakotay is captured, and brought towards the mastermind. EVIL BOOTHBY. God that’s nuts.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YbUdzjJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re infiltrating Earth, or planning to, because they’re scared of Humans, cause they developed technology to hurt them, and are doing it pre-emptively. Neither side trusts each other. So to try and show they stand by their ideals, Janeway stands down first, deactivates their weapons. Species 6969 are like “Oh. Well uh, okay”, and stand down too. Turns out they’re NOT that violent. It feels like a bit of a retcon. Remember when they were like “YOUR UNIVERSE WILL BURN”?? Oh well. Fake Boothby is like “our superiors aren’t as forward thinking, but I’ll try to get them to see you’re not violent”.</p>

<p>It ends with Valerie kissing Chakotay, cause he’s just that sexy I guess. I think Chakotay just has weird-ass pheramones.</p>

<p>This is a weird episode. This is also the last time we ever see Species 8472! Or the “Undine” as they’re known now. They will appear in Star Trek Online, but never again in any actual Star Trek media, except a few occasional mentions, but that’s about it. A shame. They’re such a cool group.</p>

<p><strong>Once Upon a Time</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oJROb1V.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got an episode about Naomi! You remember Naomi? We saw her get born two years ago, and now she’s like an 8 year old. Oh well. Anyway she’s in some kind of storybook fairytale, which is cute and goofy. It’s like Star Trek Wizard of Oz. It’s cute. I want an episode just of this, she’s a good kid actor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cOKhL6p.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, her mom is on an away mission, and can’t make it back. She’s on the new shuttle they designed the other episode as stuff goes bad. At least she’s with named characters so she has a better chance of survival. Neelix doesn’t want to let her know that her mother’s shuttle crashed, so his job is to keep her preoccupied. I think you should just tell her, but whatever. Don’t lie to kids. They’ll find out and it’ll get worse. Kids are smart.</p>

<p>Also Naomi is scared of Seven. Seven isn’t very good at stopping that viewpoint.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JSTuZrZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Naomi’s mom is injured in the crash landing. Punctured kidney, bleeding internally. Tom is a nurse, not a surgeon, so he can’t exactly help.</p>

<p>Naomi is taking classes with the doctor. The Mitochondria is the warp core of the cell. That’s SO GOOD. In this episode of Voyager, the crew gaslights a small child who wants to see her mom. Why :) Why are they doing that. Neelix pls. Neelix and Naomi go into the holodeck for another fairy tale. It’s apparently a popular kids story. They do one called “THE OGRE OF FIRE”. Sounds a bit scary. Neelix agrees. But she’s like “oh this’ll be fine if you’re with me!” It’s not fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOATixZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They watch Flotter, the blue fairy water creature, melt in front of them. It’s horrifying. Honestly, I love the accuracy for ACTUAL children’s programming, which was weirdly fucking terrifying when I was a kid. Remember The Brave Little Toaster?? I will never, EVER forget The Brave Little Toaster. :)</p>

<p>Neelix is like “Naomi shouldn’t BE HERE, a starship is no place for a kid!!” but Kim argues that it’s a great learning experience, and one she’ll never forget. Neelix has Kim replicate a Flotter doll for her, but she’s already hard at work. She’s researching evaporation to figure out how to get Flotter back in the story. Smart kid.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wQlxihk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Can’t be a cute sweet episode forever, though. Neelix is, as always, suffering from massive survivor’s guilt. He has a dream of his friends and loved ones dying. He’s struggling, so who he go to for help? Fucking SEVEN. He’s like “Do you ever think about your family?” “Infrequently. I barely remember them.” “Maybe that’s a good thing”. Constant memory and fear haunts you forever. Ask me how I know. He’s trying to protect her because of how he’s handling it. A lot of projection.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZCsDW6u.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway convinces Neelix to tell her, to get over those fears. The situation here is different from how it was for him. Why? She has him. That’s sweet.</p>

<p>Anyways, obviously Naomi is aware something is wrong. She’s not stupid. Adults are bad at hiding their anxiety. She comes on board the Bridge just as soon as she hears them talking about the shuttle crash. Ohhh, Neelix. You shouldn’t have waited.</p>

<p>They find the shuttle, but they need to dig it out. Inside, they’re recording their last messages to their loved ones. Tuvok is writing his. Paris’ is absolutely awful. Not even an “I love you”. Damn Paris, I could write a better goodbye message to my cat. Naomi’s mom’s message is heartwrenching though. The acting in this episode is very good.</p>

<p>Neelix and Naomi have a heart to heart in the burned out forest. He explains what happened to him when he was younger, how he lost everyone, and wanted to protect her. I like this, cause like, it explains WHY he did it, and it’s a good reason and understandable, but the episode does NOT show that it was right, cause it wasn’t. It shows that he’s remorseful, and makes it right.</p>

<p>In the end, they make it out. They’re rescued, and everything is good. There’s a sweet reunion, and then Naomi and her mother have fun in the holodeck forest. It’s sweet.</p>

<p>This is actually the last time Wildman, Naomi’s mom, ever shows up. Naomi WILL show up again, but not her mom. Weird.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 132</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 132" /><published>2025-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DkqsVPA.png" alt="'Know what you wanna be after you graduate?' 'Yep. Your wife.' 'Huh?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Misread It as Love!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Misread It as Love!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Blazing Dragons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Blazing Dragons" /><published>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9M9Rq3m.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is Blazing Dragons, a point and click adventure developed by Illusions Gaming Company, who mostly made point and click games you might vaguely remember based on prior properties like the Genesis Scooby Doo game, or the windows Beevis and Butthead games. It was published by Crystal Dynamics, who actually still exists, and is pretty well known for Tomb Raider. Not so much this game. This is one of the more obscure games in their repitoire, another point and click adventure game based on a prior property. This time, it’s based on the TV show Blazing Dragons… kind of.</p>

<p>Blazing Dragons was a late 90s British cartoon made Terry Jones, of Monty Python fame. My THEORY is that this game was something entirely different, and then they connected it to the cartoon because they had Terry Jones on the project. It has some of the same characters, but the designs are COMPLETELY different and a lot of the characters are changed or missing. The most interesting change is the different designs. In the cartoon, they’re very bipedal dragons, typical cartoony dragon design. In the game, they’re all taurs, which is VERY interesting. I kinda like taurs. I just think they’re neat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wVjoiyH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In the game, you play as Flicker, who starts the game as the royal inventor, I think. He’s a smartypants kinda socially unaware dork, but he has a romance thing with the princess of the realm, Princess Flame. Unfortunately, she’s set to be wed to the winner of the Knight Tournament, and Flicker isn’t a knight, much to her chagrin. So the goal of the game is to become a knight by helping the Knights of the Square table, as bumbling as they are. At the same time, the kingdom’s sworn enemy, King Geoffry the Human, is trying to take over the land with the help of his wizard Merl. They also have an evil dragon on the inside, the king’s advisor, who is not in the show. So you’ve gotta stop that too. Simple enough premise, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xtJI4GL.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game is a rather traditional point and click of the time. You’ve got a cursor that changes actions, things like look, talk, grab, use. You wander around, interract with people, solve puzzles, and collect a bunch of items that you rub on other items. The game is, for the MOST part, filled with good puzzles, but there are a couple that completely confounded me with their leaps of logic. But, in clal, it was actually a rather well crafted game, puzzle wise.</p>

<p>The big thing about the game is its writing and star cast, though. First of all, the cast is wild. Terry Kones, Cheech Marin, Jim Cummings, Rob Paulsen, Jess Harnel, it’s an all star cast, and they all do a good job. There’s ONE problem I’ll talk about later with the voice acting, though. The other thing is its writing. It’s very, VERY Monty Python. Makes sense, with Terry Jones being there. It’s a comedy that does not take itself seriously, with outrageous goofy setups and even goofier characters. It’s also very, VERY British in that way. If you can’t stand British comedy, maybe stay away. I DO like British comedy, except for oooone thing that this game is very bad at.</p>

<p>British Comedy does this thing where if there’s a female character, there’s like a 90% chance it’ll be played by a guy doing the most awful shrill cockney voice you’ve ever heard in your fucking life. British comedians playing women have ONE voice, and they really, REALLY love to whip it out at any god damn opportunity, and I HATE that voice, it’s AWFUL on my ears. This game is lousy with that voice. They got Jess Harnel to play like, one character, and then every other woman in the game is like “ELLO ELLO OIM A GOIYL”, clipping the fucking mic.</p>

<p>OTHER THAN THAT, THOUGH, the game is actually very good. Not too long or difficult, it’s well worth the time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Blazing Dragons" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Point and Click Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Blazing Dragons, a point and click adventure developed by Illusions Gaming Company, who mostly made point and click games you might vaguely remember based on prior properties like the Genesis Scooby Doo game, or the windows Beevis and Butthead games. It was published by Crystal Dynamics, who actually still exists, and is pretty well known for Tomb Raider. Not so much this game. This is one of the more obscure games in their repitoire, another point and click adventure game based on a prior property. This time, it’s based on the TV show Blazing Dragons… kind of.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 131</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 131" /><published>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9hmh7Vy.png" alt="'I love my failures the same as my successes. And I'll love your failures as well'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Curtain Call for You</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Curtain Call for You" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 130</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 130" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I6BjMEl.png" alt="'Well, can't be all bad, if it means I get to flirt with you...' *slides in for a kiss* suddenly in a crowd 'LOOK AROUND YOU.' 'Yep.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Itazura Privacy</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Itazura Privacy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 129</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/01/OOCY129.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 129" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/01/OOCY129</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/01/OOCY129.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/idnMc3u.png" alt="'So this is what it feels like when dreams come true' says a woman on a bed, as she's surrounded by all the symbols of homosexuality" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 166 - Tryrush Deppy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA166-Tryrush.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 166 - Tryrush Deppy" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA166-Tryrush</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA166-Tryrush.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sBKoZTA.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is another set that I personally made, which also means it’s a set of a game I really care about, and have also already reviewed for my obscure games series I did. So I don’t need to go over it again. But there’s a few things I can add! I had to do a BIG deep dive into Deppy to figure stuff out about it. It has a lot of hidden stuff in it I never really tackled until making this set. BTW this set’s RAM is fucked. This was an AGONIZING experience to code for.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dCWvwsX.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, Tryrush Deppy is a platformer where you play as a cute taxi cab racing across America. The thing about Deppy is that it has a lot of hidden stuff to find in each level, but the game doesn’t make it very easy or rewarding to explore a level. Usually when I play, I just try and play fast and clean to get through each level. But there are three collectables: Dramas, Stars, and Extra Stages. Each level has a Drama, some specific levels have Dramas, and each world has an Extra Stage. Stars are special mini stages where you need to get through a small puzzle room cleanly while getting all the purple stars in them. Dramas are saving different characters in a level, which can also change future level layouts and stuff. And finally, extra stages are bullshit.</p>

<p>Extra stages are hidden fake walls you can jump into by pressing up. These are USUALLY in like, billboards and things, but there’s no indication you can do this. You then get an extra bonus stage to run through, with weird-ass dog cars that bark and bite at you, and usually a mini gimmick. And if you clear the stage, nothing happens. Instead, you need to find the fake wall in the middle of the fucking level, break it, and then destroy the enemy that pops out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jLtfWDi.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Getting different combinations of collectables gives you different endings. No one knows how to get one of the endings, namely this one with the weird omake cutscenes by the author. Once you beat the game with all the extra modes, you ALSO get a time attack mode with the extra stages, getting through them as fast as possible. The times o</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Tryrush Deppy" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is another set that I personally made, which also means it’s a set of a game I really care about, and have also already reviewed for my obscure games series I did. So I don’t need to go over it again. But there’s a few things I can add! I had to do a BIG deep dive into Deppy to figure stuff out about it. It has a lot of hidden stuff in it I never really tackled until making this set. BTW this set’s RAM is fucked. This was an AGONIZING experience to code for.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 165 - Shining Force Gaiden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA165-SFGaiden1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 165 - Shining Force Gaiden" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA165-SFGaiden1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA165-SFGaiden1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JxxIbas.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>My goal this year is to play all the main, early Shining games. I finished Shining in the Darkness, now it’s time for the Shining Force games! Though for some reason I started with this one.</p>

<p>This is Shining Force Gaiden, the side story game for the Sega Game Gear, Sega’s handheld console of the time. It’s made by the same team as the Genesis one, and came out exclusively in Japan about 8 months after Shining Force did. And it is an EXTREMELY impressive attempt, to me, to translate Shining Force to a Game Gear.</p>

<p>This is also the only Shining game I can think of that’s NEVER been translated. Kind of. This game, and Shining Force Gaiden 2, it’s sequel, would later be repackaged on the Sega CD, which DID come out over here. And Gaiden 2 came out over here, but Gaiden 1? Well, fan translators decided it didn’t need to be translated, I guess, cause we already have Shining Force CD.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vkAEmux.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>SFG is a sequel to Shining Force, very directly. Taking place about 20 years after the first game, you play as the forces of Guardiana, many of which are the children of the heroes from the first game. Queen Anri is attacked by an evil wizard claiming dark powers over some evil God, and you all need to go defeat him so she wakes from her magical slumber. Or something. Look, it’s in Japanese, and it’s been a long time since I played SFCD. I didn’t follow the plot very well.</p>

<p>This game translated nearly everything from SF1 perfectly. Well, in terms of the main game bones. All the exploration of towns, hidden secrets you can find exploring maps after defeating them, and conversing with people? That’s pretty much stripped out. It’s a LOT more Fire Emblem now, with you going from one battle to another, strung together by cutscenes. And that’s perfectly fine! I didn’t dislike the exploration in SF1, of course, but it’s still a fun strategy RPG without it, IMO.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2hFJznU.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One thing I need to compliment Gaiden for is its fantastic graphics. This game looks amazing. It’s a very, VERY solid recreation of what the Genesis had for Shining Force 1, on an 8-bit handheld.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zybtYWa.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I think a lot of it is just that I really, really love the early Shining Force art style? It looks fantastic, and is translated amazingly here. Take the Narrator Girl for this game. Look at her! She’s so cute! And that usual Shining Force Character Design is here all the way through. Yes, your character of Prince Nick is pretty generic SF hero energy, but you’ve got all the centaurs, bird people, and of course Gyan/Teddy, who’s like a big tiger bear with a badass eyepatch.</p>

<p>Anyways yes, all this boiled down, it’s more Shining Force. It’s actually quite easy, though, IMO. I had some troubles with Shining Force 1 when I played it years ago, and Shining Force Gaiden 2 legitimately kicked my ass, I’ll get to that, but Gaiden 1 was easy. I didn’t use any stat boosting items or rings I found, cause it’s entirely in Japanese, and even WITH that I had absolutely no trouble whatsoever with this game, your characters are just in general very strong.</p>

<p>Even with all this, I’d prolly just recommend Shining Force CD, though note that SFCD is TWO games in one, and it feels like it. It’s long. It’s a trek. SFG is a bit more short and pleasant. It’d be great for car rides, tbh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Game Gear" /><category term="Shining" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My goal this year is to play all the main, early Shining games. I finished Shining in the Darkness, now it’s time for the Shining Force games! Though for some reason I started with this one.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 20-27</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekVOY4-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 20-27" /><published>2025-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekVOY4-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekVOY4-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lEMFojx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Vis a Vis</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pZiSY9u.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris is playing around in the Holodeck with his favorite past-time, muscle cars. It’s honestly pretty cute. I like a 24th century guy being a gearhead, it’s a fun hobby. The Doctor gets on his case about how he’s not putting enough effort into being the backup doctor, and he’s like “I didn’t even WANT to do that, I was assigned to it”. But it’s his job now, so, buh. The further we get in this show the more I like Paris. Anyways, Paris is then called to his station, so he has to arrive all covered in grease and shit which is funny, and he finds out why. There’s a weird-ass ship that’s zorping around. Paris guesses it’s a Coaxial Warp Drive, which literally folds space time around itself in order to travel real far real fast. That could be useful.</p>

<p>Too bad the warp core is exploding. Paris does some shenanigans to keep the ship from exploding, and all’s good. The alien needs some help getting his ship from exploding, so Paris volunteers, cause he’s interested in the ship’s drive. When he asks, Chokey is like “Well, you’ve had bad reports from the doctor about shirking your duties, are you okay?” and he’s like “Yes? I just don’t care about being a doctor”, and Chokey rides his ass for a minute before assigning him to work on the ship. But then he has to dip from THAT cause he had a date with Belanna. He’s late to it and she’s all pissy and angry at him, saying he’s hiding shit. Lady, he was ASSIGNED TO WORK ON THIS. What was he going to do, tell his superior officer no??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LSHXfdm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I can’t believe this show made me like Paris. I’m genuinely offended. And not only that, but it’s swapped how things were. At the start, Paris got away with a lot of bullshit, and we kept yelling at him, cause he was awful. Now, people are riding his ass and acting like he’s being awful and he’s genuinely not doing anything, just doing his job and living with his hobbies.</p>

<p>Now to be fair, Paris IS feeling that Wanderlust. He’s comfortable here, but that’s making him uneasy. He’s not USED to feeling comfortable, to being happy. So he’s kinda self sabotaging, slightly. That honestly makes a lot of sense. It doesn’t help that Steth, the alien, offers him an escape on his ship. I mean, they can go fly around and explore, and then can meet up with Voyager later! Unfortunately for Paris, Steth here has some Weird Shit going on with morphing and DNA forms and he keeps turning into a she and it’s weird. Either way, Paris gets caught up in it and gets his form stolen by this clearly fae creature, who then shoots him and takes his place on Yovager. His ship then speeds off, presumably with Paris’ corpse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I7wCo0V.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, Steth is very bad at being Tom. You’d think they’d like, actually REALLY research a person before trying to subsume their life. That seems weird.  Everyone is IMMEDIATELY sus of him because like, duh. He doesn’t even know where the fuck the Medbay is. It’s really awkward to watch. You’d think someone who’s entire life is this would be better at it. He ends up making out with Torres and then choking her out while drunk. It’s weird.</p>

<p>No, obviously, Real Paris isn’t dead. His drive has just been shut down, and he’s thrown at the people who ACTUALLY owned it, who are about to blow him up for stealing the drive. But before they can, another ship comes and scares them away, and the REAL Steth is here. Paris hastily explains whats going on.</p>

<p>Janeway confronts “Tom”, and the next thing we know, security is barging in and stuns Tom. Phew, the Doctor is safe. Real Tom and Real Steth come, and the captain is like “Okay, he’s probably the cause of all this. Hold him in a Hold on, I need to do a thing real quick”, and then dips the fuck out in a shuttle. Welp, he swapped with Janeway. But Tom convinces Chokie to let him go with a heart to heart, and he catches the DNA Swapper.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1gbfTJ2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It ends with Tom trying to open up to Torres and they make out in his Camaro. He’s all “It’s a MINT CONDITION 1960 COMARO”. Tom, it’s a hologram. Come on man.</p>

<p><strong>The Omega Directive</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KoYnbib.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Seven waking up and talking about what she’s going to do today. She’s gonna read The Christmas Carol, as suggested by the Doctor. That’s cute. Suddenly everything is interrupted by the ship dropping out of warp, and everyone is confused as an Omega symbol appears on all screens and they get locked out. Janeway is like “Hey, don’t worry. I’ll take care of it. but don’t tell ANYONE about this”. Sussy.</p>

<p>Turns out it’s sonething called The Omega Directive. Something called an Omega Particle has been detected. If that’s detected, the goal is to destroy it, at all costs. It’s very, VERY dangerous. Only Captains and above even know about it. All of the crew is curious, but not allowed to know… except one. Seven was Borg, and so she knows all the Borg knew. That includes what they learned from assimilated Starfleet captains. So she’s in on it. But she’s not interested in helping destroy the Omega Particle. She wants to harness it. The Borg think it’s possible, and ALMOST got it, but not quite. Sure it destroyed 23 Borg vessels in the attempt, but it’s worth attempting again! Oh Seven.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/M8erMDx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone has theories and fan theories. Everyone is reacting to it differently. Even Tuvok admits to being curious. That means he’s very, very, VERY curious.</p>

<p>Janeway explains to Chokie what’s going to happen. She and Seven are gonna go out in a specially reinforced shuttle with a giant bomb. Either they return happy and alive, or Voyager senses an explosion and has 10 seconds to get out or it’ll be vaporized. Chokie convinces her that this is a very special case, so she should explain to the crew what’s up. So she does. A single molecule of this stuff, when it was synthesized, existed for a second, before collapsing. The explosion killed all the scientists, but MORe important, destroyed Subspace. Warp travel is not possible in that sector anymore. Any more of this stuff could wipe out sub space in an entire quadrant, and that would be very, VERY bad.</p>

<p>Imagine that. The Federation not being able to use FTL travel. God, how horrible that’d be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nXIXBqs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They make it to the source. A planet with a horribly damaged science facility. Subspace isn’t here, so they slowly get to it and find some survivors, who explain that they lost containment, but some of their experiment survived.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vd0eOS6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven speaks to the head scientist, who explains that this experiment is his people’s salvation. He’s disgusted by them wanting to blow it up.</p>

<p>Down on the planet, they find the Omega molecules. She’s ready to destroy it, and doesn’t even want to study it at all, even when it’s stable right now. Even as a woman as science, she feels like science has limits, and she knows when to quit. It’s just too dangeorous. That amount of Omega would straight up destroy half the quadrant. That is a LOT of space. It’s even enough to throw the Prime Directive out the window.</p>

<p>Seven tells Chokie she thinks she can stabalize the particles and save them. She BEGS Chakotay to let her. She still has some Borg Programming left, and the Borg basically worship Omega as a God. It’s a perfect molecule, a million parts working together as one. Like the Borg collective. It’s interesting that the Borg basically have a religion. When Chokie can’t convince Janeway, Seven tries ONE MORE time on Janeway. She could probably beat her in combat and do it if she wanted, but she won’t. She does understand why Janeway is doing this. THIS is a good Seven and Janeway clash!!! It makes WAY more sense that that shit last time. They both have a clash of personality and opinion where neither of them come off as a complete asshole! It’s great!</p>

<p>Seven manages to see a stabalized Omega for a few seconds, before they manage to throw it out and explode it. The episode ends with Janeway and Seven discussing religious experiences. This was a nice one.</p>

<p><strong>The Omega Directive</strong> - VOY
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dfh17AB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is caught between two cloaked ships fighting. It looks like one explodes, before they get an audio message that simple says “Chakotay, please, I need your help”. Fascinating start. Too bad it will CLEARLY involve Chakotay.</p>

<p>Her ship is falling apart, and for some reason they can’t beam her over, and so they beam over to help her. Chakotay saves her from some rubble, and she’s like “Ohhh Chakotay, I knew you’d come for me~” and he’s like “who the hell are you”? When they get her over to the ship, I guess they could beam her once Chakotay was with her, the Doctor’s scanners won’t work on her either. Her name is Kellin. She begs the captain to give her Asylum, because “they” are chasing her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xCT1pAA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She explains to Chokie that her biology makes it so people forget her the next day. That’s just how her people are, the Ramurans. Some pheramone shenanigans. Apparently this also won’t let technology talk about her. Why they couldn’t just… write about her or talk about her on a log, I dunno. She claims it’s a virus that erased all data of her from the logs. And now her reason for being here is she fell in love with Chokie and gave up her life on her planet, which is VERY taboo on her planet. Honestly I believe the shit with the pheremones more than I believe someone falling in love with Chakotay after 2 weeks of being near him. Chakotay trusts her, for some reason. After all, he’s a VERY good judge of character. He doesn’t have any actual desire to continue any relationship with her. To him, it didn’t happen, he has no feelings.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/juW9Bzh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some of her people come to take Kellin away, and she helps them detect the ships, so they can actually fight back. CHakotay keeps being flaky about whether he trusts her or not. At first he does, then he’s like “No, I don’t”, then he begs her not to go when she’s like “You’ll be in danger if I’m here and clearly you’re not into me”. God. I DO get Chakotay not trusting her, after all the Seska shit, but buh. Wait until the end when we find out she’s actually a Romulan spy.</p>

<p>We also learn what her previous job was. She was the person who hunted people who ran from the Homeworld, and used a memory wiper on them to make them forget the outside world so that they want to stay home. That’s fucking horrifying.</p>

<p>Eventually things get into a nice comfort. They all start to like the idea of her become a member of the crew. Oh boy, I can’t wait for that to happen! No, obviously not.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5WeqjpV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the agents from her planet gets aboard and wipes her memory. It wipes slowly, which is ESPECIALLY horrifying. She’s like “Please, if I forget you, please make me fall in love with you like you fell in love with me this time”. Chakotay almost beats the shit out of this guy, but he’s so smug about it. He’s like “Of course I’m right for doing this. This is the wya of our world, our laws”. Fucking gross behavior, to wipe someones mind like this, but eh.</p>

<p>Of course, her memory is gone. She doesn’t remember him or why she’d want to be here, so she just… leave. He can’t convince her to stay. Chakotay, who’s going to lose all his memories again, writes the log down on paper. Neelix has a nice scene about love before the episode ends. So, I don’t think this episode is bad in concept, or even mostly in practice. Most of it is good. It’s basically a retread of that one episode with Riker loving the agender alien. The problem with this episode, and there’s only really one, is that Chakotay is a sucking black void of charisma. Chakotay is the Omega Particle of boring. He is perfect.</p>

<p><strong>Living Witness</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CpZdykM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with a scene between Janeway and an evil smarmy guy, a Vaskan. He brings JAneway and Voyager into a war. She is OVERLY evil, with Tasha Yar hair and black gloves. She agrees, if he helps them get home. There’s also a Kazon soldier who walksbuy. She then uses Biogenic weapons on the planet, despite the original evil smarmy guy’s statement that he didn’t want to kill that many people, just win the war and defeat his one enemy. The Doctor makes a biogenic weapon, and then they release it on the planet, killing millions.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lEMFojx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out this was a simulation and a video being shown many years in the future on the planet, which is owned by the Kyrians, to explain The Voyager Incident, when Biogenic weapons were put on their planet. This is an AMAZING cold open. VERY entertaining, and you IMMEDIATLEY know what’s happening (it’s propaganda). It’s mostly just fun to watch everyone over act as super evil people. And to see all the things they got wrong. They’re from Mars. Tuvok SMILES. We all recoiled in horror at it. They have multiple Borg drones on board they use as weapons. Fucking NEELIX is at Ops. Of course, Chakotay’stattoo is all over his face.</p>

<p>The Voyager Conflict ends with the leader of the Kyrians being killed brutally in a firing squad, as the Kyrian watches in terror. It’s shown this is a museum in the future. The Kyrians lost the war and are now under the control of the Vaskans, and are basically second class citizens. A Vaskan is annoyed by this, and claims they made up this just to make the Vaskans out to the villains. But the Kyrian museum curator and historian has some new evidence that should help cement the historical record. It’s some data, maybe some records!</p>

<p>He researches it and finds out it’s code… for a hologram. SURPRISE. IT WAS A DOCTOR EPISODE THE ENTIRE TIME! The Doctor finds out he’s 700 years in the future, and is horrified at the idea he’ll be a museum piece. Although probably not. On their planet, AI are responsible for their own crimes. And he DID make the Biogenic weapon.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HaMNMB8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everything in the diagram made about the incident astounds the Doctor. They’re making him out to be a murderer, and the entire crew maniacs. “Halfway across the galaxy, I hope, Janeway is spinning in her grave”. He explains that they were just doing a trade agreement with the Vaskans, and then the Kyrians started a war with them suddenly, and Voyager was caught in the middle. The museum curator is stunned, and disgusted. No way, he’s a second class citizen, how could HIS people be the aggressors? He shuts down the Doctor, but it also confused why a medical hologram would be willing to lie so much. So he eventually comes back and apologizes. He’s ready to learn the truth, no matter how uncomfortable it might be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/47C99rK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>When he shows his recreation of events, one of the other Kyrians in the Museum is disgusted by it. There’s a lot of political and racial disagreements here. I’m not 100% sure how I feel about it portraying the clearly second class citizens as willing to throw people under the bus and hurt them just to make themselves feel better. He might have a way to prove himself innocent, though. He has a medical tricorder that can prove it was Kyrian weapons that started the conflict, and help his side of events. Unfortunately he loses it in the fucking RACE RIOT that occurs over this, as Kyrians storm the museum and smash it up. The Doctor makes a decision.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QeZa3Bh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He should be erased. Him EXISTING and trying to find the truth is making more people die. Two people died already. Who cares about the truth, what matters is lives. But the museum director disagrees. They’ve been abusing history, and all its done is worsen relations. They need to try and learn the truth so they can move past it, and live together. It’s a nice moment. And then, abruptly, we find out THIS was a simulation, some further point in the future, just like it was at the start of the episode. It’s like poetry, it rhymes. The world is at peace, and all is good. The Doctor stayed with them for a while and worked as their chief medical director for years before taking a small vessel and flying back to the Alpha Quadrant… hoping to reach home.</p>

<p>So, I think some parts of this episode were maybe clumsily handled, and you could easily twist its narrative to imply it’s saying heinous shit. I could argue right now it’s a holocaust denial episode. But it’s not, it’s trying to have a more positive message, and even if it’s not perfect about that, it’s fine. I liked most of it.</p>

<p><strong>Demon</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/o5CvEIR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is out of Deuterium. They’re running on empty and people need to vacate the living spaces and sleep in one room to conserve power. But before Astrometrics is shut down, Seven finds a planet nearby with lots of Deuterium. They just need to go grab it. Unfortunately, the ship is Class Y. There’s no worse planet for supporting Human life. Worse than zero atmosphere? Worse than a GAS GIANT? Wow. Harry volunteers himself to go down and mine it, cause teleporters aren’t working. He also volunteers Paris to come with him. I’m sure this will go VERY well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4ZXnWRv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Harry IMMEDIATELY falls in some goop, and a seal breaks on his suit. He runs out of oxygen. Paris fishes him out, and then a seal breaks on his suit too. They both run out of oxygen and die, on screen. We hear the beep and everything.</p>

<p>There’s also a B-plot about Neelix trying to turn the Medbay into a barracks. That happens. The Doctor is a shitty dickhead about it. It doesn’t fit.</p>

<p>They’re about to run out of energy, and the Deuterium is down there. They can’t contact Harry or Paris. Hey, do you remember that Voyager can land? They won’t be able to go back up if they do, but they CAN land. Well, they do. And Chakotay and Seven go out to find our Dead Boys. They find out Dead Boys, shockingly alive. Not only that, but outside of their fucking suits. Paris is outside his suit and SUPER thrilled about it, he’s like “it was exhilerating! You should take off your helmets too :D Join us :D”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FxBXvbS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s creepy.</p>

<p>They take Harry and Paris back, and they IMMEDIATELY start suffocating. The doctor checks them out (not before being a dick to Neelix again) and finds some weird silver goo in their blood, which he determines bioformmed them. Like terraformation. They can only breath the atmosphere here, so either they fix it, or they leave them behind. Janeway and Torres determine it has “Memetic” properties, and can mimic things it touches.  But as they go out and explore more… they find Harry and Paris’ corpses. Well, not corpses, they are BARELY alive, even though they’ve had no oxygen for ages. The Non-Dead Kim freaks out about this, and runs off declaring that he “belongs here”, as the others teleport back.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QXh3ObB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway is weirdly aggressive, as the ship is being held down by this silver goop. She has a beam thing that can hurt it, and help them escape, and Fake Kim BEGS her to stop. She’s still aggressive, and like “okay I will blow you all away if you don’t let us go”. Kim literally says “WE DESERVE LIFE”. We’ve had arguments about this in episodes before, but we’ve not really had a Starfleet Captain willing to throw away sentient life like this.</p>

<p>So, to explain, this goop, it’s called “The Silver Blood” by Janeway. It gained sentience by finding Kim and Harry. And it doesn’t want to be alone, so it wants to use the rest to make it a family. Janeway lets people give it their DNA so it can literally create a second race of changelings to take over the Delta Quadrant, and then blast off with more Deuterium than they could ever want. This episode was alright.</p>

<p><strong>One</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dOgHjQ6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Seven practicing getting to know people better. She does this by interrogating them, then the Doctor stops the holoprogram and is like “Okay tell me what you did wrong” “Nothing.” “…Okay then.”</p>

<p>You know it’s bad when the DOCTOR is having to give Not Be A Dick lessons</p>

<p>Anyways the crew enters a nebula with some radiation and everyone is suddenly being burned like, from the inside out. They’re too hurt to even get out of the nebula, Tuvok has to Vulcan his way to the console. One person straight up dies. Yet another one gone. The Nebula is in their way, and it’ll take a month to get through it. A whole YEAR to go around it. The Doctor can put everyone in suspended animation pods, but uh, that’s a WHOLE MONTH of just the Doctor. Well, not just the Doctor.</p>

<p>Seven is immune to the radiation, it seems. Oh, Borg Shenanigans. She’ll also stay awake. Janeway is a bit worried, cause it’s bad enough that as a Borg she’s now on a ship with 150 people, but total isolation is very rough on Humans. She thinks she can handle it, though. Everyone is A Little Concerned.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xq8TtqD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things go well at the start. Sort of. I mean, things are GOING, at least. Paris is claustrophobic and does not like being in the coffin, so he sleep walks out of it. That’s weird. But at least he’s not horribly burned. But over all, Seven is being a little irritable. So is the Doctor, mind you, but that’s mostly cause he has to put up with her. So it’s more Holodeck How To Be Personable time. And you know what? She does it. HOW does she do it? By getting Neelix and Janeway into her hyper fixation so they can all gush about warp fields and shit. Everyone’s big into it, but the Doctor is like “No you’re failing”. Bitch, she did good, how dare you. You’re just jelly.</p>

<p>This is all interrupted by the warp core breaching. That’s not good. Turns out it’s not actually though, they’re fine. The Neuropacks are having problems and freaking out. And not just that, but also the Doctor’s holo emitter. He has to stay in sickbay for the rest of the two weeks. She’ll now REALLY be alone. Yes, they were just bickering and being rude to each other, but this is… a bit more. Things are already going bad. She’s having dreams. The ship is breaking down more and more. She’s hearing things, people calling out for her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7rjnPEe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But then, someone shows up. Someone else trying to get through the nebula, asking to trade some parts. Seven does so, though he’s… creepy, and uncooperative. It eventually turns to her escorting him out of the ship, but he gets away from her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g3RiuEE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She hunts down this guy, as he mocks her. She sees and hears more fucked up shit as she goes. But this guy is impossible to defeat. Impossible because… he’s not real. The Doctor manages to fix himself in time to find her waving a gun at the air. He also thinks the radiation is effecting her. Unfortunately, before he can try and help, he’s deactivated by the ship breaking down even more. Now it’s LITERALLY just her. And she’s not taking it well.</p>

<p>What follows is her being nuts and doing what she can to survive. She barely does. In the end, she cuts life support to reroute it to the engines so they could make it through. She nearly doesn’t make it, but she does. She gets them through. And she realizes what it truly means to be alone, and to want companionship. In the end, she goes to spend time with her crewmates in the mess hall. It’s sweet. Everyone is mean to Neelix for some reason.</p>

<p><strong>Hope and Fear</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rwN3reQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven and Janeway are butting heads. Seven is very competitive right now. There’s a hot scene where they’re playing Sportball. It’s good. Anyways, Janeway’s big project these days is trying to decode the message Starfleet sent them. It’s very degraded and encrypted. Luckily, there’s a guy here to help! His name is Arturis, he met Neelix while trading and is VERY good at languages. Janeway asks for his help, and he manages to fix it easily. It’s a bunch of messages, including a star chart nearby!</p>

<p>There, in the area they were pointed to, is a Federation starship! A new class they’ve never heard of, and it has a weird-ass drive called a “Warp Slipstream” drive. No one is on board, just them. The Slipstream drive should help them speed along home in only 3 months!! Wow, I can’t believe Voyager is about to end.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eywgWnz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The message from the admiral explains to them that they’ve been developing this technology, and sent it along to rescue them. Oh how nice!! It’s perfect! …Too perfect. Tuvok, Seven, and Janeway are all suspicious. They all WANT it to be true, but Janeway immediately thinks “I think this Arturis guy is sus”. Well, MOST of them want it to be true.</p>

<p>Seven decides to stay behind. When Kim tells her “it won’t be the same without you”, she smiles. ACTUALLY smiles. But she’s unhappy. Scared, about going with them. But then they make a breakthrough on the last bit of the message that Arturis said “was unrecoverable”. THey recover it. It it is an Admiral apologizing that he can’t send them any better way to return them home. Well then.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NdFyM2d.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They confront Arturis. He’s like ‘oh it was a setup by Seven! She’s been against you getting home this entire time!” And even with all the antagonistic Seven stuff this episode… no one turns on her. And it call comes out. He captures Janeway and Seven and speeds along in his slipstream ship, and explains. His species had been eluding the Borg for centuries, but finally they overwhelmed them and most of his species are gone now. He doesn’t blame THEM, they’re basically a force of nature. He DOES blame Voyager. They made a deal with the Borg and stopped them from being obliterated by Species 6969. So in his grief, he set this up to capture them all and take them to his homeworld so they’ll be assimilated.</p>

<p>Seven and Janeway have a nice moment where they basically make peace, after an entire season of butting heads. If I was in charge of his show we know EXACTLY how it would end. With sloppy makeouts. Sadly, I am not God. Anyways, they manage to get close to stopping Arturis, but he blows up his controls and makes it so now the ship can NOT be stopped before it reaches Borg Space. Buuuuut, then VOYAGER SHOWS UP! They made their OWN slipstream drive and chased after them! They save Seven and JAneway, and Arturis is off to be assimilated, I guess.</p>

<p>They don’t think they can risk using hte Slipstream again, it’s too dangerous. But now Seven is WITH them. She’s been there for a year now, but now, she’s with them. She’s working on a way to get the Slipstream drive to work again.</p>

<p>Good episode, great Seven and Janeway moments. And a great end to a surprisingly good season.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>