<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-20T23:25:15-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episode 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/20/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episode 1" /><published>2025-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/20/LizstartrekSNW3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/20/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9G4ESOr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Hegemony Part 2</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEvb4AL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Following directly after last season, the Enterprise is surrounded by Gorn, and some of their people are captured on the Gorn ship. The Enterprise is forced to retreat… but not before tagging the Gorn ship with a dud missile that’s actually a secret beacon.</p>

<p>Pike’s girlfriend, Batel, is infected with Gorn Babies and they might need to kill her, but to prolong things, they’re freezing her in a block of ice. Specifically SHE’S the one asking them to kill her if they need to. Well, at least that’s the PLAN, but turns out she’s allergic to being stuck in a block of ice, which I imagine I’d be too. Now Nurse Chapel is stuck trying to figure out how to cure Being A Gorn Mom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vvOBev.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Admiral April is like “we have to just ignore all this and let the Gorn capture neutral people” and Pike, being Pike, says fuck that shit, we’re being treated as Prey. And April agrees, unofficially, their rules are to punch the Gorn in the nose and show they’re not prey. Meanwhile, in Engineering, Scotty and Pelia the Warpcore Witch are trying to get a Gorn Cloaking Device up. Scotty says it’s impossible. Pelia is like “we’ll have it done in an hour sir”. Scotty is, one day, gonna be REAL good at doing the impossible on a deadline, and he’s gotta figure out how to get good at it real fucking fast.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Gorn ship, La’an wakes up and punches her way out of a Gorn sack. She rescues the other members of the crew captures, including Sam Kirk (Kirk’s brother), Doctor M’Benga, and Ortegas (who has had half her hand melted off). They want to get out… well, three of them do. La’an decides then and there, she’s going to save ALL the other colonists. Good luck.</p>

<p>Y’all remember Mitchell? She was a very minor background character in season 1, had some minor roles in 2, and now she’s on the bridge and refuses to leave until they can solve this. Yay, Mitchell!</p>

<p>They have some SMALL hope. Batel has a 14% chance of survival if they use Una’s blood. Yay! Also the Gorn seem to go to sleep when a certain kind of star flare happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jFp5msI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FkBzvR4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit is going way, WAY worse. Man this is tense. While exploring a weird binary star that seems to hide the Gorn homeworld because of radiation, they find a BUNCH of Gorn ships blasting out of the zone and going towards Federation space. Now Pike has a choice. He might lose the tag on the colonists and his crew if he leaves to warn Starfleet, but they are NOT prepared for an invasion. So he makes the impossible choice and leaves them.</p>

<p>Pike seems so fucking done. He’s EXHAUSTED, he’s worrying about every single little thing. And can you blame him? When he goes to Scotty and Pelia like “Hey can we make a solar flare” and Scotty is like “what the fuck no. Not without doing this this that and this which will blow up the ship” Pike is like “Sure just do it without the blowing up the ship part” and everyone just… stares at each other.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of “have faith” talk in this episode, which we keep making fun of by posting Star Wars memes. It doesn’t help when Ortegas takes over a Gorn ship and flies them out in a scene that is VERY Star Warsy. Also Ortegas becomes massively injured in the skirmish, but sticks too it. Poor Ortegas, she can’t catch a break ):</p>

<p>We get a fuzzy fisheye scene with them in the radiation, but it works. They use the flare to trigger a hibernation in the Gorn, as they come back to go eep. Ortegas raises her deathflag REALLY high but is saved just before dying, thank fucking God. <em>sees death flag in Ortegas’ mouth</em> WHAT DO YOU HAVE THERE? PUT THAT DOWN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/evmRMxM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Batel is saved, Spock and Chapel have a moment of acceptance, and the Enterprise is beat to fuck. But alive. It ends the “have faith” talk with Pike thanking God for some reason.</p>

<p>I thought it was alright! Not blowing me away, but good! Excited for more.</p>

<p>I’ll be editing this page every week and reposting it with the new episodes as they come out =w=</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 163</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/20/OOCY163.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 163" /><published>2025-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/20/OOCY163</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/20/OOCY163.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0up1Acc.png" alt="A college professor gives a lecture. 'I wouldn't be surprised if you've had far more experience with that laugh than someone like me. For whatever reason... it seems like the world is divided into those who laugh, and those who are laughed at. Novels for girls are laughed at. Pop culture writers are laughed at. Love between girls is called immature. Stories about conservative modern housewives are laughed at. People going on about 'immature women'. Those who fancy themselves modern like to laugh. And those who can't become 'someone who laughs' end up getting laughed at.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Hanamonogatari</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Hanamonogatari" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 11 - 14</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/20/LizstartrekVOY7-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 11 - 14" /><published>2025-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/20/LizstartrekVOY7-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/07/20/LizstartrekVOY7-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ammeBQI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Shattered</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9e6Hlft.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everything is nice and happy until it’s not. Suddenly some spacetime temporal distortion rips nto the ship, causing the warpcore to lose containment and hitting Chakotay with something that makes him Old. Chakoldtay.</p>

<p>The Doctor fixes him, while being a grumpy little mother fucker. He’s angry cause everyone ignores him and leaves him in sickbay all day. He also has no idea what a mobile emitter is. Oh no.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1j4nyHX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chokey goes to the Bridge and finds that it’s in the past, before they even went to the Delta Quadrant. He then goes to Engineering  and finds Seska. He manages to escape back to the Doctor and gets a Serum Against Time Shenanigans, which seems very VERY good to have handy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KgQkkLM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He gets Past Janeway inoculated, and teaches her about the future. She’s skeptical. I like this as a concept btw. Neli calls it a “glorified clipshow” but I really like temporal jumping around and seeing different timelines. They need to go around saving people and collecting a team to help them. They find two of them quickly. Icheb and Naomi Wildman…. but 17 years in the future. They’ve been working on ways to study the time lapses for 17 years, and are willing to help. They also collect Seven, though a Seven who’s still Borg’d, of course. I bet the actress was THRILLED about that shit being put back on her.</p>

<p>There’s also some hints of people now learning of the future and possibly wanting to change it. The Doctor lets slip to Janeway about the future and she doesn’t know, and she doesn’t seem THRILLED about it. Parts of this episode also seem to be a way for people to make fun of some of the previous episode they were in. The Macrovirus, for example. And then they go into that episode with Captain Proton, my favorite! :D</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qGXR2Uc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway is so checked out. Once they get out of this she goes “remind me to cancel Mr. Paris’ holodeck priveleges.” Very funny. They also keep bringing up the temporal prime directive and then Chakotay keeps ignoring it after bringing it up, telling Past Janeway more shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/c66qYCO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find a future timeline, it looks like, with radiation. Tuvok does the Spock thing and dies while going “I have been and will always be your friend, live long and prosper”, and it rips Janeway apart. That “maybe I shouldn’t change the future” part of her brain is overwhelmed by the “fuck this shit” part, and Chokey has to talk her down, and tell her about how GOOD the crew it and what positives they’ve had. It works.</p>

<p>They just have one timeframe to deal with, and it’s the Seska timeframe. How can they defeat her? By taking all the people they’ve befriended from all timeframes, even Borg Seven, as they’re innoculated to Time Shenanigans and overwhelming her. Simple as that. It’s fun.</p>

<p>Chakotay fixes the timeline and everything is all good. He and Janeway have a dinner, and alls well that ends well.</p>

<p>For a Chakotay centric episode, I liked it. He wasn’t bad, just… neutral.</p>

<p><strong>Lineage</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ammeBQI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>That fucking image, jesus.</p>

<p>Torres is happy and friendly this morning. That’s weird, I don’t like it, something’s wrong. But then she stumbles, and Icheb scans her and is like “omg another lifesign, SHE HAS A PARASITE”. Seven looks at the scans and then is like “Nope, she’s just pregnant”. Hell of a way to find that out, holy moly.</p>

<p>The mood fluctuations are because human/klingon babies apparently cause some. Paris and Torres want to keep things quiet about this, they’re a bit overwhelmed. But everyone immediately finds out because of course they fucking do. If this episode was just “everyone reacts to them having a baby” I’d be fine with that, that sounds fun. But that horrible floating baby up there is looming over me like a bad omen. But there’s lots of fun little moments. Paris going to Tuvok asking for advice and Tuvok’s just like “Expect paradoxes”. Thanks bro.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HWK1DAe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Imagine going to the doctor and he’s like “Here’s a holographic extrapolation of your future daughter’s spine”. Anyways they extrapolate the whole baby from there, as you can see up above, and Torres starts to have some breakdowns about all this. She’s having flashbacks to her childhood. Its a lot of hatred about her Klingon self. And when she learns the Doctor can do pre-natal gene therapy, she goes and looks into what genes to remove…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yIJsDCo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s trying to remove all the Klingon out of her. She claims it’s all just cause she’s worried about health problems, but Paris immediately sees through the bullshit. And is IMMEDIATELY upset about it. When she can’t convince either him or the Doctor, she goes to Janeway and asks her to order the treatment, because “its what you did to Seven of Nine, so it’s fine”. Wow she’s trying to use ANY weapon she can to do this.</p>

<p>This is an interesting topic they’re tackling. Torres was traumatized because she was different as a kid from everyone else, because she’s from two different cultures, and they’re all from one culture. So she can have that not happen to her kid, should she? It makes sense she’d feel that way, it traumatized her. To everyone else, the multiculturalism is a strength and something to lean on.</p>

<p>We also see how her father handled it. Poorly. “You have to learn to be less sensitive”. Dog. No wonder she has problems several decades later. And that’s BEFORE she overheard her dad talk about how he regrets marrying her mom and having her. Holy hell. What a shitty dad.</p>

<p>The Doctor suddenly declares that they NEED to do the surgery to make the baby fully Human. Paris is confounded, and looks into it, and WOW she fucking changed his program so he’d do the surgery. That’s WILD, and kinda fucked. She does not handle having it interrupted well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FQoGmzb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway REALLY needs to hire a fucking therapist for this ship.</p>

<p>So yeah, Paris FINALLY gets it out of her, what it’s all about. It’s not just about being bullied as a kid for being different, it’s that her father LEFT THEM after everything, and never came back. Wooooow what a shitty dad. So she’s still traumatized by that, obviously, and also afraid of the future, that it’ll happen again, happen to Paris. That he’ll regret everything and leave them, because he can’t handle the cultural differences. Paris handles this very well, and convinces her of it.</p>

<p>Congrats to Voyager, no B plot, no weird space shenanigans, a fucking CHARACTER EPISODE. Holy shit. And in the end, she asks the Doctor if he’ll be the kids god father. We ALL went “AWWW” at it, that’s so sweet. Good episode.</p>

<p><strong>Lineage</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OGxqjRD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While being who they are in space, Voyager finds a ship about to explode. Teleport them, and the two damaged lifesigns, to sickbay. Whoops it was a prisoner ship, and the two prisoners hold sickbay hostage. Luckily, it’s Seven they’re holding hostage, and she immediately handles it. That same prisoner is like “let me go or I will kill every single one of you” so they’re not neccesarily nice prisoners.</p>

<p>They’re taking these prisoners to be executed. And now the ship is discussing if it’s right to kill them. The Doctor and Seven have this discussion. Yep, an episode about CAPITAL PUNISHMENT :).</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CKrHyqS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s very subtle about the premise! Some of the prisoners seem pleasant enough, thanking Neelix for arguing for them to eat a good meal. Some, namely the one, is belligerent and says he’ll kill their children. So the alien cops start beating the shit out of him. They’re taken off the case of guarding the prisoners, but not before going “Commander Tuvok isn’t qualified to guard these prisoners!” Dude. The only reason Tuvok isn’t running this ship right now is because he doesn’t fucking want to.</p>

<p>The one nice prisoner explains to Neelix that he was arrested only because of racial profiling. Neelix is a soft easy mark. They use nanoprobes to fix the ultra violent one, and it fixes his sociopathy and now he’s feeling guilt for the first time. He fucking HATES it and begs them to take the nanoprobes out and let him die, because it’s better than this. Jesus.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NAgLUfM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We learn more of this judicial system. It favors the victims. No judges, victims and their families pass judgement. This episode is basically tackling TWO different subjects. First, of unfair capital judgement, but secondly, Iko, the violent one, is now literally a different person. Is he still the same person who killed people and should he be punished? Like, obviously it’s not right to like, change him this way, but it was an accident so that’s not the topic, it’s how to handle what happened. He has an answer, though. He thinks he should die for what he did.</p>

<p>They draft an appeal, because they think he no longer deserves to die, and he’s like “Take it back fuck that shit, let me die”. Seven argues that she also hurt and kileld people as a Borg, and wasn’t in control. Like he wasn’t either. He’s having none of it. Every argument here has a counter argument, actually being made by the person who’s being affected most by it. Not by like, cops. This gives the moral arguments a completely different look, and I prefer it.</p>

<p>It’s also about a lot of things. Seven feels like if she can save Iko, she can save herself. If he’s found non guilty, she won’t be either.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZWGpkb5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Then a tiny ship comes and attacks, knocking out power. How did this tiny thing hurt Voyager in any way? Cause the plot demands it, I guess. Anyways the prisoners escape, but Iko actually stops them, which causes the warden to be like “oh shit maybe he DID change…” and puts in an appeal. The “nice” prisoner, meanwhile, is the reason this all happened. He got to send a letter to his brother, who came and attacked them. And now he’s trying to do anything he can to get out of it. A shame.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ryg2oE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Iko’s appeal is rejected. Even the Warden seems bothered by this. He has one final moment with Seven, who can barely look at him. “You were the first person to look me in the eye. It’s how I’d like to remember you.” It’s a good moment, but quite sad. Iko didn’t get the chance to be his own person.</p>

<p>WAY better than I expected. This might be the best of this kind of episode, the “alien penal system and we can’t judge how they work” kinda episodes. It handled it SHOCKINGLY well. It was realistic, and Human.</p>

<p><strong>Prophecy</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dPIvHGX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is cruisin’ maxin’ relaxin’ all cool when suddenly they’re attacked by some fucking Klingons. It’s a practically ancient D7 cruiser, which is a TOS era ship. They easily take it out, and it finally answers their hails. “Yo wtf stand down” “WE WILL NOT STAND DOWN TO SWORN ENEMIES OF THE EMPIRE”. Dog. How long have you been out here? Is this a multigenerational ship? Cause I see no women on this bridge.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5uKCyU4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>After they meet Torres, who is there to convince them they are not at war, they immediately blow up their own ship and strand themselves on Voyager. Why? Because they, as a weird religious sect, believe Torres’ child is the messiah. The Kuvah’magh. Oh boy! Torres is not amused. Neither is Paris for that matter.</p>

<p>There’s now 200 extra Klingons on board.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5lSp9ZU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/63lFelk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TaD33es.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OeGxGPW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Don’t be a coward, Kim.</p>

<p>Anyways when the other Klingon leaders discover that Torres is only half Klingon, and that her kid is even MORE Human, they’re like “wow this was a mistake” and we’re about to get a religious war on our hands. The leader, the one who original came over, is like “We need to try to avoid religious war”. He’s a chill guy, over all. And it’s pretty clear he’s actually not really sure if she’s the Mother Mary either. But he doesn’t care. What he DOES care and believe is that his people will die out here if they don’t have hope, and this will give them hope. So he interprets the ancient scrolls in the way that will help his people the most. A pragmatic cultist.</p>

<p>He helps her both interpret the scrolls in a way that they’ll talk about her, and ALSO get back in touch with her Klingon side. She basically hasn’t done any Klingon customs since she was a kid, and it’s well known she’s not comfortable with her Klingon side. She needs a GOOD role model for Klingon customs.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of fun Klingon stuff here. One of them challenges Tom to a battle, but Janeway makes it stay nonlethal. Kim keeps trying to hide from the Hot Klingon Mommy. Coward. Neelix helps him out by making him look like a coward, and she starts going after Neelix instead. He is WAY more happy about this than Kim was. Neelix is not a coward.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yxSpdsY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>“I see fear in your eyes, Human.” “The only Klingon I fear is my wife after a double shift.” That’s a good fucking line. Unfortunately, the fight is cancelled after the Klingon warrior gets tired and falls over dying. We now learn of the Nehret, a Klingon disease. They don’t even really view it as a disease, more of “old age”. It’s highly contagious, but only to Klingons. Uh oh. We have one of those. Two of those even, if you count the baby. And yes, they’re both infected. Unfortunately, the scrolls say the messiah is stronger than old age and disease. So now they’re CERTAIN she’s not the messiah, and decide to take over Voyager instead.</p>

<p>Their attempt to take over Voyager fails as Janeway and Paris take out like five armed Klingons alone. Damn, y’all, you didn’t send your best. The Nehret is cured shortly after, because the baby being mostly Human means she made an antivirus, basically. Alright, cool. So she IS the messiah! Yay! They find a place to settle and leave, but not before… this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gTdu2UR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix appears to have won Voyager.</p>

<p>Mostly just fun Klingon moments, I’m a fan.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 187 - Donald’s Alphabet Chase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/18/RA188-Donald.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 187 - Donald’s Alphabet Chase" /><published>2025-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/18/RA188-Donald</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/18/RA188-Donald.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dbWGTUX.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the least games I’ve played.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KoPxaFu.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Donald’s Alphabet Chase, you play as Donald who’s goal is to collect all the letters of the alphabet. You move around a room as letters pop up and dance around, and you move up and grab them to collect them. Once you collect all 26 letters, the game ends with an image of Donald looking like he just fucked all these letters and is enjoying the afterglow, while the alphabet song beeps out of your speaker.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hGnK0Bv.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is barely a game. Like, even for the tiniest of babies, I dunno how effective this is at teaching them letters. It’s just some jangly keys shit. We’re ALMOST done with the Apple II games, by the way, we have two more coming up soon, though they’re actually more games than the past two things I’ve played.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Disney" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 187 - Othello</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/18/RA187-Othello.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 187 - Othello" /><published>2025-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/18/RA187-Othello</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/07/18/RA187-Othello.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oXYWoTj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Look, every console needs one of these, okay? And sometimes it’s fun to play some Othello.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wg8GCk8.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is Othello for the Apple II. There’s really not much more to say than that. You choose a difficulty from 1-3, I couldn’t tell a difference, and then if you wanna start as white or black, and you’re off. I don’t believe there’s a way to play against people. You take turns putting tiles of your color down. You can only place tiles if you’re next to an opponent’s tile, and there’s a line through your opponent’s tiles to one of your own. When you do, all those opponent’s tiles flip to your tile, and the game continues. You play until all spaces are filled, and whoever has the most tiles wins.</p>

<p>Othello is a simple but fun board game. It’s got that Chess energy of a 1v1 board game you can play on the computer but with much easier AI to program so they could actually make it for old computers. Your goal should always be to get the corners and walls, those are the most powerful spaces. Especially the corners, they can never be turned, get them at ALL COSTS.</p>

<p>Othello is fine, and this is a fine enough version of it for… wait shit, this came out in 1979?! Holy moly. Alright, fair.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple II" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 162</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/18/OOCY162.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 162" /><published>2025-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/18/OOCY162</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/18/OOCY162.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jmj0fS8.png" alt="Two women make out while one thinks, 'So warm. My mind is on fire. I'm so envous... aren't men allowed to do this all the time?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: About That Day Off From Work.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="About That Day Off From Work." /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 161</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/15/OOCY161.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 161" /><published>2025-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/15/OOCY161</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/15/OOCY161.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MtHLOzI.png" alt="A hottie blocks two dudes from another hottie. 'Sorry, but can you leave us alone? I'm hitting on her right now.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The somolier has returned</p>

<p>I read so much Yuri in my downtime at GDQ</p>

<p>source: My Goddess Spurs Me On</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="My Goddess Spurs Me On" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of town</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcement/2025/07/03/GDQ.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of town" /><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcement/2025/07/03/GDQ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcement/2025/07/03/GDQ.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m leaving tomorrow for GDQ, and I’ll be gone for almost two weeks. From July 4th to July 14th, so there’ll be no updates on this blog until after then. Thanks for reading!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="announcement" /><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m leaving tomorrow for GDQ, and I’ll be gone for almost two weeks. From July 4th to July 14th, so there’ll be no updates on this blog until after then. Thanks for reading!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 160</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/03/OOCY160.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 160" /><published>2025-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/03/OOCY160</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/03/OOCY160.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iVjjNbY.png" alt="''We can't leave things as they are now... That's why... I even asked my friends about this, and... just for a bit.. could we... maybe...' 'Give it to me straight.' 'I'n sorry... I'm at my limit.... We need to have less sex.' '?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Jewels</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Jewels" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 159</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/02/OOCY159.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 159" /><published>2025-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/02/OOCY159</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/07/02/OOCY159.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Uj9hYXK.png" alt="'I want a handsome prince that's both strong and kind! And knows how to treat the girl he likes!' The princess made her decision then. She was determined: She would become a prince!" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Ah… and Mm… Are All She Says</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Ah... and Mm... Are All She Says" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>