<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-19T23:24:15-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 90</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/19/OOCY90.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 90" /><published>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/19/OOCY90</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/19/OOCY90.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XPN1wqG.png" alt="&quot;I'm here at a lesbian bar!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>NEVER</p>

<p>source: Love Only the Body</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Flavorful" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 141 - The Legend of Ghost Lion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/19/RA141-GhostLion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 141 - The Legend of Ghost Lion" /><published>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/19/RA141-GhostLion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/19/RA141-GhostLion.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cf7aHOj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SE0sfeZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There’s a lot of interesting things about this game, but first, look at that box art. Can you tell which one is the American box art??? God, that’s bad. It looks like it’s AI generated.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/O87H9Ek.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>AND the title screen has the lesbian flag! Yay!</p>

<p>Legend of Ghost Lion is a licensed RPG on the NES, based on the 1988 movie “Beyond the Pyramids: Legend of the Ghost Lion”, which is a WEIRD-ass movie. It’s extremely obscure, not super well recieved, entirely in English, but released only in Japan. It stars the girl from Full House, and a bunch of other American actors, but was shot by Japanese producers and subbed into Japanese. The game was then roughly translated into an RPG, and released on the Famicom. And you’d think a game like this would NEVER have a chance at being translated into English, but Kemco kinda defied logic. They often translated their stuff even when it made no sense. God bless.</p>

<p>Ghost Lion is an RPG that I heard, and was often decried during the day, as just a sub-par Dragon Quest clone. But honestly that does it a lot of disservice. So it’s actually good, right? Well, no. Actually I don’t like this game very much at all, and I was EXTREMELY glad to be done playing it once I was. It starts off good but it’s an awful slog by the end. But the Dragon Quest clone bit? That I argue. It has a lot of very interesting and unique ideas! It just kind of doesn’t do any of them super well. It’s a “Dragon Quest Clone” in that it’s an RPG, with the combat showing enemies in front of you instead of to the side. That would be a Final Fantasy clone. And also the graphics are a liiiittle similar. Everything else is very different.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p8uHJYH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Ghost Lion you play Maria, a 12 year old girl (who according to the american box art is a 20 year old jazzercize instructor) who’s parents are researching old myths in Africa. They go missing one day exploring the legend of The Ghost Lion, a lion who was defeated by an ancient hero. You take the hero’s spear and go exploring the caves, where you find a lamp and fall into a river and wash away. You find yourself in a weird fantasy world, and must explore 6 different disconnected parts of this world, doing little quests and mini stories, like stopping evil werewolves and other such things.</p>

<p>The combat is unique, in a way. Yes, it’s a turn based RPG, but you have two commands: Fight and Run. Run barely ever works. If you use Fight, you can use “Tools”, or “Call”. Call is the game’s main combat gimmick. You can find items around the game, like that spear and lamp, which you start with, which can be used to summon ancient spirits to fight for you. These spirits have spiritual power, which goes down as they attack and as they’re attacked. If it goes down all the way, you need to resummon them. You can summon as many spirits as you have. These spirits each have their own abilities, stats, and levels. You’ll mostly just be using the spear, it’s by far the most helpful. The “Tools” are items that Maria can use. She can attack as well, by using weapons she finds from the Tools menu, but it can be more helpful to use status inflicting items and summon spirits. Summoning Spirits DOES use up your “Dream”, though, which is basicalyl your MP.</p>

<p>Notably, this game has no EXP. That’s the main thing that differentiates it from Dragon Quest. Dragon Quest is an EXP grinding slog, and Ghost Lion gives absolutely NO reason to do combat, at all. This is actually a problem. Instead of getting EXP to gain levels, you explore dungeons and find shards of hope, which give you (and all your spirits) a level. All the enemies give you is gold, which is used to buy very, VERY little. All the shops in the game essentially sell the same items, very inexpensive bread which heals you, and by the end it heals you VERY little. You have a few things you need to buy otherwise, but you’ll never be hurting for money.</p>

<p>This becomes a major issue by the end. The run button works 11% of the time, enemies take 3 hits to kill in the final two chapters of the game, it has you fighting three at once, you get NOTHING to fighting them, the encounter rate is WAY to high, and they dodge attacks literally half the time. It’s nuts, some enemies seem to have dodge rating, and every enemy in the last two areas are way WAY too dodgy. And since you need to summon allies over and over, combat is a little slow paced. Since there’s no real variance in this game, since you gain levels at the same rate going through it every time, this means the final two chapters are just sloggish luck roulettes. I actually enjoyed the first four chapters, those were kinda cool and fun, but the game gets VERY tedious by the end, which makes it very hard to recommend.</p>

<p>In the end, Ghost Lion is a very fascinating game with a lot of ideas, not all of which work, and is maligned for the WRONG REASONS (Dragon Quest clone, pah) rather than the actual problems it has. Its very hard to recommend, though it’s quite fun to talk about, at least. And the art is nice, I’ll give it that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Double Moon Densetsu" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 89</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/18/OOCY89.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 89" /><published>2025-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/18/OOCY89</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/18/OOCY89.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J2KXPoR.png" alt="&quot;Stop making me draw pretty girls...&quot; HOWEVER, BECAUSE THE ART WAS WELL-RECIEVED,  COMMISSIONS AND BUSINESS ORDERS INCREASED." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>NEVER</p>

<p>source: Flavorful</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Flavorful" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 140 - Double Moon Densetsu</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/18/RA140-Doublemoon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 140 - Double Moon Densetsu" /><published>2025-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/18/RA140-Doublemoon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/18/RA140-Doublemoon.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7teEcnB.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Double Moon Densetsu interested me just cause it’s a really typical classic RPG on the NES that I had neverh eard of. Also the graphics looked kinda pretty. So I decided to give it a try. I was told it’s a pretty generic and mediocre Dragon Quest clone, and no, it’s not QUITE that, it tries for so much more than that. But also, at the same time, it’s a LOT less than that. Let’s explain.</p>

<p>The game takes place in the world of Double Moon, a world with two continents, each of which sits under the light of one of the worlds’ two moons. Years ago, your father disappeared, and today on your 15th birthday, you are informed that he went after the an evil shaman who is trying to summon an ancient evil into this world. The shaman, Samoilenko, killed your mother and kidnapped your sister years ago when you were both babies, and now you have to save her and avenge your parents! Along the journey, you’ll run into Somolienko’s cult, a large cast of villains who are causing troubles throughout the world. You need to stop them in small little vignets around the world. Stuff like… stop them from sacrificing some virgins to a dark god, or stop them and their pet turtle from destroying ships. Just random nonsense.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xH8UEFt.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Along the way, you’ll find a large cast of characters to join you. Like, a LARGE cast. It’s like 13 characters. You are NOT going to be able to use all these characters, and in fact, the game can kinda fuck you over about this. Halfway in you get Sphinx, a… sphinx. They are not a great unit, but you will WANT to use them, because all these other characters? They will have to be sacrificed to enter the final dungeon, and the ONLY characters you’ll have are Sphinx and your main character. And if you choose a class like wizard or something, that’ll make it even harder. I was luckily warned about this.</p>

<p>This game is kinda mean. Not only that, but also things like… well, the difficult is all out of whack, honestly. In the first two dungeons, before you get a full party, you’ll run into enemies who do like, 1 damage to you, and then if they get a crit, or use a spell, boom, you’re one shot. From 100%. It’s nuts, and EXTREMELY frustrating, because unlike Dragon Quest, if you die, you restart from your last save, you DON’T respawn and just lose some money. Once you get a full party though, the game becomes kinda piss easy, and honestly a little boring. You just cast buff spells on your main character and go to town on enemies, as they get too tanky to one-shot. Then it becomes hard as hell again when you’re knocked down to you and Sphinx. The difficulty balance is all incorrect.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/juvidl6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Other than that, the game is… perfectly fine. Fine music, if not unoriginal. Cool graphics, lots of nice big enemy sprites. And I actually really liked the story, for the most part, it was kinda engaging and interesting with cool little vignets. But the ending is absolutely nuts. So uh, spoilers for Double Moon Densetsu, a game you were totally going to play.</p>

<p>The game ends with you delving deep into the earth, deeper than anyone has gone before. You confront the evil priest who kidnapped your sister (not before killing your dad. Or not killing him if you kill the fake clones first, to get a good/neutral ending thing. It’s weird), but are too late. You defeat him, but the ritual is done, and the DARK DRAGON is summoned to the world, using your sister as a host. You have to defeat her. But the Dark Dragon cannot be killed, and must be sealed away. So you seal it away in your body… You know that its evil corrupting presence will always be there, inside you, but to save the world, you’ll make that sacrifice.</p>

<p>THIS IS THE ENDING TO DIABLO. DID THE DEVS OF DIABLO PLAY DOUBLE MOON DENSETSU??? THIS IS LITERALLY EXACTLY DIABLO, except instead of a prince it’s your sister, and also it’s all good and optimistic in the end instead of fucking dark and depressing.</p>

<p>Anyways, like a 6/10. If you REALLY like NES-style RPGs and Dragon Quest, maybe check it out, but for everyone else, it’s a skip.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Double Moon Densetsu" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 139 - The Magic of Scheherazade</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/17/RA139-Scheherazade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 139 - The Magic of Scheherazade" /><published>2025-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/17/RA139-Scheherazade</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/17/RA139-Scheherazade.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hBF1ggB.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Magic of Scheherazade is a FASCINATING game. Made by Culture Brain, a weird-ass company who was always pushing boundaries, they’re most well known for their Little Ninja Bros/Super Chinese World series. But this is their other most well known game, a cult classic that may not have sold well, but that kept itself lodged in the brains of gamers who got to play it back in the day.</p>

<p>MoS is an RPG. What kind of RPG? <strong>Yes.</strong> It is both an action RPG in the vein of Zelda or Startropics, with a top down perspective and sword swinging action, and ALSO a turn based RPG with levels and spells and stuff.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cL2wGRl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The story is pretty interesting. There’s this evil warlock, Sabaron, summoning an ancient demon, Goragora, and you’re the only person who can stop him, a powerful wizard and descendant of the ancient hero. Unfortunately, you lose before the game even starts, and your mind is wiped. But you still have your sense of justice, and even depowered, you know you must save the world, AND save the love of your life, Scheherazade, who was kidnapped by the warlock. so now, go, and save Arabia! Yeah, it’s Arabia here, and with Scheherazade, it likens itself to 1001 Nights, though it basically just makes up all of its lore, just with an ancient middle eastern style. Anyways, you are met by the Time Spirit, Coronya, a cute cat, who can take you through time to help you in your adventure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VfM0XCl.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game has a LOT of interesting systems in it. It has a class system. You can be a warrior (your sword is larger), mage (you shoot your rod faster, the best by far) or cleric (bad sword and rod, but you can block shots, worst, used only once for a quest). It has a level up system, which interestingly has a level cap that increases by 5 every chapter, and ALSO automatically levels you up if you’re behind, so no real need to grind! It has a magic system, you getting spells as you level, but ALSO you can find one super spell each chapter. It has a day-night cycle, kinda. Every now and then an eclipse happens, darkening everything and also empowering your super spells. It has a party system, you find party members who help you during quests. And it has random battles, both top down action, and also turn based. I just ran from the turn based ones. All the enemies  had too much health and you did so little damage.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oSWMRx6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, this game does it all. But as a result, it doesn’t do everything GREAT. It does it WELL! It’s… INTERESTING, and quite fun in parts, but it doesn’t really stand out as an AMAZING NES game. Just, good. All the parts of it are good. It’s a jack of all trades situation. I do recommend it, there’s a lot to enjoy about it, but it can be a little clunky at parts, it can be a little hard to figure out what to do and where to go, and some of the bosses are genuinely annoying (Looking at you, Salamander). Good game though, it’s been on my list for years and I’m glad I finally got to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Magic of Scheherazade" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 88</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/17/OOCY88.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 88" /><published>2025-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/17/OOCY88</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/17/OOCY88.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/vYu78tQ.png" alt="&quot;Let's be best friends forever! Sound good? :D&quot; &quot;...Mm.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Friend Zoned?</p>

<p>source: Our Yuri Started With Me Being Rejected In a Dream</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Our Yuri Started With Me Being Rejected In a Dream" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">All images on the site seem to have died</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/updates/2025/01/16/Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All images on the site seem to have died" /><published>2025-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/updates/2025/01/16/Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/updates/2025/01/16/Update.html"><![CDATA[<p>I seriously have no idea why that is. I think imgur updated a thing and broke literally everything which is very, VERY annoying, because I have 260 fucking pages here FILLED with dozens upon dozens of images. I really, REALLY hope they fix it soon…</p>

<p>I know not a lot of people read this but it’s still something that brings me joy, so like, I wanna hold onto it. It’s also kind of the only part of Cohost I still got left.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I seriously have no idea why that is. I think imgur updated a thing and broke literally everything which is very, VERY annoying, because I have 260 fucking pages here FILLED with dozens upon dozens of images. I really, REALLY hope they fix it soon…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 87</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/13/OOCY87.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 87" /><published>2025-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/13/OOCY87</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/13/OOCY87.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/knFe1NG.png" alt="&quot;It's nice to go for a stroll now and then!&quot; she says, but she's just going to the convenience store to buy Magic cards." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Guess who’s back</p>

<p>source: 100 Days until the president and new hire have XXX</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="100 Days until the president and new hire have XXX" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Going Out of Town - GDQ Hiatus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/updates/2025/01/03/GDQHiatus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Going Out of Town - GDQ Hiatus" /><published>2025-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/updates/2025/01/03/GDQHiatus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/updates/2025/01/03/GDQHiatus.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m going out of town tomorrow, and I’ll be at GDQ for the next week and a half! No updates until I get home, so you’ll have to get your yuri elsewhere, sorry. If you are ALSO going to GDQ, please feel free to chat with me. Ask me about yuri, and I’ll give you a suggestion, I’ll try a different suggestion each day.</p>

<p>Thanks for understanding, and have a nice week!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="updates" /><category term="updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m going out of town tomorrow, and I’ll be at GDQ for the next week and a half! No updates until I get home, so you’ll have to get your yuri elsewhere, sorry. If you are ALSO going to GDQ, please feel free to chat with me. Ask me about yuri, and I’ll give you a suggestion, I’ll try a different suggestion each day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 86</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/02/OOCY86.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 86" /><published>2025-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/02/OOCY86</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/02/OOCY86.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7zSnOXC.png" alt="&quot;Isn't class over? Is she that committed to the grind?&quot; *walks over to girl studying* &quot;Hey, Tong Tong, you can't just do that!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1HGvphD.png" alt="&quot;You are going to become a test-taking machine, all by yourself, and betray... us... all?&quot; *notices book, which is called Guide to Femdom*" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class’s Green Tea Bitch</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class&apos;s Green Tea Bitch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>