<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-21T12:29:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 77</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 77" /><published>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q9BSf8s.png" alt="&quot;I ... I like... you...&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IMvfNDG.png" alt="&quot;You finally did it.&quot; &quot;I- I like you...&quot; &quot;I like you too.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sunday 13.00</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sunday 13.00" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 76</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 76" /><published>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WuMHUBp.png" alt="&quot;What does it mean to love someone romantically?&quot; &quot;You're interested in even the smallest things about them... in finding a side you haven't seen yet... if you realize this, it means you like them more than a friend!&quot; &quot;NOPE!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tnznnB7.png" alt="&quot;The very first thing you like about your romantic love is their face, right?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: In a Home Where Lilies Bloom</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="In a Home Where Lilies Bloom" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 134 - Zelda 2 The Adventure of Link</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 134 - Zelda 2 The Adventure of Link" /><published>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gumj4Aj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When I was really young, we had two Zelda games. We had Link’s Awakening, and we had this, Zelda 2. So a lot of my love of this is nostalgia. I’ve been playing this game since I was 2. But I think even if I played it today, I’d love it. Zelda 2 is a very controversial title, but is in my opinion one of the absolute best Zeldas, and it gets a bad wrap. I’ve lived my life on the internet, and the common pervailing idea around this game for YEARS was that it blows. These same people suck the dick of Dark Souls, but Zelda 2 is bad. Because it’s hard. They are very, VERY wrong. Zelda 2 whips. It whips so hard I mastered it, which involved me playing this game FOUR FUCKING TIMES. And I had a great time doing it!!</p>

<p>Zelda 2 is maybe the POSTER CHILD for my “NES Sequel Syndrome”. Games from that era that were sequels to a popular game that’d continue on with an amazing series, but the second game is different and weird compared to the others. I’m talking games like SMB2, Final Fantasy 2, Metroid 2 I guess, and this. The absolute poster child. Conceptually, if I explain what this game is out loud, it sounds very similar to Zelda 1. You play a little elf boy who travels around an over world fighting monsters. You explore this overworld and find dungeons, which contain an item that will help you progress further. Go through all the dungeons, go to the final dungeon, beat a boss. That’s just Zelda 1, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1V131xK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Well no, obviously. There’s a lot I didn’t mention. Zelda 2 has towns you can explore to heal up, cause there’s no health drops. Zelda 2 has magic spells you get from these towns, which can be used to do things like shield you or heal you. Zelda 2 has no money or shops. Zelda 2 has EXP, which upgrades one of your three stats, Health, Magic, or Attack. And most notably, Zelda 2 is not a top down action RPG, it is a side scrolling action RPG. You walk back and forth, jumping and ducking and stabbing with your dinky little sword. This has some VERY deep combat in places, frankly, I like it more than the Zelda 1 combat, by a large, large margin. Combat in Zelda 1 is a little… hokey and awkward at times. Fighting randomly moving enemies like Darknuts or the Wizzrobes blooooows. Here, the enemies have patterns you learn, and it’s like a beautiful dance with each one, that’s so rewarding. It feelS SO good once you can take on darknuts flawlessly. Or hell, the Dairas. GOD the Dairas.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/l8DUKvc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The world of Zelda 2 is pretty expansive, with a big-ass overworld to explore. Lots of little caves to go into and get EXP or heart containers, or items to unlock magic spells. And while some people might claim this game is bad because it’s so obtuse, this game isn’t Castlevania 2. All the people in towns give good hints. And nothing is SO obscure that you’ll get lost. Shit, it’s WAY less obtuse than fucking Zelda 1, which people still love to death. That god damn 8th dungeon bush? Burning EVERY BUSH to find entrances??? Zelda 2 has none of that. The most obscure thing here is the forest town you gotta find by breaking down trees with your hammer, but there ARE hints for that.</p>

<p>The other reason people hate this is cause of its difficulty. And yes, it’s hard. It’s a hard mother fucker. Like, I can practically play this game blindfolded now, but its HARD. Death Mountain is a cakewalk to me, but to your average joe, it is a WALL, a brick wall you must beat down with your face. I acknowledge this. I realize that I am biased. But that feeling of satisfaction when you beat it! Also, it never feels UNFAIR hard. Like, you’ve gotta learn the patterns, you’ve gotta perservere. You never need to grind, you can push through and make it. Though the option IS there if you want it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cmo3ltz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Frankly, Zelda 2 is a masterpiece, and I cannot praise it enough. It saddens me that Nintendo decided to never return to this style again, though to be fair, so many other games picked up the slack and did their hand at it quite well. Shout outs to Monster World 4. While they’ve never returned to this style, they certainly don’t seem ashamed of Zelda 2, and they haven’t forgotten it. Ocarina of Time brings some enemies back and re-uses the names of the towns for the sages. And of course you can play it in any Nintendo online service from the past 17 years.</p>

<p>So if I love this game so much, why did it take me this long to play it for Retro Achievements? It didn’t. I beat this game a year ago, securing the beat. …But not the mastery. This is a series on the MASTERIES of a game, where I 100% the achievement set for it. And the achievement set for this game required me to play it multiple times. Technically I COULD have mastered it in maybe two playthroughs, but I wasn’t going to do a candleless 1cc with no heal or shield spell on a 1st quest, so I had to split everything up into four playthroughs.</p>

<p>So yeah, I played this game MULTIPLE times this year. And you’ll find out soon, even more than that. It’s not too long, I can breeze through it in two hours, and it’s a fun two hours the entire time. Absolutely fantastic game. If you’ve never checked it out due to its reputation, give it a chance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Zelda" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 75</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 75" /><published>2024-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zjk0wG1.png" alt="&quot;I bumped into the tank today because I was thinking about you...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, since this is a repost, there’s also a very funny reaction and response I now need to share about this post…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/d194RA3.png" alt="&quot;Wow what a cute and sweet panel, I wonder what happens next in this manga.&quot; &quot;HARDCORE GAY LESBIAN SEX.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Higher the Breakwater, the Quicker it is to Crumble</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Higher the Breakwater the Quicker it is to Crumble" /><category term="NSFW source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 133 - Fire n’ Ice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 133 - Fire n’ Ice" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZgfxJ8B.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I love how god awful this cover is. What the hell is this. This is supposed to make me buy your game? No wonder this sold poorly here.</p>

<p>So I was watching a friend, Mister Radon, play some games, and someone made him play this for a bit. I was like “WOAH. THIS LOOKS LIKE IT’S EXACTLY MY JAM WHY HAVE I NEVER SEEN THIS”? So I played it the following day and DEVOURED it.</p>

<p>Fire n’ Ice is the sequel to classic Tecmo title “Solomon’s Key”. Known in Japan specifically as Solomon’s Key 2, it’s actually a prequel, showing the first adventure of the great wizard DANA! An evil fire wizard is attacking the peaceful ice island, and Dana has been chosen by the fairies who rule the island to stop him!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wdEBJiR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a single screen puzzle game. You get into a level, and then your goal is simple. Push ice onto the fire. Once all the fire is gone, you move onto the next level! Complete all 100 levels and you’re good! You can push ice, or climb up on it if it’s already up against something else. You can also create ice, but ONLY down and diagonal from you. So it can be pretty difficult to go upwards, you need to prepare ahead of time if you want to climb back up. But using these tools, you can get through all the puzzles, creating ice blocks, then clearing the way so you can push them onto the fires.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zkVpAS7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s really rewarding, and honestly, AMAZING for the NES? It’s a late NES game, but honestly it feels more like an itch.io puzzle game, or a modern NES homebrew. The animations are fantastic. Dana has a lot of personality, like his little shimmy when he’s up under a ceiling (or ice block). The fire is constantly wiggin’ out, and the music is really chill and fun. And every now and then you get a BOSS LEVEL, which is a screen that’s constantly scrolling and looping, which makes for some interesting gameplay, cause you often need to build a way up, but without blocking yourself on the second loop.</p>

<p>After you beat the 100 levels and the final boss, you can sit through the credits and get a code to unlock 50 more bonus levels. This game has SO MUCH CONTENT. It is CHOCK FULL of puzzles, and there’s really no stinkers in here! There were no puzzles I played and went “wow that fucking blew?” They can be challenging, but very rewarding to push through.</p>

<p>All in all, this is a FANTASTIC NES game, that frankly more people should know about. I HIGHLY recommend it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Fire n Ice" /><category term="Solomon&apos;s Key" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 132 - New Rally-X</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA132-RallyX.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 132 - New Rally-X" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA132-RallyX</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA132-RallyX.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P649Xo7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Last PC88 game for a bit, this is New Rally-X, a classic arcade maze chaser from the very early 80s made by Namco. It’s basically just a lightly tweaked version of Rally X, which was a little bulshit. Some new graphics, easier gameplay, new music, and the iconic Lucky Flag you can pickup that gives you bonus points. And of course, like so many early 80s arcade games, this was ported to the PC88.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JDSVDcz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’ll be real, I don’t think I like Rally-X very much. It feels… empty. Flat. To explain it very simply, you take Pacman, make the maze like 12x bigger, with scrolling, and place only a few dots all around at random. You also have a fuel meter, if that runs out you’re dead, and you can release smoke behind you to confuse the ghosts (cars in this case). Also some spaces are wider than the 1 tile you occupy, so enemies can juke you a bit easier.</p>

<p>I don’t really like it much. Like I said, it feels too big and empty, and the mini-map combined with the larger map on the left just feels confusing in a way I don’t think I appreciate. After a few levels you get a “Challenging Stage”, where the enemies don’t chase you, but instead you have shit laying around you can run into, and it’s way easier than the other stages. Another reason I don’t like it much is the AI of the enemy cars makes no god damn sense. Sometimes they’re like, ALL Inky from Pacman, good at jukes and chasing you down/doing pincer attacks. And at other times they’re all Clyde, ignoring you completely and just wandering randomly, sometimes going in the opposite direction when chasing you. It makes no sense and it makes me anxious.</p>

<p>This set was EXTREMELY easy though. It’s not a very hard maze game, all things considered.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Rally-X" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 74</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 74" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RelCIYl.png" alt="&quot;Look at me as much as you like. Like me more and more. And if you blush, use that blush to dye me red too.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Fall for me and dye me red</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Fall for me and dye me red" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 130 - Puzzle Kana?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA130-PuzzleKana.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 130 - Puzzle Kana?" /><published>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA130-PuzzleKana</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA130-PuzzleKana.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6lR1EZO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>More PC88! So the PC-88 was NOT made for games, but it has quite a few really famous and popular ones. And they all kinda have a… vibe about them. After having played a lot of PC88, my opinions are that most of them are rough and awkward, held back by the hardware its on. I haven’t played all the most popular PC88 games, of course, I haven’t touched Ys yet. But of all the everything I’ve played? This my favorite. This is my favorite PC88 game. And it’s a random fucking doujin game from 1990.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/19meAxc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Made by “Studio 4989”, Puzzle Kana is a very simple puzzle game. It’s a sokoban-style game where you push blocks into the “in” goal. In this game, blocks will slide forever until they hit a wall or another object, so it’s like ice-block puzzles. The first example I can think of with stuff like that is the ice cave in Pokemon Silver and Gold. So think that, but a bit more complex. You can’t push balls into each other, they’ll shatter, and some blocks can be pushed, but others can’t. There are a few other kinds of blocks, like redirection arrows, but its a very simple rules set up.</p>

<p>And yes, this is maybe my favorite game I’ve played on the PC88. It looks good. It SOUNDS fantastic. Every 5 levels you get a cute little cutscene or mini game. You can easily go specific levels using password systems. The little anime girl, Kana I suppose, is cute as hell. This is just a really well made doujin game. It is a tad short, and not very hard as far as sokoban goes, but that’s honestly a good thing, because a lot of PC88 games are fucking impossible.</p>

<p>I’m sure I’ll find SOMETHING I like more than this, but what do I have to compare it to? Super Mario Bros Special? Hydlide??? The Scheme maybe comes close, though I’d rather play Puzzle Kana again than play The Scheme again.</p>

<p>Anyways it’s fun.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Puzzle Kana" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 131 - Bomb Jack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA131-Bombjack.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 131 - Bomb Jack" /><published>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA131-Bombjack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA131-Bombjack.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/va5mk98.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another PC88 game here, this one is Bomb Jack, a port of the classic arcade game. Bomb Jack is one of those Tecmo games that’s more of like, a b-tier. People who play it like it but it’s not even CLOSE to the top when people name Tecmo properties. He got a few more games after this, including the sick NES game “Mighty Bomb Jack”, but is mostly remembered TODAY because of the game “Mighty Jill Off” which pays homage to it, and I had a LOT of people going “oh shit is this Mighty Jill Off” in the chat as I played it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N7fwy3O.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Bomb Jack you play as the titular Bomb Jack, who is attempting to collect all the bombs on the screen. Get them all, move to the next level. Once you get a bomb, a bomb on screen becomes lit, based on which bomb you picked up. There’s a pattern and order to the bombs, but you never know what it is until you pick up a bomb (or look it up). If you get enough lit bombs you can get bonuses and things, including an item that makes you super and lets you defeat enemies. SPEAKING of enemies, there are a few kinds. A bird is always slowly chasing you through the air, but skeletons spawn near the top and fall to the bottom off platforms. Once they reach the bottom they transform into a new flying enemy, and a new skeleton spawns.</p>

<p>As Bomb Jack, you can jump and hover. You can do a super jump by holding up, and hover my tapping the jump button in the air. It’s pretty intuitive in the arcade, but a little jank here. and that, sadly is how I’d describe this port. It’s very, very jank. A good game hampered by the hardware its on, which honestly describes MOST PC88 games I’ve played. Everything is on a kind of grid, which y’know, makes sense, but it also means hit detection is FUCKED. I’ve gone right through pwoer up coins and died hitting enemies I thought I’d be invulnerable to. And I STILL have no idea how to get an extra life, I guess I just got lucky for the achievement.</p>

<p>Bomb Jack is a good arcade game, but is sadly let down by the PC88. Just play the PC88 version. Or the NES version, which is completely different.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Puzzle Kana" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 21 - 26</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/15/LizstartrekDS96-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 21 - 26" /><published>2024-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/15/LizstartrekDS96-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/15/LizstartrekDS96-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zdayXgW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>So, there’s only one more episode left in DS9 season 6. We’re going to watch it next week, where I’ll repost this with the additional episode.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>The Reckoning</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fiK79p8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The war is going bad, though a BIT better with the Romulans entering. That’s good! Odo and Kira are cute and lovey dovey now which will take some getting used to.</p>

<p>Anyways, Sisko, Kira, and Jake go down to Bajor, cause apparently some monks found a thing that might be important for the Emissary. Jake is being a weird little bitch about it like “Why is my dad okay with being Jesus now, why are we here, isn’t there more important stuff to worry about”. Jake. You’re an adult now. You’re like, 20. You don’t need to tag along when your dad goes away. As they see some old door that says “Welcome Emissary”, Sisko gets a vision that tells him that THE RECKONING APPROACHES.</p>

<p>They bring the stone door up to the station and give it to Dax, who has one of my favorite lines. “Yep, I know what this was the moment I laid eyes on it. It’s a hunk of stone with some writing on it.”</p>

<p>Sisko: “The prophets are never clear in their messages”</p>

<p>Kai Winn: “Ah, I wouldn’t know. They’ve never spoken to me.”</p>

<p>WHY IS THIS WOMAN POPE?? Anyways Kai Winn is a bitch like she always is, and demands the stone tablet back, just cause she’s a weirdo xenophobe. And then they translate the tablet and it says, very clearly: “DS9 is going to blow up”. Uh oh. And then the wormhole gets unstable and it starts fucking up Bajor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ulIDbN.png" alt="trek" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/x5XQf56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then Sisko gets fed up with it all and throws the fucking tablet against the wall. We then see Things release from it. I’m sure that’s fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yPjAwhq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We then find out what’s happening. Some Prophets and some Pah-Wraiths were released. The Prophet takes Kira, who it says is willing so that’s fine, and says that it is going to fight a Pah-Wraith here once it takes its own body to fight with. Kai Winn is like “FINALLY, A PROPHET” and begs it to give her something to do, she wants to help, and its basically like “who are you” by just, ignoring her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KBoEKlv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They call for an evacuation, and everyone leaves, except Winn who’s being annoying as always, and we see the Pah Wraith’s choice of body: Jake. There’s a lot of body horror in his face, it’s extremely upsetting to watch. There’s a fucking DBZ-ass battle, with energy beams, and it’s unsure who’s going to win, and who might die… Until Kai Wrinn uses a button that hurts Prophets, and knocks them out of their body. Why? We don’t know. She goes “Prophets forgive me…” but uh, I dunno if they will.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that everything that follows is probably her fault. The prophets said everything would be good if they win, which wasn’t guaranteed, but it looked like it was. So yeah, she just killed a LOT of people, and Space Satan is still out there. Kira calls her out on it, and blames it on her pride, which y’know, makes sense. It’s what the whole episode was about.</p>

<p>Interestng lore, just alright episode.</p>

<p><strong>Valiant</strong> - DS9
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JLpcQmR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While Jake and Nog are going to Ferenginar to deliver a thing to the Grand Nagus, they’re attacked by some Jem’Hadar, oh no! They’re rescued by… the Defiant! Nope, not the Defiant, it’s a ship called The Valiant, which is clearled based on the Defiant. So they’re trying to mass produced the Defiant now. That’s… gonna go well I’m sure. The people on the ship are all cadets… kind of. Turns out they’re RED SQUADRON! You may not remember them. They were the Elite of the Elite cadets at the Acadamy. They ALSO tried to help set up a coup a season or two ago. They explain that they were supposed to just be on a training exercise (the same one they were sent on in that episode actually), and then all the senior crew died in an attack, and one of them, Shepard, took command and now they’re stuck behind enemy lines and basically doing run and hide tactics to hit at the Dominion.</p>

<p>They invite Nog in to join them, and Nog’s always looked up to Red Squad, so he’s on board, and they need an engineer. But Nog is a little suspicious… because this captain seems to be doing this under the radar, and all the missions are sent to the dead captain instead of him, and they don’t know he’s just assumed command. But everything is on the level so far. So far.</p>

<p>Jake befriends the doctor on board, and asks her about home. This gets her kinda emotional and missing home. Y’know, normal human stuff. But this is a WAR and we are a MILITARY. Please ignore the fact that Starfleet is not, in fact, military. They are a MILITARY. They bring her and Jake in and are like “You are not allowed to be friends because you’ll DISTRACT THEM”. Also, the captain appears to be addicted to pills, and is kinda wigging out in a very sussy way. Jake is side eying all of this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOB1m6S.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re all just kids. They’re kids who are thrust into a situation they aren’t ready to handle, and they are kids who are basically being used to play out the captain’s Captain Fantasies.</p>

<p>Jake is thrown in the brig because he’s questioning this guy’s bullshit. Everyone else has kinda swallowed the poison. The captain has them go attack a destroyer. It’s basically like the Millenium Falcon trying to blow up a Star Destroyer. It does not go well. It predictably does not go well, and everyone starts dying as the Explodium goes off. It’s now just Nog and the girl Jake befriended, and then they rescue Jake from the brig and escape in a pod, barely making it out. The girl is like “the captain was a good man, and if he failed that means we failed him.” She’s STILL drinking the coolaid, but Nog makes the episode’s message clear: He may have been a good man. But he was a bad captain. And he killed a lot of innocent people with his arrogance.</p>

<p><strong>Profit And Lace</strong> - DS9
1.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zdayXgW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Here it is. One of the big ones. This is often considered the worst episode of DS9 of all time. And as a woman myself, I am sure I will have a LOT of opinions about it. But who knows? Maybe it’ll surprise us, and be good!</p>

<p>The episode starts with Quark sexually harassing one of his workers by demanding she sleep with him or he’ll fire her.</p>

<p>Well, that didn’t last long!</p>

<p>Anywayst the REAL episode starts when Grand Nagus Zek shows up on DS9 with Quark and Rom’s mom, Moogie. She’s wearing clothes! and in PUBLIC! Zek explains that he recently passed a law that allows women to wear clothes. And if they can wear clothes, they can go out in public. And if they do that, they can make profit. Yay! Unfortunately, this caused societal upheaval, and all the men in power banded together to depose Zek, and now Brunt is acting Grand Nagus, to be sworn in in only a few days. Zek drags the other main character Ferengi in trying to get people on his side. It doesn’t go well. Everyone is sexist. Fuck, even Zek is. He’s progressive… for a Ferengi. Anyways they get ONE person on their side, ready to see a female to prove females can interface with society</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gk5PrgF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Brunt continues to be the most punchable man in the galaxy.</p>

<p>Quark and Moogie get in an argument and she has a heart attack. That’s not good. They need a woman to show to this guy, but where are they going to get one?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AHWrcp5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Good thing Bashir does gender reassignment surgeries like every other day. It IS the 24th century.</p>

<p>Yes. That’s right. This is the transgender episode. Kind of. It’s actually the Gender Bender episode, but like, this hits a lot of trans energy. And not in a good way. Quark is now a woman, MEDICALLY, like he’s filled with estrogen. And it’s making her emotional. Ha ha, you know them women. ALWAYS emotional. They have a lot of things to grill Quark on, she has to be presentable in like, 12 hours. She needs to work on her walk. And her voice. And she needs to smile more! They don’t literally have that last one, but god, they might as well.</p>

<p>This is one of those feminist episodes that…. fails in almost every way, but god, is it insulting. I mean, I guess it’s trying. Kind of. The original concept was to make it a kind of comical farce, like a Shakespearean farce, but the director, Bashir’s actor, and Quark’s actor decided to play this DEAD serious. As such, the writing and the visual intent clash in a way that is very, VERY uncomfortable.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1Pgnw9l.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We literally get three straight minutes of this guy they invited chasing Quark around her room, trying to sexually assault her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cDnTSaX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Brunt bursts it and is like “THAT’S NOT WOMAN, THAT’S A MAN, BABY” but when Quark shows her tits to this guy, he doesn’t care. Well at least he’s a chaser, I guess. Anyway alls well that ends well, and he backs Zek to put him back in office. Quark’s experience with being a woman makes him more sympathetic, at least for a bit, and he apologizes to the woman he sexually assaulted, and she’s like “oh but I was looking forward to fucking you :(“. Ha ha, what… fun.</p>

<p>Yeah, this blows a lot. To be fair, Armin Shimmerman, Quark’s actor, also agrees. He thinks the half-serious half-joke idea failed horribly, I agree, and he actually toned down some of it, because the script wanted him to cry a lot, and he felt it was a bad stereotype, and went against the feminist angle of the episode. Yea, that’s true. It could have been even worse. Also, Quark really learns nothing by the end, and yeah. THey LITERALLY go “You’ll be back to your old self soon~”</p>

<p>And obviously, this episode wasn’t built with trans stuff in mind, but as trans stuff is VERY in the public conscious these days, it’s hard to ignore that reading. And that voice outing scene made me want to gag. I hated this episode, but I can’t give it a 1. It’s at least TRYING to be good, it’s trying, but fucking god.</p>

<p><strong>Time’s Orphan</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dVWHBeg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>O’Brien is back! We haven’t seen him in a few episodes. And KEIKO IS BACK! We haven’t seen her in AGES! They’re back from Bajor, and O’Brien doesn’t want them to ever part again. The bad news is, they are immediately parted. O’BRIEN MUST SUFFER! They’re playing on a Bajoran colony on vacation, and Molly finds a weird gate thing in a cave and falls into it, disappearing as the gate closes.</p>

<p>They find out it’s a TIME PORTAL that was just sitting around I guess, and it sent her hundreds of years in the past. She’s now somewhere in the past, when the planet was uninhabited. They reactivate the portal, and get her back… but 10 years too late. She’s now 18, and is a wild child. She bites O’Brien before she’s sedated. She’s VERY unga bunga. Now they need to re-integrate her into society, and good luck with that,.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the B-plot is that Worf needs to baby sit Yoshi, and he is VERY bad with kids. At least the A and B plots fit. It’s also a fun concept.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4fCwdwq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode then becomes Keiko and O’Brien trying to rehabilitate Molly, who seems to have repressed all her childhood memories and remembers nothing. It’s actually REALLY heartwarming and sweet to watch, tinged, with some sadness.</p>

<p>Eventually she becomes a little unstable. She’s improving, but she wants to go “home”. They take her home, but no, not THAT home. HOME. They can’t go back to the planet though, so they take her to the holosuite. But they can’t keep her there forever, and when other customers want it, Molly goes…. feral, and freaks out, and then runs through the bar and STABS A MAN IN THE STOMACH WITH A BROKEN BOTTLE. Oh. Oh that’s very bad. The man presses charges and wants her incacerated, because she’s dangerous. I mean, she kind of is… it’s a very unfortunate situation. She needs wide open spaces, but they can’t really give her that on the station. And they’re going to send her to a therapy center, which is PROBABLY not going to be good for her either. And imagine her being on a transport for a few days.</p>

<p>So what are they going to do? Time for O’Brien to do crimes.</p>

<p>They kidnap Molly and drag her, sedated, back to the planet. She’s not safe there, she’s not really safe anywhere… so they try to steal a runabout, and are caught. Odo’s like “Come on Chief, I thought if ANYONE could steal a runabout without getting caught, it’d be you. On your way”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oABXZlr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They send Molly back through the portal, planning to destroy it after. It’s a tearful goodbye, but Molly goes through, to his home… and then finds out she’s been transported not to her time, but to the exact time she went through the first time, finding herself as a 7 year old. She sends her back through, and fades away due to temporal shenanigans.</p>

<p>Well, that KINDA negates the gut punch. That’s a real shame. Like, I liked everything about this episode, it was cute and heartrending, and then it meant nothing! Hmmrf. Good, but didn’t hit the landing.</p>

<p><strong>The Sound of Her Voice</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4HcpJvs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On the way home from a long tiring mission, the Defiant gets a distress call from a woman who’s apparently a star fleet officer asking for help. They head over to help her. They can’t get any messages back through the planet, and O’Brien is on the case. He leaves her SOS message on as she rambles, basically. She’s just rambling about her life, because she has no one to talk to and is scared she’s going to die. Everyone is like “why are you doing that”. And he’s like “I dunno, it just feels right, like someone HAS to listen, otherwise she’s falling on deaf ears, and that’s sad”</p>

<p>Also the B-plot is Quark is distracting Odo by reminding him of his love for Kira in order to do illegal stuff, and Jake is researching him. It doesn’t fit.</p>

<p>Anyways they connect and can communicate with her now. She’s a captain who was returning to the Alpha Quadrant after an 8 year exploration of the Beta Quadrant. She’s the only one in her squad left, and she’s dying on an L-Class planet, so they’d better get there fast, but they keep her company. Most of the crew find her boring as fuck. Especially Bashir. She tortures him for ignoring him by pretending that something got her and ate her. It wakes him up and makes him realize he was being shitty. She’s his patient.</p>

<p>It’s kinda interesting seeing this. Everyone talks to her in a different way. O’Brien practically uses her as a friend and therapist. She tries to give advise to Sisko. And she and Bashir jab at each other. But things take a bad turn; the medicine she’s using runs out faster than expected, as her last dose was tainted. She’ll die in two days of CO2 poisoning. And they’re still 3 days away.</p>

<p>The b-plot ends in a cute way. Quark gets outplayed by Odo, who hears Quark like “and after I helped him with with Kira, tsk tsk”, and Odo decides to… let him have one. JUST this one. It’s cute. Odo’s been pretty good these episodes, he’s really grown as a person.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HvaIkGS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tried taking a picture and caught this picture instead that looks like Sisko just heard someone on the bridge make a racist joke</p>

<p>They have to risk their lives in a few ways to make it in time, but they do it, to save her life.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lxajUtY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways they go, and find out she’s been dead for years. The anomaly that they had to get through caused her SOS to go forward in time. They couldn’t have EVER made it in time. She had no chance ):</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sW6ycOK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They couldn’t save her, but they have a funeral for her, because over those six days, she had become a friend. And not only that, but she taught them all that they needed to talk, that they were holding things inside. It’s really touching. A very good scene. And a good episode! The Quark B plot was alright but mostly unrelated and didn’t fit in, but it ended quite nicely.</p>

<p><strong>Tears of the Prophets</strong> - DS9
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L3PVskj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things are gonna be changing around here.</p>

<p>An admiral shows up to award Sisko an… award, and also tell him that he’s been chosen to plan the invasion of Cardassia! A big call. He only lost 70% of the fleet taking back DS9, so it’ll go better this time.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Worf and Dax are thinking of having a baby! Quark and Bashir are being weird about it because they’re being weird incels cause Dax is hot. Look, yes, she’s hot, I want to date her too, but she shot you both down SEASONS ago, get over it. You’re already dating one of the hottest lizards in the quadrant, Bashir, stop being greedy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NAAU6y4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, guess who’s back at Cardassia? That’s right, it’s Dukat! And he’s looking… a little off. His makeup feels more rough, less correct. I think it’s on purpose, especially when he’s side by side with Damar. He’s not doing so hot. No one on Cardassia, even Damar, really wants anything to do with him, but they ask him what he wants. And all he wants to do is give them the Alpha Quadrant… and all he needs is an artifact they took from Bajor and is still sitting on Cardassia, somewhere, probably</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WZFyvjX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey, our boy is back! Yes, he’s gonna be an actual fixture! He sings a serenade to “the losers”, AKA Quark and Bashir, and then tells them to fucking get over themselves, they never had a chance and this was over years ago. Namely, six fucking seasons ago. This also feels weirdly out of nowhere considering the rest of the episode is planning to invade Cardassia, but it WILL come together. For better or for worse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UUhRO5z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh hey we found out what Dukat is looking for. “We’ve spent too long fighting the Bajorans. We should have fought their gods”. And then he released a Pah Wraith and accepts it inside him. Super Powered Dukat D:</p>

<p>While the invasion is going on, Dukat beams onto DS9, murders Dax in cold blood in a VERY brutal and upsetting scene, and then released the Pah Wraith into an Orb, basically breaking it apart. Dukat, then fully in control of his faculties, is like “I never intended to do you any harm, sorry~” then beams back away. The broken orb seems to have affected Sisko out in the battle, and he’s taken to his room while Kira takes control of the battle. They manage to win the battle and ground troops land on Cardassia. So I guess Dukat’s plan didn’t work? Uh no, bad news. The wormhole is gone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HvJezFe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Dax is dying, and while Bashir saved the symbiont, Jadzia can’t be saved. She’s come down with an extremely terminal case of Rick Berman. While this might have been emotional if I watched it in the late 90s, I watch it in the mid 2020s with hindsight about WHY it happened, and I’ll be real, I fucking hate it. It also doesn’t help that this entire episode has been her being all happy and going “oh boy a baby oh gee I’m so happy I love my life I sure do love living and being alive”, like the death flags are ALL OVER HERE.</p>

<p>Everyone takes this poorly, ESPECIALLY Sisko, who is so shaken that he essentially quits, both as Emissary and as Captain. Everyone says they’ll be waiting for him when he gets back, and then he leaves with Jake. Kira thinks that he’s not coming back. Why? Cause he took the baseball with him.</p>

<p>So basically, Dax’s actor was like “So, since the show is ending next season, I want to look for more work. Can we re-negotiate my contract so I’m more of a recurring character and not a main character?” and Berman went “No, guess we’ll fire you and kill of your character”. And none of the writers or other co-producers knew this conversation at all, they just assumed that she was leaving cause she wanted off the show. And when they found out, they were PISSED. <strong>I’m</strong> pissed. Its the most Rick Berman thing in the entire series, and it’s AWFUL to me. What this means for the future of the show, we’ll see, but it already starts in a VERY gross part. And her death wasn’t even very good or exciting, like. She’s just one shot with no agency, and then is given a “there’s nothing we can do, they lost the will to live”. And this is AFTER the episode starts with two horny bachelors going “God I wish I could fuck Dax”. I hate this. A lot.</p>

<p>The rest of the episode is FINE? It’s a lot of religious stuff that’s okay, but it jumps around a lot. And it ends even worse. And that “I’ve failed as a starship captain” thing??? Like, what would have changed if you stayed home? Could YOU have stopped Ultra Instinct Super Saiyan God Dukat??? He one shot Jadzia with a Red Laser Beam that looked HORRIBLE to experience. At least now we have a foothold in Cardassia!!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>