<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-01T12:09:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 179</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 179" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179.html"><![CDATA[<p>!Out of context yuri, panels are from ‘Keeping a Jewel’ by Sachi Miyabe. Two women are on a bed, looking at each other, with a soft filter effect going on. Their hands are almost touching. One thinks, as she looks longingly into the other, ‘I’m sure the reason my heart races even though she’s a girl is because I have social anxiety…’](https://imgur.com/UYb48Ag.png){: .center-block :}</p>

<p>Sorry for no yuri in a bit, got distracted</p>

<p>source: Keeping a Jewel</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Keeping a Jewel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[!Out of context yuri, panels are from ‘Keeping a Jewel’ by Sachi Miyabe. Two women are on a bed, looking at each other, with a soft filter effect going on. Their hands are almost touching. One thinks, as she looks longingly into the other, ‘I’m sure the reason my heart races even though she’s a girl is because I have social anxiety…’](https://imgur.com/UYb48Ag.png){: .center-block :}]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 203 - Link’s Awakening DX</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 203 - Link’s Awakening DX" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TMF9nVH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I apparently never moved my Link’s Awakening review over here. God, what do I say about Link’s Awakening? Well, it’s my all time favorite  Zelda game, which means it’s one of my favorite games ever. I replay it once every few years. I own like six copies for some reason. It’s utter Zelda perfection.</p>

<p>Coming out in the middle of the Gameboy’s life-cycle, it got a port to the Gameboy Color six years later. It’s pretty similar, with only a few minor changes, and is more of the same. I mastered the original last year, and put this one off cause some of the challenges annoyed me.</p>

<p>This set has a lot of missables. No hit challenges, don’t do this in this order, etc etc. I actually had to play this game through twice to do this because it glitched out. If you kill like 80 enemies in a row or something (I was trying to farm for acorns, forgetting how that worked) it will change your tunic color, and might glitch out other things. It gave me a photograph and I couldn’t get the achievement for getting that photograph later. Oops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8hZucB7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Link’s Awakening started as a remake of LTTP, but I’m so glad it became this in the end. It’s a weird, unique Zelda game. Lots of things that are just… It. And the story! Oh man. I think it’s fitting that my two favorite  Zeldas are Majora’s Mask and this, the two games with the most melancholy and sad stories.</p>

<p>I don’t think I need to go into a full deep dive of Link’s Awakening. All I need to tell you is that it’s fantastic, and this is a good version. Not DEFINITIVE. It adds an additional dungeon, which is an okay dungeon, and the photos system, which is cute.</p>

<p>If you’ve never played Link’s Awakening, I highly recommend it. It’s not too long compared to other Zelda games, but it’s a solid thing for a Gameboy title. Do yourself a favor and check it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Zelda" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Musical Transients - Review and analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/27/MusicalTransients.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Musical Transients - Review and analysis" /><published>2025-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/27/MusicalTransients</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/27/MusicalTransients.html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MAW84RRNw84?si=bgv44V_IhUrtScs2" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>I don’t usually review music. Music is one of those things that’s hard to recommend or review on the internet. When you try to share music, I find people are very likely to just turn their brains off and ignore your suggestions. I’m not sure why this is, but I think it’s cause everyone has specific musical tastes, just to them. Everyone but me, I guess. I love all kinds of music. Every genre, I can find something in it I like. But you know what I ESPECIALLY love? Mashup albums.</p>

<p>At AGDQ2025, my girlfriend asked me if I’d heard of Musical Transients before. She knows I love mashup albums. I had not, so we went back to our room and she showed it to me. Now, that was actually my Nap Time. I would sleep for like an hour or two, because I had to be awake until 5AM. But I’d put this album on, listen to a bit, and fall asleep to it. I do it all the time. That did not happen. I put it on, and it was so interesting, I listened to all of it, then researched the meanings of the songs. I did not take a nap that day, and I was STRUGGLING at 4AM.</p>

<p>Since then I’ve probably listened to the album 100 times. I’m not joking. This is one of my favorite albums of all time now. It’s art.</p>

<p>Musical Transients is made by Psynwave, a British musician and mashup artist who made another album a few years ago, Musical Tangents. Now, I do like Musical Tangents, but not as much. That doesn’t matter much, though. Musical Tangents was advertised as having no real theme or anything, it’s a collection of mashups. Good, well constructed mashups, with the idea of taking the original songs, and completing twisting their meanings and vibes. But still, no meaning. Musical Transients, the follow up album, was advertised the same way.</p>

<p>When I show people Musical Transients, which I do often, I tell them it has no theme for a few songs, before admitting, actually, there’s a VERY central theme to the album. Can you guess what it is? Most people can guess it by the end. I guessed it immediately, but I cheated.</p>

<p>IF YOU’RE INTERESTED IN THIS ALBUM, DO NOT READ AHEAD. This is both a review and a full total analysis of the ENTIRE album. This album is very, very dense with meaning, and I want to take it apart right in front of you. If you’re interested, watch the album, then come back to me. Yes, watch. The album has a lot of fun things in the video, and the video also has subtitles for the songs, which are very useful. Okay, we good? Let’s go.</p>

<p><strong>I BELIEVE IN THE GREEN PARADE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BdAyctj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The album starts with a song called “I Believe in the Green Parade”. It’s a mashup of Black Parade and Rainbow Connection. This album is the opening thesis of the album. It sets the theme and asks a question, basically. But it also feels slightly disconnected to the rest of the album to me. This album is a story of someone’s life, but this album is setting the tone, and is this person basically looking back. It was also designed around a meme post on Twitter from years ago that went “When Black Parade talks about the broken and the beaten and Kermit talks about the lovers and the dreamers, they’re talking about the same people”. It’s a funny post. Why not make a song about it?</p>

<p>After a bit of simple mashupping, where we get the banjo with the lyrics, it bursts into Black Parade’s backing track, and some muppet Show shenanigans. And then we get this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3k8OsSY.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WxOEN4j.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I want you to read these lyrics.</p>

<p>ITs time to put on makeup, it’s time to dress up right. It’s time to raise the curtain on the muppet show tonight.</p>

<p>And then I saw her face, now I’m a believer. Not a trace of doubt in my mind. I’m in love, I’m a believer, I couldn’t leave her, if I tried.</p>

<p>And I don’t really care if no one else believes.</p>

<p>So she said, what’s the problem baby? What’s the problem, I dunno, well maybe I’m in love, love, think about it, everytime I think about it, maybe I’m in love with <em>your body</em>. How much longer will it take to cure this? Just to cure it cause I can’t ignore it if it’s love, love, think about it, maybe I’m in love <em>with the shape of you</em></p>

<p>This sets up the thesis of the album. What’s this album about? Like I said, I cheated. And I mean, come on. The album is called Musical Transients and the cover is in the trans pride flag colors. This is a song about gender discovery, and being a trans woman. This song sets it up pretty well. It shows that the feelings are there, like with the first line about putting on makeup, moving into “and then I saw her face”. Then it makes it clear, “I don’t care if anyone else believes”. This will be a happy story with a happy end. Then the last line, they change the lyrics a bit. “Maybe I’m in love <em>with your body</em>” and “<em>the shape of you</em>”. Not you. Just the shape of your body. I love the feminine body. I sure do wish I had it. Can’t stop thinking about it.</p>

<p>This WILL be a story with a happy end, though it might take a bit to get there, as shown by the next few lines. Black Parade comes back in, with:</p>

<p>“On and on we carry through the fears. Disappointed faces of our peers”</p>

<p>“Another turning point, a fork stuck in the road”, cue the rest of Time of Your Life. Followed immediately by…</p>

<p>“This is my fight! Take back my life! Prove I’m alright!”</p>

<p>Being trans in this world is a dangerous thing. Literally dangerous in many cases. Outsiders will judge and hate you for the rest of your life. It’s a turning point, do we ignore this call, or do we go through with it? The song makes it quite clear: This is YOUR life. Take it back. Don’t let others control what and who you are, through their personal fears and delusions. Be who you want to be.</p>

<p>It ends with one more “I don’t relaly care if nobody else believes in me”, with a fade out of the Rainbow Connection. It’s an uplifting song, and a good thesis statement to the entire album.</p>

<p><strong>I WANNA BE A ROCK</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tnn0g3m.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The rest of the album is a story. Its the story of our narrator as they go through their life. It starts with them, as a young boy. This song is a combination of a lot of hard scrabbled masculine songs, rip snortin’ masculine songs. We’ve got We Will Rock You, with the Ramones Blitzkrieg Bop, and then Kenny Loggins comes in with Danger Zone, and finally Nickelback’s Rockstar. A lot of masculine manly man songs. But when Nickelback’s Rockstar gets to the chorus, it’s not “I wanna be a Rockstar”, it comically cuts off with “I wanna be a rock”, as the other character in the song goes “….what??”</p>

<p>I think this song has multiple interpretations. I’ve heard someone say that wanting to be a rock is gender identity, a gender neutral “I don’t wanna be a man like you all think I should be, I’ll be gender neutral, like this rock”, but I don’t think so. I think rocks are manly. That’s a weird thing to say, but like, it’s tough and course, LIKE A MAN. It’s stupid, and intentionally so, IMO. It’s a joke. It’s one big giant joke about masculinity and toxic masculinity.</p>

<p>There’s also one other thing. Rockstar’s lyrics are SLIGHTLY changed elsewhere too. The original lyric is “I’m gonna cut my hair and change my name”. It’s now “I’m gonna <em>grow</em> my hair and change my name”. Ha ha, wouldn’t it be REALLY funny if I grew my hair out? Like, as a joke? This is a very real early gender thing, to me.</p>

<p>Anyways this continues for a while until…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/D7V00GW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>These manly man songs are interrupted by t.A.T.u.’s All The Things She Said. Which is maybe one of the most feminine centric songs I can think of. And even when the masculine songs begin to break back in, with the drum line, and then lyrics, t.A.T.u. is still there, in the background. It won’t go away, ever again. It keeps breaking through, always reminding you of that inkling at the back of your brain. And even now, the lyrics to the other songs are changed slightly.</p>

<p>“I wanna be a-“ with static, and a face behind the static. That don’t look like a rock. Or even a man’s face. Hmm, what could that be?</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z4nA3K7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This song starts with one of the best parts on the album. Lizzo’s Truth Hurts is basically unchanged. “I just took a DNA test, turns out, I’m- <strong><em>AUTISTIC</em></strong>”, with the song suddenly being interrupted by Live and Learn from Sonic Adventure 2. The artist said they were scared about putting in this joke, that it’d offend people, but are you kidding? Autistic people love Sonic. So do trans people. Autistic trans people go FERAL for Sonic.</p>

<p>This song uses Live and Learn’s backing track, with some songs over the mix, namely Green Day’s Basket Case. This album has a lot of Green Day. It also has a section right at the start, with the Avalanche’s Frontier Psychiatrist, where they say, plainly, “That boy needs therapy!”</p>

<p>This song is a therapy session. Our protagonist is at the therapist, discussing the things they’ve been hyper focusing on.</p>

<p>“Do you have the time to listen to me whine? About nothing, and everything all at once. I am one of those melodramatic fools, neurotic to the bone, no doubt about it. Sometimes I give myself the creeps. Sometimes my mind plays tricks on me. It all keeps adding up. I think I’m cracking up. Sometimes <strong>I wanna throw it all away</strong>.”</p>

<p>People with Gender Dysphoria USUALLY fear ever acting on those feelings, because society tells us it’s creepy. They’re just tricking themselves into thinking they’re a girl, anyway. They’re cracking up. Like an egg, perhaps! And then the final line is Goldfinger’s Superman, throwing in that this is all so much, it might genuinely end with self harm. This is not an easy transition to go through.</p>

<p>Then we get the chorus. Live and Learn is replaced with the very comical:</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“Always something there to remind me”</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“Cause you’re amazing, I can’t believe it”</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“I really don’t think I’m strong enough, no”</p>

<p><strong>LIVE LAUGH LOVE!</strong></p>

<p>“It’ll never be enough for me.”</p>

<p>This is our protagonist reacting to the idea that they could possibly be trans. They can’t go through with it. How could they? They’d always be reminded they’re not a “real” woman. They’re amazed by other trans women, that they could do this, but not them. They’re not strong enough. All the procedures and estrogen in the world wouldn’t be enough, they’d know what they “really” are.</p>

<p>The song continues like this for a bit, though there are a few changed lyrics. “She says my lack of sex is bringing me down” changes to “She says my <strong>sex</strong> is bringing me down”. Our protagonist gets diagnosed with gender dysphoria. But it’s not like they could really go through with this… right?</p>

<p>I’m not 100% sure what LIVE LAUGH LOVE means. Like, I know it’s a painfully optimistic phrase that helps nothing. I think that’s the idea here, that people are supplying our protagonist with platitudes that do nothing, while they have to struggle through this, practically alone, and take a giant lunge. But eventually, they do. Cue more Goldfinger.</p>

<p>“So here I am, doing everything I can, holding on to what I am, pretending I’m <strong>a man</strong>.”</p>

<p>“Danger, look behind you, there’s a stranger out to find you”.</p>

<p>The protagonist admits they’re a trans woman, but they can’t be out about it. After all, if you’re trans, there are people in this world who are practically HUNTING you. Always keeping an eye out, strangers, out to find you. Duck Tale’s “Whoo hoo!” is interspersed in the mix, more parts of the song where the vibe seems to not fit the actual theme and message of the song. On purpose, mind. This album is FANTASTIC at taking the original meanings of songs and twisting them on their heads. The next song, IMO, is the best at that.</p>

<p><strong>SHRIMPING POOL</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6IVYv6c.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If someone did not get the meaning of the album yet, if they’re paying attention, this is about where they usually get it. This song has a Katamari Damacy backing track, Lonely Rolling Star specifically, with the Kero Kero Bonito Song comically asking the question:</p>

<p>“How many shrimps do you have to eat, before you make your skin turn pinl? Eat too much and you’ll get sick, shrimps are pretty rich.”</p>

<p>Then we get Eiffel 65 bursting in with “Blue”, which is mostly unchanged. Yo listen up, here’s the story. He’s a blue guy, living in a blue world. etc etc. We then get one of my favorite parts of the album: Kendrick Lamar’s Swimming Pools, mixed up with Drowning Pool’s Bodies.</p>

<p>“Pour up” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Head shot” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Sit down” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Stand up” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Pass out” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Wake up” “Nothing wrong with me”
“Faded” “NOTHING WRONG WITH ME”
“Faded” “NOTHING WRONG WITH ME”</p>

<p>This turns the meanings of both songs on their heads, ESPECIALLY Drowning. What was once a song about an insane man refusing to accept it, here it’s a personal screed. Every day, they go about their life. It’s exhausting. This blue life, with these blue corvette, is exhausting. They’re faded. And all the time, inside, they know, these feelings they have? There’s nothing actually wrong with them. No matter what society says, there’s NOTHING wrong with them.</p>

<p>Then we get the chorus. Kendrick Lamar comes in with:</p>

<p>“Then somebody said, why you babysittin’ only two or three <em>shrimp</em>? I’mma show you got to turn it up an inch. First you get a swimming pool fool of <em>shrimp</em>, then you dive in it. pool full of <em>shrimp</em>, then you dive in it.”</p>

<p>This, alongside the question of “how many shrimp do you have to eat before it makes you skin turn pink”, tells you what shrimp is. It’s a metaphor for estrogen. This is a song about our protagonist getting on HRT for the first time. They’re alone and trying to go through it alone, in this blue world, but there’s a promise of pink in the future. And there are people out there willing to help him. Later additions to the chorus include:</p>

<p>“All the girls wanna play baywatch”</p>

<p>The girls in this case are other trans women, who know correctly how to dose HRT, probably more than any fucking doctor, let’s be real, and are willing to help younger trans women with advice. They’re watching the pool, so people can swim responsibly.</p>

<p>In the end, the song makes it clear.</p>

<p>“Yo listen up, here’s the story. About a little guy who lives in a blue world. <strong>CAN’T TAKE MUCH MORE</strong>. And all day, and all night, and all he wants to do is <em>turn pink</em>.</p>

<p>Our hero takes the plunge. On the advice, our protagonist begins taking shrimp.</p>

<p>I REALLY love how this song twists every single song on its head. It makes Flamingo and Blue actually HAVE meanings, Bodies is about self affirmation instead of insanity, and Swimming Pools, a song about public pressure and societal alcoholism, is now about responsibly teaching others how to take care of themselves through medical substances. It’s nuts.</p>

<p>The song also ends with Jimmy Eat World’s “The Middle” which is one of the most trans songs ever made.</p>

<p><strong>FACTS AND LODGING</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GnZjLYa.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is the down point of the entire album. And it’s very, VERY heavy. The first time I heard it, I had to pause the song and stare at the wall for a second. It was nuts.</p>

<p>This is a combination of two Gorillaz songs, 19-2000 and Clint Eastwood, alongside Flobot’s Handlebars, with The Eagles’ Hotel California in the background. Most people have heard Handlebars’ first line, but not the later lines. The song goes places, so I knew it’d get… dark.</p>

<p>“The world is spinning too fast, I’m buying lead nike shoes. To keep myself tethered to the days I’ve tried to lose”</p>

<p>These Gorillaz lyrics makes it clear what the song is about. The news, the world, and society is… a lot. It’s exhausting. You need to try and keep yourself tethered.</p>

<p>We also get Supertramp’s The Logical Song hitting in with our protagonist’s internal dialogue.</p>

<p>“When I was young, it seemed that life was so wonderful
Oh, it was beautiful, magical
And all the birds in the trees, well, they’d be singing so happily
Oh, playfully watching me
But then they sent me away to teach me how to be sensible
Oh, responsible, practical
And then they showed me a world where I could be so dependable
Oh, intellectual, cynical”</p>

<p>Things used to be better when we were kids. Not cause they WERE better, but we could ignore them. Now it’s impossible to ignore them. Especially when you’re the target now, to a lot of society. There’s also this part I like a lot, where it jumps between Clint Eastwood and Handlebars in a way that makes it feel like these lyrics were designed to go together.</p>

<p>“Allow me to make this childlike in nature
I can ride my bike with no handlebars
Rhythm, you have it or you don’t; that’s a fallacy
I can keep rhythm with no metronome
Y’all can’t see me now ‘cause you don’t see with your eye
I can see your face on the telephone
Intangible, bet you didn’t think so I command you to
‘Cause I can lead a nation with a microphone”</p>

<p>Eventually, Supertramps begs to ask, “Please tell me who I am”, as the rest of the song explodes around them. Handlebars reaches its end, “AND I CAN END THE PLANET IN A HOLOCAUST”, and Del the Funky Homosapiens says “I SEE THE DESTRUCTION AND DEMISE, CORRUPTION IN DISGUISE”. Supertramp cries out:</p>

<p>“I said, watch what you say, or they’ll be calling you a radical. A liberal. Oh, fanatical, criminal. Ooh, it’s getting unbelievable”.</p>

<p>The world is getting to be too much. WAY too much. We can’t live like this, we can’t live our lives while all this noise happens. So, suddenly, the song COMPLETELY changes. It turns into the theme from Balatro. The only way to escape the heaviness and exhaustion of the world is escapism, games and things. But even with that, the drums from Hotel California are in the background. You can check out anytime you like, but you can never leave.</p>

<p>This is a dark, and cynical, look on society, and how we can’t really escape it. There’s no positive message here. It’s just dark.</p>

<p><strong>PINK LION CLUB</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cQJh1cG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If the previous song is the down point of the album, this is where it lifts upwards again. I’ve heard a lot of interpretations on this song, but I’ve changed mine recently, thanks to suggestions by my friends on the meaning. This is a song that seems like it should be a downer. It’s Linkin Park’s Numb and Porter Robinson’s Lionhearted. Those are kinda darker songs. But they’re over the backing track of Pink Pony Club, and then as they’re going throguh with their darker lyrics, they’re interrupted by Lebo M’s He Lives in You.</p>

<p>“Wait
There’s no mountain too great
Hear the words and have faith
Havе faith
He lives in you
<em>We’ll be the lionhearted</em>
He lives in me
<em>For we don’t care about it</em>
He watches over
<em>We’ll finish what we started</em>
Everything we see
<em>So promise me that they’ll fall</em>
Into the water
<em>They broke the walls we guarded</em>
Into the truth
<em>But we don’t care about it</em>
In your reflection
<em>We’ll finish what we started</em>
He lives in you
<em>So promise me that</em>
<strong>I’ll be less like you”</strong></p>

<p>This is in contrast to the lyrics of Numb and Lionhearted. Numb is about losing faith in someone who wanted them to be a way, he can’t feel you. But Lebo M makes it clear: He’s still here. He watches over. He lives in you.</p>

<p>This song is about who we used to be, and who we will become. To a lot of trans women, they regret who they once were. They can’t feel the man they once were or might have been. But this song makes it clear. He’s still there. And that’s not a bad thing. It’s about reconnecting with yourself. You might have hated what you once were, but we can move on. After all, the man you once were is a lot like you now, with someone disappointed in you.</p>

<p>This is made clear with a break in the middle, with Bastille’s Pompei:</p>

<p>“But if you close your eyes
Does it almost feel like nothing changed at all?
And if you close your eyes
Does it almost feel like you’ve been here before?
<em>So promise me that</em>
<strong>I’m gonna be an optimist about this</strong>
<em>So promise me that</em>
<strong>I’m gonna be an optimist about this”</strong></p>

<p>A lot has changed. But also not much has changed. In spite of everything, it’s still you. Pompei’s lyrics are changed to, from “How am I gonna be an optimist about this” to “I’m gonna be an optimist about this”. Things will get better. They’ve already started.</p>

<p>This song is genuinely beautiful to me, and is my favorite on the album by far. Which means it’s probably one of my favorite songs of all time. I love this song to death.</p>

<p><strong>I’ve Had It With This Name</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y3nQkQT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The early songs are a little harder to get the theme of. The album is VERY blunt fron this point on. It’s not hiding <strong>anything</strong>.</p>

<p>This is a song about self discovery. Who are you, now? Literally, what are you changing your name to? But also, what are you, who are you, and what do you want to be?</p>

<p>There’s a lot of songs here, but the main one that matters is “Somebody Told Me” by The Killer. Lyrics are shifted and changed to say things like:</p>

<p>“Breakin’ my back just to know my name
Seven tracks and I’ve had it with this name (That’s not my name! That’s not my name!)”</p>

<p>This is the seventh track.</p>

<p>“‘Cause heaven ain’t close in a place like this
I said, oh, heaven ain’t close in a place like this”</p>

<p>Whoever our protagonist was before, that’s not who they want to be. That’s not heaven. They’ll find heaven their own way.</p>

<p>Other songs move in, like REM’s End of the World. The meanings are really clear, IMO, they’re basically the original song’s meanings, but then we get a great breakdown, with Radiohead’s Creep, Coldplay’s Fix You, and Keala’ Settle’s This is Me.</p>

<p>“When you try your best, but you don’t succeed
<em>I wish I was special</em>
When you get what you want, but not what you need
<em>I want a perfect body</em>
And the tears come streamin’ down your face
<em>I don’t belong here</em>
Could it be worse?
When the sharpest words wanna cut me down
<em>I don’t care if it hurts</em>
I’m gonna send a flood, gonna drown ‘em out
<em>I wanna have control</em>
But if you never try, you’ll never know
<em>What the hell am I doing here?</em>
Just what you’re worth
So tell me who are you?”</p>

<p>I’mma be real, if I didn’t know better, I’d say Creep is about a trans woman. Like, those fucking lyrics, holy hell. They’re not even changed.</p>

<p>The song ends the only way it could. With Slim Shady breaking in with “MY NAME IS-“ before getting cut off. We don’t need to know her name. We just know she’s decided who she is.</p>

<p><strong>FINALE</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HsBsHsF.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Then we get the finale, which like the intro, is less a part of the story, and more outside it. A wrap up. It sets the stage and clears it up, with Gwen Stefani’s “Just a Girl”.</p>

<p>“Take this pink ribbon off my eyes
I’m exposed, and it’s no big surprise
Don’t you think I know exactly where I stand?
This world is forcing me to hold your hand
The moment that I step outside
So many reasons for me to run and hide
I can’t do the little things I hold so dear
‘Cause it’s all those little things that I fear”</p>

<p>Again, if I didn’t know better, I’d say that song is about being a trans woman. It’s uncanny.</p>

<p>The song goes through a bit of each song, as they’re all a part of our hero, and her journey. But we they come in, eventually, they’re all wiped away. What matters is the future, and what she is. We also get Gwen Stefani’s part replaced by a trans woman who covers it, quite fittingly.</p>

<p>At the very end of the song, the album is mocking you, asking you if you know the theme. Different parts from every song come in, starting with a part from THIS song, Hey Ya asking “You think you got it? Ooh, you think you got it?” It’s fucking MOCKING you. Those parts from the earlier songs move back in, repeating over and over, caucophinously, but they’re all wiped away by Gwen Stefani, making one thing clear:</p>

<p>“I’m just a girl”.</p>

<p>Then, after four repititions, it says:</p>

<p>“I’m just a girl. Can I make it any more obvious?”</p>

<p>Four more repitions, and the song ends, making it just the tiniest bit more obvious, with a scene from Celeste showing on the screen. Any more obvious, indeed.</p>

<p>So yeah, this album is fantastic. Essentially perfect, to me. A great look into gender identity and the journey to finding and being trans. This album made me feel gender euphoria. It made me feel the gender euphoria of coming out for the first time, which I haven’t felt for <strong>ten fucking years</strong>. I can never thank it enough for that. Please, please listen to it. Thanks for reading.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Music" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 202 - Panic!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/24/RA202-Panic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 202 - Panic!" /><published>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/24/RA202-Panic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/24/RA202-Panic.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GVD2uv9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Panic!, also known as Switch in Japan, is one of the games that, to those in the know, is a MUST get for the Sega CD. It’s a cult classic that sold like shit at the time, and reviewed about as well. Developed by Sega, it was not released here by Sega. Instead, Data East did the work to translate it, which is interesting to me.</p>

<p>The story is that all machines on the planet are infected by a virus. They are all literally sick. They do random things, often just throwing up. A program, called “Panic!”, was designed to fix the situation and return things to normal. You play as Slap and his dog Stick, very fun names, who must travel to the center of the madness and turn on Panic!.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IHJUDag.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In order to do this, as you enter a room, you are met with what’s going on in that room, then shown some buttons. Each button does something different. Some transport you to other rooms, some do gags. Some do both!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XxGAkmn.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There are 20 levels in Panic, and most of the traveling moves you from right to left, looping around. The map balloons out in the middle, before going back into a point near the end. And that’s it! What, you might say? That’s it? Where’s the gameplay? Well that’s the thing. There isn’t any. This game is literally just… you press buttons, and watch things happen.</p>

<p>There are 964 gags, though you don’t NEARLY have to watch all of them, and in order to watch all of them you basically need to game over upwards of like, 7 times, due to the way the game works. You CAN game over. Either by just beating the game, or by going to the SKULL ROOMS where a member of your family tells you to stop playing games and bullies you, or by blowing up all the monuments. Some buttons are “booby trapped”, and you get to watch famous monuments blow up and collapse. Collapse em all and it’s game over, which you’d need to do to get 100% gags anyway. Also, exits are considered gags, and some are one way. So that throws complications in too.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TLj1oJg.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I worry I’m being reductive when I say “that’s all” to Panic. This is an EXTREMELY interesting, and fun, game. And there’s barely any game here. The humor and style is off the charts, the animation is quite good for the Sega CD, it’s smooth and flows well, and it’s very, VERY Terry Gilliam. You can tell that the devs of this LOVES Monty Python.</p>

<p>Occasionally you’ll also see scenes with these little creatures, and a voice over. The US voice over is kinda rough, but it’s not TERRIBLE. They didn’t really have to change that much, honestly. There’s even a Mega CD Bios room, which they didn’t change, at all, for the Sega CD version, even though the Sega CD Bios are NOTHING like that. There is a SINGLE room they changed, and by changed I mean literally just removed, and it was killed with kanji and would be hard to bring over here, so fair.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cxo3K3D.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Oh, one other thing I forgot to mention, the game’s sound effects are <strong>fucking fantastic</strong>. It’s literally just one dude making all the sounds with his mouth. Gun sounds? Mouth. Explosions? Mouth. Twisting moving things? Mouth. Zippy zaps? You better believe its mouth time.</p>

<p>There are so many fun and creative rooms here, and yes, not all the jokes or humor land. There’s a lot of vomit and grossy kinda stuff, but it’s for kids, who cares. A lot of it is REALLY fun, or cute, or clever. I think my favorite room is the Mona Lisa room, though there are other great contendors.</p>

<p>I don’t recommend 100%ing this game, but frankly, even if you do, it’s just 8 hours of watching funny animations. Pace yourself. Without that, it’s an hour or two and well worth your time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Panic" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 178</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/24/OOCY178.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 178" /><published>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/24/OOCY178</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/24/OOCY178.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rKY83SY.png" alt="A page from 'Black and White'. One woman kabedon's another by putting her leg up over her and against the wall behind her. The other woman is sitting in a chair, looking kind of stunned." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Black and White</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="black and white" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 201 - Iron Helix</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 201 - Iron Helix" /><published>2025-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/21/RA201-IronHelix.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wF4by86.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This could double as an Obscure Games You Probably Haven’t Heard Of post. I’m a huge fan of Iron Helix, and have been for a long time, but it’s completely forgotten by this point. This game is extremely important, for a few reasons I’ll get into. But first, this is the second of the two Sega CD games I made sets for! I made one for Kids on Site, and this. Someone might have made a Kids on Site set without my help, but no one would have ever made this, and that’s a promise.</p>

<p>Iron Helix is an early 90s PC-ROM survival horror game by Drew Pictures and Spectrum HoloByte. It’s possibly one of the FIRST modern survival horror games. It’s no Sweet Home or anything, but it has a lot of that Survival Horror style. You’re exploring a dangerous place, alone, and being hunted by an impossible to overcome force, while trying to solve mysteries and find clues to what happened here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IjMTg5G.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Iron Helix starts with an intro that tells the story. Some Earth Force ships are doing military training on the edge of the neutral zone, essentially. But one of them, the Obrian (it’s gonnna be SO hard not to type O’Brien) suddenly veers off, losing control. It targets a peaceful neutral world of the other super power in the galaxy, the Thanatosians. We’re in a cold war with them, but this will make it run hot, and kill an entire planet of innocent civilians too. A message from the ship’s captain explains: They’ve been infected by an unknown virus that’s weakened their immune systems and changed their DNA. The ship’s AI Defender no longer recognizes them as Human, and assumes they’re invaders, killing them. Believing they’re at war, the ship goes to blow up some Thanatosians. Nothing can be donw.</p>

<p>Except… you’re the only ship in the sector! But you’re just a scientist, onboard the exploration ship Indiana. And it’s not like you can board the ship, you’ll get infected and killed too. You’re contacted by Earth’s Forces and asked to stop it, by sending drones into the ship, and blowing it up before it can reach the Thanatosians.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/92gXUmAWv24?si=U5ehhNHeqwmiuG39" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>I think it’s a rather compelling plot. Then you’re hit with the sickest fuckin’ title theme of the early 90s, and you begin. Choose your difficulty level and dive right in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xPMWjBU.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Iron Helix plays like you’re controlling a little drone through a computer screen, which you are. It’s clunky and awkward, because it would be. You move up and down the pathways of the ship, which you can see through surveillance maps that you’ve hacked into. You always know where the Defender is, though when you interract with things on the ship, it knows where you are too, and will hunt you down. You gotta dodge it by running through access tubes and running away, though you can also use battery life to jam the Defender and stun it for a time. The Sega CD version is quite clunky about this and slow paced, the PC version is much faster.</p>

<p>Your goal is split into chunks. First, collect DNA. The Humans were killed, but the ship responds to their DNA still, and not all of it has become changed. You can find hair follicles, chunks of skin, etc, all over the place. Scanning an area, you can release your access arm and pick up DNA, which will allow you through doors to deeper parts of the ship. Once you have all the DNA you need, usually by collecting the captain’s DNA, you can access everywhere, including the information terminals.</p>

<p>The Humans on the ship were trying to stop this before it began, but couldn’t. But they left breadcrumbs for you. They have access codes that they’ve set up to do different things, like blowing up the warp manifolds, or shutting down the Defender. You need to find a code for blowing up the ship, and a code for stopping the Defender, before proceeding. Then you shut down the Defender, then blow up the ship, in that order. Otherwise the Defender will just stop you. And once that’s done, you win!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dBUaPvC.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You can beat Iron Helix in like 9 minutes on this version. Way less than that on PC. If you know what you’re doing and where you’re going, it’s easy every time. Buuuut it’s not easy the first time. If you’ve been reading this review, you’re probably picturing the game in your head and going “woah that sounds sick as fuck???” and it is! On paper. But the Sega CD version is very flawed. The PC version shows you when DNA is nearby. The Sega CD version does not, you have to scan every single square of the ship. It’s also direction sensitive, so you need to check all four sides. It’s AWFUL.</p>

<p>And it’s not very replayable. Once you beat all three difficulties, that’s it. All the difficulties do is shift the DNA and codes around. The codes are different for each difficulty, too. In the first one there’s a code for just turning off the defender. But after that, you need to use yourself as bait to bait the Defender into the cargo bay, and then vent the whole thing into space.</p>

<p>Iron Helix is also built around an FMV base, which at the time was cutting edge, but is now MASSIVELY funny and outdated. You can barely make out these characters, the quality is so low. And their acting is Rather Rough. The best part is Commander Arbok though, your advisor, who after you succeed, rewards you with a job well done by… torturing you for information and killing you. Uh oh, we’re actually the bad guys.</p>

<p>Yes, there’s a hidden thread of information in Iron Helix. I’m telling you this because I doubt you will ever actually play it. You can find logs about destroying the ship, yes, but also ones about the Iron Helix, which is a secret weapon Earth is developing with the capacity to blow up entire planets. It’s highly dangerous, and highly illegal. So to keep their information a secret… they’ll need to silence you. It’s a downer ending! Yay!</p>

<p>Iron Helix is an extremely interesting game for the time, but all of its ideas will be done better down the road, and it’s pretty rough to play these days. I still love it though, it’s very special to me.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pzkFXilM4ls?si=M5tqcRRnh33VzRtO" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Before I forget though, here’s the PC installer for Iron Helix. Absolutely beautiful. It has a lot of charm to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Iron Helix" /><category term="Horror" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - JJ Trek Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - JJ Trek Movies" /><published>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekJJTrekMovies.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>Note: This isn’t complete yet! We’re watching the first one for now. We’ll watch the others after a few Enterprise seasons.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Star Trek</strong> - 4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YHsmYFt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>As we discuss this movie, I want you to forget about it being a Trek movie. Don’t think of it as that. Think of it as JJ Abram’s demo reel for Star Wars, the thing he actually wanted to do.</p>

<p>We start with a ship in the middle of nowhere under attack. The captain is called to the enemy ship, which EASILY defeats them, and he gives command to his SO, a man named George Kirk. The captain is asked a few questions, where is Ambassador Spock, what is the stardate. And when he answers, he’s then impaled. Kirk then needs to stay on board, distracting the enemy ship as escape pods launch. We get a VERY drawn out scene of him sacrificing the ship as his wife gives birth on the escape pods. As George is about to die, he agrees to name him “Jim”. And then his ship explodes. Hell of a gender reveal party.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iaRqICf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1nd5ibe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then we get the scene made for the trailers. A young James T. Kirk steals his shitty abusive father’s car, as the Beastie Boys blasts out of the car. He’s chased by the cops and drives the car off of uh… whatever the fuck this thing is. The great gorge in the middle of Iowa. You know, what one. Then he says “MY NAME IS JAMES TIBERIUS KIRK.” End trailer! Boom!</p>

<p>On Vulcan, we see a young Spock getting bullied by some very unvulcan vulcans, and he’s beat up by them. He then gets in trouble with his dad for reacting to their bullying, as if them bullying isn’t the problem, it’s the fact that you reacted to it. I fucking HATE shit like this.</p>

<p>Time jump. We get Adult Spock. And if there’s one thing I can say about this movie, it has some AMAZING casting. My only major issue is that the Spock they get is VERY smirky. He’s in front of a board of ministers accepting him into the Vulcan Acadamy of Sciences. He ALSO applied to Starfleet, but they’re like “unneccesary” and deem it dumb to even conside going to Starfleet. Yeah cause Vulcans NEVER join Star Fleet???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oNKfx2w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Kirk being a very uh… “suave” little shithead? He meets Uhura and flirts with her cause of course he does. That alien in the middle should have been one of Morn’s species, tbh. Some Cadets beat the shit out of him for being a little shit, and then he’s saved by… CAPTAIN PIKE! He begs Kirk to enlist in Starfleet, and in 8 years he can captain his own ship. Pretty sure the enlisted don’t… do that. Aren’t they like, O’Brien?</p>

<p>That’s a major thing about this movie. If you peel back the layers and look at it under the hood, even for a fucking MINUTE, it’s stupid and makes no sense. Because JJ Abrahms doesn’t know anything about Star Trek and doesn’t care to make Science Fiction, just Science Fantasy. I could easily whine about shit like… George Kirk’s shitty little ship has the same crew retinue as the fucking Enterprise E. Or “why is the villain’s ship screaming, and why does he not look ANYTHING like a Romulan”. also “Why is his ship FUCKING HUMONGOUS AND POWERFUL BUT A MINING SHIP”. (it’s like if a bulldozer went back in time and blew up the British navy). But it doesn’t matter. This is a late 2000s action movie. Who the hell cares.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Z0y6HAq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We jump through a lot of scenes. Hello, Bones. Karl Urban is good casting. We get more of the villain, Nero, who wants to “make him watch”. Kinky, dog. We also get Kirk fucking a green space babe, and he wins the Kobayashi Maru by hacking the test. It’s like someone read a wikipedia article about Captain Kirk and tried to distill him down in 4 minutes. Keep in mind that, IMO, that’s impossible, because Kirk in the original series is a mad man with four distinct personalities that depend on who writes him through the episode. You either remake Kirk with SOME of his traits, or make him a madman. They kinda went with madman.</p>

<p>While Kirk is getting yelled at for cheating at the Kobayashi Maru by Spock, the maker of the test, they get a distress call from Vulcan. And apparently the only ships in the sector who can reach Vulcan are…. the fucking Cadets at Earth? WHERE ARE ANY OF THE OTHER SHIPS?! Everyone is split off into different ships. Kirk is left at home cause he cheated, but Bones is a bro and basically sneaks him on board. While the ages don’t really fit for making them all be cadets together, I kinda like the Bones and Kirk “roommate buddies from college” energy. Not ALL the characters are perfect here. I don’t like overly confident Uhura here, SNW self doubt but very good at her job Uhura feels more believable to me. Sulu is also here, piloting the Enterprise, but he’s young and inexperienced. And also Chekov is here, again, age problems. And his whole thing is he talks weird. Nurse Chapel also gets mentioned, cool.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t4SwLxG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nero, the villain, is attacking and blowing up Vulcan. They think it’s something natural, but they’re being attacked, and Kirk knows this because its the same thing that happened when he was born. If he can coem to that conclusion anyone should, because it’s not like it was a small problem, lots of people died. We get Kirk, having an allergic reaction, running through the Enterprise screaming and trying to communicate in a funny way to Uhura that they’re about to witness an actual genocide. This movie has a tone problem. Trek has always toed the line between humor and seriousness. It does that well. But it usually doesn’t involve ACTUAL PLANETARY genocide.</p>

<p>Pike leaves Chekov in control of the bridge to go be a hostage. What the fuck? Why him? Chekov is only like, 6 years old. He was just born yesterday, and you’re putting him in command? He also promotes Spock to Captain and Kirk to first officer. Why? Who the fuck knows. Bones is also now chief medical officer cause all the doctors fucking died. Pike sends Kirk Sulu and some shmuck to do an orbital fall to Vulcan to try and destroy this thing they’re using to destroy the planet.</p>

<p>Oh no, one of the people Kirk is going with on this mission is wearing a red shirt. Dude, I’m so sorry for you. There’s like 6 things JJ knows about Star Trek, and that’s one of the top ones. He died because he’s being a fucking idiot. It’s okay, I saw his parachute. Like, literally.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fYI07oO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a fight scene on this orbital platform that’s moving to the planet’s code. Sulu apparently brought a MOTHER FUCKING KATANA to this fight. Why? Because he’s Japanese of course!! This is the scene I remember from this movie most of all. I remember thinking it was sick as hell.</p>

<p>This movie is very loud.</p>

<p>The Romulans are making a black hole at the center of Vulcan, which is of course, destroying the planet. He goes to the planet and evacuates his parents, though his mom dies in the process. The temple they’re all in appears to be a Sith Templ- I mean uh, the Katric Chamber. Yeah. Holy shit we finally get silence in this movie, and it’s to mourn Spock’s mom’s death. For like 20 seconds, then it’ll be loud again.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3K7nSIa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A whole hell of a lot of people are dead now. Also Uhura makes out with Spock. It’s literally a student fucking their instructor, don’t worry about it. We all consume questionable stuff. But it wouldn’t be MY ship. Spock needs his lips ready for Kirk.</p>

<p>We find out Nero’s purpose here. He’s from a future, and his super ship nothing can beat is a fucking mining vessel. In the future, Romulus blew up, and he blames the Federation for not helping, especially Spock, so he decides to go back in time and get revenge.</p>

<p>Spock and Kirk get in an argument so Spock literally jettisons him off his ship to an ice planet (that claims is M class, it’s not) onto a fucking ice floe. Was Spock trying to literally murder Kirk? Because he nearly succeeded. Kirk is freezing to death and gets hunted by some alien beasts. What the FUCK, Spock??? You’re the good guy?! Also for some reason there’s an M Class ice planet that’s right next to Vulcan. Okay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vZ8FxrJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Congrats Kirk, you were saved by a 150 year old Vulcan. Kirk just RANDOMLY runs into Spock on this fucking planet. Why? I dunno, JJ Abrahms wanted to make a part of this movie that’s very reminiscent of Star Wars Episode 5. Old!Spock teaches Kirk what happened in the past/future. This part is canon. This movie? Not canon, it’s an alternate universe. But a supernova happening to Romulus DID happen. This causes a lot of awful prime timeline shenanigans. Also there’s a Federation outpost nearby. Why wasn’t Spock ALREADY THERE???? WHY WAS HE JUST LIVING IN A CAVE?!</p>

<p>Sorry, I am TRYING to ignore the stupid bullshit in this movie but it is very, very hard.</p>

<p>Anyways we’re about to get to the best casting of this movie. Karl Urban is #2. This is #1.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sJ7HOOB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Scotty’s actor is the only person here, other than Nimoy of course, who knew fucking ANYTHING about Star Trek before joining this crew. And he fits this perfectly. He’s pretty great.</p>

<p>Old!Spock demands that Kirk not tell Young!Spock that he exists. Because it’s his Destiny. WHAT DOES THAT MEAN? WHY DOES THAT MEAN? Whhyyy? Spock also claims he learned how to cheat from an old friend. I bet he’s gonna teach Kirk about Fizbin sometime.</p>

<p>Oh you know what, it’s been a while since we’ve had some scene where people run around with slapstick! We get a scene where Scott is beamed into Enterprise’s water tubes, and there’s some giant chopping blades that the water flows to. Good thing there’s no one currently in Engineering???????</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AInxFB5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Under Old!Spock’s suggestion, Kirk just pisses Young!Spock off enough to make him attack him, which will make it obvious he’s not fit to lead. He relinquishes command and now NO one is in command. Why are the only people on the best ship in the fleet Cadets? Well, we DO have a captain now. Kirk WAS made the acting first officer, so now he’s captain. You know, Spock was removed from captaincy cause he was emotional compromised, but this Kirk is ABSOLUTELY not emotionally compromised.</p>

<p>Spock comes to because his dad said he loved his wife, and sets himself as the new first officer. Status quo achieved!</p>

<p>Loud flicky pew pew action scene, oh boy. Scotty beams them to what he thinks is an unoccupied part of the ship. It’s not. Fight time. Luckily all these enemies are very bad. They’re attacking JUST as the ship starts to bore a hole in Earth like it did for Vulcan, almost blowing up the Golden Gate Bridge. Been a while since we saw it blow up! Also now that Spock and Kirk have fought together in a SINGLE fight, Spock is on a first name basis with Kirk and calls him Jim. This movie has some problems with pacing.</p>

<p>Nero: “I WILL DEPRIVE YOU OF YOUR LIFE, JUST LIKE I DID YOUR FATHER”</p>

<p>How the shit did you know that you killed his dad, you never interracted with him. Okay, man. It’s not like I’ve never made writing plothole mistakes before but whoof. This villain isn’t TERRIBLE, but I don’t like him that much. This is what everyone thinks Shinzon from Nemesis is.</p>

<p>Spock is going to sacrifice himself and blow up the red matter, but the Enterprise comes in like Big Damn Heroes to save the day. He crashes the ship with the red matter into Nero’s ship, creating a black hole, just as Kirk saves Pike and Spock is warped away. Was Spock trying to kill Kirk again while doing this? Yes. Yes, he was straight up going to kill him.</p>

<p>Wow this movie has a lot of flashing effects.</p>

<p>THey eject the warp core, and by that I mean like 8 of them, I dunno why they have 8 of them, and let the blast carry them away from the singularity. What if we had more flashing and more shaking effects? Lovely. And then they surfed the wave while listening to rock music. Wait, wrong movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9KjYFUy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a goodbye to Old!Spock as he meets Young!Spock. He explains he lied about it, because it’d make Kirk and Spock be friends. Fair enough.</p>

<p>All the cadets are still there, despite the fact that ALL of the ships they were all put in were blown the fuck up earlier in the movie, sure, okay, that’s fine. They make Kirk captain, give him a medal, and all cheer him on. Also Pike is in a wheelchair now! All is right in the fucking world.</p>

<p>The movie ends with them blasting off. Punch it chewie, etc. And then we get Old!Spock doing the voice over. These are the missions of etc etc. That’s pretty emotional. And we get a reprise of the original theme! Cool.</p>

<p>Obviously this movie is like, not great. It’s kinda bad, in many ways. But it’s not unenjoyable? My friend Elle in my group watch said it best. “This movie is a 40 minute carnival ride that lasts for two hours”. It is shlocky action that is poorly directed, because JJ Abrahms is not a good director. Also we all make fun of the lens flares and weird scaling but the REAL problem is that it was loud, too fast, and the fucking flashing was nuts. This movie is so bright, and so loud. It’s like getting flashbanged by a mediocre book.</p>

<p>At least the soundtrack is pretty good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="JJTrek" /><category term="Movies" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - TNG Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekTNGMovies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - TNG Movies" /><published>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekTNGMovies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/17/LizstarTrekTNGMovies.html"><![CDATA[<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>Note: This isn’t complete yet! We’ve only seen three of the movies. We’re holding Nemesis off until after Voyager is done.</p>

<p>EDIT: WE’RE FINALLY WATCHING NEMESIS, HOLY HELL THIS WAS LIKE 2 YEARS AGO. Nemesis review is tacked onto the end!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Star Trek: Generations</strong> - 2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g8xHqkU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The movie starts with like, a 3 minute scene of a bottle flying through space. It feels like they just up and ripped off the opening Myst.</p>

<p>Anyways boom it’s for the Christening of the Enterprise B! We’ve got some TOS characters back with us, Kirk, Scotty, and Chekov. It was GOING to be Bones and Spock with them, but Spock was like “not unless you change the script, because what’s written here, anyone could be saying these lines”. And then they proved it, by replacing them. Anyways, they leave space dock around Mars or whatever, and get a distress call. Some energy field is b lowing up some refugee ships. 3 light years away, but they’re the only ship in range. Did the Borg destroy the entire fucking Federation fleet several years in advance???</p>

<p>Well considering they’re rescuing El-Aurian refugees who are RUNNING from them, I mean, maybe? But nah we don’t gotta worry about where the El Aurians are going.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/14wRE20.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This entire scene is like, about Kirk wanting to take over the Enterprise, but it’s not his place no more. When the captain needs to do some dangerous engineering stuff, he tries to put Kirk in command but Kirk is like “no, this is your place now, I’ll do it”, which is weird. Are there no engineers on this ship???</p>

<p>Also there’s a cameo, one of the El-Aurians is Guinan! Ah, she’s fleeing her planet, and just now appearing on Earth…. EXCEPT THAT WE’VE SEEN HER ON EARTH IN THE 1800S. My chat had to tell me to “stop thinking”. This is gonna be hard.</p>

<p>Anyways yeah the dangerous situation Kirk put himself into for no reason pays off and he fucking dies. The entire deck he’s on is ripped off, and he’s presumed dead, no body ever found.</p>

<p>78 years later!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0IjdcjZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the ACTUALLY good parts of this movie, a cute scene where they’re all on the Holodeck goofing off to celebrate Worf’s promotion. There is something… weird, though. Data appears stunted, despite being here for 7 years with friends, he doesn’t understand spontinaity and humor in a way that causes him to throw Crusher overboard. Riker is gushing over women. Picard gets bad news and then locks himself in his mind palace, refusing to talk about it.</p>

<p>It’s like all the characters very suddenly reverted character growth they had gained over the past 7 years of their lives. In order to make these characters someone you can get into as a newcomer to Trek, they are dumbed down to their most basic components. Maybe I’m reading too far into it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ElGvrmu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Data is like “Clearly my not having emotions is bad cause I hurt a friend, so it is time.” and they pull out the Emotion Chip! Yes, Data originally was like “No I can’t use this cause when I DID feel emotions I was manipulated to hurt my friends”. Now it just makes him hate alcohol. Another actually good scene.</p>

<p>They get a distress signal from a research station under attack. On it they find dead Romulans searching for Trilithium (I know we’ve had Trilithium do something before, it’s new and does other stuff now, don’t think about it), and a living guy, Dr. Malcom McDowell. I mean, Dr. Soran, who we saw at the v ery beginning begging that he NEEDS TO GO BACK, and here he’s… very clearly evil. When he demands to go back on the station to get research, and Picard says no, he gives a weird villain monologue about how time is running out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZHcGQcN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay, two things about visual things this movie is doing. 1) The lighting is dog shit. Everything is so fucking yellow, or way too dark. Why. It’s like, SHOCKINGLY bad. The only scenes with good lighting were the first scene, and the one where they’re literally outside on a boat. And 2) The costuming. Half of them are wearing TNG uniforms, and half are wearing DS9. Why? Why?????</p>

<p>Data has a scene where he constantly makes jokes. I know big movies need like, a comic relief, but why did they make it Data? The emotional center of the entire cast?? I only have one thing I can say about this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aRI9eLT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways woah no way, Soran is evil! He’s actually developing a weapon that blows up suns. He attacks Geordi and Data (who is stunned by fear), and managed to escape with the weapon and Geordi as a hostage as he’s rescued by his benefactors, Lursa and Betor. Y’know, the Klingon sisters. He also tortures Geordi and is like “TELL ME ALL YOU KNOW ABOUT TRI-LITHIUM”. My man. YOU’RE the one who made the bomb. You’re the leading expert. It’d be like me kidnapping the WR holder of Mario 64 and being like “TELL ME ALL YOU KNOW ABOUT TALL: TWINS TOWER.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gSlLHqA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We learn more about Soran through Guinan. Apparently he and she were both in The Nexus, a kind of thing that travels in an energy ribbon. It’s “like being inside of Joy” itself. So a Lotus Eaters situation, kinda. Though the details are murky and it kinda makes little sense.</p>

<p>Anyways there’s a stupid situation where they do a prisoner exchange between Geordi and Picard (for some reason they negaotiate with them I dunno why), and Picard goes down to try and negotiate, because Soran is gonna blow up a sun to drag the Nexus towards him, which will also blow up a planet with millions on it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BUDD6iD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This scene happens.</p>

<p>The Sisters have hacked Geordi’s VISOR, and wait until he goes into Engineering so they can find out what Shield Frequency they’re at. Then they attack through the shields and blow them the fuck up. Riker is very VERY bad at being in charge (JUST ROTATE THE SHIELD FREQUENCIES, OR FIRE SOME TORPOEDOS RIKER? WHY ARE WE DOING THIS FANCY SHIT WITH THEIR WARP COILS?) but eventually, many casualties later, they manage to blow up the Bird of Prey, killing the sisters. Oh well, our major Klingon villains are dead. I guess now we need to make Gowron a villain now.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7o9oEKs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh no, the attack causes a WARP CORE BREACH! Instead of ejecting the warp core, or like, trying anything, Geordi goes “NOTHING WE CAN DO TIME TO EVACUATE”, and they prepare to seperate the saucer from the rest of the ship. They have to MANUALLY seperate the ship, which uh… is not how that works.</p>

<p>Look, half of this movie can be summed up as “Rick Berman did not know how anything in Star Trek ACTUALLY worked”.</p>

<p>They finally put Troi in charge of piloting the Enterprise btw. And now this happens. (tbf there was no actual helm control)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9csyEG9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I really cannot stress enough, it’s really stupid that what is described as a 20 year old junker Bird of Prey beat the Enterprise in a fight (yes they also died but they TOOK OUT THE ENTERPRISE). In an episode, if a Bird of Prey fired upon an unshielded Enterprise, it wouldn’t matter, cause the Enterprise would spin around and blast them the fuck away. Maybe they’d get a few casualties, maybe if they’re LUCKY they hit the warp core and there’d be an ejection. But they’d have to be REAL lucky to get that hit in. But no, here, Riker just kinda spun the Enterprise around and showed them their ass and let them get eight to ten shots in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tKvlWkF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I guess none of it really matters though, because Soran shoots a missile to the sun, which reaches it in 5 seconds (I guess it’s going at warp??????), and the wave takes Soran and Picard away, while everyone else is seen, on screen, fucking exploding. Rip to EVERY member of the Enterprise I guess.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eaTIPc7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard is now in the Nexus, living a happy life with a family he never got to have. I guess he’s always wanted to have a Victorian era british family or some shit like that. But he realizes this is wrong. He can leave, though, if he breaks away. And he can go to any time, because time has no meaning, so he’s gonna go back to right before Soran blew up the star. Uh, I’d think maybe go back before that, but whatever works. An Echo of Guinan tells him all this. Though he needs help. Luckily, there’s someone else here in the Nexus with him…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vkjzou5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kirk meeting Picard should have been more exciting.</p>

<p>Anyways, Picard tries to convince Kirk that he needs to go with him to save millions of lives. Kirk is like “fuck that shit I wanna make eggs kiss my wife and ride horses. Because all captains need to ride horses.” Also his wife here is  uh, Antonia. Apparently it was SUPPOSED to be Carol Marcus, but Paramount demanded it changed. Why? Why???</p>

<p>Obviously Kirk comes around, because nothing here is ACTUALLY real, nothing matters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FFFhZHv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kirk goes back, and the two of them fight. It’s three old men fighting on a big metal thing. It’s not quite as good as Metal Gear Solid 4, though I would love if Soran kissed Picard in the middle of this. There is a lot of stupid shit in this fight scene. Soran installed a cloaking device on his missile for no reason. Malcolm McDowell gives a really weird expression as he explodes. And THE stupid thing happens. An event so legendary that it changed pop culture lexicon for ALL time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iunedsM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They dropped a bridge on him.</p>

<p>Apparently Malcolm McDowell took this job EXPRESSLY because he was going to be the man who killed James T. Kirk, which is the best shit, and I love it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qPYSOSb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Plot conclusion. Picard finds out that Riker destroyed the Enterprise, which was prolly a big fucking shock. The Enterprise couldn’t be salvaged, but they go aboard the rubble and find what they can. Data saves Spot (also he keeps his emotion chip, which… feels weird cause I feel it never comes up again), and Picard throws some of his important memorabilia away, only collecting a family portrait, cause that’s what’s important I guess, and it also fits the thesis of the movie. And then they leave the Enterprise just sitting there on the planet, forever. Yeah just…. leave Federation secrets sitting on this fucking planet, okay whatever.</p>

<p>This movie is bad! It is not good! Like, duh, it’s really bad. A lot of the ideas of it are just, bad. The major ORIGINAL concept and thesis for this movie is “we need to kill Kirk”. That’s it. That’s the plan. And they fucked even that up. Almost every plot point is very poorly concepted. The Nexus is stupid, Data’s emotions are unpleasant to watch except for a single scene and a bad waste of Brent Spiner acting. They bring back Kirk and don’t give him a big damn hero moment, and no, jumping one foot onto a collapsing bridge does not count as a big exciting heroic sacrifice.</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek: First Contact</strong> - 2/10</p>

<p>Goddddd this one is even wooooorse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5KdndxA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard has a bad dweam about his time as Locutus of the Borg.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PTEo8ic.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s a good image here that I did not edit in any way, it is VERY wide.</p>

<p>Anyways I’m sure there’s no reason this is important. Oh wait no, the Borg are back and attacking!! The Enterprise is told to fuck off to the Neutral Zone and make sure the Romulans don’t attack. Everyone is offended by this, cause &gt;:( How DARE THEY not send us to fight, but the reason is because Picard used to be Locutus and that might be bad. I DO get it, tbh.</p>

<p>Anyways the pacing so far is VERY VERY weird. We have a new Enterprise, the Enterprise E. It’s not explained. Geordi doesn’t have his VISOR, and has implants, even thoguh we were told that’d be impossible before. It’s not explained.</p>

<p>The Federation gets their life fucking obliterated, and the Enterprise comes to save the day because of course they do. The Defiant is here, and they save it from being exploded, saving Worf, who beams over and is now part of the crew again. Can’t have TNG without Worf! They blow up the Borg Cube, but it releases a Sphere which blasts off to Earth and goes through a temporal wormhole back to the past. The Enterprise chases, and as they go, they scan that all of Earth is now Borg. They’re safe though, cause of the Temporal Wake or whatever.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dYstxkg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s now 10 years later after WW3, and the Borg are attacking, the day before First Contact with the Vulcans.</p>

<p>One of the issues I had with the previous movie is that it was absolute terrible with its humor. It decided that Data was the comic relief character, and some of it was good, but msot of it was bad. Data’s first thing in this movie is they’re being attacked by someone with a machine gun, and he’s like “I can handle this”, and just walks at her like a terminator, soaking up all the bullets lol. THAT’S good Data comedy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L0bxDMh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Turns out the Borg snuck onto the Enterprise! Through teleporting before their sphere blows up, I guess. I know we can scan for teleporters but ignore that here. Anyway, so they’re killing and assimilating people. Apparently it’s THAT EASY and FAST to assimilate people now??? This movie is playing it really fast and loose with everything. I guess there’s no time. But to keep the Borg away so they can escort people out of Sick Bay, they summon an EMH! EY, IT’S THE BOY! He’s used as a glorified distraction but that’s okay. Nice cameo.</p>

<p>The Enterprise is getting all tubilated. I really, REALLY feel a way about this. It would have been more effective and powerful if we saw the Enterprise and its crew getting slowly and painfully assimilated, but also this is a replacement enterprise that we unceremoniously have now. So maybe it wouldn’t have.</p>

<p>Instead now, the Borg are straight up zombies. They can assimilate you now with a single touch, but boop, nose boop, you’re now a Borg. It’s kind of stupid and I really don’t like it actually. It’s kinda ruining the Borg and turning them into something they never were. They were ALREADY scary and intimidating, because of what they were. They were many, infinite, and all powerful with disgustingly strong tech. Now they’re easy to blow up, easy to kill, but repopulate themselves through touch. Might as well be zombies.</p>

<p>This movie then splits into two bits. We’ve got Geordi, Troi, and Riker on the ground, trying to talk Dr. Cochrane into doing his flight that’d cause the Vulcans to show up and instigate first contact. On the Enterprise, it’s the Borg assimilating everything and killing everyone, with graphic gross body horror all the way. They saved a woman on the ground, Cochrane’s friend Lily, and she basically takes Picard hostage cause she’s terrified. Eventually Picard calms her down by showing her they’re in space, through a window. Oh sorry, not a window. A force Field hole in the Enterprise. Why? What is the purpose of this room that just has a single hole into space????</p>

<p>This movie seems to exist entirely on Rule of Cool but it is NOT cool enough to justify that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3LSikDc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look we have a villain. Apparently the people in charge complained that the Borg were just zombies, so they needed to make a leader for the Borg. MAYBE IF YOU DIDN’T MAKE THE BORG EVEN MORE ZOMBIE LIKE THIS WOULDN’T BE AN ISSUE??? Anyways, this is the Borg Queen. The details around her are hazy and not well explained, but she’s here to be sexy towards Data to convince him to go over to their side.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ArHN4oj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gonna be difficult, movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cONTLx2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Borg chase Lily and Picard into the Holodeck, with a kinda fun scene where they’re in a Dixon Hill novel, and Picard starts firing his gun wildly into the crowd. Fucking wild.</p>

<p>Oh hey Reg is here too. Everyone is being hero worshippy towards Cochrane, and he’s fucking weirded out about it, cause he’s a grumpy and drunk old man. He tries to run away and Riker just fucking shoots him and tells them off for weirding him out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FzT6uWO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I watched this movie once as a child, and this is basically the ONLY part of the movie that I remembered. Worf, Picard, and some red shirt are doing chip swaps and nipple twisting in zero grav on the surface of the Enterprise, while the Borg try to turn the Deflector Dish into a beacon for present-day Borg to come and assimilate Earth. The Borg occasionally go over to stop them, because the Borg kinda sometimes don’t wanna bother fighting people. But only sometimes. I remember SPECIFICALLY thinking that Hawk was Riker in this scene as a kid, cause he gets assimilated and then killed.</p>

<p>Back inside, everyone is like “Captain, the Enteprise is overrun, we need to self destruct and escape on the escape pods”. Picard refuses. Everyone like “what why” “Because I said so. None of you understand the Borg like I do, so you all have to kill yourselves for this.” Everyone goes with it, except Worf who’s kicked off the bridge for speaking up, and Lily, who’s like “You’re being a sick mother fucker who just wnats to hurt the Borg back because they hurt you.” She’s totally right.</p>

<p>And he’s being a fucking idiot. He’s EXTREMELY out of character with this. He’s angry and pissy and lashes out, breaking shit and acting like a spoiled baby. “I WILL MAKE THEM PAY FOR WHAT THEY’VE DONE”. We’ve seen Picard dealing with the trauma for this for years. He breaks down. He cries. He freezes up. He DOES get annoyed and give up his “modern sensibilities” to do things he’d consider inhumane, like with Hugh, but… Murr. I hate this, I really do.</p>

<p>Anyways Lily convinces him to blow up the Enterprise, so he does. He puts in the self destruct sequence and everyone else escapes, when he hears a whisper of Data. Uh oh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7woQcai.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Also back on the Planet, they’re blasting off. Chochrane blasts some rock music as they blast off. What a goofball. The planet stuff for this is actually pretty good, I’m a fan. Feels MUCH more Trek than the action sequence up above.</p>

<p>Picard stays behind to try and save Data, and we get some Historical Revisionism. Locutus’ whole job was apparently to be a king for the Borg Queen, basically. A “bridge between humanity and borg”, that’s why he’s so important. Unfortunately, she’s found a NEW one for that. Data, who’s become an evil humonculus mother fucker. She demands he turn off the self destruct and give her control over the ship thropugh the encryption codes. He does. Oh no! She tells him to blow up Cochrane’s ship, so he fires Photon Torpedos at it. He does, but they miss. Oh, he’s been good this whole time! He says “RESISTANCE IS FUTILE”, then busts off the tanks of the reactor.</p>

<p>So uh yeah. Why did he turn off the self destruct, why did he give them control, why was he pretending at any point? I mean it DOES work out in the end, the reactor kills all the borg, cause the Queen falls in it, and all the Borg die cause she dies. Also he had a VERY easy chance to do that earlier, because she let him go and wander around. He could have broken the reactor then. But okay then. It all worked out in the end.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4Hyl4wK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Vulcans show up, and first contact happens. It all goes well, they leave, using the Moon’s something something to hide from the Vulcans. And boom, they’re done. Uhh, gg.</p>

<p>I hated this movie even more than Generations. I kept watching Generations, I wasn’t checked out. I was checked out here. This is not a Trek movie, it’s a shitty action movie. The characters are barely anything (Geordi and Crusher might as well not be here. At least Troi gets a scene where she’s drunk thats fun, but she still might as well not be here), and the ones that ARE here a lot are AWFUL, and out of character. What the FUCK, Picard? He’s so out of character and awful. You should not have put Picard screaming and swinging around a tommy gun murdering his OWN people who were assimilated, with him going “they were assimilated there’s no way to save them” WHEN HE WAS ASSIMILATED, AND THEY SAVED HIM. I hate what they did with the Borg. I hate what they did with Data. They murdered SO MANY of the Enterprise’s crew, and barely even talked about it. There was no emotional THERE there. And the pacing is all SO terrible.</p>

<p>I hated this. I think Generations is like, bad, but I watched it, and felt kinda not a lot. Mostly annoyed at Data. This was bad, and I ACTIVELY disliked it.</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek: Insurrection</strong> - 7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ERXeuJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our movie starts with an idyllic paradise-like world. It’s a very “Look at the birds, daddy!” moment. This is a clearly pre-space flight civilization, and we’ve got Federation people there watching them with hidden bunkers and people in cloak suits. Cause I guess the federation has cloaking suits now. Data is apparently going hay-wire, and rips off his suit, so he’s just a floating head, terrifying the fuck out of the aliens, the Baku, and annoying the Feds. Data then blasts the bunkers, getting rid of the holograms and revealing them to the Baku. Oh no!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a93IIyh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, they’re having a fancy dinner to welcome some new aliens into the Federation. Apparently the Dominion War and the Borg have uh, made this all exhausting. Understandable, so they’re trying to find new allies. Interesting that they can just have some fancy dinner function in a war, though. IMMEDIATELY, this movie is more quippy. And not in a bad way, I LIKE Trek quipping. While on their way to the function, hey, Worf is here. He literally goes “I was in the neighborhood”. Not even coming up with a good reason to have Worf here, but at least he’s here.</p>

<p>An Admiral calls the Enterprise like “hey, send me Data’s schematics, he’s having issues. Do not come. We don’t want you, things here aren’t safe for your crew so please stay behind.” So obviously they show up anyway. The Federation is working with this people, the Son’a, who are kinda sketchy conquerors, so no one really knows WHY the Feds are working with them while studying the Baku.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qxvsXhS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the Son’a leader. He’s a smarmy sassy mother fucker, got some gay villain energy, and he has his flesh like, hooked and stretched all over him, it’s fucking creepy but not in a bad way.</p>

<p>Anyways so they hunt Data, who’s been attacking the Federation with a stolen ship. Picard decides its HIS job to take Data out, he’s his captain, and friend. So they go in a shuttle to fight him, and he’s clearly still functioning enough to have tactical reasoning. So how do they outsmart him? They distract him with GIlbert and Sullivan. This is very, VERY silly, and a little random, but I kinda don’t hate it. I weirdly love it. They manage to capture him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VQDew4g.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard and crew then go to “rescue” those who are being held by the Baku after Data’s rampage, and we learn about them. They are actually VERY intelligent, very technologically advanced. They once had ships and warp drive capacity, but don’t really want it. “If you use machines to take the job of a man, you remove a part of the man”. They’re THOSE kinda people. They do yoga.</p>

<p>Also there’s some scenes where Riker and Troi are rekindling their relationship. (I originally had this as “Crusher and Troi”, because freudian slip I guess) They’re very random and don’t quite fit here, but it’s very cute actually. I love them. They are the most queer straight couple in the federation.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F9Oftsi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, this ends in Riker’s beard being shaved off. 0/10. Worst movie in the entire series. This goes against everything I believe in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f6l7hIJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Though to be fair, if Marina Sirtis says “I will kiss you but only if you shave your beard”, that beard is getting shaved, I don’t care who you are.</p>

<p>The quips and writing in this movie are really on point so far. The actual budget feels like it’s less than the previous movies, some of the green screening is low quality. But honestly I couldn’t care less about that. Its OBVIOUS this movie is trying to be more humorous, which is interesting since the topic is so heavy.</p>

<p>So what HAVE the federation been doing? They’ve built a fake ship that’s just a holodeck that simulates the Baku’s planet. They were GOING to capture them and just kick them off the planet. That’s pretty fucked up. Why? Well, Picard figures it out fast. The planet’s rings cause a radiation that gives immortality, and increased vitality. Apparently this small group of Feds, working with the Son’a, are trying to steal it from them. Pretty heavy, literal colonialism. But Picard isn’t going to let them! GOD PICARD IS SO MUCH BETTER IN THIS MOVIE THAN THE LAST MOVIE, FUCKING CHRIST.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RQ0O86e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The things this radiation can do are incredible, and it makes SENSE why they’d WANT it. Geordi’s eyes are healing, and he’s seeing a sunrise for the first time. This is the best moment Geordi has had in 3 movies. In the second movie he did nothing. In the first movie he was tortured. Let the man rest.</p>

<p>So yeah, the Admiral explains his reasoning. He’s acting on orders from the Federation council. Due to semantics, the Prime Directive doesn’t apply here because of two reasons. 1) They don’t want it to. And 2) These people aren’t from this planet so they weren’t “meant to be immortal”, whatever that means. 3) It’s JUST 600 people :) Who cares?</p>

<p>Yeah it’s obviously extremely evil. And it does make sense, you get it. It’s just… how people work. And it’s all politics. Apparently the Son’a are going to blow up the planet to get all the particles and use them to fix their conditions immediately, so the Federation are doing this to SAVE the Baku in their eyes. Cause otherwise the Baku would have just killed them, blowing it up. But yeah, it’s orders. Picard has to stop.</p>

<p>So he doesn’t. He quits. He tries to leave quietly, but everyone else notices. And what to do they do?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v6b3hNU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Exactly what you’d expect.</p>

<p>The Baku leave to try and reach some caves, which will block teleporters. They’re trying to keep people on the planet long enough for the Enterprise to go and make things Political.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Sqhfjyg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got some character stuff here. Data’s role here is to connect to a kid, and try to figure out what its like to be a kid. Picard is having romance moments with a lady who’s lived here for 300 years. Troi and Crusher get to shoto guns. Worf is uh, going through puberty. Lots of jokes about Klingon puberty. Data makes a joke about his tits. Okay, not ALL the jokes land. Those are huge anti-jokes. Poor Worf. I guess we have too many characters in this show for ALL the characters to be good and have things to do in a movie. Unlike y’know, a tv show that’s 1/4th the length.</p>

<p>Riker and Geordi are on the Enterprise trying to escape, but are attacked, while being negatively effected by the briar patch. They’re hit really hard, and have to eject the warp core, but at least we get to see the Enterprise-E DO something.</p>

<p>There’s also a Trill pilot on the Enterprise. Riker says he’s going to release the ramscoop and shove it down the Son’a’s throats, and she gives him this look.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zEghUXy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Christ on the cross, she can shove her ramscoop down MY throat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xpVKQvG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Romantic moment with Picard and the older lady. She almost dies from a cavein, but he distracts her enough to keep her with them. It’s not bad. I’m not super into the romance, but it’s not the worst. But as they escape, both Picard and the lady, Anij, are teleported off the planet.</p>

<p>But we get a plot twist, something Crusher finds out. The Son’a and the Baku are the same people. The Son’a broke off years ago from the others, wanting to go back to being space faring peoples, and were exiled. Now enraged and seeking revenge, they really actually want to just kill their own people. Also this being an internal fued within a species, this now makes it a prime directive matter. Which makes sense why the Son’a never brought it up. The Son’a leader murders the Admiral with a face stretch scene thats horrifying.</p>

<p>Picard convinces the villain’s second in command to turn on him, in a good scene. “You disgust me. A coward too scares to stop an atrocity.” “Is this how the Federation pleads for its life?” “I’m not pleading for my life. I’m pleading for your’s.” And it WORKS. This is how you write a Picard. Kill them with words. Not with a tommy gun.</p>

<p>They manage to outsmart them by making them shift their shield for a small second, and while they do, they teleport them into the holodeck ship. And while they fuck around on that, the others teleport onto the Son’a’s ship and take over. There’s a GREAT scream from the villain, Ruo’fo, as he fidns out what happens. It is VERY funny and goofy. “UUWAAOOOWWW!”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9EGlmoZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard and Ruo’fo teleport onto the collector, Ruo’fo to make it launch, Picard to stop him, and it becomes a giant action fight scene in the collector that’s gonna blow up the ship. It ends with Picard potentially sacrificing himself as it explodes, but the Enterprise makes it JUST in time (after the Enterprise plays chicken with them), and Ruo’fo explodes. They COULD have saved him I guess, but eh. Whatever. Fuck him I guess. It’s an actiony movie, it fits. Though it IS weird of them lol</p>

<p>The Son’a 2nd in command reunites with his mom, and all’s well that ends well. The Federation is “halting the Baku relocation” to do some checking to see if it’s very illegal (it is), Data frolicks in the hay bales and has fun, before its time to go home, his mom is calling him. But they can’t stay, it’s time to go home, and leave the Baku to where they want to be.</p>

<p>Movie over, GG.</p>

<p>Maybe it’s cause I hated the last two so much, but this was pretty good? Good crew moments, good quips, maybe a little too much jokes, but still very enjoyable. It’s like, on par with Star Trek 3. A fine movie. Pretty Trekky. Very inconsequential to the plot of the series as a whole, but eh, whatcha gonna do. Not their fault they kept bringing back the Borg Queen instead of the Son’a.</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek: Nemesis</strong> - 6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v9iTr64.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’re FINALLY watching Nemesis! It takes place directly after Voyager is done, so we had to wait for Voyager to be done. This, to me, ends the 90s era, even if it came out in 2002. Here we go.</p>

<p>We start with some Romulan military people making a proposal to the senate, which is rejected. A senator steps out over this, and I’m like “oh shit we about to get a coup”. We do in fact get a coup, a thing she left behind very conspicuously, which she had been playing with, opens up and creates water droplets. These water droplets cause the Romulan senators dry up violently and painfully and they turn to stone and shatter against the  ground as they fall. If I saw this as a kid it would have given me nightmares. Reminded me of the Tuxedo, the only movie I’ve ever seen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0UMGVca.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>When did Star Trek get so woke?</p>

<p>Troi and Riker are married now! They’re gonna be going to a ship called the Titan for this, and Picard is sad but also happy. This is very funny considering the finale of season 3, like 10 years before this, where he went “what the fuck are you still doing here, Will”. Also, Worf is here. He’s just a part of the crew still. It’s not explained. It was barely explained in Insurrection but it’s even LESS explained here, he’s just here for the ride. I mean obviously he’d be here for the wedding, but ah.</p>

<p>While heading to Betazed to deliver the newlyweds, they’re pulled off course by a strange reading. Positronic readings, some kind of Data Brainmeats on a remote planet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TnJh9oE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the stipulations Picard had for being in this movie was that he demanded to drive a dunebuggy. This is a little silly but that’s okay, I don’t mind too much. Patrick Stewart looks so happy to drive it.</p>

<p>That happiness is cut out pretty quickly as they find the causes of the positronic signals. Some data-like body parts, strewn about. An arm. A leg. And finally, a head. It seems like Data’s head, who responds with a “fascinating”. Then suddenly it becomes a mad max movie as some natives of the planet come at them with buggies and machine guns. It’s a turret vehicle section, in my Star Trek. I never much liked how the TNG movies try to be like, action movies.</p>

<p>They escape, and that’s it. The action sequence means nothing to the rest of the story. They reassemble this Data, find he’s some kind of prototype named B-4. He doesn’t know why he’s there, but he’s friendly enough.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EZNkqz1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Say hello to the reason we waited like 2 years to watch this movie. A fucking cameo. She’s here to tell them to go to Romulus. She’s an admiral now which is cool. And then we’ll never see her again… until Prodigy! :D Bye, Janeway!</p>

<p>They’re sent to Romulus. Troi and Riker are still here, I guess. Apparently a “Reman” is now the praetor, which seems to be an underclass in their society. A slave class. Seems to be a coup of some kind, possibly military coup? Also at the same with they download Data’s… data into B-4. As they sit over Romulus, they’re kept waiting for a long-ass time, but eventually a dangerous looking ship appears and gives them transport coordinates, and we go to meet Shinzon, the new leader of Romulus.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X7iWbET.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shinzon is a creepy little fucker. He’s “never seen a Human woman” and wants to touch Troi’s hair. But he’s also offering peace with the Federation, which is nice. But he’s also shrouded in darkness. And also obviously a Human. Not Romulan, OR Reman. He’s a bald little fucker, and he also has a lot of… similarities as Picard. And he’s NOT subtle about this. “Come to dinner, just the two of us. Or should I say, just the one of us”. He cuts his fucking hand and gives the blood to them, and is a weird little mother fucker.</p>

<p>Sure enough, yes, he’s Picard’s clone, according to the blood. Also he’s played by Tom Hardy pretending to be a young Patrick Stewart, which isn’t 1 to 1, but it’s better than some CGI monstrocity. Also, his viceroy, a Reman, is played by Ron Perlman doing a growly voice in heavy makeup. Man, Ron Perlman will do whatever, won’t he?</p>

<p>We also see Shinzon talking to his advisors. A Romulan commander is a little shit about the whole thing, confused why the hell the Enterprise is here, and why aren’t they nuking the Federation yet, he just really wants to see some Federation people die, please, just this once. Shinzon tells him to fuck off. And the other commander is the girl who did the assassinations of the senate, and she tries seducing him, but he’s fucking disgusted by it, and claims “You are not a woman, you are a romulan”. Yay racism? Shinzon DOES mention something about “Romulan lashes” so clearly he has history.</p>

<p>At the dinner date with Picard, he explains. He was a clone which the Romulans made, considered a failure, and threw in the Reman dilithium mines cause fuck it who cares. The Remans took pity on him and treated him as a brother. He’s here now to be like “We should ally and be friends! I want peace!” Man, I’m so glad this movie is going to immediately end with no problems at all and we all become friends :D No obviously not. Picard goes “yes I’d love to be friends but we’ll need to make sure y’all are actually good for it first” and leaves. And of course shit isn’t all above board, it’s pretty obviously. Someone has apparently hacked into their computers, and there’s some very deadly radiation that they’ve found scans of.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EpdhYto.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the things I knew about this movie was that it had a very troubled production, and they cut out a lot of scenes. Like, a lot. Way too many. But then why the FUCK did they leave THIS in??? Troi has sex with Riker, but then he turns into Shinzon who appears to be sexually assaulting her through psychic stuff???? I dunno. Like… it’s so bad and all out of nowhere. And does not matter to anything, just… wow look at how evil this guy is he mind raped Deanna. We already saw him do a political coup, killing dozens, and is planning some evil shit, we did NOT need this too.</p>

<p>Suddenly Picard is kidnapped, and B-4 is with him! Shenzon explains that as long as Picard lives, he’s nothing but his shadow. That… that comes out of nowhere, for being his main driving force? Like, I like the stuff about him viewing himself as Reman culturally, not a Human, and not Romulan. It’s a Nature VS Nuture argument, and that’s cool. But “I can’t live as long as you do”? That doesn’t make any sense to me. Like obviously he’s not 100% mentally stable. But I don’t find that super compelling unless it’s like, over the top? And he can’t be the dashing brilliant foil to Picard who outsmarts him at every turn while also being coo coo bananas with flawed logic and reasoning.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tqBofQX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Data was B-4, take a drink! Yes, they actually saw this COMING and replaced B-4 with Data! Now Data and Picard gotta break out of the ship. They actually have a teleportation thingy but it’ll only work for one person. It turn turns into an action movie again, Picard dual wielding phaser pistols and shooting down a bunch of random guards. Okay, again, I don’t like how they tried make TNG action movies, but this is SO much better than it was in First Contact, with Picard screaming as he fired a tommy gun. I still don’t think we needed to try and make Star Trek into Star Wars, but if we have to, this is as good as we can do, honestly.</p>

<p>Data and Picard break out with another action scene, using a shuttle they steal to blast down some tunnels in this giant ship they’re in, like it’s fucking Descent. Again, pretty okay actually. They make it back and warp the fuck out, with Shinzon planning to chase.</p>

<p>There’s a scene where Data deactivates B-4 because he’s dangerous. It’s pretty sad tbh. Poor B-4. He doesn’t understand what’s going on. We also learn Shinzon is apparently dying due to Clone-itis. Okay, NOW the cloning blues makes some more sense.</p>

<p>They determine that he has a radiation weapon that can destroy Earth, the same radiation that did the Tuxedo stuff from the start that freaked me the hell out. So they prepare for battle and go to meet some of the Federation for backup. Also there’s a scene with Data and Picard, Picard going “He’s what I could have become, he is me” and Data is like “No sir, that’s stupid”. I guess it’s the thesis of the movie. Needed a bit more than a one and a half minute scene.</p>

<p>Shinzon’s ship easily disables the Enterprise and then Shinzon sets up a hologram in Picard’s ready room. Hey, remember when we were trying to make this technology a thing for like 8 episodes? Still dunno why we just kept wanting to make TNG Star Wars.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5YrLllp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is actually a good scene tbh. Picard tries to petition to Shinzon’s morality, and say “you can be better than this, you can grow as a person” and he eventually rejects it. He is what his life has made of him. And he has to do this. And once he does, Picard will be nothing in the end but a dim memory, as his name echoes through history. It’s a good scene. And it’s nice to see Picard actually do speeches, you know, the thing he’s good at.</p>

<p>Shit seems bad, but the Romulans from earlier who were working with Shinzon show up and go “yeah fuck this guy, let’s kill him together”. Temporary alliance maybe (they literally did this so that they could destroy the Federation), but alliance nonetheless.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/H9tfA7C.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a pretty neat fight, which we lose, pretty heavily Our allies don’t DIE but are dead in the water quite fast. Though clearly Shinzon is struggling with his clone-itis.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/h3sw1Fl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The sexual assault scene from earlier comes back, unfortunately, but Troi gets her revenge, using the psychic link that Shinzon’s viceroy made with her to allow him to sexually assault her to control him just long enough so they could hit them where it hurts. She even does a “Remember me?” line. Hell yeah, I love Metroid Other M (I do not, actually). Also hey, return of the eye-lighting from TOS. Always a cool effect.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nsWZ5LU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They lose. Shinzon has them dead to rights. They’re floating in space, all weapons dead, basically, and there’s a hole in their fucking view finger. Several people are dead, and Troi has to fly the ship now. Shinzon is sure, because he’s Picard after all, that Picard would surrender and save his crew. He does not. He flies the fucking Enterprise DIRECTLY into Shinzon’s ship. People love to point to this scene as “hurr hurr Troi is woman who can’t drive”. Bitch, she was told to do this.</p>

<p>It’s a cool scene ngl. They seem to do a LOT more damage to Shinron’s ship than he does to them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/obqh8hR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Riker is fighting the Viceroy, Shinzon’s 2nd in command, who tried to physically take the Enterprise. Their fight goes to…. I don’t even know. It’s a giant vertical shaft with a rickety-ass bridge over it. It breaks, and Riker holds on for dear life as the Viceroy falls miles down into… again, I dunno. Where the fuck is this?! Did Cetacean Ops fucking drain??? This is the silliest thing in this fucking movie.</p>

<p>Both ships are basically dead, so Shinron decides he doesn’t NEED to live after all. His body is basically becoming mouldy cheese at this point. He’s going to send out the radiaton and kill all of them, then fly to Earth, while dying, and blow it up. Their mission WILL succeed even if he doesn’t live to see it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DK5Ccp3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard beams over to fight Shinzon one on one. It’s a suicide mission. Teleporters immediately go offline after that, of course. But Data is having one of it… He THROWS himself out of the fucking Enterprise through one of the open holes in the walls and flies towards Shinzon’s ship in a scene I probably should not be laughing at but absolutely am.</p>

<p>Picard kills all of Shinzon’s guards and assistants, but refuses to kill him, and they struggle. He has a gun, but he won’t shoot Shinzon. Well of course. You wouldn’t expect Picard to KILL people, would you??? <em>glances over at all the fucking corpses surrounding Picard</em></p>

<p>I guess if he did we wouldn’t get a cool climactic final fight but come on, Picard.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SaUkKQd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shinzon impales himself, then DRAGS HIMSELF on the pole towards Picard, staring at him and grabbing him. Picard doesn’t like, leave in order to stop the radiation. Or do anything. He just stands there in shock for some fucking reason. Picard, my mans… wh- why? Why??? You’ve killed before, you’ll kill again, and you didn’t care about killing all those random people, but now that your evil clone has impaled himself you FREEZE UP??? Data comes in, teleports Picard off with his little tleporter button that he mentioned earlier, and then blows up the ship, saving everyone but sacrificing himself. Rest in peace, Data.</p>

<p>It’s okay, I can see his parachute. He literally set up his parachute earlier in the fucking movie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TklwWXT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone drinks to Data. Riker starts the ceremonies of talking about the positives about Data. It feels awkward, like no one wants to hear it.</p>

<p>We get a scene with Riker FINALLY leaving the ship, as was set up this entire time. He’s leading a task force to make an alliance with the Romulans.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8kQhCd2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Picard reactivates B-4, who again, had Data’s memories downloaded into him earlier, but it didn’t seem to work. B-4 isn’t Data. But some parts of him are starting to come back through. Yep, we’re ALREADY getting the replacement Data set up. I guess we’ll see that in Picard, huh? And then the movie ends!</p>

<p>Also, we watched some deleted scenes. All of these were deleted for reasons we cannot possibly understand. Like, it was a very long movie sure, but apparently Berman just said “fuck this we need to make the movie make less sense”.</p>

<p>We get a scene with Wesley Crusher, who WAS in the movie as a cameo, but here he’s like “Yeah I’m excited to serve on the Titan :D.” WHAT? WTF??? He QUIT Starfleet and is now a fucking God, why would he serve on the Titan?! Okay, THAT scene can be removed, sure.</p>

<p>The next deleted scene is Picard talking to Data about why he’s happy AND sad that so many people are leaving the Enterprise. About how they’re like his children, and he’s seeing them grow up. It’s a good scene and helps set up the themes of the movie. But we had to keep the Troi scene in, so it could set up a scene later that didn’t actually do anything :)</p>

<p>There’s also a scene where they introduces Shinzon’s assistants earlier, alongside Shinzon. They removed it so that the scene with Shinzon being shrouded in shadow hits harder. I guess that makes sense.</p>

<p>Another scene with Riker and Troi talking with Worf about their happy honeymoon plans. Removing this means Worf only had like 7 lines in the movie. We also see Data teaching B-4 to eat. This scene can also go, that’s fine. Though I do love Brent Spiner.</p>

<p>Another Worf scene, one where he is racist against Romulans and gives in a suggestion which Picard ignores. We actually get a conclusion to this scene down the way with him going “the Romulans fought with honor”. That seemed out of place tbh. This saved what, 40 seconds? Keep it in. Let Worf earn his pay.</p>

<p>Most of the things they cut were just… more set ups for the themes of the movie. Unneccesary cuts.</p>

<p>OH MY FUCKING CHRIST, THERE WERE TWO RAPES IN THIS MOVIE ORIGINALLY?! THEY ACTUALLY CUT ONE?! WHAT THE FUCK, RICK BERMAN?! WHAT THE FUCK?!?!</p>

<p>One more deleted scene, showing the new First Officer who was replacing Riker. Riker tells him that Picard likes being called “Jean-Luc”. It doesn’t go over well. It’s pretty funny, and would be a more pleasant ending than the ending we got which was like, kinda flat. They end the movie properly with a “where no one has gone before” and it’s kinda nice tbh, with a glory shot of the Enteprrise. A fine final scene.</p>

<p>Over all, the movie is fine. Lots of stupid decisions and weird moments but over all, it was entertaining enough, and actually had ideas and a theme to say rather than whatever the fuck the first two movies were saying. It’s messy though. It has a lot of unneccesary stupid scenes and ideas for a movie that appears to be missing 25% of its fucking scenes that were shot for it. I do wish we had gotten a better TNG sendoff, but I’m not unhappy with this. It’s fine.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="TNG" /><category term="Movies" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 177</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/16/OOCY177.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 177" /><published>2025-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/16/OOCY177</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/16/OOCY177.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kVbTIrB.png" alt="A page from 'She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat'. One woman is staring at another, who's just sitting there, and she's freaking out a bit, before finally going 'um...! how.... how much of you can I touch...?' while the other just stares." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She Loves to Cook She Loves to Eat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 176</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/14/OOCY176.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 176" /><published>2025-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/14/OOCY176</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/14/OOCY176.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rvUJkOc.png" alt="A panel from 'For Some Reason Suddenly I Wanted to... With the Coworker Who Sits Next to Me.' A woman is staring forward, blushing, and exclaiming, 'I asked you to come over because I wanted to have sex with you, is that so wrong...?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: For Some Reason Suddenly I Wanted to… With the Coworker Who Sits Next to Me.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="For Some Reason Suddenly I Wanted to... With the Coworker Who Sits Next to Me." /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>