<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-22T12:15:17-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 32</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/22/OOCY32.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 32" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/22/OOCY32</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/22/OOCY32.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lvBrKMe.png" alt="&quot;Sh-she's not straight...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3RYhH5C.png" alt="&quot;Sh-she's not straight...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Same</p>

<p>source: Hana Ni Arashi</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Hana Ni Arashi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 52 - Conclusion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-52.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 52 - Conclusion" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50#52</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-52.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WNpJ4yk.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO50 was a collection of 50 games made over the course of seven years by LX Systems, later UFOSoft. It was made in celebration of their 50th game, and while it seems like it might never have been released, it was found 30 years later by some nerds in an old warehouse, as seen in the cracktro intro for the game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KjLr1JU.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, what’s the purpose of all this? UFO 50 is just a collection of 50 games with a fake backstory. Why go through all the trouble to make a fake backstory, with fake characters, a fake murder coverup, and a fake CEO who hordes games instead of releasing them for people to play and use, cultivating a collection for himself and no one else? What is the point of UFO 50?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0N91bUn.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO 50 is about preservation.</p>

<p>As we get further into the future, more and more games are lost to time. People made these. These aren’t just products to make a profit, and they aren’t just code with no purpose. People put hours, days, years into creating them. They are the culmination of creative people who care about the thing they love. Games. And it’s easy to forget that, especially as these people and their work is swept under the rug. As the game are forgotten, lost to time, locked away behind CEO’s vaults in case they might possibly sell them in the future, or locked in personal collections and never shown to the public, those people are forgotten as well. All their work, their love, their passion, it’s lost.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RHsIeEW.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO 50 is about preservation. Greg Milk’s entire goal, from creating UFO 50, under Nemuru’s leadership, to hiding hints and messages and an entire game that shows him, his coworkers, and the world they had to live in, it’s a bright, blinding message that they were there. They were the people, the love, and the passion behind those games. And while someone like Nemuru might try to seal away play for himself, some might leak out, and be preserved, by those who love it. It might be played, and enjoyed, for years to come. It might, some 30 years in the future, be the topic of 33.8k words of reviews written by a dork in her basement. It might even be her game of the year.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nMQoRA2.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO 50 is about love. And I hope we don’t ever forget that. May it shine on, forever.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 51 - The Terminal &amp;amp; Miasma Tower - SPOILERS AHEAD</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-51.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 51 - The Terminal &amp;amp; Miasma Tower - SPOILERS AHEAD" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50#51</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-51.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pw6QMPV.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO50 has a built in terminal. It’s not a secret thing, it’s right there, in the menu. This is implied to be the terminal of the computer itself, which you can use to access files and execute commands directly, rather than use the GUI of the game itself. There are a lot of more obvious uses for this terminal. Several games will tell you codes that can activate hidden modes and cheats, like the WOLF-PACK code that lets you play as four dogs in Grimstone, which I mentioned. But there’s also more to the terminal. A secret. A very, very in depth secret, which will blow the story of UFO 50 wide open.</p>

<p>The story of Miasma Tower is a very deep and interesting thing, and I am going to go very in depth. If you want to experience it for yourself, do not read ahead, as I am going to go FULL on with spoilers. Everything will be laid bare. Ready? Okay, let’s go.</p>

<p>There is a secret 51st game in UFO 50. Even before I started playing the game, I guessed there might be. This is the kinda game that screams meta secrets. But how do you find this hidden game? The most obvious, and correct answer, is the terminal. It’s gotta be chock full of secrets. But how do you get at them? There are a few ways to discover Miasma Tower, the hidden 51st game. I discovered it by noodling around in the menus. The terminal is like an old computer terminal. It has commands, and once you have a general idea of those commands, you can do a lot. A common command from back then was HELP. And sure enough, it works here. Each game has a four letter name, like UFO1 for Campanella, SAC1 for Mortol. But they are also numbered. So 0001 is the first game, Barbuta. You can do HELP-0001 to learn all the commands you could use with Barbuta. It’s very simple stuff, basically stuff you can find in the GUI already. The history, the name, etc etc. But if you put in HELP-0051, you get shown a different game. And it’ll helpfully tell you its name. MIAS. Input EXEC-MIAS to start the game…</p>

<p>That’s the way I found it. But there’s another way. A more complex way, and the way most people found it. When you look at the terminal, you notice something. It’s two words, each four letters, seperated by a hyphen. Where have we seen that before?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ssoYojM.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Our boy, Greg Milk. Milkdud here gave us a clue. Remember, Gregory Milk is the person who MADE UFO50. And he also made Miasma Tower, and he wants it to be seen. But it’s hidden away. Why? Miasma Tower was never meant to exist, and it was not meant to be in UFO 50. But it had to be, for reasons we’ll get into, so Greg hid it, deep in the terminal. And your first clue is by typing in GREG-MILK, which will give you a cryptic message.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VgPY6ct.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’m not going to go in depth with these messages. They are a hidden meta puzzle that will take you into many of the 50 games in the pack. You need a knowledge of all 50 games to proceed, and as you follow Greg’s trail of bread crumbs, you’ll eventually come to a message that says “EXEC-MIAS”. So there you go. The other way to find Miasma Tower. But what IS Miasma Tower?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OHQb5rt.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Let’s hop in and find out…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sGniQ2S.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Miasma Tower, you play as Gregory Milk. This is an autobiographical adventure game, not quite a game as much as a visual novel, showing you what life is like at UFO Soft. The game is explicitely from the point of view of Mr. Milk, who’s opinions, views, and thoughts are on full display. As you interact with things inside the UFOSoft office, you’ll see what Greg thinks of them, and how they effect the world, and the people around them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BwzGKx0.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game takes place inside the current UFOSoft HQ, and has all the workers and coworkers there. They’re all represented by weird little critters, but it’s not actually that hard to put a name to a character. This wasn’t really meant to be seen by outside forces. It was a game made by Greg, basically for Greg. He knows who they are. We have to do a bit more sleuthing, but based on where people are, what they say, and what their job is, we can make a guess. This is Meesha! The characters are all represented by little weird critters, and I like how Greg represents himself. He’s a brown lumpy… thing, with a permanent frown. If you read Greg’s inner thoughts, the man is clearly depressed and anxious. The years have not been kind to him, and the recent events at UFOSoft have left him with serious scars.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VqDT6h9.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3FNqXWv.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/amfRxi5.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DOvoUgb.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Greg isn’t the only one. A lot of the people around the office are overworked, and exhausted. They’re being put on jobs that aren’t really what they’re good at, and being milked, and it’s pretty obvious they know. The corporate culture of the office ia also quite toxic. There’s references to a kind of hazing ritual that poor Shayn had to go through recently, which Greg is HORRIFIED at the idea of ever happening to him. Thorson Petter is hard at work in his office, as it lights on fire around him, as he overworks himself to death to add more games to Campanella 3. Why? It’s never explained.</p>

<p>And that last one there, that’s Benedikt Chun, the only founder left. He’s getting neurotic himself. He sold the company over to the devil a few years ago, for just the safety of being able to make the games he loves, and now he’s asking if Greg thinks anyone will ever play their games. What does he mean by that? I’ll get into that in a moment…</p>

<p>First, you should know the structure. This game is split into a few parts. You start in a closed space, and then find a disk and play it. It’s an old beta demo disk. After beating that, you get more puzzles which lead you to a new execute command, and now more of the offices are open. You then find another disk, beat THAT demo, and get more puzzles, and then even MORE of the offices are open. It’s an interesting progression mechanic, as you go through the past to reach the present.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6Ez95fA.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x86uYkS.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fTBCpLN.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6mqVmbZ.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All throughout the offices, you’ll find references to the fact that the games that the company has been making for the last year do not seem to actually be released. The workers seem to know this too, as is hinted from that message in Diskonia I mentioned: “HOW FAR IN THE FUTURE ARE YOU READING THIS?”. What kind of company can continue running when it’s not even releasing its games? For what purpose? There are so many expenses, but no income. And yet, the HR accountant tells you flatly that the boss has allowed her to give out raises. They’re spending a LOT. The offices are filled with things that aren’t neccessary to make games. A barely used gym. A dormitory which Greg feels weird about using. A whole arcade and game room, filled with Nemuru’s personal collection. How can they justify this?</p>

<p>Becuase the point isn’t to sell games.</p>

<p>Tao Nemuru has connections to a company that’s hinted at in Miasma Tower in a few places: &lt;MPI. Or the Murtzbach Preservation Institute. There was a tester called Sten Murzbach, who’s name also leads to a code that shows a bunch of time capsules. What does this mean? What is the purpose? It’s never said, but we can make some inferences. And to reach that conclusion, let’s talk about the people in charge.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xpqwsvd.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P0it4OC.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CYsPBd1.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AAp49kk.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GXjNsBq.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eNFmHWm.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All of Greg’s coworkers and friends are represented by weird critters, but the people Greg doesn’t like are represented in two ways. The boss’s minions and enforcement, HR and the middle manager Ian Spinzer, are represented by giant groteqsue dinosaur like monsters. And the boss, his child, and their psychophant tester, are all represented by bugs. Nemuru is shown as having a kind of… cultist energy to him. He has a book of philosophy he pushes on others, the psychophant following it heavily. And that book is this one:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLZ5X1s.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Grasshopper: Games, Life, and Utopia. I have not read this book. But it’s clearly at the root of the grasshopper and ant imagery, especially seen in Combatants, Nemuru’s baby. It’s based on the classic kids story of the grasshopper and the ant. Y’know, the grasshopper plays all summer while the ant works, then winter comes and the grasshopper starves like the ant plays. The book itself takes this further and turns it on its head a bit. It’s a book of philosphy that consists of rumination on the nature of games, told through reconsideration of the fable in ways that parallel the game, ranging from both the concept of saving games in preparation for a future utopia where we will play forever, and the framing of games as an obstacle.</p>

<p>That first part is the thing that really hits at key here. Nemuru is a games collector. He is shown to have a vast collection, and he’s gathering more. He’s very, very into preservation, but in a… bit of a twisted way. More of a collection for a collections’ sake. What it took to make that collection, and what it contains, doesn’t quite matter, so much that he has it. Murzbach Industries seems to be some kind of group, almost cult like, which collects and is locking away games in a kind of time vault. That’s why Nemuru is so interested in pumping out more games, and in UFO 50 as a culimation, a grand testemant to what they’ve made. That’s why there’s a paper showing multiple game companies, and next to UFO Soft, it shows the words “Almost done?”. They’re almost done using up UFO Soft, and then these games will be locked away, forever. For some idyllic future where the billionares will play and play.</p>

<p>I have a lot of thoughts on this, and I’ll talk about them in a conclusion to this entire story. For now, there’s a few other things hinted at in the backstory of UFO 50 through Miasma Tower that are extremely interesting, and should be shown.</p>

<p>I’ve seen people going “this game feels like it could hold a creepypasta meta secret, I sure hope it doesn’t”. I have bad news for you. We’ve got to talk about Chiffon Bola.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/feDbrKy.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qwB17sA.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chiffon Bola was one of the first people to join the company. She was a game designer, a developer, a bit of a jock. She likes bikes. She thanked bike clubs in the special thanks of her games. Some time in 1988, she went missing, and was presumed dead.</p>

<p>https://imgur.com/MMvWEoK</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MMvWEoK.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mIe5mCg.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p0REdQZ.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Hints of her are still in the company, and any time you come across them, Greg averts his gaze. When he enters her old cubicle, he spells out I’m Sorry on the wall, and doesn’t elaborte or comment further. He doesn’t even say who’s cubicle it was, you just have to theorize. When he gets to her name in the company’s registry, he stops reading. He’s HAUNTED by Chiffon Bola. Later on, near the end, you run into a ghost of a floating bike helmet…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f6YacfY.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The ghost blames Greg for what happened to her. Or Greg blames himself, more accurately. What happened? What happened to Chiffon Bola? Well, Greg has some theories…</p>

<p>Chiffon Bola very obviously chaffed against the new leadership as soon as they showed up. Everyone kind of did, but Chiffon seems to have been a rather independant woman, and would make her opinions known. In one of her games, Vainger, she shows the space station has being taken over by a malignant, insect-like force, who only wanted to save themselves, the universe be damned. In her cancelled game that you can find in her old cubicle, the cyberpunk RPG I mentioned, she deliberately calls the evil supervirus calling all the problems the Spinz/net.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0mZRZI8.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chiffon Bola clearly chaffed against leadership, especially Spinzer, who is a raging meathead dinosaur, according to Greg. And Greg has some ideas as to what happened to her…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/O1xgJBS.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gPy0fhq.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jl5fb22.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W5qkxzQ.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You can find several hints that her disappearance is foul play. A detective is snooping around. There are stains near the bike rack, now empty. There’s a shattered bike hidden in the vents. The only way into the vents is a ladder, which is in Spinzer’s office. One of Spinzer’s coats is missing a button, which can be found in the stairwell. You find photos being thrown away, and you quickly avert your gaze, as if you don’t want to see them. It’s never directly said or explained, but I think the implication is clear.</p>

<p>In the end, Greg has had enough. Everything that’s going on here is too much. He cannot be a party to this. After he finished Miasma Tower and UFO50, no matter what happens, he’s done. You end the game by taking the Nemuru’s chopper and flying away into the sunset. I don’t think Greg LITERALLY stole their chopper, I think it’s just a metaphor. He’s moving on to different pastures.</p>

<p>And that’s Miasma Tower.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 31</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/21/OOCY31.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 31" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/21/OOCY31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/21/OOCY31.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XRTeqZ1.png" alt="&quot;Sh-she's not straight...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Night Owls and Summer Skies</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Night Owls and Summer Skies" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 50 - Cyber Owls</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-50.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 50 - Cyber Owls" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50#50</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-50.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pw6QMPV.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And now we finally reach the end. The final game, Cyber Owls, released July of 1989. The 50th game that UFOSoft released, and as far as we’re aware, the final one. Cyber Owls is the biggest and most ambitious game to date. The brainchild of Tao Nemuru’s son, Winston Nemuru, who had a GREAT idea. It’s the late 80s, and you know what’s popular? Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles! Or things similar to that, at least. So why not make a game with its own tie in comic book, and create a MULTIMEDIA FRANCHISE?! Cyber Owls is goin’ UP UP UP, BABY, WE’RE GOIN’ PLACES!</p>

<p>It’s been a while since I mentioned it, but this pack is clearly inspired by a lot of sources, and one of those sources is Action 52. And alarm bells might be ringing for some of you, because this is EXACTLY what happened in Action 52. The CEO of the company was SURE that his idea of a super hero team of Cheetahs was going to take the world by storm, so the game was almost less a collection of games, and more a pilot for his Cheetahmen series. That’s what Cyber Owls stinks of. But it’s also just EXTREMELY, PAINFULLY of its time, in a way almost no other game here is. It SCREAMS TMNT. And Battletoads. And all those things from that era. It’s a team of quipping owls fighting pun-filled animal enemies. They have a favorite food, dim sum. They have a little mascot owl that acts as their mission control. It is EXTREMELY of its time. And while this kind of thing being popular might have been a reason for its creation, it’s not the only one. You see, Winston Nemuru was either dating, or was interested in, a girl at this time. And her son liked owls. That’s the actual reason this game exists. It’s a rich man’s vanity project, in an attempt to get a girl to like him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OQhW9mB.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But with ALL THAT BUILD UP, what is the game like? Cyber Owls is a multi-genre game, with what I’d describe as five games in one. You’ve got four owls, each with their own playstyles that you play twice throughout the adventure, and then a mini game you play if you game over, to try and save an owl. The plot is that the evil H.A.W.K. has a nuclear bomb, and you’ve got to find that bomb and stop them!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dlKpLVe.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Your first playstyle is Octavio, the dumb muscle of the group, who knows Kung-hoo. Yes. It’s THAT kind of world. Anyways, it’s a side scrolling brawler. You can punch and kick your way through waves of enemies in a side scrolling platformer level. Think a mega man, without the gun, ESPECIALLY later on where there’s a quick man level. You can charge up a punch to let loose a powerul blast that sends you forward, often into pits. I liked this gameplay style at first but it REALLY wore on me after a while.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JvfdjFD.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Next is an over the shoulder gallery shooter with Engle. Something like a Dynamite Duke. This is probably the best gameplay style, but it’s very on the nose. It’s exactly what those games are, and it’s VERY short compared to the others. Guin’s levels take like 20 minutes, this one will take you two and a half. Also at the end you find Mani-yak and Psy-cow. Because of course you do.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HMWPCbo.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Next comes Huxley, who rides a hover bike and blasts away enemies on the mean Hong Kong streets. It’s like a shmup, or like the Battle Toads Turbo Tunnel with a gun. Your bike is VERY large though, so it’s a lot smaller in scope. It’s alright, prolly my second favorite style, but just okay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0wIlm0m.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Finally there’s Guin, the leader of the group. Of course a girl is the leader, this was made to impress a woman, remember? Guin is a smart hacker spy lady, and her gameplay style is shitty metal gear. This was immediately my least favorite style, and it still is. It’s… FINE, but there’s NO nuance like in Metal Gear. The guards are dumb as fucking bricks, and basically just have laser vision that you shouldn’t trip. If you leave a room and come back they INSTANTLY forget about you. And it’s just a giant fucking maze that’s really annoying to navigate and learn. And it’s so slow paced compared to the other levels, as I said, your first time, this will take your 20-30 minutes, and the next Guin level is like 30-40 minutes. All the other styles will take you at MAX 5 minutes to beat. Hope you like shitty metal gear.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8gxG5pX.png" alt="Owls" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The final gameplay style will only happen if you game over. You can save an owl in a turn based roguelike-esque puzzle. I hate these stages, I never understood them, and I still don’t. They aren’t explained, they’re very annoying, and not very fun. Frankly, just don’t game over. Just reset if you do.</p>

<p>In conclusion, Cyber Owls is a land of contrasts. 3/5ths of the game is at least okay, 1/5ths is actually GOOD, and 2/5ths is annoying and unfun. And I didn’t even mention the cherry requirement. Beat it without dying, a single time. This game drove me fucking batty. Or Owly, I guess. This was my final cherry, and it took me HOURS to do. I basically had to speedrun Cyber Owls, and I will never forgive the game for that. Something ELSE I will never forgive this game for is the implication that it helped kill the company. A beautiful company with an amazing backlog, creative and skilled developers, killed by a vanity project to get a nepo baby’s dick wet. I will never, EVER forgive Cyber Owls.</p>

<p>Also, you know how they stopped crediting anyone but Spinzer and the Nemurus by their actual names? Well this game finally credits someone else by name!! …The girl Winston Nemuru likes, and her son. They get mentioned in the credits. But none of the people who actually made the game. Fuck this.</p>

<p>4/10</p>

<p>Well, that’s it. That’s all the games in UFO 50.</p>

<p>…or is it?</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 49 - Campanella 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-49.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 49 - Campanella 3" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50#49</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-49.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ncjnQqA.png" alt="UFO3" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Way back in the Campanella 2 review, I brought up the “NES 2nd game black sheep” syndrome. I think in this universe, it’s actually the third game that fits that, because I can totally see alternate universe nerds playing this game and going “yes it’s good, but it’s such a departure from the rest of the series that it’s a bit of a black sheep”. Campanella 3 is the only game in the series that does not use the original game’s engine or gameplay style. While the other games were about navigating treacherous areas carefully, there’s no walls to avoid here, it’s empty space. While the other games had you use a slash attack to hit enemies, the Campanella has a gun here. It’s a VERY different beast.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u8RO11C.png" alt="UFO3" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Campanella 3 can best be compared to onrails shooters of the late 80s, games that are trying to push the limits of 2D and go for a 3D look. Games like Space Harrier. And I love those games, but I may love Campanella 3 even more than them. This game plays so well. You’ve got a small playfield, which you can better position yourself in thanks to the orange borders that pop up as you get near. It LOOKS like a bit open space, but it’s eally a 6x4 grid, and as long as you shoot in that grid, you hit the enemy that’s in that spot in the foreground. You also have a side blaster, for when enemies get too close and enter the foreground. Fly around and blast the enemies. That’s it. It’s simple, but it’s fun as hell, especialyl as new enemies and patterns emerge. The game is the same every time, and quite a challenge, but very learnable. At the end of every wave of enemies, you are graded by the percentage you shot down. If you get a 100 you get a cute cat, probably the office cat, Lancelot. I tried getting a picture, but couldn’t get it in time ): You’ll have to get a 100% yourself.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w0sRuLT.png" alt="UFO3" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There aren’t many stages, just five of them, I think. It’s not a long and complex game, but what’s here will keep you very entertained. This is my personal favorite Campanella game. I know. The other two are very good and fun, but this fits my interests and tastes just a tiiiiny bit more. But it’s so hard to compare them. This could have EASILY been its own thing.</p>

<p>Perhaps the msot jarring thing about Campanella 3 is the ending, though. They just… left it at that? I assume they were going to continue the story with some twist in Campanella 4, but holy moly.</p>

<p>Also important to note, this game is ITS OWN UFO 50. Games within games, it’s the way of the future. Using the 2nd controller, you can play little mini games on the mini screen there. It’s a little unneccesary, and they’re very simple micro games, but it’s wild that they decided to include it. You can thank Thorson Petter for that, who at this point in UFO Soft, after having worked there for 7 years, as getting a little neurotic and overworked. He was the Artist, and this is a very Artist thing, but uh, didn’t you maybe go overboard by building FIFTY mini games for this one game, Petter?</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 48 - Seaside Drive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-48.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 48 - Seaside Drive" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50#48</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-48.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p16HxQn.png" alt="Seaside" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Seaside Drive is the brainchild of long-time artist Shayn North, and his only time in the director’s chair. Thanks to his influence, Seaside Drive is a breath of fresh air, with unique art and style that makes it once of the best games in the collection.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sPPmDNB.png" alt="Seaside" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Seaside drive is my personal favorite shmup in the collection, and it’s not even really close. While Star Waspir was top down, like 1942 or something, and Caramel Caramel was clearly a Gradius game, this is a side scrolling land-based shmup, akin to something like Heavy Weapon. You play as a cool dude in a car, equipped with little but a submachine gun. This gun has a power meter, which is only increased by letting your car skid backwards. Enemies come from above, and from the side, where you can use your secondary fire to shoot side bullets.</p>

<p>The graphics are pretty and vibrant. The music is wonderful. The levels are the exact same, but ENTIRELY different, as unique new enemy patterns come and go. It’s not too long, and maybe a little too short. It certainly doesn’t overstay its welcome. Inbetween each of the levels there’s a bonus stage, which is just breakout, which is pretty cool. The action is fast and intense, you always gotta focus to swerve and dodge enemy fire.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6jT0swy.png" alt="Seaside" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I do kind of wish there were three buttons on this controller, so you could lock your gun’s direction. There were several times where I wanted to swerve to dodge and still shoot at enemies coming at me. But you just gotta not put yourself in those situations. Seaside drive is an utterly fantastic game, and while simple, it shows not every new game in 1989 has to be a Mini &amp; Max or a Combatants, some big budget high concept adventure. They can be just a good god damn game.</p>

<p>9.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 47 - Quibble Race</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-47.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 47 - Quibble Race" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50#47</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/21/UFO50-47.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xUMykF4.png" alt="Quibble" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I got a surprising amount to say about this game, which is funny, cause it’s not what I’d expect.</p>

<p>To start, this is a remake of an ancient game from 2004 that is still up on Newgrounds, and you can play it now. It hasn’t changed very much in the past 20 years.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sAr3WnM.png" alt="Quibble" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Quibble Race is a horse racing simulator, with some REALLY dark twists. You bet on Quibbles, using their previous wins and losses as information about their stats, and then let ‘em rip. Quibbles have speed stats, and clumsiness stats. If they’re too clumsy, they’ll trip all the time, which is DEVESTATING. It’s not JUST horse races though, as you have several buttons at your disposal between each race.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/240ikcc.png" alt="Quibble" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got the Infobot, which can tell you the stats of one quibble a day for a fee, very useful. You’ve got the loan shark, which I didn’t use once. You’ve got the ability to sponsor a Quibble, where you’ll make money each time they win. You’ve also got the ability to train those quibbles, which can be useful, but Quibbles retire randomly, so your hard work might not pay off. And then you have the back alley.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Thubiih.png" alt="Quibble" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This cute guy can directly interact with races. You can dope quibbles, place trash in their path, injur them, make them go WILD, just wanting to constantly attack other quibbles, poison to straight up fucking kill them, or protect a quibble, in which case all other effects are stopped, and if another person is trying to effect that Quibble, they’ll face a fine. This ALSO blocks positive effects, like doping, so two betters trying to help the same quibble can cancel each other out. It can be very useful to defend though, because nothing is worse than you betting on a long shot Quibble, doping it up, and having it near the end only to watch it fucking die in front of you, alongside all your winnings.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fJEfGoR.png" alt="Quibble" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I should also note that this game fits nicely into the greater UFOSoft canon. You’ve got a lot of playable characters. Pilot, of course. Alpha makes her return. You’ve also got the alien from Onion Delivery, Brazz from Hyper Contendor, and this girl, Val. Val is a character from a cancelled UFO Soft cyberpunk RPG. Ah, what could have been.</p>

<p>Quibble Race is really just a horse racing sim at its core. You have a number of rounds, and you bet money in each of those. Whoever has the most at the end wins. It’s that simple. It’s good for what it is, but like… I’ll be real. I don’t give a shit about horse racing. At all. It’s not interesting, and it’s not very fun. But the game is still GOOD, it accomplishes what it wants to. I just dunno why it would ever strive to be that. It was alright to power through a victory once, but I’d never want to go back to it.</p>

<p>Also, some quick lore at the end. From this point on, something… troubling starts happening in the credits. For the final four games, no one is credited, except for the Nemurus, and Spinzer. Every designer, developer, coder, artist, musician, they are only given initials. We know who they are, because we know their names, but they aren’t credited. This is a very real unfortunate thing that happened, trying to stop people from having credits so that they wouldn’t be poached. It’s disgusting behavior, and it did not sit well with the people actually making these games. But don’t worry, Ian Spinzer, the guy who’s only job is to yell at the workers, is still credited! This shit sucks.</p>

<p>6/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 46 - Combatants</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-46.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 46 - Combatants" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50#46</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-46.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pr3rR0q.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Ahhh, this is one of the big ones, and a perfect game to usher us into the End Times. Often times when people play this game on a stream or something, conversations happen about the quality. What’s your favorite game? Your least favorite? There’s a lot of answers for favorite, but for least favorite, there’s usually only three. This one is the most common of those. Combatants is almost universally considered the worst game in the entire pack. And there’s GOOD reason to assume it’s bad on purpose. Let’s talk about it.</p>

<p>It is 1989, the final year, and while up until this point, Tao Nemuru has been funding the games as producer and not much else, this time he’s taking a more direct approach. Mr. Nemuru had a vision for a game, and he wanted it realized, and using his little army of game devs, his little army of ants, he had it created.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pevx3mJ.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Combatants is a top down strategy war simulation game with some RTS elements. You play as the blue ants, who are fighting back against the red ant menace. Red ants are more dangerous, stronger, more numerous. So the odds are not with you. AT ALL. But you have to fight back! You control a little soldier ant, and you can issue commands to nearby ants. You can tell them to stay, follow, or follow their instincts (let the AI take over). You can also order the queen to make workers or soldiers. Soldiers can shoot bullets, but take 2x the food. The AI will always go and collect food, unless it sees an enemy ant, then it will go and attack that ant. When there’s no more food they’ll just beeline straight for the enemy queen to kill it. Once all enemy ants are down, that’s level done, onto the next level.</p>

<p>There’s a few problems. Well #1, the game is slow as shit. It’s awkward, and all the ants move in a weird stilty way. This is bad, but also good, as I’ll explain later. #2 problem: The AI is dumb as shit, and the game is weighted in a way to take advantage of that, against you. Look at that level up there. The blocks are aligned in such a way that often, your workers, if they’re set to going by themselves, will just get stuck on the rocks and not get to the food, because the AI is fucking dumb as shit. And then there’s problem #3: The game is weighted against you in every other possible way. Again, look at the image. Notice the rocks block you, but not the enemy. Notice the enemy has more food on their side. Notice they start with more units. And if that’s not enough, a red ant is literally 2x as strong as a blue ant. For every red ant death, you need to sacrifice 2 blue ants. When an ant meets another, they will scrum like it’s For the Frog the Bell Tolls, and then come out of it weakened or dead.</p>

<p>This game is intentionally unfair. It is built in a way to be frustratingly unfair. There are hard games in this pack, sure, but none weighted this heavily against you. But the problem is, it has to be. Because the AI is so fucking stupid, that if it WEREN’T weighted against you, you’d win instantly, cause you’re not the AI.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jq2AHYH.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If you try and play this game as intended, it is an exercise in frustration. You don’t want to play this game how it wants you to play it. Instead, you need to make your own rules, your own strategies. You need to cheese the fuck out of it.</p>

<p>There are a few cheese strategies that work. You can set up soldiers behind your queen and use her as a meat shield, dragging enemy workers who are holding food to her, where the soldiers hiding in her folds can then snipe them, and boom, free food for more soldiers. You can cheese enemy soldiers, because their AI is terrible, and once they start shooting at something in their range, as long as it stays in their range, they will never turn. You can dodge a shot to the side, then just walk around them and shoot them in the ass, they won’t stop you. You can get enough soldiers to make a Murder Ball and have them clump up and follow you, creating a machine gun of ant murder. And of course there’s the spiders.</p>

<p>I did not find this game very fun, EXCEPT for the spider. The most fun I had in this game was domesticating these things for Ant Murder. You can go to a spider, and it’ll slowly (very VERY slowly, cause everything in this game is slow as fuck) follow you. You can then lead it to the enemy encampment and let it go to town, devouring every enemy spider in its wake. It can eventually be killed, but it can do a LOT of damage as you go off to work on other projects, like other enemy queens, cause very often this game has 2 or 3 enemy queens to your 1.</p>

<p>Is Combatants intentionally bad? I don’t think so. I do know it was very smartly created, they didn’t accidentally make it this way. If the AI was good and it moves fast it’d be impossible to play. So they made it like this, cause it’s the easiest way to handle it. Combatants is problably the worst game in the collection based on quality, but it is certainly not my least favorite. But I’m scoring based on actual quality, so sadly…</p>

<p>3/10</p>

<p>Also work noting, the credits do something weird here. No one is credited by their actual job. Nemuru is the head, Spinzer is the thorax, everyone else is the body. Y’know, the people who actually did the work. Hmm.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ac9bIZY.png" alt="Combatants" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Tao Nemuru loves his bugs :)</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 45 - Mini &amp;amp; Max</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-45.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 45 - Mini &amp;amp; Max" /><published>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50#45</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/20/UFO50-45.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MdFA1qY.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Here it is. One of the big ones. When people talk about this game, it’s usually listed as their favorite. It WAS my favorite, but it’s fallen a bit. Still top 10 for sure. I’ll talk about my reasons why later. But yeah, this is a very VERY beloved game. Let’s find out why.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pmqsCrM.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Taking place in the Partyverse, Amy the Party Girl is throwing yet another party, but she has to watch her kid sister. So she just locks her in the closet instead, alongside her talking pet dog, Max. The two sit there bored for a while, after Mini throws a mirror at the door in frustration. They just need SOMETHING to entertain them. Max suggests that they just become small. Mini is like “We can do that?” and Max is like “well I’ve never tried, but we could explore this whole room as small for a new perspective. Lemme try!” and then he becomes smol. Mini follows suit, and the adventure begins.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tdlzdhV.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mini and Max is a platforming game, kind of like a Mario 2 in some ways. You can run around, picking up and throwing objects and enemies as your primary attack. you hold down to shrink, and up to regrow. There’s not much to do in the room, but it can be used as a kind of level select, as you can grow big and stand near where you wanna go, then shrink again. There’s a BIG WIDE room to explore while tiny, and you are QUITE tiny. But that’s not all… early in the game, you meet someone who can teach you how to get EVEN SMALLER. This is where I slapped my forhead and went “Holy shit HOW BIG IS THIS GAME?!”</p>

<p>It’s big.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jx3Cbr4.png" alt="M&amp;M" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got the upper room, a big wide room while small, all one big level, and then microscopic worlds you can explore. These worlds are a lot more procedurally generated, though apparently it’s the same every time, it’s less polished and specific than the other areas, though there are PLENTY of things to find. Villages of chlorophyte people, little mushroom men called Mol Dolks (another reference to Night Manor, neat!), lamp people who worship the lamp. And like I said, the middle level ain’t no slouch either. It’s filled with bugs waging war on each other and a bunch of toys and things.</p>

<p>The main conceit of the game is that, a while ago, shinies fell to the mini’s world. Little shards shaped like stars, they’re so pretty and shiny, and now capitalism has infested the entire tiny world. Wars are fought and people die for these shinies, and it’s all shown as a Pretty Bad Thing. I wonder what was going on in the dev’s minds as they made this, huh. Money corrupts, don’t it? :) Anyways, that’s all fun and good, but the goal of the game is literally to get shinies. You can explore and find power ups and find fun settings, but the #1 thing you’re doing is getting shinies. There’s no real dungeons, per-se, no major powerups you need to complete major areas. They can HELP, for sure, but you can beat the game kinda bare bones, actually. Just… get the shinies, give them to the king, and he’ll open the door for you. Boom, that’s the game.</p>

<p>Some might view that as reductive, and it kinda is. There’s a LOT to discover and explore, and that’s the main fun of the game. There’s a bunch of things to do to GET those shinies. But once I realized it was JUST shiny hunting I ended up having a “is that it” moment. I feel this concept could have been refined to something really cool, and while what’s here is cool, I can’t help but have that “what could have been” moment. But I seriously am just splitting hairs. Mini and Max is a FANTASTIC game, and honestly worth the 25 dollar admission all by itself. It’s my #6 favorite game, after all. There’s a reason people love it. It’s creative, cute, filled with a bunch of references to earlier games, and the PERFECT late era UFOSoft game to show they weren’t losing their touch yet!</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I view this as the beginning of the end for UFOSoft. Things are starting to get… bleak around the office, and the golden days are over. With one last beautiful swan song, we now enter the Closing Era of UFOSoft. The final five games.</p>

<p>9.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>