<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-10T23:22:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episodes 1 - 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episodes 1 - 5" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekSNW3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekSNW3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Hegemony Part 2</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEvb4AL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Following directly after last season, the Enterprise is surrounded by Gorn, and some of their people are captured on the Gorn ship. The Enterprise is forced to retreat… but not before tagging the Gorn ship with a dud missile that’s actually a secret beacon.</p>

<p>Pike’s girlfriend, Batel, is infected with Gorn Babies and they might need to kill her, but to prolong things, they’re freezing her in a block of ice. Specifically SHE’S the one asking them to kill her if they need to. Well, at least that’s the PLAN, but turns out she’s allergic to being stuck in a block of ice, which I imagine I’d be too. Now Nurse Chapel is stuck trying to figure out how to cure Being A Gorn Mom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vvOBev.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Admiral April is like “we have to just ignore all this and let the Gorn capture neutral people” and Pike, being Pike, says fuck that shit, we’re being treated as Prey. And April agrees, unofficially, their rules are to punch the Gorn in the nose and show they’re not prey. Meanwhile, in Engineering, Scotty and Pelia the Warpcore Witch are trying to get a Gorn Cloaking Device up. Scotty says it’s impossible. Pelia is like “we’ll have it done in an hour sir”. Scotty is, one day, gonna be REAL good at doing the impossible on a deadline, and he’s gotta figure out how to get good at it real fucking fast.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Gorn ship, La’an wakes up and punches her way out of a Gorn sack. She rescues the other members of the crew captures, including Sam Kirk (Kirk’s brother), Doctor M’Benga, and Ortegas (who has had half her hand melted off). They want to get out… well, three of them do. La’an decides then and there, she’s going to save ALL the other colonists. Good luck.</p>

<p>Y’all remember Mitchell? She was a very minor background character in season 1, had some minor roles in 2, and now she’s on the bridge and refuses to leave until they can solve this. Yay, Mitchell!</p>

<p>They have some SMALL hope. Batel has a 14% chance of survival if they use Una’s blood. Yay! Also the Gorn seem to go to sleep when a certain kind of star flare happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jFp5msI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FkBzvR4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shit is going way, WAY worse. Man this is tense. While exploring a weird binary star that seems to hide the Gorn homeworld because of radiation, they find a BUNCH of Gorn ships blasting out of the zone and going towards Federation space. Now Pike has a choice. He might lose the tag on the colonists and his crew if he leaves to warn Starfleet, but they are NOT prepared for an invasion. So he makes the impossible choice and leaves them.</p>

<p>Pike seems so fucking done. He’s EXHAUSTED, he’s worrying about every single little thing. And can you blame him? When he goes to Scotty and Pelia like “Hey can we make a solar flare” and Scotty is like “what the fuck no. Not without doing this this that and this which will blow up the ship” Pike is like “Sure just do it without the blowing up the ship part” and everyone just… stares at each other.</p>

<p>There’s a lot of “have faith” talk in this episode, which we keep making fun of by posting Star Wars memes. It doesn’t help when Ortegas takes over a Gorn ship and flies them out in a scene that is VERY Star Warsy. Also Ortegas becomes massively injured in the skirmish, but sticks too it. Poor Ortegas, she can’t catch a break ):</p>

<p>We get a fuzzy fisheye scene with them in the radiation, but it works. They use the flare to trigger a hibernation in the Gorn, as they come back to go eep. Ortegas raises her deathflag REALLY high but is saved just before dying, thank fucking God. <em>sees death flag in Ortegas’ mouth</em> WHAT DO YOU HAVE THERE? PUT THAT DOWN.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/evmRMxM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Batel is saved, Spock and Chapel have a moment of acceptance, and the Enterprise is beat to fuck. But alive. It ends the “have faith” talk with Pike thanking God for some reason.</p>

<p>I thought it was alright! Not blowing me away, but good! Excited for more.</p>

<p>I’ll be editing this page every week and reposting it with the new episodes as they come out =w=</p>

<p><strong>Wedding Bell Blues</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9FnKzZH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s 3 months after the nightmare of the last two episodes, and the Enterprise is repaired and ready! Everyone is going to a gala to try and relax! I’m sure this’ll go exactly as expected! To try and get into the spirit, and to practice for getting things going well with Nurse Chapel, Spock is practicing dancing with La’an.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Yol3Cdf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>BUT NOT A BRAIN! :D</p>

<p>Anyways, Chapel comes on board with the doctor she’s been working with for three months, Roger Korby. He’s a very friendly guy, but a bit eccentric. Anyways Spock almost makes an ass out of himself before we find out Korby is, in fact, dating Chapel now. Whoops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AkPLZfu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy HELL, Uhura’s outfit is on point.</p>

<p>Ortegas is doing better. Physically, at least. We meet her brother, who is flirting a bit with Uhura, who seems reticent. Ortegas isn’t into it, though.</p>

<p>Everyone gets together to drink a bit. Spock is, as usual, awkward. He steps away for a drink at the bar, and we get this like, weird Mxptlk mother fucker who’s tending bar. He appears as a Vulcan to Spock, but to us, he’s a weird mother fucker. He gives Spock a drink, who…  wakes up later that night next to Chapel. They’re getting married! Oh boy! I’m sure Chapel will handle this very well!</p>

<p>This Mxptlk ass dude is basically acting as wedding planner and getting everything all right and dandy. Is he a… shipper? Of Nurse and Spock?? I will say, over all, I haven’t really… been into the Chapel and Spock thing? It’s not JUST cause I know it won’t go anywhere, but also cause of how they just… don’t go together lmfao which I think this episode is doing its best to try and show.</p>

<p>Korby is the ONLY person who seems to realize something is wrong. He can remember things how they SHOULD be, and is trying to subtly sabatoge the wedding. Spock catches him, and he explains that this is all wrong. Spock punches him out, but then for some reason remembers that yes, this IS wrong, and… well yes, feels bad, but most importantly is like “this needs to be fixed”. He and Korby work together, they’re both smart science boys, and though they love the same woman, they have to work together to figure out what’s wrong.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3XmlT3E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s kinda fun to watch these two try and wander around a changed reality, testing at the waters and touching the boundaries to find where they are. Spock tries to get others to realize something is wrong. He tries to get Kirk to punch him. He insults his mustache. It doesn’t work.</p>

<p>When they confront the Wedding Planner about this, he reveals he’s a giant fucking baby and this is all a game to him, which they’ll have to play, or he will wipe everyone from existence. Welp. Korby and Spock change up their plan and yeah, the only thing they can possibly do now really, is try to go along with it. When Korby DOES act up, he’s turned into a dog, and no one else seems to care. They’re really just his puppets.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JsdWJEP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually Chapel snaps out of it too, thanks to Spock, and when the Wedding Planner announces everyone is going to die. But he’s interrupted by his… dad. Who is, in fact, played by John de Lancie. Hmm. The bartender is just a kid, and he’s made to clean up his toys. Everyone is like “WELL THAT WAS WEIRD” and then tries to celebrate the actual reason they’re there, the Cenntenial. La’an dances with Spock, who has no regrets. We have one of the three armed aliens from TAS, who joins the crew as their bartender, yay! Aaaaand Ortegas has a PTSD episode. Yay!</p>

<p><strong>Shuttle to Kenfori</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uMeF8wz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Somehow, the Gorn Tissue has returned. Patel is still sick cause of Gorn, but they think they have a way that can fix it. It takes a flower, but it can only be found in a no-fly zone that would cause a Klingon War if they went to it. So Pike does an off the books mission, setting himself up as the person who’d take the fall if it goes bad. Mbenga goes with him, cause y’know, it’s a medical thing. It’d be a good idea to bring a Klingon War Vet to this possible Klingon area~ And on the way they get a warning beacon of “GO BACK OR DIE”, which is weird to have on a planet where no one’s supposed to be there.</p>

<p>There are no life signs on the planet. It’s a jungle, but no animals, at all. And they find a corpse that probably died after the evacuation. Welp, it’s Aliens time or some shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vZ8WhBe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While going through an old building and gathering their flowers, a Klingon shuttle (the first in the series? At least that I’ve seen) comes and blows their ship up. Now they’re being hunted by some Klingons, oh boy! It’s two guys and a woman who appears to be in charge.</p>

<p>The Klingons get them, but then they’re attacked by… zombies. Just, straight up zombies. They eat a Klingon alive. Jesus CHRIST. I dunno if we’ve ever seen ANYTHING like this in Trek? It’s now a fucking zombie horror movie. By the way, this planet, Ken Fori, is named after Ken Foree, the lead actor in Day of the Dead.</p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, they plan how to rescue their crew. Still radio silence, they dunno what happened, they just haven’t heard anything from the ground team, so they go after them with a very slow, but safe tactic. Ortegas is VERY unhappy about this and pretty insubordinate. La’an is worried about her health, which we know isn’t doing very well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XiJNsUb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So this flower causes genomes to like, fuse, basically. Hybridize people into different things. They tried to use it on a moss that could grow anywhere to make a super food. It accidentally hybridized with corpses and now there are zombies. Mbenga refuses to call them Zombies. Pike keeps using the “Z” word. And now that he knows what the Chimera Flower does, he knows that it’ll turn her into a Gorn hybrid. He is NOT happy about this, but it was her decision, and is the only way anyone knows to save her.</p>

<p>They get chased by more Zombies, and find themselves with the Klingon girl behind a force field. She stabs Pike, and we find out that she’s the daugher of Dak’Rah. Remember him? He was the dude from last season who was a straight up war criminal who was trying to act like he had changed, and was killed by M’Benga in a scene where it’s not clear exactly what happened, if it was self defense or not. Now it’s coming back to bite him. She hated him so it’s no problem there, but she’s sure that if SHE had killed him, she would have brought honor back to her house, and now she has to kill his assassin. And M’Benga admits that he intentionally killed Dak’Rah, it was NOT self defense.</p>

<p>We get PTSD War Hero M’Benga again.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8tXJNvH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a fight scene between M’Benga and this Klingon, fighting with D’ktaghs. In the fight, they damage the force field generator, which is probably not good. M’Benga then wins the fight and chooses not to kill her, which is maybe the rudest thing you can do to a Klingon. So she chooses an honorable death by sacrificing herself. No one will know, but she will. And so with M’Benga, who respects the choice.</p>

<p>Some good flying by Ortegas gets them to save the away team, though Una is VERY unhappy with how Ortegas has been acting. And now Pike has to decide whether or not to turn M’Benga for doing a murder. But luckily, M’Benga only told a story to save Pike’s life when there was a knife to his throat, so, y’know, checks out.</p>

<p>Uh oh. Ortegas intentionally did a bad job so they’d do her idea instead. It was unneccesary, because Pike and M’Benga were going to get on a shuttle anyway and would be safe, and she endangered everyone. So she gets a slap on a wrist, but a “please do not EVER do this again”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5tW9bd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel and Pike have a heart to heart about it. He’s like “why didn’t you tell me?” “Because it wasn’t about you, and we both know if I did tell you, you’d tell me not to do it and find another way even though there is no other way”. Which y’know, he did. On the planet. So she’s right. And then it just… ends. I guess we’ll find out next week how it goes!</p>

<p>This one was uh… fine. I dunno how much we needed zombies in Star Trek but that’s fine. Fun Klingon fight!</p>

<p><strong>A Space Adventure Hour</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/62SIAKV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ohhhh no, those outfits. Holy SHIT, La’an is on point.</p>

<p>So, I’ve not been enjoying this season as much so far. But I’ll stick with it, maybe it’ll get better! Anyways this episode starts with one of the best scenes I’ve ever seen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P7kebx2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Kirk’s actor, Chapel’s actress, and Ortegas’ actress doing some… kind of thing here. It’s obviously a pastiche of TOS. Though I WISH TOS looked and acted like this. It’s got a lot of really like, Dr. Who style models and special effects, and it feels more like an adventure serial of like, the 40s. But Kirk’s actor is here doing an EXTREMELY good Shatner impersonation. The intro is for this Space Adventure show, and it’s great.</p>

<p>Anyways back to actual Star Trek. The Federation is developing a new kind of technology. It’s for entertainment on long-term space exploration voyages. It’s called The Holodeck. THIS MEANS THIS IS THE CANONICAL FIRST HOLODECK GOES WRONG EPISODE? YAY! Pike gives testing to La’an and tells her to push it as HARD as she can.</p>

<p>We get more La’an and Spock dancing, as Spock seems to be continuing dance training. He’s ABSOLUTELY, CLEARLY making moves on her. I was not expecting Spock to be the horndog of SNW? I don’t HATE the idea, though this is maybe better. La’an is one of the characters we don’t know what happens to after this, clearly Chapel and Spock aren’t dating in TOS era, soooo, this works better.</p>

<p>La’an decides to give the computer a challenge. She really loves detective novels, and asks it to…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iXIxKLc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>LA’AN, NO! THIS IS HOW WE GET MORIARITIES!!!</p>

<p>You KNOW they did this on purpose to get this reaction. We’ve been here before!! This is a good style of “We’ve been here before” though. It’s not retreading it in a boring way, but it’s an exciting idea we’ve had before that lights up your day.</p>

<p>We get a murder mystery story with La’an investigating the murder of a TV executive. The show he was in charge of was getting cancelled and someone in the room murdered him, so she has to go through all the suspects. Everyone is played by Trek actors, because canonically the best source of high def recordings they have are transporter buffer scans, so they go with those. The show was, of course, the shitty Trek pastiche from earlier. We watch as La’an solves the case (it’s Una, who’s the exec’s ex-wife) but the game changes the rules and ups the difficulty, killing her basically. La’an decides she needs help to put this story to its end, and enlists Spock. Oh boy, pushing THAT ship still. Also all the acting here is top notch.</p>

<p>Meanwhile energy is fluctuating on the Enterprise and poor Scotty is running overtime to fix it.</p>

<p>There’s some themes in the investigation. Emotions and romance getting in the way of things. Huh, funny that. Anyways La’an is almost killed in a trap set by the murderer, aaand is actually injured. Whoops, the holodeck is malfunctioning! Who could see THAT coming?! :D Scotty is already on it, but it seems the only way to fix it is if La’an solves the case from the inside.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w6ry2wT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They give Uhura’s character a speech about how important Trek COULD be. It shows the lense of people’s lives through rubber masks and science fiction. It can inspired generations of kids! That’s wonderful that they gave this speech to her of all people.</p>

<p>The stakes are raised as the Enterprise is about to be destroyed by some radiation that’s coming their way, and they don’t have the energy to dodge it. Gotta solve stuff fast!</p>

<p>The solution to the murder mystery is actually a really fun twist. I won’t spoil it.</p>

<p>La’an’s assessment is that the Holodeck is NOT a good idea for starships to have installed on at this time. Scotty asks for a footnote to be added that maybe if they fix the energy problems. Pike wants it buried in a box in a basement somewhere. Then Una is like “Scotty why the FUCK didn’t you ask any of the rest of us to help you??? We could have died” and the answer is PTSD. Una’s job now is to try and wrangle PTSD addled kids on this fucking starship.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/860zCki.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get one last dance scene and Spock and La’an and they kiss, of course. This is the third woman Spock has made out with in three seasons. Down, boy.</p>

<p>But that’s less important than THIS:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xqdvmxK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>CHEESY TOS ERA BLOOPER REEL!</p>

<p>This episode was just loads of fun. Okay, good. We can still do stuff I absolutely love.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 198 - Final Fantasy III DS</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/10/RA198-FF3DS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 198 - Final Fantasy III DS" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/10/RA198-FF3DS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/10/RA198-FF3DS.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4hAVPl7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Last year I played Final Fantasy 3 for the first time ever. I also beat FF5, which is basically FF3-2, and LOVED it. I wanted to play more FF5, so I played it three fucking times for Four Job Fiesta. And even after ALL of that, I still kinda wanted to play more… so I pulled out FF3 for DS.</p>

<p>When I’m playing all these old games I try to go older to newer, and I usually go for the oldest version first. This means I usually don’t get to remakes. There’s too many games to play and I don’t replay games often. FF3, however, I loved so much, AND people were gushing about the remake as I played the NES version, so I was excited to play it. Funnily enough, as I played this version though, people’s tunes changed, and they were like “Oh, this version isn’t very good, it has too many flaws, it’s too difficult”.</p>

<p>Now, FF3 is the hardest Final Fantasy game I’ve ever played. And people were telling me that this was harder. I was surprised. How could it be? So I’ve now beaten it, and I can say, they were wrong. This is not harder.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6UBahEh.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There are a lot of changes between FF3 and FF3DS, but less than you’d expect. When they were remaking the first Final Fantasy games around this time, they mostly updated the graphics and mechanics, on the GBA. FF3 took longer to make though, because they apparently lost the source code and had to do it from the ground up. So it came to the DS, and direct remakes were less in vogue then. You needed to spice it up. PLUS it was 3D now, so they decided to take the time to completely redo the vibe and story… kinda. I was expecting more. These are now characters. In FF3, they were all just blank slates. They talked and existed as characters but they were blank slates to put your thoughts and characters into, really. Here, they are characters. One is a generic hero, his childhood friend who’s shy and sweet. An independent fiery blacksmith’s daughter, and finally a royal knight who joins them. But they still do and say basically the same things as the original game, so it doesn’t really add as much as you’d expect.</p>

<p>The best thing about it is that these character designs were made by the same artist who made Bravely Default, and I love the designs.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HjwktBG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You still meet the same characters, go on the same mini stories, and do the same dungeons. Even the dungeon and level design is pretty much the same. There were a COUPLE of rooms and floors that were changed, but it was shockingly accurate to the NES designs. Even some of the suspect stuff. The NES had dungeons that I was like “woah, this is fucked up and rude”, like the mini and frog dungeons, the Dark Dungeon, or the final Dungeon, the most fucked up final dungeon I’ve ever seen. None of that is toned down. It’s the same as it was in the NES verison. But I still think the game is easier, for a few reasons.</p>

<p>One, in the NES version, you could fight up to 9 enemies at once. Here, it’s 3. Their health is increased to account for this but it’s still easier to take on 3 tankier guys than 9 slightly weaker guys. Secondly, the numbers are just… a bit nicer. I didn’t have to grind as much to handle the Dark World. In the NES version I had to grind HARD, but here, nope. I could beat the game without much worries. Even the fucking Garuda fight, which again had an achievement where I had to do it without Dragoons, was SO much less of a problem in this version, and this version’s achievement was HARDER. In the NES achievement, it didn’t matter how many of my units died, but here they all had to be alive, AND not use any Dragoons. But I still found it easier, just cause the numbers were nicer.</p>

<p>There was just one problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V3GFYwy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Iron Giant is a bonus fight made for the DS version, and he is fucked up. I literally had to grind to level 99 to handle him, and it still took me like two tries. TBF, I also had to beat him with no one dying, but like, he’s REALLY tuned. But that’s a bonus boss in an RPG, like, they’re all overtuned, and I won’t hold that against the rest of the game.</p>

<p>Over all, I liked this version. The music is, for the most part, better. The story changes didn’t add as much as I’d hoped, and I think I prefer the NES graphics, but it certainly wasn’t ugly. It being on the DS added literally nothing, the touch screen basically did nothing. You COULD use it but why would you? All in all, it was another pleasant way to play a good game.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="DS" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 174</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/10/OOCY174.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 174" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/10/OOCY174</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/10/OOCY174.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Wu645az.png" alt="An excerpt from 'She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat'. Nomoto is thinking about Yako-san, who taught her well. A small head of Yako-san floats above her, explaining clearly, 'it's called consent.' 'Thank you, Yako-san...!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She Loves to Cook She Loves to Eat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 23 - 25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekVOY7-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 7 episodes 23 - 25" /><published>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekVOY7-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/08/10/LizstartrekVOY7-6.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5UJb0zM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is it. The final Voyager episodes. Let’s go.</p>

<p><strong>Homestead</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qEJhSzj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Neelix throwing a celebration on Voyager for First Contact Day. It’s cute, I love Neelix. I’m not ready for this episode. I already know where it’s going to go. The celebration is ended as Voyager scans life signs of Talaxians in a nearby asteroid field. Neelix, Tuvok, and Paris go out in the Delta Flyer to try and find the Talaxians. They’re attacked by an unknown force and crash land on the Talaxians’ asteroid.</p>

<p>Neelix awakes to a lady Talaxian who’s cagey. They don’t trust them. Neelix is isolated, and the Talaxian explains they’re pacifistic. They were hit by a mining explosion, by accident basically. The mining aliens actually contact voyager and go “yo be careful we’re mining. Oh, your people got hit? We’ll look for them, stay out for your safety.”</p>

<p>The Talaxians eventually let Neelix out, and explain they already let the other aliens out, who are fixing up the Delta Flyer. Neelix says if his friends aren’t welcome here, he doesn’t want to stay and chat, so he goes. He is sad, though. This is probably the last time he’ll ever see other Talaxians.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rRRX2Hc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We learn the miner aliens are just bullies who claimed these asteroids and are going to kill the Talaxians if they don’t leave. They don’t WANT to kill them but it’s nbd, tbh. Pretty awful. Neelix saves the kid of the woman he met from being taken by the miners cause he’s the only one with a gun. There’s some discontent among the Talaxians who feel like Neelix’s actions and “violence” will only escalate things but these guys literally said “we will kill you in 3 days if you do not leave. We don’t care that that’s impossible”. Neelix offers to help negotiate a treaty with these aliens.</p>

<p>Holy SHIT, THEY MENTION TUVIX. WHAT THE FUCK.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xc49qeK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Basically, if we want to help these Talaxians we either kick the can down the road and transport them, OR defend their asteroid now. Tuvok helps kick Neelix into gear. Those Talaxians need a leader to help them. Neelix is qualified. During his time on Voyager, he’s become far more than a simple cook, or a “wanna-be diplomat”, as he says. He’s so much more than that.</p>

<p>He goes to the Talaxians and leads them to build a shield perimiter, and puts his life on the line in his personal ship, the Baxial, which has just sat in Voyager for YEARS now, to distract fire from the Miners.</p>

<p>With Neelix and the miners working together, and help from the Delta Flyer, they do it.</p>

<p>Now Neelix has to make a difficult goodbye to the Talaxians, as he returns to Voyager. He spends a bit of time with Naomi, then finds Janeway alone in the mess hall. He has a lot on his mind… but she has an idea, and brings it up. Now that they have the ability to do two way communication from this distance… they need a Delta Quadrant ambassador, someone who can keep them abreast of the situation back here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SaxXn5w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix is promoted to Ambassador, and its time to say goodbye. He gets a salute and a farewell, and one last goodbye from his very good friend Tuvok, who does in fact dance for him, as Neelix said he always wanted to see. In public, no less. Live long, and prosper indeed. It’s a touching scene actually.</p>

<p>Goodbye, Neelix. Neelix gets a lot of shit and I make it no secret how much I like him. He’s a GREAT character, and it’s sad to see him go.</p>

<p><strong>Renaissance Man</strong> - VOY
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/INHv6MU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor and Janeway are going to a medical symposium together. He wakes up Janeway with his singing and then announces that holograms are superior to organics. He’s being kinda weird about it. It’s not like he’s ever acted like this before? It’d be like if out of nowhere, Data went “I am superior to organics, do not worry Captain, I am here to fix all your troubles because you cannot fix them yourself”. Okay dude.</p>

<p>Paris tries to make a romantic getaway with Torres. She actually appreciates it which is nice, but can’t have a date with him. Hope this B-plot is nice.</p>

<p>Janeway returns from the symposium and announces that a species called the R’Kaal are here, we’re violating their territory. Based on their laws, we need to eject the warpcore and give it to them and settle on a nearby planet. The captain agrees to this. Chakotay is like “what the fuck”. Janeway gets started on this, but is acting weird, and locks herself in the room. Chakotay asks the Doctor to scan her, but everything is fine. We also get this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PEKvPJr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay tries to tackle the situation and is knocked out and put in the morgue by… the Doctor. He is, in fact, playing the part of Janeway, and now Chakotay. Janeway’s actress was actually REALLY good at doing Doctor-isms and playing the part. Now we have to see Chakotay’s actor try to do that. Oh joy. Anyways we find out it’s actually the Hierarchy… or well, two ex-members of the Hierarchy. They actually left the Hierarchy, stealing a vessel and are trying to steal the warp core to sell it to a buyer.</p>

<p>The Doctor is trying to play a million sides of this. He has to take Torres’ identity too, and it becomes VERY obvious when Tom comes up to her offering more food, and she gets uppity about health. Okay, Torres’ actress is ALSO good at acting like the doctor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/onyX9hR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It obviously can’t last. Especially not with Tuvok on the job. The doctor now has to run through the ship and work double time to eject the warpcore, which he does, shutting down power and trying to escape. He manages to stop Tuvok and flies away in the Flyer, towing the warpcore.</p>

<p>Back with the Captain, the REAL Captain, she befriends one of the Hierarchy peoples. The Doctor delivers the cargo, and iiiis betrayed, of course. The leader is gonna adjust his program to make him do what he wants. Janeway is piiiiiissed at the Doctor. “Well, Voyager can survive without a warpcore, it can’t survive without a captain!” “NOW IT HAS NEITHER.” Damn.</p>

<p>Back on Voyager, they reactivate the ship and get… the doctor’s calling card, some music he played. But it’s edited slightly. It has the warp signature of the enemy ship. They go to rescue the Doctor and Janeway, just as they start destabalizing the Doctor. The nicer Hierarchy person betrays the meaner one and all is well…. well, no, it’s not. The doctor is still dying.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BnbYNvn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The doctor freaks out about dying and confesses to a bunch of not BAD, but petty shit, and then the problem is solves easily and instantly. Welp.</p>

<p>This episode was whatever. Just, fine. Neli described it as “trying to do Ferengi with no Ferengi”. Weird that this is the penultimate episode. The Neelix one felt much more penultimate.</p>

<p><strong>Endgame</strong> - VOY
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sxtUWkkf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is it. The final episode. It’s extra long. Let’s see how it holds up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WjBKmpI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We see Voyager flying over the Golden Gate bridge, triumphant, returning… we learn that it took them 23 years. So we can get 16 more seasons of Voyager?! :D Anyways, this is actually a recording. It’s been 10 years since then. So 40 years after they teleport away. Janeway is looking out her window, old as hell, hair gray.</p>

<p>Janeway throws a party, a yearly reunion. Janeway is now a vice-admiral, which worries me for how her brain is doing. Harry is a Captain, thank God, he’s FINALLY promoted. Tuvok can’t be there, he appears to be ill. Someone also seems to have died recently. Paris is a holonovel author. Torres is an ambassador to the Klingons. The Doctor got married, and named himself Joe. I love Paris’ reaction. “IT TOOK YOU 33 YEARS TO COME UP WITH JOE?!”</p>

<p>Janeway is also a guest lecturer in Barclay’s class he’s teaching on the Borg. She’s a good teacher, but she’s touchy on the subject of Seven of Nine… and also she seems to be working with Paris and Torres’ daughter on something…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t67b2Sc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’re jumping around a lot. There’s a lot to learn. Tuvok is doing some weird work, and appears to be mentally… not all there. Some kind of dementia. Janeway tells him she may be… going away, and won’t see him again. It’s a sad scene.</p>

<p>Janeway invites the Doctor over for a nice conversation, a physical, aaaaand also asking him to give her some fucking experimental drug. Where could she be going? It’s hush hush and only a few people are in the know. Apparently the second person in command of this mission is… Reg! Good ol’ Reg. He seems a lot more stable now, I’m proud of him. We get one last scene of Janeway talking to a gravestone. It’s Chakotay! He’s become the bones of our ancestors!</p>

<p>ANYWAYS back on Voyager, like 23 years ago, Belanna is giving birth! Oh false alarm. This happens a lot. Also…. guess who’s fucking dating Seven. Chakotay. Mother fucking Chakotay. Why? I’m tired of this already. We also get to see Neelix! He’s talking to Seven and playing Kadis-kot with her! Seven, for the record, denies that she’s dating Chakotay. She’s just going on dates with him. Well, Seven is canonically polyam, so</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8UfUHZy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’re jumping between the past and the future. Janeway is trying to get…. SOMETHING from some Klingons. Now they’re under attack by the Borg back in the past, and the Borg Queen is here again. It’s the first actress too, the one from First Contact. Oh boy. My favorite. The Borg are basically protecting some wormholes that could possibly send them home. Kim wants to sneak around them. Everyone is like “I’d rather not die, thank you.” Also, the doctor is going to actually turn off Seven’s emotion inhibitor. Man, this Chakotay x Seven stuff is going to really be important huh? Does ANYONE ship these two, other than Robert Beltran?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oAgKIbR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway fucking STEALS THE DEVICE, activates some sick-ass shielding on her shuttle. But then she’s stopped by Kim, who found out from the Doctor, who interrogated Reg, and knows what she’s doing. He’s like “are you NUTS?” Kim. You of all people have no damn right to lecture her on this shit. You remmeber the episode where in the future you did time travel crime to try and save Voyager???</p>

<p>So yes, she’s trying to do time travel crimes. Specifically to save her girlfriend, and also her emotional support cardboard cutout that she kisses sometimes. I’m just saying, there’s a reason Chakotay x Seven of Nine has 400 works on AO3, and Seven of Nine x Kathryn Janeway is literally 4 times more.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xl4vW1Y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Future!Janeway goes back to the past and announces she’s here to save them. The Borg Queen watches and tries desperately to be subtle. She fails at it. Past!Janeway, or just Janeway I guess, is really unhappy about everything. Seven walks in after scanning the Admiral’s ship, sees two Janeways at once, and her cortical node short circuits and she dies of an orgasm. Future!Janeway literally goes “Temporal Prime Directive Temporal Prime Shremective.”</p>

<p>The Borg Queen keeps being in this show, and I hate it. She announces that she knows the Admiral is here, and will assimilate them all if they try to enter her nebula. Meanwhile, Chakotay keeps being in this show, and I hate it. He’s being smarmy and showing favoritism to his girlfriend, showing why you should probably not date your superior officer.</p>

<p>Using the future armor, Voyager is being shot at by three different Borg cubes at the same time. They make it through, blowing up a cube, and find out that the wormholes in there is actually a transwarp hub. No wonder the Borg didn’t want them there. The Admiral demands they go through, Captain Janeway is piiiiiiiissed. Admiral Janeway explains “Three years from now, Seven is going to die.” This puts the wind out of her sails. Also Tuvok can be cured if they get home early. But mostly, her girlfriend will die. There’s some shit about her having a husband at the time, but that shit is dumb, and I’m choosing to ignore it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gr1zSK1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The crew doesn’t care. They believe in the Captain, and will go with her plan. What’s her plan? Blow up the Transwarp conduits, save a LOT of lives, and go home the slow way. They can wait. But both Janeways come up with a plan… A way to possibly have their cake and eat it too. Admiral Janeway goes to the Borg Queen and asks her drag Voyager home for her, since the Captain intends to hurt the Borg. So she’ll save the Borg, if the Queen helps her. They compromise and come to a deal. Or do they? Nope, the Queen betrays her and captures her instead, immediately assimilating her. RIP Admiral Janeway…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qTejxlS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Queen could have just been “Okay, whatever. Get Voyager out of my fucking quadrant, I am so sick of their shit”, but no, she has to be weirdly aggressive and violent for no reason, which is ALWAYS her downfall. She assimilated a virus alongside the Admiral.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qTejxlS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Borg Queen dies, like “Well if we kill Captain Janeway this will never come to pass :)” lol yeah okay, dude. That’s not how your time travel works, at all, but you’re too fucking stupid to know that. The system blows the hell up, killing them all.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a transwarp hole appears near Earth, and they rush to try and fight a Borg invasion. Voyager is chased by a Borg Sphere, but they basically blow it up from the INSIDE OUT, in front of the entirety of Starfleet, while ALSO having just blown up the Borg’s transwarp conduit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F6yoWnX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It ends with the Paris baby being born, and then Janeway announcing they’re home, and that’s uh, it.</p>

<p>Okay. That was an abrupt ending. I think this episode should have gone like, 5-10 more minutes. It should have shown them happy and celebrating, and ended with Janeway turning the lights off and walking off the empty bridge. We don’t get that, it’s just, BAM, sudden, done. It doesn’t even clean up all the plot threads this EPISODE opened up.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 173</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/08/OOCY173.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 173" /><published>2025-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/08/OOCY173</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/08/OOCY173.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hffSVU5.png" alt="A woman leans on another'Better hurry on back, 'cause I'll be waiting for you.' This proves to be the last straw, and the other woman's head goes POP." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Lying Bride’s Case for Same-Sex Marriage</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Lying Bride&apos;s Case for Same-Sex Marriage" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 197 - Angel Paradise Vol. 1 - Sakaki Yuko - Koi no Yokan in Hollywood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/07/RA197-AngelParadise.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 197 - Angel Paradise Vol. 1 - Sakaki Yuko - Koi no Yokan in Hollywood" /><published>2025-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/07/RA197-AngelParadise</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/07/RA197-AngelParadise.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bodAozZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So a while ago I played a smut game for the Saturn where you play rock paper scissors to see videos of women stripping. I expected this to be like that but it’s actually not, at all. I can’t find a lot of information on this. Shockingly, it and games like it are not very popular when you can just look up pictures of beautiful women easily these days, but here’s what I gather.</p>

<p>This game is a collection of videos and gifs of beautiful women doing things. You have two modes of play, depending on the level: you have a sliding puzzle, and you have a jigsaw puzzle. All the pieces to these puzzles are animated video, which makes it much harder to solve, but adds an interesting little dimensionality to a puzzle.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FEYoKz7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The sliding puzzle is kinda easy to understand so I’ll explain the jigsaw, because it is not. Honetly, I mastered this game and it still makes little sense to me. The concept is simple: you have the pieces on the right, you click and drag them where they belong. They have different shapes to help you narrow down where the piece could go.</p>

<p>When you place the piece, however, it seems to… weaken? The spots around it? And you can use this to kinda clear entire sections and lines. If you manage to do this properly, and in the correct spot, you’ll get a bonus item that unlocks a bonus video. You could also get bonus items that help you in puzzles, like stopping the image or giving you more time. I never found the puzzle so difficult that it’d take me more than two tries, though.</p>

<p>The thing that surprised me about this game is that it’s not very pervy. Like, at all. It’s listed as mature and I expected porn, but it’s not. It’s just videos of women… a woman? I can’t tell honestly cause I have face blindness, but I think it’s multiple women, doing random things. Riding a bike. Playing on a beach. Rollerskating. It’s much more innocent. I cannot find information on any women who are in this, so my guess is it’s idol shit? Idol culture is weirdly chaste at times.</p>

<p>Anyways, it’s a weird little curiosity, but not much more. There WAS a volume 2, which I played, but it’s ONLY the Jigsaw puzzles, no sliding puzzles. And honestly? I prefer the sliding puzzles. So I was uninterested.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="GBA" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 172</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/06/OOCY172.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 172" /><published>2025-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/06/OOCY172</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/06/OOCY172.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ya5PdqH.png" alt="'It took me some time to realize it.. but I also... love you romantically. I really do.' '..............' 'While we're at it... I think it's cute how you blush all the way to your forehead.' 'UUUUGH! Gee, thanks...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She Loves to Cook, She Loves to Eat</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She Loves To Cook She Loves To Eat" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 196 - Final Fantasy V Advance - Four Job Fiesta</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/06/RA196-4FJ.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 196 - Final Fantasy V Advance - Four Job Fiesta" /><published>2025-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/06/RA196-4FJ</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/06/RA196-4FJ.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UsLdYsX.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So last year, I beat Final Fantasy V for the first time. It’s one of my absolute favorite Final Fantasies, and I adored it. After I was done, I started having a desire to go back and play it again… but I knew I should wait. Because every year in June, an event goes on called Four Job Fiesta, and I’d want to get in on that.</p>

<p>See, in FF5, you unlock new classes, called Jobs, and you can swap your characters between these. The FJF is a kind of challenge run. You go on the website, and any time you unlock knew jobs, you roll to decide which of those you can use. Once you unlock 4 jobs, that’s it, those are all you can use. Those four.</p>

<p>There are a lot of modes of play, though for the RA set, I had to do three different kinds. Yes. Three different playthroughs of Final Fantasy 5, which I did, one after another, in a few days. And yes, I still kinda wanna play this game, writing this two months after. It’s just a really good game, okay?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zCFxaba.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>FJF turns Final Fantasy 5 from an RPG with a lot of tactical choices to a puzzle game. How can I tackle this obstacle with the tools I have available to me? Every job combo has the capacity to beat the game, it’s been tested. But you have to do some WILD tactics and strategies, especially if you get Berserker. Or god forbid you’re playing on a mode that allows doubles and you get MULTIPLE berserkers.</p>

<p>I played three different styles. I played Regular, Onion, and Meteor. In Regular, any time you get a new crystal, you roll for jobs from that crystal. So for example, the first crystal, Wind, gives you White Mage, Black Mage, Thief, Blue Mage, Knight, and Monk. You can ONLY use that job, so for the first little while, you have four of one class. For example, my first run, I got monk. So I had four monks until the next crystal, then I got any combination of Monk and Mystic Knight, but I HAD to use at least one of each class I have. So I could use three Mystic Knights and 1 Monk.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7S56Qpe.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The second style I played was Onion. This uses only jobs from Final Fantasy 3. And then finally, Meteor, where you can get ANY job at any point. So even with those wind crystal jobs, you could get like, Chemist, and have to just use Freelancer until you get to the next crystal. This DID happen to me, though luckily I got Summoner so that I only had to Freelance up through the Water Tower.</p>

<p>If you know anything about FJF, you’re looking at those classes I rolled for my three runs, and going “Holy SHIT. Your luck was incredible”. And it was! A Mystic Knight/Bard run, ANOTHER Bard run but also white White Mage and Black Mage, and finally a Chemist/Time Mage/Summoner run? Omega stood no chance.</p>

<p>The thing with FF5 is that a lot of jobs are broken as fuck. Just, in different ways. And you need to know a little about each of them to understand that. Like for example, Time Mage has access to a spell called Quick, which allows you to immediately do two more turns. However, due to a bug, poison damage still procs, so if you poison, then quick, you can sit there doing nothing for 20 minutes until Omega dies. I did that one for my last run~</p>

<p>The goal is to beat ExDeath and the two bonus bosses, Shinryu and Omega. Those last two are tough, trust me.</p>

<p>Each of these runs took me like…. 10-20 hours? So it was a LOT of FF5 in one week. But I’m already looking forward to next year, I think this will become a thing for me~ Though I might only do one run each year, going forward. RA edits this achievement set to add in a new ruleset every year, so I’ll probably do whatever that is when the time comes~</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="GBA" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 171</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/04/OOCY171.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 171" /><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/04/OOCY171</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/08/04/OOCY171.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mEvxKEn.png" alt="'Her girlfriend got stolen away.' 'Wassuuuuup! Can you see us? You were always going behind her back with other girls and making her cry, so we're giving her an extra special good time today!' 'Ahhh... I'm so sorry, Yuuki...' 'Your skin's so smooth~' 'WHAT THE HELL?! THAT'S SO FUCKING HOT! You're telling me I still get to watch this for free?!' 'But she's complete trash, so it was no problem.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Amazaki Suika</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Amazaki Suika Comic Collections" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 195 - Dragon Quest 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/04/RA195-DragonQuest5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 195 - Dragon Quest 5" /><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/04/RA195-DragonQuest5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/08/04/RA195-DragonQuest5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sHV0TKH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I finally played all of the Dragon Quest games on the NES. So it’s only fair I jump to the next console too, right? There’s plenty more Dragon Quest games to play.</p>

<p>This one never actually came out here. After Dragon Quest 4, or Dragon Warrior as it was called here, came out, the series went slightly dormant for a while in America. Frankly I’m stunned DQ4 came out here, but the prevailing idea was that as RPGs were becoming more and more popular in Japan, the American market was dead. So what was the point? This version has NEVER been released over here, so all we get is fan translations, but that’s okay. This actually got two re-releases. A PS2 remake, and then a DS remake, which we FINALLY did get. But enough about the background, how’s the game?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7Asm3gN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Dragon Quest 5 is considered one of, if not the best, games in the entire series. I think it’s… good! If I had to rank them for you, I’d put the series right now at 4 &gt; 3 &gt; 5 &gt; 1 &gt; 2. So, in the middle right now, but that doesn’t mean it’s bad. 3 and 4 are just fantastic. This game is better than all those in one particular standpoint: It’s story.</p>

<p>Dragon Quest 5 is about the life of a single guy. I called him Abel. Abel’s mom was stolen by demons as a kid, and his dad has basically been doing his best raising this son and also trying to find his wife. He’s also the king of a foreign country. Anyways, you play as Abel, starting as a young child, making friends, and throughout the game you go through like, 20-30 years of life.</p>

<p>The game doesn’t do an amazing job of showing this? Like, you leave your friend prince’s castle, take a boat, and go to another continent. You do one quest there, and go back, and your friend is like “damn, it’s been a few years! You’re lookin’ good, I got married! :D” and I’m like “it’s been 20 minutes”. There are time skips that are more visible, but that’s the general vibe you’re gonna get. Your wife gets pregnant and gives birth in a 15-30 minute dungeon.</p>

<p>Oh, yeah, your wife. This game has a Wife feature. You have two wives to pick from. One is your childhood friend you fought ghosts with, and have a connection with, and one is this random rich girl you met for 2 minutes who is clearly into someone else. So like, it’s not really that much of a choice.</p>

<p>Two other fun things about this story. 1: It’s a continuation of 4! You almost couldn’t tell, because the world map is so drastically different, but it’s the same world. One of the dungeons is the same thing, but falling apart from age, and the Dragon God is here. The other fun thing is that you are NOT the legendary hero. This world, as most DQ games do, has a Legendary Hero who is supposed to save the world from the coming darkness. That is NOT you. At no point do you overcome that like it’s some Wind Waker plot, no, it’s just not you. It’s your son instead :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Hg4p53y.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I do like the plot, it’s really good and makes you feel some things in a lot of moments. But I’m just not as into the world and dungeon design. DQ4 had a fun story with great characters, but it also was fun to play for me, with a big fun world and dungeons to explore, but this for some reason wasn’t quite as fun. I dunno. Maybe it was the mood I was in? Who knows.</p>

<p>Oh, it does have one other feature to set it apart. This game has monster catching! Monsters have a percent chance to ask to join your team after a battle, based on the type of monster. Some monsters can’t join, but there’s a wide selection to choose from. This wasn’t as in depth of a system as like, Megami Tensei to me, and you don’t get to name your monsters, instead they come pre-named based on their type. But it’s not a BAD system. I’ve just played better.</p>

<p>Over all, good game! Like an 8/10, it comes recommended. I hear DQ6 is a serious letdown compared to 4 and 5, so I’m taking a break before tackling that. I think I’ll work on another RPG series…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>