<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-22T02:32:28-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 3" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/22/OOCY3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dJF1W2N.png" alt="&quot;You didn't forget anything, did you? Take care! I'll have some side dishes to pick up once you get back!&quot; They gained another mom." class="center-block" />
Source: About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: About a College Girl Who Gets Picked Up at a Mixer by an Older Girl]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 1 - Ristar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 1 - Ristar" /><published>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/09/22/RA1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2Lv7cF3.png" alt="Ristar title screen" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So a year ago, I started my journey on Retro Achievements. I’ve been posting about it a lot of Cohost, where every mastery, I talk about the game. But I started at like, game #40. So I have a lot of posts I just never made. Gonna fix that here. We’re starting from the start.</p>

<p>If you’re wondering what this series is, I basically play a game, and then do a review of it. Simple. Retro Achievements is a site where you can play a game, and it gives you achievements for it. Simple as well.</p>

<p>My first choice for a game to master was Ristar… Ristar is my favorite game of all time. I’m literally named after it. You may not have realized Lizstar is a Ristar pun, but now you do. This game is in my DNA. I know this game better than I know my own hands. I am way too close to this game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G6wYIQk.png" alt="Ristar " class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Ristar you play as uh, Ristar. He’s a 90s Sega mascot, so he’s cut from the same cloth as Sonic. He’s inspired by a pitch for Sonic, which was a bunny that grabbed things with its ears. That idea evolved all the way to this. Basically, Ristar was built with one core philosophy in mind. You experience most games with your sense of sight. Can we make a game where you use your other senses? This game is all about the sense of touch. You play as a child exploring the world, reaching out and touching things, or feeling them. This game’s working title was Feel for a reason.</p>

<p>Ristar can jump and strech his arms out, just for you. He’ll grab anything he can reach, which depending on what it is, will have different effects. He might swing around on a pole. He might hand on a thing, or climb ladders. He might turn switches. Or he’ll grab the enemy and slam his entire head into it. You’ve gotta figure out what everything does in the classic way. Grabbin’ it!</p>

<p>Ristar is slower paced than Sonic. He takes his time, sauntering through levels, exploring. It’s got a lot of that same DNA though, and is just as fun. The levels are colorful, well designed. And the music is, of course, fantastic. This might be the prettiest Genesis game. It was pretty late in the console’s life cycle, so it’s not a big surprise.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xujUvrt.png" alt="Ristar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The main time when Ristar speeds up is with the star poles. Ristar can grab these poles and spin around them, gaining increasingly more speed as he spins, before he releases and flies through the air. He’s hard to control, but you can explore and get to new areas this way. Again, all about that exploration!!</p>

<p>The story of the game depends on if you’re playing the JP version or not. This game actually changes a lot with the American release. In the JP release, the evil Kaiser Greedy is invading the solar system, and is taking over the planets and their leaders with his mind control magic! The people pray to their goddess Oruto for help, who sends her son Ristar. The US version keeps that kind of, except there’s no Oruto. Instead, his dad is the Galactic Hero who goes to stop Greedy, but is defeated, and Ristar has to save both the star system, and his dad. I guess they thought Americans would freak out about a non Christian God? Some of us would. There’s also other changes, like changing a cat monster to an ice monster, but both versions are fine to play.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WToUEKs.png" alt="Ristar" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is not an easy game. But if you play it, you’ll find a LOT to enjoy about it. It is endlessly charming. Ristar is so cute, and he has so many fun idle animations, like making snowmen! It’s a good challenge, Greedy is one of the hardest Genesis boss fights. And of course, it’s just fun. The devs of this wanted to make a sequel, but Sega never cared about it much, and sent them all away to work on Nights into Dreams. Which y’know, is a good game. But I wish more had been done with my boy.</p>

<p>The actual set was good too btw. Though it had an achievement for grinding out points, which was kinda boring and annoying lol</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Genesis" /><category term="Ristar" /><category term="platformer" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DO YOU REMEMBER?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/shitpost/2024/09/21/DYR.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DO YOU REMEMBER?" /><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/shitpost/2024/09/21/DYR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/shitpost/2024/09/21/DYR.html"><![CDATA[<p>NEVER WAS A CLOUDY DAY</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="shitpost" /><category term="shitpost" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[NEVER WAS A CLOUDY DAY]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/21/OOCY.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 2" /><published>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/21/OOCY</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/21/OOCY.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TecvJJ9.png" alt="&quot;W-w-we can't! If we do that, someone will die! Namely me! We shoul start with holding hands!&quot; &quot;We've already held hands many times!&quot; &quot;Why?!&quot; &quot;Because... we're girlfriends. Is something the matter with you, Mariya-san?!&quot;" class="center-block" />
Source: I Won 300 Million Yen in a Lottery so I Started Rasing a Freeloader Pretty Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Won 300 Million Yen in a Lottery so I Started Rasing a Freeloader Pretty Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: I Won 300 Million Yen in a Lottery so I Started Rasing a Freeloader Pretty Girl]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Obscure Games You May Not Have Heard Of - Episode 1, Dharma Doujo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/obscuregamesyoumaynothaveheardof/2024/09/20/OGYMNHHO-ep1-dharma.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Obscure Games You May Not Have Heard Of - Episode 1, Dharma Doujo" /><published>2024-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/obscuregamesyoumaynothaveheardof/2024/09/20/OGYMNHHO-ep1-dharma</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/obscuregamesyoumaynothaveheardof/2024/09/20/OGYMNHHO-ep1-dharma.html"><![CDATA[<p>So people seemed very down for me just rambling about games I love that they probably have not heard of… Let’s make this a semi-regular thing! So for Episode One of Obscure Games You May Not Have Heard Of, let’s start with one that I’m kinda known for in some circles, Dharma Doujo!</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/h5yfTo4.png" alt="Also known as Daruma Dojo" /></p>

<p>Dharma Doujo is a puzzle game for arcades, and as we’ll see later, for the Super Famicom as well. It’s from that golden age of puzzle games for me, the lovely mid-90s, where every game in the genre was trying to innovate into something new. I promise I’ll try not to make all of this series just puzzle games but I might fail in that endevor.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Q6aPtJp.png" alt="I don't know what to do with alt text. Hey look, a cool game" /></p>

<p>So in Dharma Doujo you play as either a monk (I call him Eyebrows Krillin) if you’re playing as player 1, or a shrine maiden if you’re player two. Your goal is to clear all of the blocks. Each time you hit a block, it moves to the bottom of the screen, and if you hit all of that block color/type in a row, you clear it. Otherwise it rises back up and pushes everything up. When you hit a block, blocks behind it move forward to the left, and blocks will also fall down to fill empty spaces. Your goal is to line up your blocks for easy access so you can clear them all before the yokai on the left climbs to the top! Also, if your stack gets too high, you immediately lose.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/oFnawYF.png" alt="I have been called 'a sentient sorting algorithm' while playing this game." /></p>

<p>It’s not very complex, but honestly most good puzzle games from this era aren’t. There’s no bonus features, no real weird mechanics. Clear blocks, and if you clear blocks, you hit the Yokai and stun it for a bit. Unless it’s one of those blocks with the characters on them, then you just get points. You get more points for faster and cleaner clears. Simple. But VERY difficult, and as it throws more of each block in, eventually when you’re doing like the 8-per-type levels, it’s a freaking nightmare. But in a good way. And you feel SO powerful when you finally beat it after feeding a hundred quarters in.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Yh3rmb2.png" alt="In this cutscene they smack the bear, and its mom comes after them angrily. It's cute." /></p>

<p>Also the game is charming as hell. It’s got nice Japanese-inspired music, and inbetween some levels are these adorable cutscenes. And yes, the game is very VERY Japanese. I had no idea what a daruma doll was before this, but I learned a lot! It’s very educational. But also… not at all, I just had my chat tell me as I played it. The game actually uses a daruma doll to symbolize your halfway point too, at 10 levels. The game has 18 levels though, which is… odd. Anyway, great game.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/9RC3Z4l.png" alt="Fite me on Fightcade, cowards" /></p>

<p>Also the game has a multiplayer mode. It’s not the best, coulda used like a punch button (which the game’s semi-sequel had, maybe I’ll talk about that game sometime). But it’s loads of fun on Fightcade. After I got my WR in this game on Frame Fatales, I went “btw the game has a multiplayer mode does anyone wanna fight me sometime” and someone in chat went “FUCK no I do not”, and that lives with me rent free.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/adh7KcR.png" alt="One of the only times I'll willingly play my SNES." /></p>

<p>So a year later, the game gets its Super Famicom port. Of course, only in Japan. Can you imagine this game getting a US release? How could they pretend ALL of these things are jelly donuts?! No, it was JP only still, but adds on a lot! In many ways this is the definitive version, but I prefer the arcade version because I’m more used to it, and also for one reason I’ll get to later.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/tCprdbp.png" alt="Oni be ready to climb" /><img src="https://i.imgur.com/EOeVFra.png" alt="She happy and so am I" /></p>

<p>So, it’s Dharma Doujo but on SNES alright. Not much has changed. Still as charming, has a story and more cutscenes now and they’re as adorable as ever. There’s some new yokai, like some kitsune and kappas you can fight. But the only actual gameplay difference is that, in the arcade game, you have to also move left and right. Here, it’s just up and down, and your character automatically follows the side of the stack. This is good, before it was just a punishment for whiffing and added difficulty that was… fine. I know many people prefer this version for this reason alone. On top of that, the characters are differentiated now. Eyebrows Krillin is normal, but the shrine maiden’s yokai only goes up when she misses, so it’s good for slow planning gameplay. Oh, and the game feels a lot faster. You just smack blocks and clear em a lot quicker.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/yDylGQN.png" alt="Lookit that Kitsune!" /></p>

<p>This game has ONE flaw to me, and that’s that when it starts to get to the later levels, they make the blocks smaller. I have very bad eyesight, and when things get smol, I squint. And when I squint, I get migraines. I don’t play this version often ONLY for this reason, the later levels become a migraine nightmare.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/t9wcf3z.png" alt="Endless mode!" />
<img src="https://i.imgur.com/KrTbTJN.png" alt="I dunno who this guy is but he replaces the weird bird guy from the arcade I think" /></p>

<p>It also has a few additional bonus modes the arcade doesn’t have! It reminds me of Columns on Genesis, where it’s almost just a straight up better version cause it has more features. Why even own the arcade PCB? Oh wait, I own the arcade board for Columns. Oops. Anyway, it has an endless mode and a puzzle mode too. More ways to play is never a bad thing!</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/K5cQPaT.png" alt="Nyeh nyeh" /></p>

<p>And that’s Dharma Doujo! Nothing else to really add. It is quite difficult but seriously, it’s one of those games that takes a bit of practice and you eventually get better and better. It ramps, in a good way, and you will too. It’s one of my absolute favorite games of all time, thank you for reading about it =w=</p>

<p>Hmmmm what game should I ramble about next time~… maybe I’ll wait to talk about my other favorite puzzle games.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="ObscureGamesYouMayNotHaveHeardOf" /><category term="Obscure Games You May Not Have Heard Of" /><category term="Games" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="Arcade" /><category term="Puzzle Games" /><category term="Dharma Doujo" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So people seemed very down for me just rambling about games I love that they probably have not heard of… Let’s make this a semi-regular thing! So for Episode One of Obscure Games You May Not Have Heard Of, let’s start with one that I’m kinda known for in some circles, Dharma Doujo!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/20/OOCY.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 2" /><published>2024-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/20/OOCY</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/09/20/OOCY.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G0vNxhe.png" alt="A girl goodgling yuri" class="center-block" />
Source: Lily Love</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wl9KdWK.png" alt="A girl searching for girls dating online" class="center-block" />
Source: Nana Yuri</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I41pHIf.png" alt="A girl looking up what two girls do beyond kissing and being AMAZED" class="center-block" />
Source: Kase-san</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="Out Of Context Yuri" /><category term="Lily Love" /><category term="Nana Yuri" /><category term="Kase-san" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Source: Lily Love]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - TNG Season 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/03/05/LizstartrekTNG1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - TNG Season 1" /><published>2023-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/03/05/LizstartrekTNG1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/03/05/LizstartrekTNG1.html"><![CDATA[<p>No more Kirk! No more Spock! A little more Bones. It is finally time</p>

<p>Continuing on my quest to watch and talk about EVERY Episode of Trek ever made, we’re on to THE NEXT GENERATION</p>

<p>It’s been a long time. And season 1 has… growing pains. But I’m excited</p>

<p>Energize</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Encounter at Far Point Part 1</strong> - TNG
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/PSXT9B6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A tentative seven. All the stuff with Q was… annoying? Like, John Delancy is great. But he was written poorly here, a lot of it probably Roddenberry’s work.</p>

<p>And yet MORE “Humans are warlike and need to prove themselves”. We’ve done this like eight times. It’s a little old.</p>

<p>Once we’re past that, though, the character points are very nice! Some characters haven’t quite hit their stride (Beardless Riker, <em>shudder</em>) but it’s so good to finally see them. I kept yelling out “MY BOY!”</p>

<p>And of course, McCoy shows up to be cool. A solid 137 years old, and Deforest Kelley once again bein’ the type of actor to just go “LATHER THAT SHIT ALL OVER ME” when they need him to do old man makeup</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/e4Xtv2P.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I’ll also be saying this a lot, but I love Data. He’s the best.</p>

<p>A few more thoughts:</p>

<p>Tasha Yar’s job is to make dumb decisions and be yelled at. What an unfortunate character. She deserved better.</p>

<p>Apparently the original script had Wesley as a 15 year old girl named Leslie. Can you imagine how different life would be????</p>

<p><strong>The Encounter at Farpoint Part 2</strong> - TNG
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/al9vgZw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Better than the last one, cause the weird Q bullshit is much better here. Everyone still feels wrong, not quite how they should be, but it’s honestly a good start to the TNG series.</p>

<p>Nice intrigue and concept, too.</p>

<p>But yeah, most of the characters are really uncharacteristic. The only ones that feel correct in any way are Crusher and Data. And Worf. Poor Worf. At least he caused one of the best lines</p>

<p>“…Are you about to blow a hole in the viewfinder???”</p>

<p><strong>The Naked Now</strong> - TNG
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/jCSKnta.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Why does Tasha Yar have the Superman curl</p>

<p>This episode is an homage to The Naked Time from TOS, but it’s not NEARLY as good. Alas, no one swings a sword, but thats the least of our worries</p>

<p>No one knows how to write/act drunk, write women, and ESPECIALLY not both at the same time</p>

<p>I mostly found all the characters really obnoxious? And not just while drunk, it’s just a matter of growing pains in mostly the writing. Some silly moments.</p>

<p>“Worf, stop trying to tell me the star is going to vaporize us, I need to yell at this child!”</p>

<p>The entirety of Yar and Data. God, poor Yar, so mistreated.</p>

<p>Worf is the only one who didn’t get infected and he STILL was barely allowed to do anything.</p>

<p>Horny Picard makes weird grunting mating calls and I do not like it.</p>

<p>Riker was somehow NOT the horny one!!</p>

<p><strong>Code of Honor</strong> - TNG
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/5W48ORx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ah yes. The Racist Episode. The “space africa” episode, as I’ve heard it called, but I’ll call it “Space Africa as imagined by old white men” episode.</p>

<p>I expected this to be racist. I did not also expect it to be sexist. But holy shit.</p>

<p>As a note, the alien species is not written as black in the notes. But they were ALL cast as black, because of fucking course they were.</p>

<p>It’s an episode where a black guy kidnaps a woman and engages in a Traditional Ritual to make her one of his wives. Good lord.</p>

<p>I will say, it’s still not the worst episode I’ve seen so far. But PROBABLY 2nd worst, and almost certainly the worst for TNG all together. I can’t imagine it being worse than this.</p>

<p>The ToS sexism ep is still worse to me cause at least it shows women can fight.</p>

<p>…though actually</p>

<p>Okay, in this episode, it shows Yar being attracted to her kidnapper. And Troi baits on her being attracted to his masculinity, and it is FUCKING DISGUSTING.</p>

<p>And then directing anger at the wife instead of him, ughhhh it’s so fucking nasty.</p>

<p><strong>The Last Outpost</strong> - TNG
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/D1QmJtZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE FIRST FERENGI EPISODE! And my GOD are the Ferengi done poorly. You know, the rest of the episode is actually pretty good? But the Ferengi are SO DISTRACTING. They’re set up as Big Bads and they try hard to sell it but its so goofy.</p>

<p>It has some fun character moments? The first beginnings of the Data and Geordi Bromance. Riker handling an ancient guardian super well. But then in the background, the entire time, are a bunch of Ferengi dancing like gremlins in the background like idiots</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/0TMIY4g.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Fun fact, Armin Shimmerman is in this episode! And when he came back as Quark, he announced that his plan was to take what he did here, and do THE EXACT OPPOSITE, because of how horrible it was.</p>

<p>And then we got Quark. I love Quark.</p>

<p>This episode feels noncanon lol… tbh, most of this season feels noncanon.</p>

<p><strong>Where No One Has Gone Before</strong> - TNG
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/M1GnqSJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I liked this in spite of some of its flaws, but its probably the best so far. The Traveler is a neat character, with a cool concept. Part of me is disgusted at the “Wesley is the Chosen One” vibe, but its done well here. I shouldn’t discount this episode for how that plot point can be done poorly later. Here, Wesley is just shown to be talented, and someone wants those talents cultivated. That’s nice.</p>

<p>The one asshole character was annoying, but seeing him deflated is hilarious.</p>

<p>Other things I enjoyed: Showing off some of the other random crewmembers doing fun stuff. I liked the violin scene.</p>

<p>The guy in the skirt. Fuck yeah man skirts.</p>

<p>Riker standing up for Wesley against Picard’s weird annoying anti-kid shit.</p>

<p><strong>Lonely Among Us</strong> - TNG
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/iW6FcT5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>ඞ sus</p>

<p>So uh, this episode was super messy. Lots of things just felt irrelevent. The entire B plot with the two aliens was padding, though the designs were cool. They added nothing. Also the mutiny added nothing. Basically everything was irrelevent.</p>

<p>Like it’s to add tension but it kinda… doesn’t work. And smiley happy Picard upsets me greatly.</p>

<p>This isn’t a BAD episode though, because it gives us Data in a Pipe. Which is one of the best character moments so far, for sure.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/8zP35El.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I gotta say, I’ve been saying all the characters feel like they’re off, except for three: Riker is not QUITE as good as he will be but he’s still great. Geordi isn’t as relevent as he will be but he’s still Geordi</p>

<p>But Data is 100% Data. He starts great, he stays great.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/5zxtGSx.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>EDIT: Oh my god I forgot something about this episode that annoyed the shit out of me. So, this season has a weird rotating cast of Head Engineers. This is cause Roddenberry wanted to focus more on the bridge than anywhere else, though we hang out in Engineering all the time anyway so this seems like a waste of time. Anyways in this episode we have another new head of engineering who gets killed. He’s an Indian dude named Lt. Jg. Singh</p>

<p>And I’m just like…</p>

<p>Y’ALL KNOW THERE ARE OTHER INDIAN SURNAMES THAN SINGH, RIGHT?</p>

<p>There are literally five characters in this fucking franchise with the last name of Singh. For fucks sake. At least with the newest one, La’an Noonien-Singh, she’s y’know, connected to Khan. Who is ONE OF THE MOST WELL KNOWN TREK CHARACTERS. Maybe come up with another fucking surname so we don’t constantly think back to Khan. Or so you don’t seem like you only know one Indian surname.</p>

<p>Continuing on our multi-year long voyage of adventure and discovery, we find ourselves deep in the first season of The Next Generation. It is… not good!! God I cannot wait to get out of this quagmire.</p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. By our estimates, we’ll be out of Season 1 by March. Heavens preserve us.</p>

<p><strong>Justice</strong> - TNG
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/rOzMcvi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The only good thing about this episode is this Picard expression.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/qEO9IoK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s also the expression I was making the entire time.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/hP4ODy5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It was just extremely uncomfortable. The Idyllic Hippy People were so awkward and uncomfortable to watch, and the actual plot and concept was mostly annoying. I DID like the ending of “there is no justice with a law that’s absolute and inflexible”, that’s a nice moral I guess. But Christ, the acting is stilted, and it just made me so uncomfortable. And the god exploration wasn’t very interesting either. Honestly the second half was way batter, but the first half set me up REAL bad to hate this.</p>

<p><strong>The Battle</strong> - TNG
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/VzoQhHn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is a REAL good episode. I usually like to go “this is the TOPIC episode”. But here I’d have to say “This is the Picard PTSD and gaslighting episode”. But there are a lot of those. This is one of them, and it’s a good one.</p>

<p>This would be a WAY better introduction to the Ferengi. The villain, Bok, is a fun villain, especially cause of how unferengi he is, and how that’s a plot point. The other Ferengi aren’t offended by his evil actions, more that he’s doing stuff for revenge instead of personal profit.</p>

<p>I love how Picard is like “Doctor, I have a headache” “What?” “A headache, don’t you know what that is?” “Of course I do, but we don’t see many of those anymore”</p>

<p>Crusher, you did NOT cure stress headaches in 2364 there’s no fucking way migraines are now a thing of the past, like the Measles. What, are their inoculations against migraines now?? Did you isolate a weakened migraine germ for vaccines?</p>

<p><strong>Hide and Q</strong> - TNG
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/p9g68Xd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Damn, it didn’t talk long at all to actually get Q. The Q in the opening episode barely felt like Q. This feels like he’s ACTUALLY Q, and it’s so good to see him. He’s a shithead and I hate him but it’s good to see him.</p>

<p>This was fun. Lots of fun moments. Q turning into Data made me scream. Q and Picard doing a Shakespeare off was also hilarious. NEVER challenge Sir Patrick Stewart to a Shakespeare off!! Also this episode had a lot of this face, which I found really weirdly entertaining.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/0SsqklG.jpg" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What it was doin’ with Riker made me… very uncomfortable. But that’s the point, it did it well!! Also, the scene with the “gifts”…. I like how everyone reacted. ESPECIALLY Data. GOD I LOVE DATA. HE’S SO GOOD. “You could certainly snap your fingers and make me a human, sir. It would be real for everyone. But not for me.”</p>

<p>That’s a common view of thought with trans people as well. Like yes, many people would like a snap of the fingers. But not for many others.</p>

<p><strong>Haven</strong> - TNG
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/xSQJsj8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A Betazoid episode!! Troi is sadly the worst character in Season 1. She’s just… done so poorly. It’s gotten to the point where we’ve been poking fun. “I am sensing great annoyance from the audience”. Her fiance is a doctor and is like “You already knew that though because you’re psychic, right?” and we went “I am sensing much doctor from him”</p>

<p>There’s not a LOT to this episode? It’s mostly an awkward wedding with a Jewish Mom and a Catholic Mom arguing a lot. The issue is resolved really easily with no problems, and it feels a little sudden but it was honestly mostly fun, though I’m bad with awkward humor.</p>

<p>It DOES have the Trashiest Woman In Trek, though.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/pLfX1AK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Also another funny thing about it was the opening. Riker was sitting in his room, watching a hologram of two women playing the harp, looking weirdly horny. I was like “is this alternate universe pornhub, harphub?”</p>

<p>And thus Harphub was born.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/e0yU2KG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Big Goodbye</strong> - TNG
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/0TlxrOQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The first “Shit Goes Wrong In The Holodeck” episode! I was almost wishing this episode was JUST a Holodeck episode. I felt this episode is at its best when Picard, overworked and stressed, is enjoying 1930s detective novels in the holodeck. He’s just so adorkable and goofy. I came to love it more by the end, though.</p>

<p>The actual action is exciting and tense, though. They have to escape the Holodeck both because gangsters are trying to murder them, AND there’ll be a diplomatic incident otherwise.</p>

<p>Big fan of Data in this, as always. He always gets real into this shit in a fun way. Also the ending is WILD. The holodeck getting EXISTENTIAL and DEPRESSED about the world disappearing. “After you leave, will I still exist?” “I honestly don’t know. Goodbye, my friend” is… SCARY.</p>

<p>It’s just fun though. Trek has always done gangsters well.</p>

<p><strong>Thoughts</strong></p>

<p>Okay, so thoughts on this cluster… Yeah we had a pretty big stinker early on, but the rest were good, or great even! This gives me hope, maybe the season will get good after all. They just had to run through all the Phase 2 scripts they still had sitting around and actually write good shit.</p>

<p>I am sensing great quality in this.</p>

<p><strong>Datalore</strong> - TNG
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/KjD0PVB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are you prepared for the kind of review you’ve earned, little man? If you are not a little man, please disregard this message.</p>

<p>Possibly the best episode so far, and this is because Brent Spiner is the only actor who feels at 100%. Data is the best character already, but also the best in season 1, and this is a VERY GOOD lore episode. It’s also a good Lore episode! Evil twins as a concept are nothing new but god does Spiner chew the scenery in a good way.</p>

<p>Also this is the most quotable episode of this season, by far. The “prepared for the kind of death you’ve earned” line is my favorite in many all of TNG, and “Shut up, Wesley” is of course, classic.</p>

<p>Speaking of Wesley, my only major problem with this entire episode is Wesley himself. It makes sense he’d be the first to realize Data is actually Lore pretending to be Data, he interacts with him first, and also is friends with Data, but everyone else should have realized it too, and I’m just not a fan of the “the kid is right and all the adults don’t listen wah” concept trope, it’s boring. There’s no way Data’s other friends wouldn’t have noticed, it just feels shoehorned for Roddenberry’s OC to be The One To Solve It All.</p>

<p>P.S. There was a segment where Picard was referring to Lore as an It, and Data was like “You keep using it, which implies he is a thing, and also implies you view me the same way”. Picard went “Oh no, I see your point, I’m so sorry, never my intention.” And then they RESUMED CONVERSATION. That’s it! Imagine. When did Star Trek get so woke.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/cQL8DY5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Here have a fun picture of all the Stunt Datas</p>

<p><strong>Angel One</strong> - TNG
1.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/PapKUGm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Feminism is when women are men and men are women. And when women are misandrists. That’s VERY feminist.</p>

<p>This is the dumbest shit I’ve ever watched in my life. It’s just sexist and gross while trying to be the opposite of sexist but oh my fucking god it is SO sexist. See, it’s a world where women rule… So they’re the ones who are bigger and stronger and more assertive! And the men are small, effeminate, and like wearing perfume!</p>

<p>I want to die.</p>

<p>Also the B plot is here, Wesley gets the captain sick, and he puts Geordi on command. Not any of the people ABOVE Geordi but eh I like Geordi, and he looked so giddy, it was cute. No one can act sick btw. Especially not Sir Patrick Stewart. Sick Worf is funny though. By the end though this B Plot just felt like it was elongating the episode and I did not appreciate having to watch this any further.</p>

<p>Also the first Horny Riker moments. “Diplomatic relations” indeed. Too bad the rest of the episode made me so uncomfortable that I couldn’t even enjoy him looking so fucking sexy in that dumbass outfit.</p>

<p>Anyways the plot of this is that there are men who crashlanded here and are so attracted to Amazonian Women that they wanted to stay, but were annoyed when the women didn’t Make Them A Sandwich, so they’re kind of political dissidents. Fuck this episode.</p>

<p>Also the ending had a really bad plot hole but I wanted the episode to be over so much I didn’t even care.</p>

<p>Apparently, the original concept of this wasn’t to be some take on feminism or anything, but <strong><em>a take on apartheid</em></strong>. And then Roddenberry fucked with this. Quote from a meeting about this, from Roddenberry, loudly: “Women are untrustworthy, vicious creatures”. So thank you, Roddenberry. This episode would have been bad anyway but my god.</p>

<p>For some reason I cannot give this episode a 1/10 though. It DOES have Riker’s Hairy Man Chest, and Geordi in command. But that’s it.</p>

<p><strong>11001001</strong> - TNG
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/dsc7chG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I love that TNG has an actual alien budget. Look at these aliens, the Bynars. They’re so cool. What a good concept too.</p>

<p>This episode is like 60% no plot, just vignettes about random fun stuff. I was almost hoping no plot or crisis would happen. Sadly, a crisis does happen, but it’s pretty exciting and the mystery of it is quite engaging.</p>

<p>I did find Picard Boomering and trying to figure out a computer fun. But I was slightly confused/annoyed by the Bynars not just… explaining what they were doing. Why not explain it? Everyone would have helped them. Yeah I know the Bynars are like “You might have said no” but would the Federation REALLY have gone “yeah no, our allies? Fuck ‘em”. Also the end with Minuet just disappearing… why would the Bynars have done that? Just ask em to reinstall it. What the heck.</p>

<p>Fun things about this episode:</p>

<p>Captain Picard is like “Ahhh, we have two days without anything! I’m going to turn on my relaxation light and read”. Picard is a HUGE fucking loser oh my good god.</p>

<p>There’s a scene in the middle where Riker gets weirdly horny in the holodeck. The Bynars upgraded the holodeck, and it makes a sentient program (which has no ethical implications I’m sure). It’s uncomfortable but I like seeing Riker get excited about Jazz. I love how just last week I was joking about whether people fuck in the Holodeck and there’s no way its not what Riker does in this scene.</p>

<p>Riker also plays Trombone in this episode, which Frakes plays IRL, and he’s played trombone on multiple albums, including a 1991 album by Brent Spiner! Exciting. I think he’s good at it but the “don’t give up the day job” line fucking SLEW me.</p>

<p>“Hey man, that girl seems real into you”</p>

<p>“How can you tell?”</p>

<p><img src="https://media.tenor.com/5G3H_QBnuO0AAAAd/will-riker-william-riker.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>“The way she’s staring at you unblinkingly is so hot”</p>

<p>And then Picard walks in like “Oh I’m sorry I didn’t mean to interrupt” and I fucking cackled.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/a8Ph3GA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nice bulge, Worf.</p>

<p><strong>Too Short a Season</strong> - TNG
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/RIkmX8S.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode has one of my least favorite tropes in Star Trek, The Commodore/Admiral. A shitty useless dude who waves his dick around, takes over command, and fucks everything up. And this time, the Admiral looks like one of the puppets from Genesis’ Land of Confusion music video, so it’s even worse.</p>

<p>His over-acting as an old man was PAINFUL to watch and listen to, I weirdly hated it. Also he’s only 85! Why does he look like that? Bones looked and moved better, and he was like 140!! TBF, it’s cause of some fake disease called Iverson’s.</p>

<p>He gets a medicine that reverses aging, one for him and one for his wife. It has a super high mortality rate, unless you take it slowly over 2 years. But instead, because it wasn’t working in time for this mission, he downed his bottle and his wife’s, like that was the smart thing to do, and gets pissy when people are rightfully bothered by it, especially his wife.</p>

<p>The main problem with this episode really is that the admiral is so unlikable, and this episode is 80% this admiral, and he’s SO unlikable. Like “let’s just fuck the prime directive up the ass” unlikable. That’s the issue with this trope in general, though. And god, it really is my least favorite trope in Trek. Or at least VERY up there.</p>

<p>At least he dies of Young Age. Fuck that guy. This is a leftover TOS script that is just so poorly fit into this, straight down to that little moment where the captain talks to the other on the bridge to try and make a moral. “Just goes to show. The quest for youth is futile, number one”. No. That’s not the moral. Don’t try and make a moral out of this. BTW this was inspired by the Iran Contra Affair. The moral they should learn is to stop being inspired by IRL political stuff. They do it so poorly.</p>

<p>Here’s some backstory too: Roddenberry’s attorney, Leonard Maizlish, wrote edits for the script, with his own edits, adding in stuff with Wesley, claiming the edits were made by Roddenberry. DC Fontana, the writer, and Rick Berman grilled him, cause Roddenberry was at his home sick, and Maizlish admitted he had made it instead, trying to force his own view on what Trek would be. Berman threatened to get the writer’s union in here to protect DC Fotnana, and sue the pants off of Maizlish and Roddenberry, and he backed down. The ONLY GOOD THING BERMAN EVER DID.</p>

<p><strong>When the Bough Breaks</strong> - TNG
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/upNsonE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>In this episode, a species is dying out because of climate change, and they kidnap children so that their lessons and culture is passed on, since they can’t have children due to some genetic problems.</p>

<p>And then the children form a union.</p>

<p>This isn’t a BAD episode, but it wasn’t super interesting. But for an episode with a bunch of children, it was better than I’d have expected.  Some parts of it were cute and sweet though, and it’s the start of Picard’s Redemption Arc around kids.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3FLcEax.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>LOOK AT THE AMIGA BALL, WITH ITS CAMEO IN TREK!</p>

<p><strong>Home Soil</strong> - TNG
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/l40vhEK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The first 8 minutes are people doing technobabble awkwardly and grumpily and it’s very boring and uninteresting and then people start screaming and that makes it a little better. Data dodges lasers which is sick but then people get angry that he breaks a laser that was trying to kill him. Come on y’all.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1ZKjPHE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find a speck that they think could be life, but it’s inorganic, no carbon. And they’re like “THIS HAS NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE” as if the Horta aren’t canonically a part of the federation and fucking rad. How DARE you ignore the Horta, by favorite rug covered in meatballs &gt;:( Also we had a fucking Crystalline Entity earlier this season y’all</p>

<p>Troi: “I can’t really make heads of tails of this woman. Maybe you can!”
Riker: “Seduce her, gotcha”</p>

<p>If literally anyone other than Frakes was playing Riker I would not like him.</p>

<p>Anyways the episode in general is really quite good. The idea isn’t super original but I like how they handle the “oh god we didn’t know it was life” and the life declaring war on humans. Also the line “SEND US HOME TO WET SAND” is a good line.</p>

<p><strong>Coming of Age</strong> - TNG
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ITBlh30.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh BOY! Another asshole Admiral episode! AND a Wesley episode! Okay first let’s complain about the Admiral shit</p>

<p>An asshole Admiral shows up, explains nothing, says something is wrong with the ship, and makes his goon go around and watch everyone. Gives me big Customer Service vibes, with some corporate shitbag who doesn’t know you or your job showing up and watching your every move, judging you for each time you don’t remind someone of the extended warranty and hoping you can be fired. And if you ask any questions or get snippy they abuse their power to fire you anyway.</p>

<p>Like yes. He’s supposed to be a shitbag. We’re supposed to hate him. And we do! But it doesn’t make it pleasant to watch!! At all! :D</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SspeMd2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The second part of this episode is Wesley. Which again, I think people shit on Wesley too much but I’m still not a big fan of his writing. It’s also not pleasant to watch! Though I do REALLY like him and Worf’s conversation about fear. Worf is VERY underutilized this season. Let my boy be Klingon. Let him DO THINGS. I’m glad they’re doing it.</p>

<p>Also like, I’m glad more recently they’ve made the Acadamy less of a “This is for GENIUSES” thing cause it makes me uncomfy here. Some of the parts of it are nice though, like the angy guy who bumped into them, it’s cute. Also, Benzites are so cool. Good alien design. Also there’s a Vulcan here. TNG has a big derth in Vulcans for some reason. You’d think, since they’re like the most popular alien, there’s be more.</p>

<p>I ended up liking the Wesley portion more than I thought I would by the end (though only getting ONE of the four candidates in seems silly. They’re all qualified??? It feels very 20th century thinking), but most of the episode is still just this asshole with a preconceived notion that he should get the captain fired investigating everyone, and every officer is sick of him. And it tries to set up a thing for later with a conspiracy within Starfleet. The Wesley stuff (especially Picard being a dad to Wesley) really did warm this episode up for me by the end though.</p>

<p>This episode DID give us this gif as well. A classic.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x0iPqgr.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>Heart of Glory</strong> - TNG
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8SjnO3t.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><em>raises head up</em> AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA</p>

<p>THE FIRST KLINGON EPISODE! Gosh I love Klingons. They’re my favorite (other than the Horta of course), and I was JUST complaining that Worf didn’t have enough to do, and they didn’t know what to do with him. The meme is his job is to be thrown around by the Monster of the Day to show how strong it it, but that’s not even here in this first season!!! But at least he can do some KLINGON LOREBUILDING!</p>

<p>The episode starts without that though. Instead it’s Geordi lorebuilding! Picard gets really weirdly into being able to see how Geordi sees, in the middle of a rescue mission and Data and Riker are like “uhhh sir?”</p>

<p>I do like how Geordi’s view of Data looks like a character portrait from Disco Elysium though</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N5DNG7q.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways they get to the Klingons who say that the broken freighter they’re on, they were in a fight with some Ferengi (they’re still trying to make the Ferengi a threat). In order to beat them, they surrendered, and then beamed over bombs when the Ferengi lowered shields and moved forward. So uh, they did a warcrime! Yay! That’s… honorable!</p>

<p>This is good foreshadowing that these Klingon are kinda shitty. It’s a neat struggle with Worf, battling his upbringing, what he knows is right, and his heritage, who are trying to lead him astray because “peace sucks”. It does kinda sour for me when Picard doesn’t trust Worf. Like c’mon. It’s Worf! He won’t betray you! And he doesn’t. That’s one single negative thing there, though, and it’s very brief and out of nowhere. The rest of it is so good, ESPECIALLY the stuff with Worf. He’s so good, and there’s little trickles of what he’ll become. This is more than a trickle. This is like the start of the river.</p>

<p>Anyways, the Klingon stuff here slaps. It shows how fractured the Klingon empire is, it builds Worf up in a great way. And it shows us THE KLINGON DEATH RITUAL. God I love it. I did it with them. Be warned, dead. A warrior comes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FmIitnp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Arsenal of Freedom</strong> - TNG
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cf4o5kE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode kinda surprised me at every turn. Lots of good twists. I expected it to be a Riker episode, it has some good Riker lore, but a lot of characters get a good change to shine. Even Yar! Yar gets to be actiony and make good shots in fighting off a powerful enemy, Picard and Crusher have a great moment trying to keep her alive and awake after a major wound and being seperated. And Geordi! Ahhh, Geordi. He’s a badass running a good ship and putting up with some asshole. Yet ANOTHER chief engineer, the third one we’ve seen. God I can’t wait for them to give Geordi a real job.</p>

<p>This engineer is a shithead. At the first sign danger, he’s like “LEAVE AND ABANDON THE CAPTAIN AND THE AWAY TEAM, ALSO GIVE ME COMMAND.” Then Geordi’s like “no fuck off” and eventually he calls him back up and orders the Enterprise to run away. He’s then like “You’re ABANDONING them?!” and I just…. come on. I’m fine with an asshole character but he’s literally contradicting himself and it’s makin’ me GRUMPY.</p>

<p>This episode is tense and fun, pretty good, but nothing BREATHTAKING, y’know? Nice action scenes though.</p>

<p><strong>Symbiosis</strong> - TNG
2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7QP9DNl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is fucked UP. Like oh my god. Okay to explain: There are two societies. One society only makes a drug, and nothing else. They are uber capitalists, they make that drug, and then sell it to the other society, which is filled with people dying of a plague the drug can cure.</p>

<p>That’s already fucked up. The Brekkians (I’ll call them Pfizer from now on) are like “Yes sure you’re dying. But hey, we need money!” that’s fucked up. BUT IT GETS WORSE.</p>

<p>TURNS OUT THERE’S NO ACTUAL VIRUS. THERE’S NO PLAGUE. The drug is a narcotic and it’s actually just WITHDRAWAL SYMPTOMS. And the Brekkians are intentionally keeping this ENTIRE civilization drugged. Just to make money. And Picard is like “Well we can’t come between that, sure we think it’s evil but we can’t push our morality on them” LIKE. LIKE.</p>

<p>And then there’s a weird drug PSA, where Wesley is like “I don’t understand, Yar, why would anyone start doing drugs?” and then they do a Just Say No PSA and it feels like Reagan was breathing down these fuckers necks, making it a “very special episode” where you gotta teach the kids about the War on Drugs. God I hated this. And not just because I have actual PTSD involving drug use. Which I do. But also cause it’s just poorly done. They wanted to do it well but they failed real hard.</p>

<p>And Picard is like “Hey no that’s the Prime Directive, we can’t stop these parasites from leeching off of an entire civilization and making them drug addicts. We could easily fix this, Crusher has ways to ease the withdrawal symptoms. Instead we’ll abuse the prime directive and make it so they won’t be able to leech off them down the line, cause they won’t help fix their ships, and the shipments will eventually stop.”</p>

<p>That is… NOT HOW THE PRIME DIRECTIVE WORKS. AND THAT’S NOT HOW IT….. AGGHHH.</p>

<p>“Beverly, the Prime Directive is not just a set of rules!”</p>

<p>You’re right. It’s a set of rules that writers can abuse and twist around and claim works one way or another each episode so they can create drama. This episode would have been over instantly if it did work how it’s supposed to.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7kCo7TF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At least we got this Riker good face!</p>

<p>Also, I’m thinking to make these posts stand out a bit more from each other in the tag, I’m going to put an image of the most striking scene from that group of episodes. And uh… there’s no more striking image in all of season 1 than this fucking thing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/edMypnu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Skin of Evil</strong> - TNG
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/gH9tzxQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I can’t believe they waited until her final episode for actually enjoyable moments with Yar. Her and Worf at the start, with Yar apparently being in some fighting tournament, and happy that Worf bet on her for the tourny. Bet with what, I dunno. I like to imagine it’s just poker chips, and whoever has the most at the end “wins”.</p>

<p>This episode is known for a single thing and one thing only, and they do it in the first 12 minutes. Talk about blowing your load. The rest of the episode is fine. A weird psychopathic blob shadow monster holds Troi hostage, and I’ll be real, this is probably the first good Troi scene. This episode is in Yar’s shadow forever, but this is actually a Troi episode, and she’s good here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WMLafHL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode is mostly just a godlike asshole torturing people though, and that’s not…. super fun. Not terrible, though. The funeral scene made me tear up. Look at this moment where Riker is gasping for breath in a tar monster btw. That’s some printer ink and other garbage, and Frakes dove right into that. Imagine though, if they had killed off Yar AND Riker.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sW10gGS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Look at the elusive Green Uniform. This means that Dr. Crusher is a Goblin. (I have no idea why it’s green for two shots of her, and then it’s back to blue. I dunno why.)</p>

<p>Time for some Fun Facts about Natasha Yar and her actor, Denise Crosby , TNG’s most Unfortunate Character. She deserved so much more. So, the story behind her conception is hilarious. You see, one day in the late 80s, Gene Roddenberry was watching Aliens. A good movie. But he loved one thing in particular from it. The character of Private Vasquez. And immediately after, he was so beholden by her, she went “I WANT A CHARACTER LIKE THAT IN TNG”, which was in pre-production at the time.</p>

<p>On that day, Gene Roddenberry discovered lesbians, and discovered how hot they are. This is the only time I have ever related to Gene Roddenberry.</p>

<p>BTW killing her off was Roddenberry’s idea. He thought it’d be shocking. Thus giving us less of a chance to make the character with the most potential actually fill that potential out. Fuck Gene Roddenberry.</p>

<p>After recording her final scene (from the previous episode for some reason, not this one) the crew threw a party for her. Years later on Twitter, exec producer Rick Berman showed off her communicator, saying that Crosby gave it to her as a gift. Crosby responded to the tweet with “No, you ripped it off my shirt and said I wouldn’t need it anymore”. Fuck Rick Berman.</p>

<p><strong>We’ll Always Have Paris</strong> - TNG
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jYJh19W.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The start of this episode is <em>so good</em>. I love seeing Picard just… BE PICARD. He’s such a hardass in a… OKAY way, but he can be so much more. I like him a lot here. I love him fencing. I like him wistfully wandering Paris. Seeing Sir Patrick Stewart try to be horny for this random woman I enjoy less but I don’t really like watching ANYONE act horny, it always falls flat in Trek.</p>

<p>It’s a tense episode, with you slowly trying to unravel Picard’s strong emotions around these two people they picked up.</p>

<p>And then the timey wimey bullshit starts to happen and you get awesome shit, like that picture with Data up there. Stakes are HIGH. Most other stakes are like, “oh no we’ll all die” or “oh no, this planet and all its people will die”. Here, it’s “oh no, <em>THE UNIVERSE WILL UNRAVEL AS ANOTHER CONTINUITY RIPS THROUGH IT</em>”. That’s… a lot. And it’s really cool! It’s done well, and is exciting! I LOVE the scene with three Datas. I also love how Picard is like “Data we need to send you” “Oh, because I am a disposable machine?” “What? No, any human seeing two hundred of themselves in a time bubble would disassociate. You can handle that.”</p>

<p>And the ending is beautiful too. A great emotional conclusion. Powerful, and fitting. I’m surprised how much I enjoyed this episode. Best episode of this season maybe? It’s either this or Datalore, with Heart of Glory following close behind.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Rddb9CU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Here’s a fun continuity error…. That’s Yar’s arm!! BUT SHE DEAD! Let’s just say it’s more Timey Wimey bullshit.</p>

<p><strong>Conspiracy</strong> - TNG
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1XMPyKh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE GORIEST STAR TREK EPISODE! Look at that fucking thing. This is some god damn 80s horror movie special effects. It looks great! But it’s VERY jarring.</p>

<p>A follow up from a previous episode, with many characters returning. Specifically Coming of Age, and that annoying flunky and his fucking Admiral returning. Well… at least we won’t have to worry about that flunky appearing again!</p>

<p>This shit is <strong>tense</strong>. In a fun and good way. The Admirals are a very good set of intimidating villains, and things infiltrating the minds and bodies of the Top Brass of a military-like organization is a scary but super interesting premise. I always feel like Star Trek pussy foots around “the Federation can be bad”. This isn’t that, of course, the Federation isn’t bad, bad aliens infiltrated the spines of the top brass. But it’s unsettling in a good way.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ttTJrRu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Good action, good creepy concepts. It’s…. not very Star Trek tbh? It’s fucked up in a way that is NOT trek-ish. This episode is so weird. It feels so extremely out of place. The first like, 3/5th or so are fine, but then it veers HARD.</p>

<p>AND THEY ALSO DID A STINGER AT THE END. Remmick (the guy who’s head asplode), was sending a beacon! To some unexplored sector of space! Ohh nooo, what could that mean for-</p>

<p>It means nothing. This never comes up again. It was set up, had this weird payoff, set up more, and then nothing. Also they killed 2/3rds of the top brass of the Federation, but that will apparently not effect anything or be any problem cause it’s also not mentioned again. This almost feels non-canon. It’s GOOD. It’s ENJOYABLE. But I dunno if it should even be here. The writer says that the script was apparently shot down by Maurice Hurley, the head behind the scripts at the time, cause it wasn’t Trek. It was too dark and fucked up. But Berman liked it so much it was put back in. Also, the original concept was YET ANOTHER take on the Gulf War??? This guy loved that. Originally it was going to have NO aliens, and instead was going to be a straight up military coup. Which like I said earlier, is something I’d kinda like to see Trek tackle, but Roddenberry was like “NO THE FEDERATION IS BIG GOOD AND WOULD NEVER STOOP THAT LOW”. Which is why I want them to tackle it, because power corrupts, mother fucker, no matter how futuristic socialist we are.</p>

<p>I wouldn’t trust this guy to do it right though. We gotta wait to DS9 for that.</p>

<p>AND IT’S SOMEHOW NOT EVEN THE FINAL EPISODE OF THE SEASON.</p>

<p><strong>The Neutral Zone</strong> - TNG
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/honAWSv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I dunno how you can follow up Conspiracy. But we have a throwback to Space Seed (they discover a derelict that has people in cryo-stasis) and the first Romulans in TNG, so they’re pulling out THE BIG GUNS! These two things clash, and complicate everything. It’s kinda… jarring. The A plot and B plot do not fit together. Apparently it was due to a writer’s strike. Makes sense.</p>

<p>The frozen people are from the early 90s, they died and were frozen until their problems could be cured. And now they’re a bunch of capitalists (and some random woman) in Space Socialism and are very confused. And all the Space Socialists are literally like “how did we live past the 21st century????”</p>

<p>Parts of the 90s People B Plot are VERY interesting. I do like seeing a realistic outlook on how people handle this. You have three characters. A housewife, a rich financier, and a rockstar. The housewife breaks down depressed everyone she knows and loves is dead. The financier is confused and frustrated that suddenly he has no power anymore. The rockstar is mostly just bored, and not distressed. It’s a really interesting view on how people would legit handle this situation, more than Space Seed.</p>

<p>Anyways then Romulans are here. The GIANT Romulan ship is a good re-entry to them. They mostly show up to be scary and threatening, and say “WE ARE BACK”, which is good because it means they’ll stop trying to make The Ferengi a threat so the Ferengi can start being enjoyable to watch.</p>

<p>This is a good episode. I understand some people’s issues with the weird capitalist posturing, or the tonal shifts, or how it doesn’t feel like a season finale (at least it’s not a clip show). But I think it was done very well considering it was cobbled together from a script outline.</p>

<p><strong><em>SEASON ONE OUTLINE</em></strong></p>

<p>I did it. We’re done. No more season 1. Okay look, people mock this season for a reason, but I think it’s more growing pains than “this is shit”. There’s a LOT of good here. We’re lucky it even continued and had the CHANCE to grow, but I’m glad it did. This season shows a lot of potential. And it was better than like, most TOS seasons tbh.</p>

<p>I’ll see you all next week, for the start of season 2, which is actually one of my personal favorites (it has my two favorite episodes). See you then!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="TNG" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[No more Kirk! No more Spock! A little more Bones. It is finally time]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - The Animated Series</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/29/LizstartrekTAS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - The Animated Series" /><published>2023-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/29/LizstartrekTAS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/29/LizstartrekTAS.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, over the past year, I have been watching the entirety of Star Trek, and been posting my thoughts on all the episodes and movies as I watch them. Now, I’ve been posting them on Twitter, and I’ll probably continue to do so until that website explodes. But I’ve been putting off putting all my thoughts on this site…. but I’ll go ahead and do that now!</p>

<p>SO! If you’re interested in my thoughts on every episode of Star Trek, and boy why wouldn’t you be, or if you’re interested in just re-living Star Trek with me, go ahead and read on! For future series where I probably ONLY post here, these will have a lot more thoughts on them, but the first few were only one Twitter post, so maybe not in depth.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Beyond the Farthest Star</strong> - TAS
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/qubjSRS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Pretty solid first episode. Good action, good setup and tension, some good “how are they gonna get out of this”, with a fun villain that sounds like me when I’m doing my Goblin voice</p>

<p>“OBEY ME! lizstarFiteMe”</p>

<p>The voice acting so far is trying much harder than I expected, and while the animation is bad, it was made on like 12 cents, and I really think that they did the best they could. I like the tell-tale signs of this series so far, small glances and no other movement.</p>

<p><strong>Yesteryear</strong> - TAS
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/ObMGHoV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While I think this episode is very good I also hate it and I will explain why</p>

<p>The time travel goofiness is… nonsensical but who cares, I like the big lorebuilding, the big character building, building Vulcan and the Vulcans, and Spock.</p>

<p>It’s very good, and well done. Like genuinely. But I also hate it, because it has a big goofy sabertooth cat dog named I-Chayah, and it SACRIFICES ITSELF TO SAVE SPOCK, and DIES.</p>

<p>It FUCKED ME UP. I cannot BELIEVE they put that in this.</p>

<p>I wondered this earlier, but I ask it again here… who is this for? NOT CHILDREN</p>

<p>Well actually, it was for all ages, but in a way, this is an important thing to show to children. The corpos wanted it removed, I’m STUNNED they finally allowed it.</p>

<p>RIP I-Chayah</p>

<p><strong>One Of Our Planets Is Missing</strong> - TAS
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/QhkPVqS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Amazing episode name.</p>

<p>Just a solid episode. I kinda don’t have a lot to talk about with it, it’s a cool premise, and quite tense in an enjoyable way. It gets dark and slightly fucked, which is rad as hell.</p>

<p>They get to show a lot more that’s super cool. A giant space cloud that eats you. Also they show the crew doingh so much more. They had contingency plans. They were gonna blow up the Enterprise. They were evacuating a planet.</p>

<p>God bless D.C Fontana btw</p>

<p><strong>The Lorelei Signal</strong> - TAS
Like 4/10, but also 9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/QvTCRNc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Allow me to summarize this episode.</p>

<p>A race of vampire women, made that way by their planet’s ambient energy, seduce all the men of the enterprise to drag them to the planet to consume their “life energy”.</p>

<p>All of the women on board the Enterprise are unaffected by the vampire’s siren call, and are confused and annoyed. Eventually they get fed up and beam down, with Uhura in command. The vampires get angry and refuse to give over the men until Uhura shoots EVERYTHING.</p>

<p>Now we know why they never put Uhura in charge, she’s a fucking menace. IMMEDIATELY just fucking blasts away everyone. Then when they refuse to tell her where the men are, she blows up their pottery. Finally, at the end, she teaches them to blow up their computer??</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FjvlKCdXgAAkElG?format=png&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s a serious feminism power trip in a very good way. The episode and its plot and its writing are unfortunately kinda middling, but the certain parts of it are the best thing I’ve ever seen. We need to give Uhura control more often.</p>

<p><strong>More Tribbles, More Troubles</strong> - TAS
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/w7VyoCF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Very solid fun episode, good follow up to TwT. Lots of cute references, fun jokes and energy to it. It dragged a little in the middle but the episodes are so short that’s no big deal. Animations errors galore, but who cares</p>

<p><strong>The Survivor</strong> - TAS</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/tajVSjb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>8/10</p>

<p>A really good episode, very strong, fun infiltration, enjoyable action of all damn things, neat alien, everything is resolved real well and doesn’t feel gross like so many TOS plots where “lady falls in love with monster of the week”.</p>

<p>Like, a thing I need to note, is the quality of the animation is obviously quite bad. I’m ignoring that entirely for my ratings. This is on writing and everything else, mostly. And so far this series is… REALLY good? Like just very solid.</p>

<p>Also this was the first reveal of M’Ress, the Catgirl. I saw her and went “YAY!” then realized she was assigned to work Uhura’s station and she wasn’t there and was like “BOO! Why give us another girl just to replace ONE OF THE TWO WOMEN WE HAVE?”</p>

<p><strong>The Infinite Vulcan</strong> - TAS
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/gKG8996.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s fine, I wasn’t as interested tbh. Like it’s an okay idea and it has a nice conclusion but it just wasn’t quite as interesting. Amazing name though, and it has a giant spock mind melding with tiny spock, which is SOMEONE’S kink</p>

<p><strong>The Magicks of Megas-tu</strong> - TAS
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/e7b5bs5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>In this episode, the Trek cast finds Satan, and befriends him. Turns out, all Demons are real, they were mistreated and esnalved by Humans, and now the Trek cast is on a witch trial, where they also defend Satan.</p>

<p>What.</p>

<p>Satan literally teaches them Magic, which is powered by the Power of Gay.</p>

<p>All of this is shown as a good thing.</p>

<p>How in the FUCK did they do this in 1973</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FjwA3XMWAAEP7_2?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>Once Upon a Planet</strong> - TAS
4.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/KwIpAFF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This one disappointed me slightly, the writing has been real smart and good so far, but the crux kinda failed. “Oh you’re an AI who’s sick of serving meat people? You should continue to be a slave!” “Oh okay yes that makes sense”.</p>

<p>I do have to say, I love TAS’s willingness to make sequel episodes. Like… sure, a sequel to the Mudd episodes or Tribbles was maybe obvious, but a sequel to the Shore Leave Planet?? Never woulda expected that.</p>

<p>That’s the episode where Sulu shot a gun btw.</p>

<p>Still one of my favorite moments.</p>

<p>Sulu had more good moments here, though cause of animation error. He was down on the planet, and the teleporters were down so they couldn’t get back up. But every time they showed the cockpit, he was there. So Sulu can teleport.</p>

<p><strong>Mudd’s Passion</strong> - TAS
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/c3KRo5F.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I love Mudd, he’s so good. And when he tends to be around the episodes get just absolutely batshit, and this one is no exception. On this episode, everyone gets infected by a love potion and they all fall in love with each other. Oh boy</p>

<p>It all started cause Nurse Chapel bought into Mudd’s swindling, cause she wanted to make Spock fall in love with her which is… kinda fucked, and unfortunate. Like come on Chapel, be smarter than that. We’ve dealt with Mudd twice now already.</p>

<p>Also they No Homo the love potion. “Oh if two people of the same gender take it, they just become best friends! Opposite genders fall in love!</p>

<p>Nah. Fuck that shit. There is no heterosexual explanation for this.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkTZlMSWIAAk5Gc?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode kept jump cutting to things like “HELP THERE’S A ROCK MONSTER, TELEPORT US UP NOW” <em>jump cut to the teleporter crew dancing</em> and it made me crack the fuck up</p>

<p>Also had this fun animation error. There was no red shirt on this landing party. WHO IS THIS??</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkTaDMCWAAInD6t?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Terratin Incident</strong> - TAS
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Xjtvhdc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A solid episode, very Trekky, but they’re really pushing what they can do here. There’s no way this episode would work in live action, they’re goin’ pretty wild with the ideas.</p>

<p>Every is shrinking, is the concept. Does it well.</p>

<p>Cute writing, cute concept, fun ways they try and tackle their problems while tiny. The ending felt a little… okay I guess, I feel it was maybe a tad rushed? It’s the weakest part of the episode for sure, the sudden conclusion with the Terratins.</p>

<p><strong>The Time Trap</strong> - TAS
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/SQ65POY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Yeah it’s fine. Klingons are always fun. It just feels maybe… a little undercooked, like they could make it a bit more exciting, a bit more fun. Instead it just didn’t QUITE capture me, and I was like “yeah, that was good I guess :)”</p>

<p>They brought back Kor though, which is sick. Also this is the last time we ever saw smooth-head Klingons (except for Trials and Tribblations), as they never appear again in TAS. A shame, but if we gotta say bye to Klingons, Kor is a good note to go out on.</p>

<p><strong>The Ambergris Element</strong> - TAS
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/bXmtk8n.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE TF EPISODE! Kirk and Spock are TF’s into mermaids. It’s not as sexy as one would hope.</p>

<p>Pretty fun, tense in places in a good way, and it’s a neat concept. Quite trekky, but not much else. There are Conservative Mermaids. Conservative Boomer Mermaids suck.</p>

<p><strong>The Slaver Weapon</strong> - TAS
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/GA5Yiwi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This was a very interesting episode. The first one without the captain, at all. Kirk was NEVER seen. It’s just Spock, Sulu, and Uhura, which is an interesting combo, that I like.</p>

<p>Also it had these fuckers the Kzinti. I love them.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkT05YPWIAEHjni?format=png&amp;name=360x360" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They apparently were in Lore Limbo for years, because the writer of this episode, Larry Niven, just imported this race from his book series, Known Space.</p>

<p>They feel out of place, but also like proto TNG ferengi. Very “FEEEMALES”, and weirdly aggressive for no reason</p>

<p>Because this episode is almost a tie-in episode, I guess, it feels odd but I like it. Lots of really weird lore and backstory for this “Slaver” race that’s never done with, ever again.</p>

<p>But hey, the Kzinti are cool. Lookit this sad one with big ol’ eyes.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkT1tEGWYAQabnH?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Eye of the Beholder</strong> - TAS
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/GA5Yiwi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Anti-Zoo episode! As a small summary, Captain Kirk goes to an alien zoo and shoots all of the animals, before being captured by Super Advanced Space Slugs and is locked up. Eventually the slugs let them go.</p>

<p>This episode feels like a GOOD Threshold. Threshold was trying to say “what if the future of humanity isn’t energy gods, but something you wouldn’t expect, like a fish?” and this is that. The future for us is Telepathic Slugs.</p>

<p>This episode was loads of fun.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkT8N0eWIAEa7io?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Jihad</strong> - TAS
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkUCK55XkAAw2Sw?format=png&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Despite having such an unfdortunate name, this episode is great, and it feels like it expands the universe in a really nice way. It’s basically a heist episode, with six of the best aliens for the job, including Kirk and Spock.</p>

<p>I like the alien designs a lot, and they’re all… distinct, and fun characters. Even the woman! Imagine writing a fun and good lady character in the 70s, stunned they had it in them.</p>

<p>This is a great way to end the season. A shame NONE of these designs and species ever came back</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FkUClq1XwAI57bf?format=png&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Pirates of Orion</strong> - TAS
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/X8uZfHs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The start of Season 2! There’s only like, six episodes. But it feels like they got an additional like, hundred dollars of budget, and used it where it counts. Animation is improved, lots of angles, especially for the spaceships.</p>

<p>The episode itself is rather strong too. Lots of fun character moments (albeit weird Bones racism), tense moments, good clever Kirk trying to figure out how to handle an alien menace, lots of lore building. A genuinely solid as hell episode.</p>

<p><strong>Bem</strong> - TAS</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/jHSBdsT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>6.5/10</p>

<p>I found points of this annoying. It was trying to do a high concept thing, and the designs are sick, but I think it missed the mark slightly, and Bem as a character is really annoying, just an asshole.</p>

<p>BUT they let Uhura run the ship! YAY!</p>

<p>The best way I can describe this is “one asshole creates problems on purpose to test people who weren’t ready for it, then lets them die when they fail, running off to create more problems.”</p>

<p><strong>The Practical Joker</strong> - TAS
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/DU2no6A.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Enterprise becomes sentient, and she’s a fucking asshole. This is the first Holodeck episode, and the first “shit goes wrong in the Holodeck” episode, which is the only kind of Holodeck episode.</p>

<p>Mostly kinda funny, not much else.</p>

<p><strong>Albatross</strong> - TAS
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/fl8yZSh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A good episode, nice who dun it, intense, fun designs and concepts, trekky ending and figuring out where the plague comes from, and Spock doing a fucking jail break to save everyone is SO wild, Spock would never do that, but I love it.</p>

<p>Everyone gets infected by this thing that turns you blue, then green, then red</p>

<p>GOBLIN KIRK!</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FlbqhxQWIAQRtLs?format=jpg&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>How Sharper Than a Serpent’s Tooth</strong> - TAS
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Mk52gg9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A very Trek episode name. And a very neat episode! It’s kind of a god-episode, but I feel it’s done nicely, and it helps it’s a very Native American centric episode, written by someone from the actual culture. It shows.</p>

<p>Apparently, it’s made partly to spite white people going “oh those native savages couldn’t make cities, aliens must have done it”. In this episode, it shows that this Native American God came to earth and taught EVERYONE how to build cities.</p>

<p>It’s Adonais, but good.</p>

<p>And while usually I don’t like aggressive god characters, this one, Kukulkan, is less an aggressive bratty godlike being, and more a lonely old guy who views us as his kids, and wants to help people. While also being kinda stubborn. It’s cute. I feel bad for him.</p>

<p>Hilariously, everyone pronounces Kukulkan correctly except Shatner. Oh, Shatner. Also, this is the only Emmy Trek ever won! Good job Trek.</p>

<p>Also, one more thing. There’s this animation error where Uhura is white.</p>

<p>White Uhura isn’t real, she can’t hurt you.</p>

<p><img src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FlbxuyqXEAEqd8-?format=png&amp;name=small" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>The Counter-Clock Incident</strong> - TAS
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/zDKdNzI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A universe where everything works the opposite is silly. Dead stars supernova into a live ones. A person’s children are old. It’s silly, and needs a LOT of handwaving. I can’t suspend my debelief enough for this.</p>

<p>But the over all theme of the episode is nice. An old, about to retire Commadore (at the ancient age of 75, the only good Commadore apparently) is with them and ages to being young, but decides to go back to being old. It’s silly but heartwarming.</p>

<p>And that is Season 2 of The Animated Series, and that’s the Animated Series all together! Bad animation, obviously, but there were like, no bad episodes. At all. It was very enjoyable, and I highly recommend people just watch the entire thing.</p>

<p>It’s not even long!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="TAS" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, over the past year, I have been watching the entirety of Star Trek, and been posting my thoughts on all the episodes and movies as I watch them. Now, I’ve been posting them on Twitter, and I’ll probably continue to do so until that website explodes. But I’ve been putting off putting all my thoughts on this site…. but I’ll go ahead and do that now!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - The Original Series Season 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/01/LizstartrekTOS2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - The Original Series Season 2" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/01/LizstartrekTOS2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/01/LizstartrekTOS2.html"><![CDATA[<p>So, over the past year, I have been watching the entirety of Star Trek, and been posting my thoughts on all the episodes and movies as I watch them. Now, I’ve been posting them on Twitter, and I’ll probably continue to do so until that website explodes. But I’ve been putting off putting all my thoughts on this site…. but I’ll go ahead and do that now!</p>

<p>SO! If you’re interested in my thoughts on every episode of Star Trek, and boy why wouldn’t you be, or if you’re interested in just re-living Star Trek with me, go ahead and read on! For future series where I probably ONLY post here, these will have a lot more thoughts on them, but the first few were only one Twitter post, so maybe not in depth.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Amok Time</strong> - TOS 7.5/10</p>

<p>IT’S FUCK OR DIE FRIDAY! HORNY SPOCK TIME! #LETSPOCKFUCK</p>

<p>First Season 2 episode! What a wild time. Like, I GEDDIT, but it’s still weird to me that no one knows how Vulcans fuck. If you asked a human, they’d love to SHOW you how they fuck.</p>

<p>I have to say, Spock’s fiance? The worst person in this entire series. What a fucking asshole. “Oh I didn’t want to marry you, so I made you kill your best friend instead :) Highly logical”</p>

<p>Highly go fuck yourself lol hope you’re both miserable together</p>

<p><strong>Who Mourns for Adonais?</strong> - TOS 1/10</p>

<p>Not ONLY is it a Manchild God Alien episode, but it’s also a Women Ruin Everything episode! It has a surprising amount of good lines but no, I hated this. Also, this is the first episode where Scotty is an idiot. I HATED this. I am so fucking sick of the episodes where there’s a woman, only for this episode, who ruins things for the crew, and joins the bad guy cause he’s hot and seduces her. It’s happened like literally four times. It’s very 60s and it’s RUINING episodes for me.</p>

<p>“Oh but he’s so nice and kind to me and I LOVE him!”</p>

<p>YOU’VE KNOWN HIM FOR TWENTY MINUTES, AND HE’S INTENDING TO ENSLAVE HUMANITY, I DON’T GIVE A SHIT HOW HOT HE IS</p>

<p>The good lines are the ONLY positive thing to this. “I’ve never met a god before” says the woman in love with the God. “You still havent”, says Kirk</p>

<p><strong>The Changeling</strong> - TOS
6/10</p>

<p>This is fine. Pretty tense. The Uhura subplot seemed unnecessary, and the final bits were weird and unfitting, but I liked the tense setups and the conclusion to the villain exploding. ERROR. ERROR.</p>

<p>Also how Scotty gets FLUUUUNG</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Sva0Iqb.png" alt="blue" /></p>

<p><strong>Mirror Mirror</strong> - TOS
9/10</p>

<p>Classic for a reason. Very tense and fun premise. I love how this autocratic alternate universe with ruthless monsters has all these races living together in harmony. Mirror Universe is fucked up, but cool.</p>

<p>I wanna say, Mirror Spock? Amazing. Makes me love Spock even more. Spock is the only character to be y’know, a legit great individual in this entire universe. Everyone else is fucked up</p>

<p>Also <strong>holy shit Nimoy with a beard is so fucking hot jesus christ</strong></p>

<p><strong>The Apple</strong> - TOS
3/10</p>

<p>Mostly boring, but the parts that weren’t as boring were bad. Why did Chekov and this random woman fuck in the middle of these woods? I dunno. She never even shows up again. Unsatisfying ending too, just “oh we shot it to death let’s go, after we Teach Tribals To Fuck”</p>

<p><strong>The Doomsday Machine</strong> - TOS
7/10</p>

<p>Good setup, but the Commodore RUINS this for me. Coulda been pretty great but he’s an unstable asshole with power and no one can stop him cause that’s how military works. I have no tolerance for that shit and I can’t enjoy seeing it. Then the fucking episode tries to get me to SYMPATHIZE FOR THIS GUY? No. No I cannot do that. He attempted to kill everyone on the Enterprise and swung his power-dick around to make sure it’d happen. Fuck him, he can stay eaten in the Giant Space Tube Sock.</p>

<p><strong>Catspaw</strong> - TOS
2.5/10</p>

<p>A few good lines, but this was a real stinker. Another “Bored God who does what they want” episode. Even Shatner seemed checked out, he mumbled every line. The special effects are laughable, but that doesn’t save this episode. I don’t mind the idea of a “Bored God Who Does What They Want” ep, but it has to be actually good. This was just ludicrous, and obviously an attempt at a Halloween episode, and I know that, because they held back on the release schedule to release it on Halloween.</p>

<p>Also, in this episode, every single senior officer is on the planet, except Uhura, who SHOULD be in charge, but they invented a guy to suddenly be in charge so the black woman wouldn’t sit in the captain’s chair. He’s an ASSISTANT ENGINEER. WHY IS HE IN CHARGE?</p>

<p><strong>I, Mudd</strong> - TOS
10/10</p>

<p>Wow I loved this. I disliked the previous Mudd episode because the topic was uninteresting/sexist, but when you just let Mudd be Mudd, he’s VERY entertaining. All the characterization in this ep was astounding, I loved the acting and silliness.</p>

<p>Mudd should have come back for more, this series needed more reoccuring characters. Trek never really had that until like, DS9 maybe?</p>

<p>When this episode gets off the rails, it gets REAL off the rails, but the actors were clearly having a blast, and I was too.</p>

<p><strong>Metamorphosis</strong> - TOS
5.5/10</p>

<p>Perfectly passable. Fun lore, interesting enough concept, a god-like being that’s NOT an asshole is cool. I like how that whole war thing that was VERY important is handwaved at the end. Absolutely skippable tho.</p>

<p><strong>The Trouble with Tribbles</strong> - TOS
10/10</p>

<p>A classic well loved one for a reason. I don’t even have much to add. Loads of fun. I want to note, I think I’m realizing my favorite thing in Trek is the characters riffing off each other. This has that in SPAAAADES.</p>

<p>Oh forgot to mention about the Tribbles: Bones describes them as “bisexual”. I assume he meant they produce asexually, but I’ll just go ahead and accept that they’re bisexual, which means the Tribbles are officially the first queer characters in Star Trek!</p>

<p><strong>Journey to Babel</strong> - TOS
7/10</p>

<p>Stressful but interesting, I like all the Vulcan stuff, and Sarek is fun. I was confused why Spock’s mom was so anti letting Spock donate blood, then in the next scene was ANGRY he wouldn’t? Humans be fickle I guess.</p>

<p>Sareks a bottom lol</p>

<p><strong>Friday’s Child</strong> - TOS
4/10</p>

<p>I like the Ensign who saw a Klingon and immediately tried to shoot him, despite the peace treaty. RIP Racist Redshirt Grant.</p>

<p>I mostly found this uncomfortable and uninteresting. Usually I’d like alien culture stuff but these weren’t super great. The McCoy romance thing was also pretty uncomfortable. I felt the entire plot with that woman wasn’t done super great. And Kirk’s weird aggressiveness is on full display here for a bit… before it’s completely forgotten again. Maybe that’s even worse.</p>

<p><strong>The Deadly Years</strong> - TOS
4.5/10</p>

<p>Good ideas but lots of missed opportunity. I feel like the entire scenario with Kirk getting court martialed was… unnecessary. Just step down, dude, you’re clearly dying and unfit to lead right now.</p>

<p>Also everyone being grumpy is understandable… but not pleasant to watch.</p>

<p>The Commodore was the only high ranking officer I’ve seen who I respect and understand the orders from, but the episode makes it act like he as in the wrong when he was nooootttt.</p>

<p>The age makeup was also a bit disappointing. Old does not = being blond? I love how no seemed to want the old age makeup but DeForest Kelley was like “LATHER THAT SHIT ON ME”</p>

<p>Coulda also explored what aging is like. Instead everyone is grumpy and mean. Ah well.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/kvw4PWr.png" alt="blue" /></p>

<p><strong>A Piece of the Action</strong> - TOS
10/10</p>

<p>If you want a solid piece of Star Trek, that’s very Star Trekey, don’t watch this. This is a shitpost. It was so unbelievably entertaining, and so fucking stupid, I really couldn’t help but fall in love. What the fuck is this ep.</p>

<p>I’m starting to realize when the actors are just hamming it up and having clearly a good time just acting and being dumb, it’s the best thing ever. It reminded me of I, Mudd. Kirk and Spock doing dumb Gangster impersonations. Kirk driving a car badly. All perfect.</p>

<p>What are the implications of this? How does this reflect on how Kirk is as a captain? Is it in character? Who gives a shit? It’s fucking hilarious. I could spend maybe five tweets just saying quotes from this episode, and I wouldn’t get to em all.</p>

<p>Oh one more thing…. I think Kirk is at his best when he’s showing how extremely clever and quick on his feet he is in tricky situations. That card scene was genius Kirk at his best. Other Kirks? Throw em out. Angry Kirk? No. Horny Kirk? No. Clever Genius Kirk? Yes</p>

<p><strong>Obsession</strong> - TOS
1/10</p>

<p>Oh good, it’s Angry Kirk again! I know last ep I said Kirk acting out of character was okay, but there’s a difference: That episode was fun. This wasn’t. Kirk got five men killed cause of revenge, and that’s NOT KIRKISH AT ALL.</p>

<p>The episode tries to go for a Captain Ahab Moby Dick thing, but the writers didn’t realize Ahab is the VILLAIN, AND YOU’RE NOT SUPPOSED TO LIKE HIM. He’s a madman getting everyone killed for no reason. This shit didn’t work with the windsock ep, it doesn’t work here</p>

<p>I’mma codify something.</p>

<p><strong>Lizstar’s Sliding Scale of Kirks</strong>. There are four Kirks in ToS depending on writers</p>

<p>1) Socially Clever Kirk. Can get out of any sticky wicket. #1.
2) Emotionally intelligent Kirk. Morally upright.
3) Horny Kirk. Boring but okay
4) ANGY KIRK. AVOID AT ALL COSTS.</p>

<p><strong>The Gamesters of Triskellion</strong> - TOS
2/10</p>

<p>Ugh. Weird, creepy, Horny Kirk is here and I hate him. Also this is VERY stereotypical bad Trek like, this is what people think Star Trek is. Naked Kirk horning on space babes, Kirk-fu-ing, and yelling at Space Brains.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/Y0f0izZ.png" alt="blue" /></p>

<p>Whoever Kirk hired to do his top surgery needs to be sued for malpractice.</p>

<p><strong>The Immunity Syndrome</strong> - TOS
7/10</p>

<p>Quotable, stressful, and fun. Full disclosure, I passed out for ten minutes due to pain, I don’t blame the episode on that.</p>

<p>When everyone was giving commendations, sure they wouldn’t survive, it was actually emotionally powerful.  If the episode was extremely shit for the ten minutes I was passed out, I’ll take full responsibility lol but it was probably of even quality</p>

<p><strong>A Private Little War</strong> - TOS
2/10</p>

<p>Ugh. Like I see what they were going for? But it wasn’t resolved in ANY good way. And the random sexual assault and “weak woman” was SO unnecessary.</p>

<p>Just remove that character, and it becomes… better, but not good. Ugh.</p>

<p><strong>Return to Tomorrow</strong> - TOS
9/10</p>

<p>THIS is how you do a God Episode! I was shocked by how good this was, most of the TOS episodes in late season 2 have been… bad.</p>

<p>Very interesting and fun. I really loved evil smiling creepy Spock, too.</p>

<p>I was literally astounded how empathetic this godlike being was, Sargon. Star Trek doesn’t have… good track records with god entities? And yes, two of the three aren’t as good, but I think that made sense and fit the story very well</p>

<p>Also Polaski is here! :D Kinda. It’s her actor lol</p>

<p><strong>Patterns of Force</strong> - TOS
7/10</p>

<p>You know, for an episode where the thesis is “The crew of Star Trek visit Nazi Germany”, I liked it WAY more than I expected. When I first saw the nazi uniforms I went “oh my GOD.” Like, they’re seriously going there? WW2 was still very fresh when this was shot. Most of the people there lived through it. Shit, Scotty’s actor fought in it. So like, it was much better than I thought. But it didn’t quite… go as hard as I was hoping. Like, Wolfenstein showing Nazis as idiots style.</p>

<p>The ending didn’t hit as good as I wanted. Oh here was the GOOD nazi, who didn’t want bloodshed, and believed in the fuhrer’s original message of… fascism. Hes going to make it better!</p>

<p>I don’t even know how they would have made it work otherwise. But whoofa doofa</p>

<p>Also holy shit imagine being a historian in a socialist utopia in the year 2268 and thinking “you know what was a great society, and what political body we should emulate to uplift this planet? The fucking NAZIS. Truly the only bad thing about them was the murder!”</p>

<p>Also I don’t know if it was fully intended, but I did find this point amazing: You know how in ToS, all aliens are just humans? That works well here. They’re racist to aliens but CANNOT TELL THEM APART IF THEY’RE IN UNIFORM. It’s so blunt with the message, I love it</p>

<p>I had a LOT to say about this episode, for an episode I only gave a 7/10, but it had a lot of potential to really say something, about how societies turn to fascism, how good people buy into evil. But it kinda just pinned it all on one evil guy in the end. A shame.</p>

<p><strong>By Any Other Name</strong> - TOS
8/10</p>

<p>Quite fun. Had that eerie energy, and really sets up the bad guys as sinister and unstoppable. But how are they stopped? By humans being fucking weird.</p>

<p>The Scotty drinking scene is legendary. “It’s uh, well… it’s green!”</p>

<p><strong>The Omega Glory</strong> - TOS
1/10</p>

<p>Wow, this is shit. When they brought out the American Flag me and Neli just screamed out ‘WHAT THE FUCK IS THIS WHY IS THIS EPISODE DOING THIS”</p>

<p>Alternate Earth, if the Commies won. Racist, unscientific, trying to do… something, failing</p>

<p>There was a mother fucker who was evil for no reason who was just Gehn from Riven. The plot about the “yellows” (ACTUAL TERM THEY USE) and the diseases is ignored and forgotten for weird American self masturbation.</p>

<p>Absolute garbage, prolly the worst episode so far. This was one of the three pilots they wrote. Thank fuck they made the other two first and re-used this later cause if this was pitched as the pilot, Lucille Ball would have gone “fuck this shit”, and she’d be right to.</p>

<p>Star Trek succeeded in spite of Roddenberry.</p>

<p>This episode was so extremely bad that we checked out 10 minutes in, kept going “oh my god there’s still so much episode left” and started pausing it to look at dumb shit, like when we paused it to point and laugh at Kirk’s underwear being in the shot</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/qHJFvww.png" alt="blue" /></p>

<p><strong>The Ultimate Computer</strong> - TOS
6.5/10</p>

<p>Langstrom had a great actor, good energy to him. I like Clever Kirk outwitting a computer again, he’s good at that. Also, an actual good Commadore! I’m just not into the theme of “IF I CAN’T HAVE POWER AM I REALLY A MAN?!”</p>

<p><strong>Bread and Circuses</strong> - TOS
3/10</p>

<p>I have a lot of thoughts on this. First, this season had a LOT of “weve lost a guy on a planet! Oops, turns out they betrayed the prime directive and are fascists now” type stories. This is like the third one. Heart of Darkness its not</p>

<p>Second, ToS has too many fuckin’ “this planet is just Earth again but X”. And they’re NEVER done well. As a history buff and a big fan of alternate history, a world where the Roman Empire never fell would be NOTHING like this. WHY ARE THEY SPEAKING ENGLISH? It’s not even just a “oh come on Liz they’re just using the translator”, no, THEY SPECIFICALLY STATE THAT THEY SPEAK ENGLISH.</p>

<p>And then the final stinger of the fucking episode. Oh that cult that helped us? The cult that worshiped the sun? You all misunderstood. They worshiped the son! PRAISE BE TO JESUS!</p>

<p>This writer can bite me.</p>

<p><strong>Mission: Earth</strong> - TOS
3/10</p>

<p>This episode almost offends me as a Star Trek fan, because its not a Trek episode. It was a back-door pilot for Roddenberry’s Dr. Who knock off cause he thought Trek would be cancelled. And it’s all just kinda boring/bad.</p>

<p>Any of the actual parts that involve the Trek characters is annoying cause they’re acting like idiots. Why the fuck are they time traveling into the past for “observation”. That’s dangerous. Cut that shit out.</p>

<p>Any of the parts with this Gary Seven dude just read like bad fanfiction.</p>

<p>The best part was the cat doll that was flung at people and made chimpanzee noises. The rest was kinda boring or annoying.</p>

<p>…Welp, that’s season 2 of ToS. It got… pretty bad by the end there. Hopefully season 3 is at least FUNNY bad instead of just boring.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="TOS" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, over the past year, I have been watching the entirety of Star Trek, and been posting my thoughts on all the episodes and movies as I watch them. Now, I’ve been posting them on Twitter, and I’ll probably continue to do so until that website explodes. But I’ve been putting off putting all my thoughts on this site…. but I’ll go ahead and do that now!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - The Original Series Movies</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/01/LizstartrekTOSmovies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - The Original Series Movies" /><published>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/01/LizstartrekTOSmovies</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2023/01/01/LizstartrekTOSmovies.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve finished watching the Original Series, so now it’s time for the MOVIES! I’ve decided to make a new thread for all of the Original Series movies, so if you’re interested in my thoughts, follow through!</p>

<p>Engage!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Star Trek the Motion Picture</strong></p>

<p>5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0598/2925/products/18X24_120.jpg?v=1598887171" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s not… bad. It’s just kinda boring. It has some cool ideas, neat effects and setpieces, relatively good acting, but oh my god. The movie starts with 2 minutes of a black screen and half the scenes are that interesting.</p>

<p>The infamous scenes are the scenes where they’re flying by the Enterprise and it’s glamour shots while cutting back to Kirk and Scotty smiling, for like 3 minutes. Or the scene of Spock in a space suit.</p>

<p>This movie is kinda “We have 2001 A Space Odyssey At Home”.</p>

<p>It’s to the point where the Director’s Cut REMOVES LIKE 45 MINUTES FROM THE MOVIE. How do you even pull that off?</p>

<p>So yeah, its pacing is the only really terrible part, apart from all the behind the scenes horrible sexist shit like Roddenberry always pulled.</p>

<p>The plot is… interesting. I really like the Voyager plot twist actually? I think it’s kinda creative and cute, out of left field. Pretty Trekky. Dekker having sex with V’ger was… weird and unnecessary, and the “new lifeform” part was also… cheesy and meh.</p>

<p>Some parts of this movie are shockingly fucked up, like the teleporter fuck up. And then they immediately beam over Bones, prolly not telling him what just happened cause he’d threaten to maul them if he knew.</p>

<p>Also, Bones with a Beard is WAY TOO SEXY. FUCK.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/RqMEpVn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A lot of this movie really feels like “we need to differentiate ourselves from Star Wars” but to its detriment. I often mock the series for shoving in fisticuffs to bring in some action but this movie maybe needed a BIT of it. But it really is beautiful.</p>

<p>The fact that this movie’s main problem is pacing considering the hellish production cycle it went through is honestly impressive. Oh, one more fun thing, all the new designs feel VERY proto-TNG, a lot of the designs feel like how they’d be in TNG, years later.</p>

<p><strong>Trek II The Wrath of Khan</strong></p>

<p>10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BNmZiZmM2OTUtZDlmOC00YzYyLThkMGEtZWFkMjJmM2EwZDVkXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMjUzOTY1NTc@._V1_.jpg" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Good fucking God, watching this after The Motion Picture was like night and god damn day. This movie being so damn good RUINS TMP even more. That movie gets so much worse when compared to this, it puts spotlights on its inadequacies. I almost feel its not fair on the poor movie.</p>

<p>First of all, the writing. Like, the themes of getting old was in TMP, but it’s much better here. The Moby Dick inspirations are here like they were in two TOS episodes, but here it’s SO much better cause THE AHAB CHARACTER IS THE VILLAIN, TOS. COME ON.</p>

<p>And most importantly, the characters are… the characters. Many of em felt off in TMP, here they bicker and snark like they usually do. There were no good Trio Conversation scenes in TMP. Here they’re in spades, and the characters feel GREAT and the lines are FUNNY</p>

<p>Secondly, the acting. On god damn point, every part of it. Even SHATNER acted well, and that’s only because the director intentionally made him act out scenes dozens of times until he got lazy and toned down the ham acting. It works well.</p>

<p>And Spock. Whoo boy.</p>

<p>I, of course, cried. How can you not?</p>

<p>This is not a perfect movie. But the things I’d change are like a few minor things. As it is, it’s a Trek Movie done perfectly. It’s a great entertaining film while ALSO being Trek, which is hard to do.</p>

<p>Absolutely loved it.I gave the Motion Picture a 5/10, and watching Khan immediately after feels unfair to it because now I wanna give it like a 3/10. I was like “yeah it’s boring but a bunch of things in it are nice” and now I’m like “holy shit THEY COULDA DONE THIS THE WHOLE TIME?!”</p>

<p>It’s worth noting Roddenberry had barely anything to do with this movie. He had notes, they were ignored.</p>

<p>Also, the Spock scenes at the end. Nimoy wanted OUT of this franchise, then loved making this movie SO MUCH he asked to be put back in, and to direct the next~</p>

<p>Oh, one more thought.</p>

<p>The costume designs. TMP had “throw away one use outfits, cause that’s futuristic”. Khan has outfits that FEEL ACTUALLY FUTURISTIC, and look REALLY cool. Thank GOD they ignored Roddenberry this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/D1U2w0L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/SQzTmRG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/KKp7gQX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><strong>Star Trek III: The Search for Spock</strong></p>

<p>8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://pics.filmaffinity.com/Star_Trek_III_The_Search_for_Spock-610988897-large.jpg" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Super strong movie. It’s funny, any time you hear ANYONE bring this up, they go “Oh yeah, 3. It’s the best of the odd numbered movies!” which yes it is. But it’s a great character driven piece, and it surprised me!</p>

<p>This movie is Nimoy’s first directing credit, and for his first movie, he decided the story would be about his best friends wanting to give him a traditional Jewish funeral which is funny</p>

<p>Khan was much more… focused, but this is good in different ways.</p>

<p>A lot of the scenes were really fun too, like it felt less like one solid plot like Khan did but more a bunch of tiny but great character moments.</p>

<p>Also, Christopher Lloyd was… more subdued than I expected. I wanted him HAMMY AS HELL. He was only KINDA hammy.</p>

<p>It was nice to see a prototype for TNG Klingons, tho. Its the first time a Klingon says the word “honor”! Q’PLAH!</p>

<p>Also Horny Spock Needs To Fuck was the ONLY thing I knew about this movie but it wasn’t as bad as I expected. That was apparently aaall Roddenberry.</p>

<p>Also lots of emotional scenes here too. Kirk’s son’s death, the fucking Enterprise blowing up. And the self destruct scene is JUST like it was in The Racism episode, too! Cool!</p>

<p>…..I’m VERY excited to watch the next movie, though &gt;w&gt;</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek IV: The Voyage Home</strong></p>

<p>10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BZmU3ZGE3NzEtYTdmYi00YTYxLWIxYTItZGY5YjFlOTA2NWI3XkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMjUzOTY1NTc@._V1_.jpg" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Let me preface this by saying this is an EXTREMELY DIFFERENT 10/10 to Wrath of Khan, because this is a very different movie. It’s almost untrekky, in a way. It’s a lot of screwball goofy comedy, done very well.</p>

<p>I feel like whichever is your favorite (2 or 4, maybe you’re a weirdo who lives 5 the most I dunno you), it just depends on taste. Because both are really practically perfect movies that set out to do what they wanted to do. Which do I prefer?</p>

<p>Well, I’m a goofball</p>

<p>I just really admire the fucking audacity of Nimoy writing this concept. What do we make the movie about? Okay, whales are extinct, a probe is killing the Earth, we need to go back in the past and find some whales.</p>

<p>What the fuck. That’s so silly</p>

<p>I fucking love it</p>

<p>It almost reminds me of A Piece of the Action. Is this the most logical realistic story? No. Who the fuck cares. Space Whales.</p>

<p>Is Spock saying “Damn” and “Hell” to try and blend into Earth Society realistic? Who gives a shit, it’s fucking hilarious</p>

<p>The movie really sells it too. Like yeah it’s goofball comedy, and if they winked and nodded to the audience going “ha ha isn’t this WACKY?” it woulda been AWFUL</p>

<p>But it’s treated as so serious, it really makes me latch on and go “Hell YEAH we gotta save the whales”</p>

<p>I think it’s a great conclusion to the 2-4 trilogy. 2 and 3 are… so serious, so emotional. It’s real good, and hits and lands well, but this is like a breath of relief. The fun at the end. Yes it’s still serious and the stakes are high, but the levity is needed.</p>

<p>I want to add, I’m really bad with awkward comedy. But I kinda still love it? I muted the movie during the “hello computer” scene cause Scotty being silly was hilarious but also gave me The Office vibes.</p>

<p>Also omg the fucking Hospital scene with the wacky music</p>

<p>Bones and Spock keep bouncing back and forth as my favorite characters, this movie made Bones bounce to the front. “My GOD it’s the dark ages!” <em>grows a woman a kidney</em></p>

<p>Or the scene where he and Scotty say “is it right to change the future? Eh. Whatever.”</p>

<p>This movie was the highest grossing Trek film until 2009’s Reboot Film. When I said it’s less Trekky, that also means it’s more… accessible. I get why this was popular. My mom said it was her favorite lol</p>

<p>This woulda been a good one to end on. Alas…</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek V: The Final Frontier</strong></p>

<p>4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0018/7337/9427/products/ST-V-P-Premium-Stain-Poster-RO_620x.png?v=1603469944" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>If I was rating this on enjoyment, it’s like a 6/10. Way higher than TMP. Rating on just quality, like a 3, 3.5 on a good day. So I’ll even it out to a 4. I weirdly liked a lot of parts of this, but not for good reasons</p>

<p>I’ll say, #1 reason I enjoy this in any way, is Sybok. His actor is good (and very hot, jfc), he’s a fun villain who’s like, barely a villain. I think a lot of him could be better explored, themes and whatnot are just… left on the table. Especially involving god</p>

<p><img src="https://i.imgur.com/MYEhXTI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The premise of the movie is easily mockable. It’s SO easy to make fun of, but it’s way better than I remembered/expected it to be. The problem is, it was supposed to be serious but Shatner is a bad director, so that failed, then Executive Meddling forced it funny</p>

<p>Which makes sense, the previous movie pushed the funny to 11. That sold, let’s do that again. But they slashed the budget and the writing fails too. Lots of jokes just don’t land, or are awkward. And it doesn’t fit the serious bits.</p>

<p>I really love how there’s a scene where McCoy tackles the grief and guilt he feels about euthanizing his father. It’s touching, and kind of powerful. This was 20 minutes after Uhura does a half naked caberet dance to distract some guards. I’m saying it’s got a tone problem.</p>

<p>Some things are also just not the deal they’re made out to be. Wow, the Enterprise is breaking down (PS, why is the Federation so shit at making new ships). This won’t be a problem in the plot. Ooh, here are our three hostages. Only one has any plot significance.</p>

<p>It did its best in the circumstances though I think. The original plot involved literal Satan and going to hell to save McCoy, so it COULD HAVE BEEN WAY WORSE.</p>

<p>Anyway, I love Sybok, he is my sexy Vulcan boyfriend. Plus, canonically into trans women, based</p>

<p><strong>Star Trek VI - The Undiscovered Country</strong></p>

<p>11/10</p>

<p><img src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BYzJiZDdmODQtMDM0Yi00ZTcwLWJjMjItM2QxOWJjZDdmYmQ5XkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyMjUzOTY1NTc@._V1_.jpg" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This did it. It broke the scale.</p>

<p>This was actually my first time watching this movie, and uh, holy shit. I knew it was supposed to be good but I was stunned how good it was. And such a perfect send off to TOS.</p>

<p>It really feels like the perfect end to the storyline of the series, and moving forward into TNG. And that’s what it’s about, moving forward, constantly forward, progressing, becoming better, despite all things trying to hold us back.</p>

<p>ALSO IT HAS A LOT OF KLINGONS!</p>

<p>I LOVE KLINGONS. THEY’RE ALL SO GOOD. Gorkon is like Abraham Lincoln Gorbachev, Chang is SO GOOD as a main villain.</p>

<p>Also Trek had never done anything like this. This movie had… MYSTIQUE. ESPIONAGE. Who dunnit, politics, conspiracy. And it did it SO WELL.</p>

<p>The other 10/10 movies are so good, obviously, but they’re, for Khan, a strong tense character piece, and for Voyage Home, it was super funny character piece. This is both. And also great lore building. This is the most lore building Trek EVER had to this point.</p>

<p>I dunno if I can even come up with flaws. Like there’s parts I disliked, but that was the point. Most of it, I was stunned how into it I was. On the edge of my seat, constantly. I was ENRAPTURED.</p>

<p>Wow. I fucking loved this. I can’t imagine anything topping it.</p>

<p>This is also the end to my ToS movies thread. Over all? Real enjoyable movies. I didnt NOT enjoy any of em. I barely enjoyed TMP I guess, but I did enjoy em all. I’m surprised I liked em all so much, and how good they were over all.</p>

<p>Next up… the animated series.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="TOS" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve finished watching the Original Series, so now it’s time for the MOVIES! I’ve decided to make a new thread for all of the Original Series movies, so if you’re interested in my thoughts, follow through!]]></summary></entry></feed>