<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-15T12:13:04-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 134</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/15/OOCY134.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 134" /><published>2025-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/15/OOCY134</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/15/OOCY134.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QXH50nQ.png" alt="'There's a girl I like. But I've realized she'll never be mine alone. So I've decided I'll start by getting to know her girlfriend and her girlfriend's girlfriend.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Let’s be friends first</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Let&apos;s be friends first" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 168 - The Yakyuuken Special - Kon’ya wa 12-kaisen!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/15/RA168-Yakyuuken.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 168 - The Yakyuuken Special - Kon’ya wa 12-kaisen!!" /><published>2025-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/15/RA168-Yakyuuken</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/15/RA168-Yakyuuken.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EhzjRxr.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I can promise you, by the end, this will be the longest written document about this game on the internet. I could explain the entire game in two sentences, but instead, I have a lot to say.</p>

<p>Yakyuuken Special is porn. You might look and go “wait a minute, what? Porn on the Saturn?” Yes. There’s actually like, 4-6 Saturn games that are porn. Notably, softcore porn. I don’t think penetration happens anywhere on the console, but there are some titties if you know where to look. This is one of those cases. Though, Yakyuuken is actually not originally from the Saturn. This is a port of a 3DO game, and it also got an unlicensed release on the PS1. All versions are essentially the same, except this has 4 more girls than the 3DO version, and the RNG is slightly different. I’ll get into it.</p>

<p>Why DID I play this game? Do I want to ogle 18 year old Japanese girls? Not particularly. See, on Retro Achievements, the site tracks who has the most masteries for each console. And I noticed I was close to the top for Saturn. So why not tackle some of the easier Saturn games and get a free mastery, right? That was the idea, and this game actually was in the “Free Points” hub, showing it was a piss easy game that would take you like 20-40 minutes, and give you free points, however few. By the time I’d be done playing this game, 8 months later, it would not have that label anymore, and it wasn’t by my hand. Someone else looked at it and went “oh god, no, we’re leading people into a trap”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/03CUnBs.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Allow me to explain how this game works. The game starts up, and you press start to get past the title screen. Then you get a menu of 12 girls, A brings you in to the girl you want. Then you see the girl, there’s a bit of info, her age, her sizes, shit like that. Then a little FMV with her, and then it’s into the game proper.</p>

<p>Each battle, as it were, starts with the girl doing a goofy little jig. She swings her hips left and right, does a little spin, shakes her ass into the camera, spins back around, jumps, and throws her hand out. At this point, the FMV freezes and you must press A, B, or C. Each will send out either Rock, Paper, or Scissors. Then you get an animation of your hands clashing, and if you win, she loses health, and there’s an FMV cutscene of her stripping. More likely, though, is that you lose, and it jumps back to the ass jig. If you DO win, she strips and her ass jiggling is with a little less clothing on, until you take all five HP off of her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UM2725F.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If you DO manage to do that, she will remove her last article of clothing, her panties. She will turn herself in a way where you can’t even really see the panties being removed, and then she’ll curl her leg over anything, so you in fact see LESS than when she had her panties ON. But then it freezes, so I guess you can jork it, and then you can press any button to go to another girl. It doesn’t track that you’ve won, and there’s no unlockables, but look at all 12 girls, and you’re done. You win, as it were. Easy peasy, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZShdZWH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I did not, in fact, play this game for 8 straight months. I played it on and off. But by the end, I was getting annoyed, and I developed a strategy. See, the game can play itself.</p>

<p>If you hold X and Z, it skips the ass jiggle cutscene, jumping you right to the RPS. This does not skip the stripping, but that’s okay. And if you hold A as well, it’ll just throw out rock over and over. But isn’t that bad? Won’t the game realize it, and stop you? Nope! See, the way RNG works in this game, is with every move you make, it determines whether you win, or lose. That’s it. That’s all it decides. Win, or lose. I won most of these matches by throwing rock over and over and over. It was straight up the real version of that fucking Simpsons meme. Good ol’ Rock. Nothing beats that.</p>

<p>Of course, the RNG is stacked against you, but that’s okay. We just need one more thing to make this game play itself. Put the start button on turbo, so it’s always pressing start, and you’re good. You can’t HOLD start to get past the title screen, but pressing it is fine. The game then keeps track of which girl you were playing, and with those three buttons held down, and start being pressed every few frames, you have the game playing itself. I put all of those buttons on one button, and put a fucking candle on my space bar, and went to bed. Game solved, right?</p>

<p>Nope. This worked for most of the girls, but then I got to my nemesis.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rsu15KR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is Rie Kouno. My villaness. Pretty sure she’s the oldest girl here, actually. She’s got this like, Japanese Housewife energy to her, as if 22 is 45 years old, cause this game is make by perverts with bad views on women. But anyway, my strategy did not work on her. I left the game playing, on double speed, for <strong>two days</strong>. And I did not win. By the end of the five days, I had assumed I had run through the entire RNG track, and it didn’t work. So I tried on Paper. Still nothing, two days later. Scissors? Nothing.</p>

<p>So, she beat me. I knuckled down and played the game legit for this one last girl, and yes, eventually I did it. She took her stupid panties off, and I won. I felt nothing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wnBP3sD.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This expression will haunt me for the rest of my life. This is the face of a woman who knows you’re not getting any tonight. She’s seen the future and knows every single move you’ll make. Imagine being a horny Japanese pervert, tired after a long day of work, and you get home, ready to jork it to your favorite game, and this girl looks at you like this and goes “nuh uh, no tits for you” with that fucking smile on her face.</p>

<p>I think it’s safe to say I did not enjoy The Yakyuuken Special: Kon’ya wa 12-kaisen!!. It made me feel gross if I even considered using it for its original purpose, which I did not, even for a minute. It frankly fails in that purpose. It is not sexy. Most of these girls have the look of “god, this is my life now, huh?”, and call me a sex maniac, but I need a bit more than just the knowledge a girl took her panties off to jill myself. I’m not a Victorian getting the vapors from some fucking ankles. And it’s not like the actual GAME itself is fun. It’s rock paper scissors with really shitty, mean RNG. Over all, this took me like, 60 fucking hours. Just use pornhub, for however long that website will exist.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="smut" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I can promise you, by the end, this will be the longest written document about this game on the internet. I could explain the entire game in two sentences, but instead, I have a lot to say.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 6-10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/13/LizstartrekVOY5-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 6-10" /><published>2025-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/13/LizstartrekVOY5-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/13/LizstartrekVOY5-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HdgPHCc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Timeless</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xRzFF0k.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with a pan on an icey world, which considering the quality of the video, makes it look like a 70s nature documentary. Two figures beam in, and announce “WE’RE HERE” as it zooms out to show Voyager under the ice. Very, very good setup.</p>

<p>They beam inside Voyager, and take off their masks to show that they’re Kim and Chakotay. They wander through the ship, trying to find things, as they walk past the long frozen corpses of Voyager’s crew. They find Seven’s corpse, teleport her to their ship, and activate the EMH, who’s like “What the FUCK is going on”, much like us. Chakotay says it clearly, without explaining anything, so it’ll be a good spot to go to break: “We’re here to change history”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1RQkGLc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a flashback. They built a slipstream engine, and it LOOKS good. Everyone is celebrating, excited for the trip tomorrow. The engine’s designer, Paris, is the only one not celebrating. He’s running tests and diagnostics and finds a small slip up, which means they’ll PROBABLY all die. That’s bad. Harry though, uses his ingenuity to plan a way to fix it. He will use the delta flyer and basically tow Voyager to Earth. Now we know why Harry is alive. Chakotay goes with him. Now we know why CHAKOTAY is alive. Kim is VERY pushy that he can do this, he wants to get the fuck home.</p>

<p>Back in the future, 15 years in fact, they finish explaining it to the Doctor. And they’re here to use magic tech shit to send a temporal message back into the past. Future Harry is jaded as fuck, and looks great. He’s got a VERY small amount of gray in his hair, and his hair is in a new hair style. It helps make him seem like he’s much older. Meanwhile, Chakotay just put flour in his hair, and he doesn’t seem older, because he can’t act. Meanwhile they have a woman with them, Tess, who’s Chakotay’s girlfriend, who’s here to help them out.</p>

<p>They’re EXTREMELY wanted for stealing everything, and Federation ships are after them. So they’ve got very little time to break the Temporal Prime Directive. Tess and Chakotay have a moment in Voyager, while Kim work with the Doctor. Kim is jaded as fuuuuuck. He tells about how he got home, got honors and medals, and how he spent the entire time wishing he was dead in this ice rather than them. MASSIVE survivor’s guilt.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HdgPHCc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get contacted by the ship here to take them home. Hey, look who it is! Geordi is an apologetic attacker here. He admits that if he was in their shoes, he’d probably be doing what they’re doing, but he has to protect his crew and the timestream, so he will stop them. They push their ship to stay away from Geordi, which ends in it starting to warp core breach, and Geordi’s like “Let me teleport you over, please”. Oh, Geordi.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j58IyRt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kim sends a message back to Voyager with corrected telemetry, basically the correct message he was SUPPOSED to send. It doesn’t work. They’re still there. Kim freaks the FUCK out. He failed then, and he failed now. The Doctor basically slaps him to his senses, and he sends a message INSTEAD with incorrect telemetry that’ll drop them out of the slipstream immediately. He sends them JUST as they blow the fuck up.</p>

<p>It works, they’re all thrown out of the slipstream, nice and safe. Our episode ends with Kim watching a message from himself from the future.</p>

<p>This was a good episode. I was expecting more temporal angst about doing a thing they consider bad, but no. THey were pretty clear this was the correct thing for them.</p>

<p><strong>Infinite Regress</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9bEMghw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a weird cold open where Seven of Nine stalks around and hunts some meat, while in the mirror we see a Klingon devouring the meat. Is this an episode where Seven is possessed by Klingon Ghosts??</p>

<p>In the bridge meeting, Neelix laments that their late night bandit was back at it once again. Time to make locks. Locks, on a Starfleet vessel, my gosh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cRTDBHO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey, Naomi is back! She’s following Seven around, observing her, because she wants to be perfect too, like her. Basically the writers saw that one scene with Naomi being scared of Seven, and thought it was a great idea to give them a continuous relationship thing. They were right. Anyways she suddenly SHIFTS, and is all happy and sweet and it’s extremely awkward to watch Seven SMILE. We see more people in mirrors and reflections, it’s VERY good.</p>

<p>She becomes a Klingon again, claims she’s Son of K’Vok, and tries to mate with Torres. It doesn’t go well. She knocks out a guard, and then becomes a scared little girl calling for help, because someone got hurt. Then she becomes a Vulcan ambassador, and then the Klingon again, before Tuvok knocks her out.</p>

<p>The Doctor basically diagnoses her with Borg Multiple Personality Disorder, as she’s displaying the memory engrams of people who she assimilated. They think the reason for it is a borg beacon from some debris near them, go they go and investigate.</p>

<p>Neli mentioned that this episode reminds her a lot of Masks, a late TNG episode with Data displaying multiple personalities. That episode was a chance to let Brent Spiner flex as an actor. This episode is doing the same exact thing. And it’s the exact same, an episode with a LOT of actor flexing.</p>

<p>One thing I like about this is Torres. Season 1 Torres, after being scratched by a Seven trying to fuck her? Would have been pissy about it for hours. This Torres? When Seven explains that the Klingon will not be with them, due to the dampener they have that’s supressing the personalities, Torres is like “Oh, so this isn’t our second date?” SHE JOKES ABOUT IT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TGdAnts.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find out what the issue is. There was a recently assimilated group of people with a disease that spread through the link. Her neural pattern is not surviving this well, the Doctor almost loses her. And as one of the recently assimilated peoples arrives to explain it was a manufactured disease to try and hurt the Borg, they find there’s no treatment to the disease. But MAYBE Tuvok can mind meld to fix it, cause Vulcan mind meld magic.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7EPOWQf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tuvok mind melds into a nightmare. There’s children screaming, very unpleasant, the effect is ugly and nauseating, meanwhile it keeps jumping back to Voyager where people are going “oh god shit’s fucked” as the alien of the week is attacking them to get the disease spreading thingy back, isntead of just waiting ten fucking minutes for them to be done with it. Anyways, I can’t even tell if the mind meld helped, it was just him getting thrown around for 3 minutes until they turned the fucking thing off, beamed it into space, and the episode ends.</p>

<p>All the acting from Seven was good. Everything else was meh.</p>

<p><strong>Nothing Human</strong> - VOY
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7EPOWQf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with the Doctor basically doing a Vacation Slides scene, and the quipping from everyone is SHOCKINGLY good. And then the fucking wave from Star Trek Generations comes and rocks the ship.</p>

<p>Afterwards, everyone is fine, but they get some kind of distress call that’s all screeching and alien sounding. I wonder how many aliens sound like that before the translator gets to them. They go to the call’s source, beam the nonhuman thing to sick bay, and then it jumps on Torres and the actress has to pretend that this fucking Zerg Body Pillow is attacking her, it is VERY funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/khredDd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They need an expert on exobiology. The best one they can get from the holodeck is a Crell Moset, a Cardassian. He’s a VERY friendly guy, super pleasant and social. I can’t WAIT for this to become horrifying! All of the people on the ship are a little uncomfy. A lot of them ARE still Maquis, and they’re racist. Crell Moset gives a few signs into his nature. He laments that the Cardassians were ever on Bajor. He likes using scalpels, as it gives him more insight into the body of who he’s working on, more than laser cutters. He’s willing to kill this alien, which SEEMS to be sapient, if it means saving Torres.</p>

<p>The hologram destabalizes slightly, so they enlist the help of an Engineer. He’s a Bajoran Maquis member and ohhh we know where THIS is going, huh.</p>

<p>Anyways the REAL Moset did war crimes. Because of this, Torres refuses to let the hologram work on her, and half of the crew is angry about it. This Bajoran is going to resign his commission because of this. Y’all. It’s a hologram. And the personality engrams they made for this hologram are based on the known data on him that the Federation has, which does not include war crimes. Just make him look like a friendly Bolian, who GIVES a shit.</p>

<p>The Doctor holds the idiot ball, upset that people are trying to slander this guy cause of racism, though yes, he did war crimes. For the record though, Belanna IS racist. She directly admits, “guilty as charged when it comes to Cardassians, as far as I believe, they’re all scum”. And for some reason the hologram is like “YES I AM EVIL. WHO CARES, I’M HELPING SAVE PEOPLE.” so for some reason, yes, he has his “real personality”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UmyFzxY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the dumbest shit in a while. There are a MILLION solutions to this problem. Here’s another one. Just use another fucking hologram. He can’t be the ONLY xenobiologist you have on file???? CHOOSE ANY OTHER ONE, WHO CARES.</p>

<p>Another alien ship shows up, and Frank Welker goes fucking ham. He’s the voice actor for the alien creatures, and he’s so squeely and awful that Janeway is like “can we turn that down, please”. They save Belanna’s life using Moset’s research, and the life of the alien, beam it to its friends, who leave happily, and then Janeway tells Torres to shut up about being angry they used his research on her. The Doctor then decides to delete Moset, deciding that he cannot in good conscience use research gained through suffering. The end.</p>

<p>I did not like this episode very much. They already did this episode better, without any of the easily fixed plot nonsense, with that episode with the doctor who saved Neelix’s life, after having killed most of his people in a nuclear blast. Anyways, meh.</p>

<p><strong>Thirty Days</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FSPLUeC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Paris getting demoted. Seems they’re FINALLY done with his bullshit. Though again, he’s been way better lately. He’s demoted to Ensign. Damn, Paris got demoted before Kim got promoted, guess I lost the office poll. Janeway sentences him to 30 days in solitary confinement. Jesus, solitary  confinement in the 25th century? What the hell did he even do. He defiantly walks his way down to the brig and goes in.</p>

<p>While in there, he decides to write a letter to his dad. “Hey dad. You’ll never guess where I ended up!” yeah he probably can, Harry, this is not the first time. Anyways it’s just a framing device… for how it all went down.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YjInB3I.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager finds an ocean world. Not a world with an ocean in it, a planet made ENTIRELY of water, no land at all, being held by a containment field. Voyager is attacked by the people from the surface, but a quick explanation shows there’s no hostilities. The aliens there, the Moneans, offer to let Voyager scan their ocean, in exchange for them trying to help. The ocean is disappearing, and no one knows why. Paris IMMEDIATELY jumps at the opportunity. He LOVES the ocean, always has as a kid, and it fills him with a sense of wonder.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5J00ZRb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>As they explore below the surface, Voyager does its OWN scans and determines that the ocean will be gone within 5 years, so whatever they need to do they should do it fast. Down below, Paris and crew find the core, which is weakening. Why? Well, it turns out the ocean is getting denser, and it’s crushing the core, so its using more power to protect itself rather than keep up the containment field. But WHY is the ocean getting denser?</p>

<p>It’s pollution, basically. Industry and stuff is causing problems and it’s going to destroy the planet, the ocean, and the entire civilization if they don’t stop. Paris tries to convince them to, but “that would be giving up our ways of life! Never!” Ah. It’s one of THESE episodes. I think we’ll see how Paris got arrested soon. Paris yells at the consul about it, and Janeway snaps at him about it. She agrees with him, but they have the prime directive to worry about.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pvS9e5r.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tom makes a decision. If they can shut down the refineries, while they work on fixing them they can ALSO fix the pollution. Anything to save the ocean. So it’s time Tom becomes a fucking ecoterrorist. Yes. Now, I want to make it very, very clear. I am EXTREMELY pro-enviromentalism, and I have eco-terrorist sympathies, I will not lie. So I’m with Paris here. The episode wants you to be, mind you. The people he’s up against are stuffy beaurocrats who don’t want to lose profits. Who fucking cares?</p>

<p>Tom’s missile is intercepted in time before it blows up the refinery, and Tom is captured. Janeway admires his principles, and understands why he did what he did, but this IS a ship and they need people to follow orders. So he’s demoted, and given 30 days of solitary confinement. Though, of note, throughout the episode we saw that Janeway let multiple people visit him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L898B31.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This letter he’s writing is to show that yes, he went to jail. But this time, he did it for a good cause, and something he believed in. I liked this episode.</p>

<p><strong>Counterpoint</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dgkwlg0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is being boarded by a Devore inspection team. Apparently this is routine. They beam on board, and one beams directly into Janeway’s office, takes command of the ship, and tells her to come to her office and “make herself at home”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dgkwlg0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>If this shit was any more Nazi coded it would be an Enigma Machine. He plays some classical music over the intercom while his people go around inspecting the ship. He’s the overly friendly nazi type, offering her coffee as his people walk around and are dickheads, breaking shit on purpose as the Doctor is like “Please, thats fragile-“</p>

<p>The lead nazi is like “You need friends here. I can be that friend~” while still being a y’know, nazi. They do not find what they’re looking for and leave, though. What they’re looking for is telepaths. Luckily for them, the two Vulcans on board died a while ago in an accident, so they have no telepaths at all</p>

<p>No obviously that’s not true. They’re just holding them in the teleporter buffer. And not JUST the Vulcans; other refugees too! Yes. This is an episode about hiding the jews from the nazis. Just, fucking straight up. It’s not hiding it. Their plan is to send the refugees through a wormhole that’ll take them out of this space.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cFVNlK2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The inspector, Kashyk, shows up again, alone, and explains that actually, fascism is bad. And all that shit he JUST told her 8 minutes ago about how telepaths cannot be trusted? He doesn’t believe it anymore. He wants to help the refugees, which he knows they’re harboring, and warns them that they’re about to go into a trap, which they find out is true. No one trusts him, understandably. But there are plenty of sympathizers in his people, so the refugees are like “He could absolutely be telling the truth”. But you never know.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ev6zlQT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway straight up tells him she does not trust him, but he’ll be kept on the ship, cause they can’t just give him up if he’s asking for asylum. But he’s under CONSTANT surveillance, and they don’t trust him. He understands. Anyways from that point on he’s in all major meetings, on the bridge as they’re doing stuff, and giving advice. Why is he here? Why is she letting him do this?? They have a cute scene together that’s clearly romantic. Please do not do this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bghR7XP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>For some reason, now everyone trusts him. I have no idea why. There was no real thing where he risked his life to save anyone, or anything. He DOES declare that he’s going to sacrifice himself to save them, though. He’ll take his ship and go back to the Devore, taking command of their inspection team, and in the confusion, letting Voyager pass. Okay, it has to be a trick, right? Like, they tearfully let him go, he kisses Janeway before leaving, but they have to be setting a trap. And yes, Janeway’s expression as he leaves makes that clear.</p>

<p>Anyways another inspection happens, and this fucker is back in his post as the head inspector, doing his shtick he did the first time around. Yep, he betrayed them! What a fucking surprise! But whoops, Janeway tricked him and never ACTUALLY trusted him! He decides to let them go so that this isn’t on his permanent record, and because some of those feelings were real! She’s sad he did this, but it is what it is.</p>

<p>Wow! This episode kinda blew! So, if this episode was JUST Janeway Bugs Bunnying a nazi, I would have liked it. That would have been good. But no, the intention, and how you’re supposed to read it, is that she DID develop feelings for him, and was genuinely hoping he’d go with them. The design concept for this was “it’s been a while since Janeway had a romance partner!” YEAH, BUT WHY <strong><em>THIS</em></strong> ONE?!</p>

<p>God almighty, it’s such an absolute BLUNDER of a concept that was actually quite good! Janeway bugs bunny’s some nazis. That’s good, let’s run with it. NO. DO NOT HAVE HER FALL IN LOVE WITH CHRISTOPHER WALTZ’S CHARACTER FROM INGLOURIOUS BASTERDS, WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING?! It was also OBVIOUS what was happening from the very start. As soon as that guy showed up and said “I am requesting asylum”, I knew beat for beat how the entire rest of the episode was going to go, and it did not surprise me, in any way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Shining Force Gaiden II - The Sword of Hajya</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/10/RA167-SFGHajya.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Shining Force Gaiden II - The Sword of Hajya" /><published>2025-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/10/RA167-SFGHajya</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/10/RA167-SFGHajya.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gHBQFxH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, Shining Force Gaiden 1 came out, though only in Japan. It was its own concise little story, but before Shining Force II could come out, half a year after the first Gaiden game and only a year after the first Shining Force game, Shining Force Gaiden II came out. It’s a continuation of Gaiden 1, which was technically a sequel and continuation to Shining Force, though the two games are now VERY seperated.</p>

<p>See, Gaiden 1 is about a kingdom, Cypress, that was taken over by an evil demon worshipper. The true king was killed, and the prince fled. Prince Nick is your player character, who seeks help from the forces of Guardiana, the setting of the first game. So you get help from them while also building your own forces from rebels and other people in your shattered kingdom.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SFUviZ7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>At the end, you win, and are reinstated. Like, duh. Spoilers, I guess. In this game, you are playing as soldiers of THAT restored kingdom. Guardiana IS mentioned, as they’re allies. But you only see a single character from Guardiana, and that’s late game, who shows up triumphantly to help you. Most of the time you’re using either new characters, or returning units that Nick found along the way in Gaiden 1.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ObY1S58.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You are NOT play as Nick though. Nick’s gone off to war with the evil Iom and gotten captured! Instead, you’re playing as… well, that’s difficult. This is the only Shining game with duo protagonists. Your main character, Deanna, is NOT the leader of the Shining Force in this game. Instead, that’s Natasha. Both of you have Egress, and neither get a lot of dialogue or characterization, but Natasha is technically the actual leader, NOT Deanna. Deanna is just a soldier. One who has plot relevence to what’s going on, but just a soldier. This means Natasha is the ONLY female lead in the entire series…. and of course, she’s relegated to co-lead. A shame.</p>

<p>Anyways you may remember that Gaiden 1 did not come out in the US. This one did! So this story was probably VERY confusing to those who played Shining Force and then wanted to play this!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A0upWQg.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Other than the story, it’s really just more Shining Force Gaiden. Same exact engine and everything. The only gameplay difference is that this one is way, way harder for some god forsaken reason. The reason is very clear, though: There’s a bug. The numbers for damage for level 3 spells are accidentally too high. So late game, when there’s two to three units who can use Frost 3, you BETTER chase them down and blow them up before they can move, because Frost 3 has a very wide space, and it WILL do 50 damage per attack, wiping out entire armies who are max health.</p>

<p>Other than THAT, which was very annoying, it’s an enjoyable game. If you liked Gaiden 1, it’s still worth your time. Though MAYBE just play Shining Force CD.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Game Gear" /><category term="Shining" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, Shining Force Gaiden 1 came out, though only in Japan. It was its own concise little story, but before Shining Force II could come out, half a year after the first Gaiden game and only a year after the first Shining Force game, Shining Force Gaiden II came out. It’s a continuation of Gaiden 1, which was technically a sequel and continuation to Shining Force, though the two games are now VERY seperated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 133</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/09/OOCY133.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 133" /><published>2025-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/09/OOCY133</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/09/OOCY133.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BiBaHwe.png" alt="'You wanted to become a girl and be loved by girls, huh?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Manga About a Hero who Pulled Out the Holy Sword and Became a Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Manga About a Hero who Pulled Out the Holy Sword and Became a Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/06/LizstartrekVOY5-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5" /><published>2025-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/06/LizstartrekVOY5-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/06/LizstartrekVOY5-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lEMFojx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Night</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w6YtUOn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with a cheesy B-movie with big Flash Gordon energy. Both Kim and Paris are super into it. All the special effects look like shit and its black and white, I genuinely love that. Paris claims it’s sociology, cause they’re studying how the 20th century viewed the future. Thats really cute. I love seeing each group love a different kind of classic shlocky story (Detective Noire, James Bond, and then this.)</p>

<p>Also, they FINALLY have Seven out of that fucking corset. They realized they didn’t need to try and force her to be hot, she was just… naturally hot.</p>

<p>Anyways the ACTUAL plot is that they’re two months into an expanse, and there’s no signs of any stars anywhere near them. For two fucking years of travel. It’s only been two months, and they’re all feeling kind of stir crazy. There’s been no exploration, nothing. They’re doing FINE, they’re able to survive, but it’s making everyone grumpy… and freaking out others. Poor Neelix has a panic attack while trying to calm down others who are angry. And all the while, they’re picking up some theta radiation…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eJluwa6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway seems depressed as hell. She’s secluded herself in her room, beating herself up about making everyone stuck in the Delta Quadrant for years. It’s kind of a bad time for this, considering everyone likes her and are feeling restless. Like, she’s upset that she chose to save people she didn’t even know in episode 1, rather than her own people. This will probably be a theme for the episode.</p>

<p>The silence and boredom gives way to sudden massive panic as Voyager turns off. No thrust. No power. Nothing. This does NOT help poor fucking Neelix. I hate watching Neelix have panic attacks. We’ve got everyone split up in different groups. And then it turns out we’re not alone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zd9OaXb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some aliens, cloaked in the blackness of space, have shut down the power of Voyager and boarded. They’re aggressive, and do not react to diplomacy. Seven IMMEDIATELY knocks one out because of course she does. And then they’re saved by a ship coming in to save the day.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MIE2K3T.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Emck, of the Malon. They’re the Druuj. They’re just STRAIGHT UP the Druuj from Star Control 2. He’s a sleezy little fucker who demands compensation for saving them, says he’s just here to transport some stuff. Oh I’m sure. But he DOES offer them a way out of this space, a vortex that takes them to the other side. Well that’s helpful! Let’s get the other side, though… the Night Alien explains that his people have been there for a long-ass time, peacefully living, but then the Malon showed up and are killing them with some kind of radiation they don’t understand. That’s the theta radiation. They look into what Emck is doing, and yep, he’s just dumping a shit ton of toxic waste into the expanse. They offer him a way to teach how to recycle, and he’s like “Nah that’d put me out of business, I make LOADS of dosh off of polluting this space, I’m good”. He’s a sleezy fuck.</p>

<p>Well, the MORAL thing would be to destroy this vortex they use to hop here, and save the Night Aliens. But they can only blow it up from this end, which would strand them here for two whole years. The crew claims they can live with that, but Janeway can’t. So she goes and declares what’s going to happen, stepping onto the bridge for the first time in two months. She’s going to commit suicide, allowing them to go on ahead and then blow up the vortex, leaving her behind in the Void. So she tells them to go on ahead as she uses a shuttle, aaand everyone refuses.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XJHXqnH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s a sweet reaction. Everyone cares about her, and no one blames her like she blames herself.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/u5cIkIH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They do a dangerous maneuver to blow it up with torpedos thrown behind them, and ride the shockwave to the other side. The Malon ship is stronger, but the Night Aliens show up to save the day, and they blast forward through the vortex, which was destroyed behind them. That maneuver didn’t take them ALL the way through the expanse, they still have a bit left. But they’re close. And then they see the first star at the end of the expanse, and make it through to a bright new day.</p>

<p><strong>Drone</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K5u1Bgv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Seven practicing smiling in the mirror. I hate it. To be fair, so does Seven.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nJx1nET.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, Paris, Torres, the Doctor, and Seven are on a shuttle watching a thing explode, but it explodes too well, and they need to be teleported out. This new dude, Ensign Mulchaey, is like “I can’t seperate their patterns”, so we’re threatened with a DOUBLE Tuvix, but thankfully that’s avoided and it all seems fine. Uh, except that the Doctor’s holo emitter is on the fritz. They take it off him and set it aside to work on it, and then Borg tubules splorp out of it.</p>

<p>Anyways, after a day, Seven detects some Borg on the ship. But no scans show up anything. And then the tubules Splorp into the Ensign, extract some tissue from him, and she detects Borg one more time. They go to investigate, and find that the thing had turned an entire station into an incubation chamber for some fucking reason.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VfNRA7w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is Voyager’s answer to that fucking Troi Gets Gregnant episode from TNG. This is a new kind of Borg, growing in there. They don’t want to literally abort this fucking thing, but it’s growing FAST. It’s also connected to 29th century technology in the holo emitter, so it’s a VERY advanced Borg. It’s dangerous, but without connecting to the Borg, it has no real direction yet. So Janeway wants to give IT a direction.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1R50d2Z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s not immediately reticent of… anything, really. It’s like an empty computer. Seven has to basically handhold him learning things, putting info into his brain, and he’s IMMEDIATELY more friendly and pleasant. He’s also like a little puppy, following Seven around. Neelix also kind of adopts him. I love that they needed to have Neelix and Seven take care of this guy, because everyone else is fucking afraid of him, and they’re the people most likely to not be racist.</p>

<p>Neelix says he needs a name, and tells him to name himself. He chooses “One”.</p>

<p>One is very smart. He’s a bit awkward, in that Borg way, but he’s very, VERY observant. He immediately sees ways to make the engine better and do Torres job for her. She’s at first angry at him even EXISTING, but once she spends time with him, she doesn’t seem to mind. He’s valuable, but above that, he’s also becoming a personality. He’s being his own self. He is also very much wants to learn more about the Borg. They decide not to tell him anything, in case he wants to go after the Borg. When he sleeps though, he accidentally contacts the collective… who are VERY excited to meet him, and send a sphere to collect him. Obviously can’t let THAT happen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GpbDZQw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They show One what the Borg is all about. At first he’s kind of into the idea, but when they explain it a bit further, he actually feels anxiety. In that Borg Way. “I am experiencing cardiovascular increases” and whatnot.</p>

<p>This is the first time they’ve gone up against the Borg since Seven joined them. She doesn’t want to go back. As she says, “Voyager is my collective”. One does what he can to improve their weapons, but it’s not enough… so he teleports onto the sphere and does a fucking Musou against a horde of Borg, interfacing with them to blow it up from the inside out.</p>

<p>Everyone is STUNNED, but then they get a life sign in the debris. One survived.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HoqiZ1v.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But not for long. The doctor needs to do surgery ASAP, but One has come to a conclusion. As long as he exists, Voyager is in danger. He cannot let that happen. He erects a forcefield around himself, as Seven BEGS him to let them save his life. But he refuses, making his decision. It’s actually a really powerful scene, in a nerdy Borg kinda way. Though maybe it’s more funny than it needs to be, with the way they’re talking</p>

<p>The episode ends as Seven tries her best to adapt, the new emotions moving through her.</p>

<p>I dunno WHY I feel like this isn’t a 10. Maybe it’s too close to the Lal episode, beat for beat?</p>

<p><strong>Extreme Risk</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xgIOjj5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Torres jumping out of a shuttle and skydiving onto a planet from space altitudes. She deactivates some safety and hops into space. Then she’s called the Engineering. Yep, holodeck. She’s a bit grumpy about it, and calls out, asking Seven to take over for her.</p>

<p>Anyways, a Malon freighter is harassing a probe of theirs, and so they hide it in a gas giant. The Malon try to chase it down there and fucking explode. Now the probe is stuck down there and they can’t get it back. I dunno why they need that probe that fucking bad.</p>

<p>Paris has a suggestion. One he’s apparently made a dozen times. Just build a better shuttle. Oh, just a better shuttle? Easy peezy. He’s already planned out some stuff for it, and is VERY excited to work on it more. He gets a team together, Seven, Kim, Tuvok, and of course Torres who is uh, not really there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/34eMGvf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris asks her about it. They’d gushed for years about how it’d be great to actually work together to make something, and now she doesn’t give a shit. She seems tired. EXISTENTIALLY tired. She refuses to explain, then goes back to the holodeck, turns off safeties, and beats the shit out of a Cardassian.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Malon are still anxious to get a hold of that Probe. I like how apparently the Malon are our new threat this season. Just a bunch of capitalists who want to dump garbage everywhere.</p>

<p>Tuvok: “These dials you are installing are illogical.”
Paris: “Look, I am tired of just TAPPING PANELS. I need something physical!”</p>

<p>GOD, PARIS, SAME. THANK YOU FOR SAYING IT. I CAN’T BELIEVE I’M AGREEING WITH PARIS.</p>

<p>Torres does more suicide attempts in the holodeck, almost dying, but Chokie saves her in time.</p>

<p>Janeway stages an intervention. She KNOWS something’s wrong, and kicks her off the shuttle project. She doesn’t seem to care, so Janeway KNOWS something is wrong now. No one wants to dig into her personal life or her files, but she’s a danger to herself. They HAVE to.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sR3tdB4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s diangosed with depression. As someone with depression, especially depression that’s been really bad lately, I’m NGL I’m seeing a lot of myself in her, and I’m unhappy. Anyways Chokie gets an in by pretending to be a friend who’s here to restore her holodeck privileges. And then he activates a SPECIFIC program and forces her into the holodeck. She demands that it gets shut off. He drags her through it. Chokie that’s uh, that’s not the right way to do this, I don’t think.</p>

<p>This episode has been pretty good at handling depression. So far. But this is a terrible, TERRIBLE way of handling it. Yes, Chokie, go ahead and re-traumatize the person in crisis. That’s a great fucking idea. STUPID fucking Chokie, jesus christ.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8rGGf0L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She doesn’t feel anything. Not about her friends, about her job, about Tom. She’s depressed. That’s just the definition of depression. She’s getting herself hurt not to die, or for suicide, but just so she can feel ANYTHING. This is good. This is a good subject, powerful, worthy of being shown, and being shown well. Chakotay is just handling it in the WORST WAY I COULD EVER FUCKING IMAGINE. Intervention is good. But NOT LIKE THIS. Shut the FUCK UP, CHAKOTAY.</p>

<p>And then when Torres decides that she DOES want to work, she wants to help, because she’s the best they’ve got and she wants to help her family now so nothing bad happens again, Chakotay’s like “NO, YOU’VE HAD YOUR CHANCES” before FINALLY letting her go on. Holy shit, SPACE HIM.</p>

<p>They launch the new shuttle, trying to reach the probe first. With some quick thinking and work by Torres, they manage to survive without the shuttle imploding. Seeing her do quick thinking engineering in a tanktop is cool. And hot as hell. She macguivers some phasers into a handheld shield generator. Hot.</p>

<p>She thanks Chakotay for being a shitty therapist, and then threatens to break his neck if he ever tries it again. She should have just said that second part. Then she eats some banana pancakes, and tries to let herself feel again.</p>

<p>Part of this episode is really good, but holy FUCK that Chakotay part was bad. It’s like 80% good. They were originally going to let Paris be the confidant for Torres’ problems, but they made it Chakotay to avoid melodrama. Terrible decision, but tbh if Paris had done EXACTLY what Chakotay would have done, I wouldn’t have liked it! It still would have been bad!</p>

<p><strong>In the Flesh</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zd2gdEO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got a scene on Earth, at Starfleet Command. Boothby is there! There’s also a bunch of Ferengi. How pleasant. Uhhhh and also Chakotay is there, examining it, confounded. Yeah, me too dude.</p>

<p>Boothby has a pleasant conversation with Chakotay. Well, Boothby is pleasant. Chakotay’s charisma stat is like, a 7. And then a woman comes up to him and starts flirting. Again, charisma stat of 7. And then a dude in the corner has a VFX attack.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zd2gdEO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The girl is like “Oh that’s his third time reverting this week. You know how hard it is to keep pretending to be Human. Breathing is so weird. Sleeping is even weirder. Anyways, we’re not supposed to be talking about this. How about a date? :D”</p>

<p>Chakotay and Tuvok try to leave… wherever this is, and then a guy catches them, so they knock him out and drag him up to Voyager too. Yeah, so these are some kind of aliens who recreated Earth. For what reason, who knows. When the alien wakes up, he freaks the hell out, refuses to let anyone touch him, and yells “DISEASE! HUMAN!” before releasing a toxin into his bloodstream and killing him. The Doctor finds a way to revert him back to his original species, whatever that is…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uBxoLeb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Species 11 million and 2!!!</p>

<p>Okay, so they know WHO they are. But why??? Chakotay has an in, at least. Valerie Archer, that girl who was hitting on him. He can try and infiltrate. God I can’t wait for this episode to end with Chakotay fucking a Species 8472.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tBxAUdW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Me too, Kim. Me too.</p>

<p>Neli described this as “when an anime does an episode in America”, which is very funny. Chakotay has to pretend to be at least slightly ignorant of Earth stuff, but it’s hard to tell, because he can’t act, so it just looks like he’s ignorant.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6fHmSIB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>TRANS SPECIES 8888! LFG! I’m IMMEDIATELY imagining a better version of this series, that version of the series where they add new characters on. Y’know, the one where Janeway’s girlfriend Amelia Earheart went into space with them. In this version, this girl realizes she’s wrong about how Humans are, and that Humans are cool and she likes being a Human, so she joins Voyager. Oh well. We’ll never get that reality, sadly.</p>

<p>We get a burlesque scene, basically. She strips in the bathroom, we see her naked body as a silhouette on the wall. She walks back out in a nightrobe, explains she needs an injection, and injects herself as her body blorp borps around the injection. H-hot.</p>

<p>They make out, she seems to kinda like it, and then she tells Boothby that they were right, she tested his DNA. Chakotay is captured, and brought towards the mastermind. EVIL BOOTHBY. God that’s nuts.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YbUdzjJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re infiltrating Earth, or planning to, because they’re scared of Humans, cause they developed technology to hurt them, and are doing it pre-emptively. Neither side trusts each other. So to try and show they stand by their ideals, Janeway stands down first, deactivates their weapons. Species 6969 are like “Oh. Well uh, okay”, and stand down too. Turns out they’re NOT that violent. It feels like a bit of a retcon. Remember when they were like “YOUR UNIVERSE WILL BURN”?? Oh well. Fake Boothby is like “our superiors aren’t as forward thinking, but I’ll try to get them to see you’re not violent”.</p>

<p>It ends with Valerie kissing Chakotay, cause he’s just that sexy I guess. I think Chakotay just has weird-ass pheramones.</p>

<p>This is a weird episode. This is also the last time we ever see Species 8472! Or the “Undine” as they’re known now. They will appear in Star Trek Online, but never again in any actual Star Trek media, except a few occasional mentions, but that’s about it. A shame. They’re such a cool group.</p>

<p><strong>Once Upon a Time</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oJROb1V.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got an episode about Naomi! You remember Naomi? We saw her get born two years ago, and now she’s like an 8 year old. Oh well. Anyway she’s in some kind of storybook fairytale, which is cute and goofy. It’s like Star Trek Wizard of Oz. It’s cute. I want an episode just of this, she’s a good kid actor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cOKhL6p.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, her mom is on an away mission, and can’t make it back. She’s on the new shuttle they designed the other episode as stuff goes bad. At least she’s with named characters so she has a better chance of survival. Neelix doesn’t want to let her know that her mother’s shuttle crashed, so his job is to keep her preoccupied. I think you should just tell her, but whatever. Don’t lie to kids. They’ll find out and it’ll get worse. Kids are smart.</p>

<p>Also Naomi is scared of Seven. Seven isn’t very good at stopping that viewpoint.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JSTuZrZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Naomi’s mom is injured in the crash landing. Punctured kidney, bleeding internally. Tom is a nurse, not a surgeon, so he can’t exactly help.</p>

<p>Naomi is taking classes with the doctor. The Mitochondria is the warp core of the cell. That’s SO GOOD. In this episode of Voyager, the crew gaslights a small child who wants to see her mom. Why :) Why are they doing that. Neelix pls. Neelix and Naomi go into the holodeck for another fairy tale. It’s apparently a popular kids story. They do one called “THE OGRE OF FIRE”. Sounds a bit scary. Neelix agrees. But she’s like “oh this’ll be fine if you’re with me!” It’s not fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOATixZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They watch Flotter, the blue fairy water creature, melt in front of them. It’s horrifying. Honestly, I love the accuracy for ACTUAL children’s programming, which was weirdly fucking terrifying when I was a kid. Remember The Brave Little Toaster?? I will never, EVER forget The Brave Little Toaster. :)</p>

<p>Neelix is like “Naomi shouldn’t BE HERE, a starship is no place for a kid!!” but Kim argues that it’s a great learning experience, and one she’ll never forget. Neelix has Kim replicate a Flotter doll for her, but she’s already hard at work. She’s researching evaporation to figure out how to get Flotter back in the story. Smart kid.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wQlxihk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Can’t be a cute sweet episode forever, though. Neelix is, as always, suffering from massive survivor’s guilt. He has a dream of his friends and loved ones dying. He’s struggling, so who he go to for help? Fucking SEVEN. He’s like “Do you ever think about your family?” “Infrequently. I barely remember them.” “Maybe that’s a good thing”. Constant memory and fear haunts you forever. Ask me how I know. He’s trying to protect her because of how he’s handling it. A lot of projection.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZCsDW6u.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway convinces Neelix to tell her, to get over those fears. The situation here is different from how it was for him. Why? She has him. That’s sweet.</p>

<p>Anyways, obviously Naomi is aware something is wrong. She’s not stupid. Adults are bad at hiding their anxiety. She comes on board the Bridge just as soon as she hears them talking about the shuttle crash. Ohhh, Neelix. You shouldn’t have waited.</p>

<p>They find the shuttle, but they need to dig it out. Inside, they’re recording their last messages to their loved ones. Tuvok is writing his. Paris’ is absolutely awful. Not even an “I love you”. Damn Paris, I could write a better goodbye message to my cat. Naomi’s mom’s message is heartwrenching though. The acting in this episode is very good.</p>

<p>Neelix and Naomi have a heart to heart in the burned out forest. He explains what happened to him when he was younger, how he lost everyone, and wanted to protect her. I like this, cause like, it explains WHY he did it, and it’s a good reason and understandable, but the episode does NOT show that it was right, cause it wasn’t. It shows that he’s remorseful, and makes it right.</p>

<p>In the end, they make it out. They’re rescued, and everything is good. There’s a sweet reunion, and then Naomi and her mother have fun in the holodeck forest. It’s sweet.</p>

<p>This is actually the last time Wildman, Naomi’s mom, ever shows up. Naomi WILL show up again, but not her mom. Weird.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 132</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 132" /><published>2025-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DkqsVPA.png" alt="'Know what you wanna be after you graduate?' 'Yep. Your wife.' 'Huh?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Misread It as Love!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Misread It as Love!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Blazing Dragons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Blazing Dragons" /><published>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9M9Rq3m.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is Blazing Dragons, a point and click adventure developed by Illusions Gaming Company, who mostly made point and click games you might vaguely remember based on prior properties like the Genesis Scooby Doo game, or the windows Beevis and Butthead games. It was published by Crystal Dynamics, who actually still exists, and is pretty well known for Tomb Raider. Not so much this game. This is one of the more obscure games in their repitoire, another point and click adventure game based on a prior property. This time, it’s based on the TV show Blazing Dragons… kind of.</p>

<p>Blazing Dragons was a late 90s British cartoon made Terry Jones, of Monty Python fame. My THEORY is that this game was something entirely different, and then they connected it to the cartoon because they had Terry Jones on the project. It has some of the same characters, but the designs are COMPLETELY different and a lot of the characters are changed or missing. The most interesting change is the different designs. In the cartoon, they’re very bipedal dragons, typical cartoony dragon design. In the game, they’re all taurs, which is VERY interesting. I kinda like taurs. I just think they’re neat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wVjoiyH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In the game, you play as Flicker, who starts the game as the royal inventor, I think. He’s a smartypants kinda socially unaware dork, but he has a romance thing with the princess of the realm, Princess Flame. Unfortunately, she’s set to be wed to the winner of the Knight Tournament, and Flicker isn’t a knight, much to her chagrin. So the goal of the game is to become a knight by helping the Knights of the Square table, as bumbling as they are. At the same time, the kingdom’s sworn enemy, King Geoffry the Human, is trying to take over the land with the help of his wizard Merl. They also have an evil dragon on the inside, the king’s advisor, who is not in the show. So you’ve gotta stop that too. Simple enough premise, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xtJI4GL.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game is a rather traditional point and click of the time. You’ve got a cursor that changes actions, things like look, talk, grab, use. You wander around, interract with people, solve puzzles, and collect a bunch of items that you rub on other items. The game is, for the MOST part, filled with good puzzles, but there are a couple that completely confounded me with their leaps of logic. But, in clal, it was actually a rather well crafted game, puzzle wise.</p>

<p>The big thing about the game is its writing and star cast, though. First of all, the cast is wild. Terry Kones, Cheech Marin, Jim Cummings, Rob Paulsen, Jess Harnel, it’s an all star cast, and they all do a good job. There’s ONE problem I’ll talk about later with the voice acting, though. The other thing is its writing. It’s very, VERY Monty Python. Makes sense, with Terry Jones being there. It’s a comedy that does not take itself seriously, with outrageous goofy setups and even goofier characters. It’s also very, VERY British in that way. If you can’t stand British comedy, maybe stay away. I DO like British comedy, except for oooone thing that this game is very bad at.</p>

<p>British Comedy does this thing where if there’s a female character, there’s like a 90% chance it’ll be played by a guy doing the most awful shrill cockney voice you’ve ever heard in your fucking life. British comedians playing women have ONE voice, and they really, REALLY love to whip it out at any god damn opportunity, and I HATE that voice, it’s AWFUL on my ears. This game is lousy with that voice. They got Jess Harnel to play like, one character, and then every other woman in the game is like “ELLO ELLO OIM A GOIYL”, clipping the fucking mic.</p>

<p>OTHER THAN THAT, THOUGH, the game is actually very good. Not too long or difficult, it’s well worth the time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Blazing Dragons" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Point and Click Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Blazing Dragons, a point and click adventure developed by Illusions Gaming Company, who mostly made point and click games you might vaguely remember based on prior properties like the Genesis Scooby Doo game, or the windows Beevis and Butthead games. It was published by Crystal Dynamics, who actually still exists, and is pretty well known for Tomb Raider. Not so much this game. This is one of the more obscure games in their repitoire, another point and click adventure game based on a prior property. This time, it’s based on the TV show Blazing Dragons… kind of.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 131</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 131" /><published>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9hmh7Vy.png" alt="'I love my failures the same as my successes. And I'll love your failures as well'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Curtain Call for You</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Curtain Call for You" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 130</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 130" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I6BjMEl.png" alt="'Well, can't be all bad, if it means I get to flirt with you...' *slides in for a kiss* suddenly in a crowd 'LOOK AROUND YOU.' 'Yep.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Itazura Privacy</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Itazura Privacy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>