<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-28T15:33:04-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 62</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/28/OOCY62.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 62" /><published>2024-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/28/OOCY62</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/28/OOCY62.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FJYKc7S.png" alt="&quot;I'm showing you my boobs, so could you look at them?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Don’t Know Which One is Love</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Don&apos;t Know Which One is Love" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 61</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/27/OOCY61.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 61" /><published>2024-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/27/OOCY61</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/27/OOCY61.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f4apHOq.png" alt="&quot;I'm showing you my boobs, so could you look at them?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Step 1: Lovers.</p>

<p>Step 2: Uhaul.</p>

<p>source: Love Allergy Syndrome</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Love Allergy Syndrome" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 16 - 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/25/LizstartrekDS96-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 16 - 20" /><published>2024-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/25/LizstartrekDS96-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/25/LizstartrekDS96-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YdQsQqo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Change of Heart</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jdgvTjA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with an ACTUALLY GOOD scene with Worf, where he bets on his wife playing a game of Tongo. O’Brien: “…You have no idea how this game is played, do you?” “…No. But I know my wife.” That’s cute.</p>

<p>Our plot happens. Dax and Worf are sent into Dominion space to get information from a Cardassian operative who’s been spying for the Federation. This is a lot catty married banter, which is pretty fun, and we get this famous line (sorry for the terrible quality)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/310q8MH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The B-plot is that O’Brien is trying to get Bashir into Tongo so they can break Quark’s streak. Namely, O’Brien is trying to gode Bashir into beating Quark for him. Dunno if these plots will intersect much, but this is a funny concept. It eventually turns into Quark defeating Bashir because he distracts him with how hot Dax is and how they “let her go” which is SUCH a Quark move, in order to win. Very dirty. Also I don’t like it much. I liked The Bashir that I thought had gotten over Dax in season 2, YEARS ago.</p>

<p>Dax and Worf need to try and get the spy out by sneaking through an alien jungle. They’re still joking around, as Dax said she likes Worf With A Sense of Humor, but as they’re joking around a fire, Dax is attacked by some Jem’Hadar and injured. Now Worf has to continue the mission AND make sure she lives. But she’s not getting better, and Worf needs to continue to extract this spy, with the information he has that can save lives, but it’ll mean death for Dax. But he can’t. He goes back and saves Dax. The spy is killed, and Worf makes it back.</p>

<p>Sisko tells him that although there’ll be no formal charges, because it was a spy mission, it WILL go on his permanent record, and he’ll probably never get a command because of this. Even if they, y’know, all survive. Worf made a decision that could cost a LOT of lives, and he saved his wife instead. No one BLAMES him, but he and Dax are NEVER going on missions alone again</p>

<p>Actually kinda good Worf episode!! Imagine that.</p>

<p><strong>Wrongs Darker than Death or Night</strong> - DS9
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/haVhHZf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s Kira’s dead mother’s birthday, and she’s trying to celebrate it, but is interrupted by a message by Dukat, of all people, who’s like “Hey I’m here help you :D Did you know I FUCKED YOUR MOTHER? ENJOY HER BIRTHDAY!”</p>

<p>I know they’re trying to show that Dukat is unhinged now but that’s maybe going too far. It is funny that maybe the biggest fugitive in the ENTIRE QUADRANT came out of hiding juuuust long enough to go “I fucked your mother”. What an asshole.</p>

<p>Kira is obviously bothered by this, even though he’s a stupid asshole who says things to get under people’s skin, and it weighs on her, so she asks Sisko to let her go to THE ORB OF TIME. Y’all remember when we were collecting the chaos emeralds? Yeah, so the prophets send Kira back in time. She sees and protects her mom and dad (and herself and brothers) from an attack by some thugs, and then Cardassians show up and announce that they’re going to be taking some “Comfort Women” to Terok Nor, taking Meru, her mother, and Kira, under the guise of Luma Rahl. They befriend each other.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YXBP2BI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is a lot of watching Cardassians, who mind you colonized and enslaved this population, skeeving and using women as sex slaves and objects, and it is very VERY uncomfortable to watch. And of course Dukat is there, being his slimy self, “protecting” who he can out of the kindness of his heart (namely Kira’s mom, because she’ll get his dick wet).</p>

<p>It gets a bit more ugly. Kira is kicked down to the slums cause she doesn’t take no guff, and her mom starts to, as far as Kira can tell, ACTUALLY fall in love with Dukat. So she decides to change the future and assassinate her mother, AND Dukat. Wow, uh, kinda extreme Kira? I mean, I can’t relate in any way, but it feels like a stretch. But yeah, she’s PISSED. She hates collaborators, you know how it is. But after she sees how her mother cries from a message from her dad, she warns them of the bomb and is sent back to the future.</p>

<p>I dunno how to feel about this one. It kinda just made me uncomfortable. Also this episode was made because everyone wanted Kira x Dukat, and Nana Visitor was like “FUCK no.” so they did this instead. Which feels gross. Very gross.</p>

<p><strong>Inquisition</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QLRs89b.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>O’Brien hurt his shoulder kayaking in the holodeck again. It’s very funny that this keeps happening to him, dating back to season 2 of TNG. Bashir fixes him, then gets ready to head out for a medical seminar. He’s stopped, however, and assigned to quarters, alongside every other main staff member. Someone in staff is a spy, and internal affairs needs to find out who is it. They call Bashir out and this Willem Defriend ass mfer is VERY friendly. Very good cop energy. NEXT time they send him back, this guy is not so good cop. He’s grilling, hard, and Bashir gets a transmission from O’Brien who’s like “They are grilling me HARD about you, they think you’re a spy- okay bye”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dLpCcoq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Bashir is clad in irons because they decide he’s a spy, seemingly just cause they want to find one. Sisko is annoyed as fuck, and is like “nope, I’m still in command, I will sit on the interrogations and make sure that you don’t violate his rights”. All of it boils down to him being genetically enhanced, and it’s a lot of circumstancial evidence and speculation, based on what feels like bigotry. They also believe that Julian has had his memories repressed and is a sleeper agent, basically. It’s like that episode where Geordi almost murdered O’Brien after being trained by Romulans. Remember that?</p>

<p>They’re about to illegally drag Bashir away and put him in jail, and he’s instead teleported out by Weyoun, who’s like “All of it was true :D You’re our spy &lt;3” Bashir refuses to agree with it cause yeah, why would he be a spy, he wouldn’t ever do that. So he’s like “why are you and Sloan BOTH trying to get me to admit the same lie… you’re working together for the same goal”</p>

<p>He’s “rescued” from the Dominion, and everyone on the bridge is SURE he’s a spy, and are all angy and disgusted with him, including O’Brien, who shoves him away… with his hurt arm. Bashir is like “But you hurt it with Springball” “Yeah, but it’s fine now”. ….It’s not real. NONE of it is real. He’s taken out of the holodeck, and Sloan comes clean. He’s part of something called “Section 31”, which is a secret branch of Starfleet that no one else knows about and answers to know one. They’re the Starfleet secret police. tHey were set up 200 years ago and have just been running… which is SCARY and VERY ominous. They try to recruit him, and he’s like “this is fucking disgusting, no.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wHxMVs4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Don’t hold your breath.</p>

<p>Everyone comments on how fucked up secret police are, and that they should do what they can to oppose them. And they’ll do it by having Bashir join them, and play double agent.</p>

<p>So, I know where Section 31 GOES. And I know I don’t like it .But that doesn’t reflect poorly on this episode. This episode was good and set them up as direct villains in a good way, IMO. Like, they won’t handle it well, but… I don’t hate the idea of “Star Fleet can be bad actually”, but I AM worried they will turn it into “Starfleet IS bad actually”. We’ll see.</p>

<p><strong>In the Pale Moonlight</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YdQsQqo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is one of the big ones.</p>

<p>Our episode starts with an exhausted Sisko opening a log, and telling a story of 2 weeks ago… something that happened, something that’s been weighing on his mind.</p>

<p>Two weeks ago, on a Friday, like all Fridays, Sisko posts the casualty list of the past week. As everyone is morose and sad about dead people, they remark that a lot of deaths recently have been because people are over the Romulan border and then the Dominion kill them, because the Romulans are neutral. And that’s the moment when Sisko decided. He was going to bring the Romulans into the war. But the Romulans won’t just join the war, they need a REASON. They need PROOF of the obvious: After the Dominion defeat the Klingons and Federation, they WILL go after the Romulans. But that information is hiding in the Dominion.</p>

<p>We know who can help with that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hAVYaNm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is as much a Sisko episode as it is a Garak episode. Sisko needs Garak, who is willing to help, though it’ll rip through all of his assets. And as things get worse, with Betazed being invaded, things warm up. They need Garak NOW. Unfortunately, all his operative friends were killed IMMEDIATLEY after he contacted them. Oops. But he has a plan. They’ll get the senator MOST into allying with the Dominion to come, and give them a forgery proving things are bad. It’s kinda… immoral, but come on. They WILL attack anyway. He’s practically saving them.</p>

<p>They get a guy out of jail to help them make the forgery. This guy attacks Quark like an idiot, and now Sisko needs to bribe Quark to not press charges, cause this guy isn’t on the station, you dig? It disgusts Sisko, and makes him almost call off the entire thing… then he gets to his office, and sees another list of casualties. People are out there dying.</p>

<p>His list of deeds grows. He has to take biomemetic gel, VERY illegal, and sell it to someone for a rod. He disgusts the people he works with, Bashir especially, for this. He threatens the forger that he will get him killed if things don’t work right. He’s falling deeper, and deeper into this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GGR2XrH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Romulan comes aboard the station… he’s pretty anti-Federation and pro-Dominion, but Sisko IS a pleasant man, so he eventually agrees to many of Sisko’s points, but of course he wants proof. And Sisko gives it. And now it’s waiting time… to see if the forgery worked.</p>

<p>It does not. The Romulan is PISSED AS FUCK, and says he will share this deception with the entire quadrant. But as he returns to Romulus…. his ship is blown up. All signs point to Dominion sabatoge. When Sisko learns this he immediately goes and DECKS Garak.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZNEo3lp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Garak had planned this from the start. He was pretty sure the forgery wouldn’t work, so he was going to kill Vreenak and blame the Dominion. The Romulans will enter the war, and all it will cost are a few lives, and the self respect of one man.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RahkexB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sisko says he can live with this. He repeats this multiple times, trying to convince himself, and then deletes the log. Episode end.</p>

<p>We had a lot to say about this… I liked it, a lot. I dunno if it’s an ALL TIMER, but it’s very good, and very interesting. And Garak is of course perfectly.</p>

<p><strong>His Way</strong> - DS9
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MIXM0L5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s time for the new main cast member of DS9. This is Vic Fontaine. He introduces himself with song. He’s a jazz singer from the 20th century, put into the holodeck! Oh, and one more thing, he’s self aware that he’s a holosuite program in the 23rd century. Why? Bashir, the owner of the program, says its just better that way. Sure. He’s a lounge singer, a nice one, and very, VERY observant. He immediately realizes Worf and Dax are married, O’Brien misses his wife, and Odo and Kira are… well, let’s not get into it.</p>

<p>Actually, let’s get into it. Odo is feeling anxious about his crush on Kira, and that she still just thinks of her as a friend. Especially because she’s visiting her ex, Shakaar. The fire is under his ass. He’s terrified of trying to change this, and also is, y’know, Odo. Quark gives him a push, tells him he’s gotta do SOMETHING, cause he cares about his boyfriend and wants him to be happy. But what can Odo do? He needs someone to help him…</p>

<p>He enlists Fontaine, who’s like “Dude you have no charm. We’ve gotta work on that”. We then get maybe the goofiest scene in the entire series. It maybe has some competition with them playing hopscotch in season 1, or the time Odo taught a jar of beer what a cube was. It’s three minutes of Odo pretending to play the piano, getting more and more into it, and it is so good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rMk8bw7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Odo doesn’t get very much character development. At least, not like, PROGRESSIVE development. And here we go. He has to loosen up. Show his emotions more, he’s bad at that. He’s already a good guy, and charming in his own way, but he’s gotta loosen. We also get an AMAZING scene where Odo starts humming and singing to himself in Sisko’s room, and he’s LOVING it, cracking up almost.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8xKgsJ5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>KIRA, KISS ME, PLEASE</p>

<p>Fontaine, being basically a benevelent God in the holosuite, creates a Kira hologram to flirt with Odo and allow him to practice. He almost kisses her and then is like “Uh no, it’s weird, she acts nothing like her. You programmed her to like me. I could be reading prisoner reports.” When Kira comes back, and goes to meditate in the holosuite, Fontaine forces himself into her program… again, a God, and convinces her to go on a date with Odo. At the same time, he hacks the intercom and tells Odo to go on a date with his new Kira hologram he made tonight, for more practice. HE’S PLAYING THEM SO WELL. A BENEVOLENT GOD OF LOVE.  It’s also very fascinating cause he has AMAZING chemistry with all the main characters, like he’s alwaysb een here, and always well… and maybe…~</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TNruJeC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They have a date. Odo thinks she’s a hologram. Kira thinks she’s ACTUALYL on a real-ass date with Odo, and seeing this more loose Odo, who’s just being himself cause he’s not up in his own head with fear and anxiety about the consequences, she’s really liking it. She’s enjoying herself… a lot. Way more than she expected. And she keeps bringing up that it’s their first date. Their… FIRST date…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ji7uiRo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It goes AMAZINGLY… Until Odo mentions that she’s a hologram, and ruins the mood. Cause then he’s like “oh shit she’s REAL” and gets up in his own ass again. He’s like “I’ve ruined EVERYHTHING” and Kira is like “oh god I’m in love with Odo.” She’s like “should I act on this clarity?” to Dax who’s like “uh, yeah?” and then all the tension is released, as Kira confronts Odo. They get in a yelling match like “Yeah, why don’t you just TAKE ME TO DINNER?” “WELL WHY DON’T I JUST SKIP THE FORMALITIES AND KISS YOU?” “YEAH, WHY DON’T YOU?”</p>

<p>And then he does</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PCeHxFz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Please ignore that his makeup keeps rubbing off onto her.</p>

<p>Everyone watches in awe. I would be too. Also some jealousy.</p>

<p>The episode ends with Odo thanking Fontaine, who asks him to leave the holosuite up for a few minutes. He feels like singing. He sings as Odo walks away, snapping his fingers.</p>

<p>I fucking LOVED this. It was actually amazing payoff. And Fontaine shows his first showing here AMAZINGLY, very entertaining. I am STUNNED I liked this more than the previous episode, but I mean hey, I’m nothing if not an idiot with bad taste.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 124 - Final Fantasy 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/25/RA124-FF3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 124 - Final Fantasy 3" /><published>2024-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/25/RA124-FF3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/25/RA124-FF3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rMFJlW1.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s just Firion again. Come on, Amano.</p>

<p>Final Fantasy 3 is the third game in the Final Fantasy series, as well as the last one on the NES, and the last one made by coding superstar Nasir. Final Fantasy 1 came out in the US, and then FF2 was GOING to get a US port, but by the time they were getting to the end of it, the SNES and FF4 were already out in Japan, so they decided to just… port FF4 instead. But this game, FF3, had no plans to be ported. It was skipped. And when they made the GBA ports years later, porting FF2 and FF5 for the first time over here in the US, they completely skipped 3. I’ve heard it’s cause Nasir’s programming was so hard to understand and he never left ANY notes, so they couldn’t even MAKE a GBA port, but it still means that FF3 was stranded in Japan until it FINALLY got a port on the DS in 2006, 16 years after the original game hit the NES. But that game is far more than the GBA remakes are, it changes the characters, adds more plot, and tries to modernize it. What was FF3 like waaay back when? And why is it so forgotten compared to those around it? Well, the most obvious reason for that is FF2 is a weird black sheep, and FF4 is one we got here in the US. But there’s also more to it. Let’s get into it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0bGhAS5.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’ve noticed something about the Final Fantasy series, at least the early ones. Every even game is story-based, and every odd-game is more mechanics based, with a job system. FF1’s job system was much more simple, this is the first real “job system” as we know in the series. You’ve got your four characters, and as they progress in the game, they’ll gain vocations from the four crystals, which give them new classes they can swap to. Your characters, much like in 1, are pretty much blank slates. They DO talk, but never with any real personality, and most of the time the character you have in the lead is the only one doing the talking, and they all say the same things. This DOES mean at the end that the princess was flirting with the femboy in the catsuit, which is nice. Well, I say femboy. The genders of these characters are ambiguous. They get actual character in the DS port, but like I said, this is the original. They’re basically all genderfluid blobs for you to play with as you want.</p>

<p>The plot is simple. You are four orphans who were chosen as the Light Warriors to stop the encroaching darkness, lead by the dark wizard Xande. Xande’s master passed and left gifts for his three apprentices. To one, he gave ultimate magic. To the next, he gave the power of dreams. And to Xande, he gave mortality. Xande was not very happy about this. I don’t blame him lmfao. Everyone keeps talking about how it’s the greatest gift of all and they don’t know why Xande is acting up, like they’re fucking gaslighting him. Anyway, he is summoning darkness into this world. You see, it’s a cycle. Years ago, the Dark Warriors saved the world, because the ancient peoples were using Light Energy too much, and it caused an imbalance that almost tore apart the world. And now you’re the Light variant, stopping the darkness. Neither is neccesarily good or bad. It’s a nice idea, though it’s not explored here as well as it could be.</p>

<p>You basically travel around, helping people here and there. You get guest party members, though they don’t fight with you, it’s more like the guests from Earthbound. The best of these guests are The Old Men, four guys who think they’re the Light Warriors and you have to save them from some Goblins. They’re fucking amazing tbh. The story and plots aren’t anything to write home about, but I found the writing and characters more enjoyable than 2, and that’s not even the point of this game. It’s a bit more light hearted and silly, which helps.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/c6jap6u.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The REAL star of the show is, in fact, that job system. There are 22 jobs, which you get dripfed throughout the game. You can swap at any time, though you have to unequip the character manually first, which is VERY annoying. Your stats and all that change on the fly as you swap, the only stats that grow and matter with the job are your health stat, but it’s not a big deal tbh. Like, mages gain less health, that kinda thing, but the variance was pretty small. There’s no real harm in experimentation and hot swapping, except for the Capacity system. As you beat enemies, you get points, used as a currency to switch. It was intimidating and I was always worried of running out, but tbh I never even came close.</p>

<p>As you level up, you have two levels: Your level, and your Job Level. Both increase your stats, so a level 99 person but level 1 warrior is gonna be about equal to a level 1 guy but a level 99 warrior, though there’s no way of that happening obviously. Job levels are a BIT less important than they’d seem, cause of this? There was no real reason to grind them, I found, but they’re not bad to have.</p>

<p>The real issue with the job system, that I found, was it’s a bit imbalanced. Some jobs are just kinda Bad. Like you can still win with them obviously, but you could do much better. Red Mage (tragic cause it’s my favorite), Geomancer, (my OTHER favorite little scrimblo), Bard, Black Belt, Monk, and kinda Evoker are all weaker than they could be. And there’s really only one reason to use Dragoon. And other jobs are good, but are DIRECTLY UPGRADED by other jobs, and thus become outdated and a waste. Warrior, Monk, White Mage, and Black Mage are entirely replaced by Knight, Black Belt, Devout, and Magus, for example.</p>

<p>Also of note, the Vancian system from FF1 is back, where you get a certain number of spell casts per level, based on your job. You can heal this by sleeping or drinking elixers, but you get way WAY more spell casts than FF1. Like, 99 max instead of 9 max.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/M6y7sMy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Over all, I found the system and gameplay very enjoyable, designing teams on the fly is fun. And the achievement set gave me a bunch of job related challenges. “Beat this dungeon with only these jobs” kinda stuff. This DOES mean most of the achievements were like “use jobs that don’t interact with this mechanic”. Like, there’s a boss who’s whole gimmick is supposed to interract with the Scholar class. Don’t use Scholar. Or the many dungeons that want specific jobs…</p>

<p>Okay, so the main flaw of this game, IMO, is its damn dungeon design. Some of the dungeons are good and fine, and they were trying a lot of interesting ideas to spice shit up, but my god… It was bad at the start, with the Mini Dungeon. A dungeon you must play through while mini. This means that all your attacks to 1 or 2 damage. You have to use spells (and I was forced to use a useless warrior in the dungeon for an achievement). That was a bit rough, especially as the boss had REALLY high magic defense, but the real problem is the back 1/5th of the game.</p>

<p>There’s a dungeon in this game called the Dark Cave, or something. You go in to get the Earth Horn so you can get to Xande. All of the enemies in there have an effect where if they take any physical damage, they will split into two exact copies. So you either have to use Magic, which at that point means using Black Mage, which is EXTREMELY outclassed by this point, or the Magic Knight, who’s attacks don’t cause the split. This is basically the reason Magic Knight exists, otherwise it’s kind of a weaker Knight. Uh, guess what I couldn’t use :D</p>

<p>I went through the dungeon to get the items, then again without MAgic Knight, then again with ONLY Magic Knight for the “beat the boss with only water crystal vocations” achievement, then again when I realized at the end that the achievement said “DIFFERENT” vocations. All told, I went through that dungeon fully four times, five to six if you count the times I died. The dungeon is like 10 rooms long, with long, winding, hidden paths. It fucking BLOWS. Even WITH Magic Knights it was AGONY. This is, in my opinion, probably the absolute worst dungeon in the entire series.</p>

<p>The final dungeon isn’t really much better. Okay, picture this: You enter the dungeon, a 5-room fortress, with no way to teleport out. At the end, you exit back to the world map, so you get to save, but there’s no heals, cause this game has no tents or cabins. Then you enter the Crystal Tower, an 8 floor tower. Still no heals, still no teleport. There’s also a side dungeon hidden in this dungeon, where you get the super jobs, about 6 rooms deep, and then you have to walk back out, cause again, no teleport. There IS a heal at the end of it but like, you’re not gonna walk 6 rooms in just to heal, so you’re relying on elixers. The enemies are all strong and will stomp your ass. At the top of the tower, you fight a boss, then get sent to the Dark World, which is ANOTHER six room dungeon, still no save, still no heals. This gauntlet is infamous, and is very, VERY mean. FF3 might be the meanest Final Fantasy game of them all, I swear.</p>

<p>When I got to the Dark World, I thought I was kinda over leveled, I was kicking the ass of everything in Crystal Tower. I got into the Dark World, opened a box, out came Xande’s clone, who hit me with a meteor as an ambush, bringing everyone from 5000 health to 1000. Oh, I thought, that’s bad. I tried to use my strongest attacks, but Xande’s clone attacked first, with another meteor, boom, all dead. Literally could not do anything. So I grinded.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Wy2q4v3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Thankfully, if you know what you’re doing, you can cheese some things. Like these Xande’s Clones, they will die to Toad. Which is very funny.</p>

<p>All in all, FF3 is a very interesting game, and probably my favorite of the three NES games. I had the coolest mechanics that work the best, though this idea will be greatly improved down the line. It’s a shame this was never really seen over here, because this game pushes the NES to its VERY limits. Like, you can feel the console straining against this game, it’s REALLY pushing it. Lots of ideas and QOL (though not enough lol). Oh yeah, one other thing, you remember how annoyed I was in FF2 where it kept putting people in the back row when they died? In this one, back attacks happen, and you have to directly move characters into the other row so they can actually hit, and then it doesn’t move them back, so every back attack was a “AWW FUCK I FORGOT AGAIN” moment. There’s always SOME of those in these games, I’ll never escape it.</p>

<p>Anyways, I put it to a vote after this if I went to FF4 or FF5… and my chat voted very hard for FF5. Which is basically FF3-2. So we’ll be talkin’ about that one soon~</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 60</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/25/OOCY60.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 60" /><published>2024-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/25/OOCY60</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/25/OOCY60.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RfaWc5Z.png" alt="&quot;I'm showing you my boobs, so could you look at them?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Don’t Know Which One Is Love</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Don&apos;t Know Which One Is Love" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 59</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/24/OOCY59.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 59" /><published>2024-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/24/OOCY59</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/24/OOCY59.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IDYPClZ.png" alt="&quot;I guess there's nothing left to do but go from &quot;sleepover friends&quot; to &quot;sex friends&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Happy birthday to me</p>

<p>I am also in my thirties. And I absolutely have the time and energy for casual same-sex flings. Hit me up, ladies, I spend all my time playing Final Fantasy games. I’m a real catch.</p>

<p>source: The Marriage Partner of My Dreams Turned Out To Be… My Female Junior at Work?!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Marriage Partner of My Dreams Turned Out To Be… My Female Junior at Work?!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 58</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/23/OOCY58.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 58" /><published>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/23/OOCY58</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/23/OOCY58.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/piGlc9n.png" alt="&quot;I guess there's nothing left to do but go from &quot;sleepover friends&quot; to &quot;sex friends&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Evolutionary Progression of Friends Platonically Sleeping Together</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Evolutionary Progression of Friends Platonically Sleeping Together" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 57</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/22/OOCY57.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 57" /><published>2024-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/22/OOCY57</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/22/OOCY57.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EtMt0Ed.png" alt="&quot;Lesbianism isn't a compromise, it's an adventure!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Fuafuwa Hakusho</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Fuafuwa Hakusho" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 123 - Final Fantasy 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/22/RA123-FF2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 123 - Final Fantasy 2" /><published>2024-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/22/RA123-FF2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/22/RA123-FF2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZWD691N.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So after FF1, I was still kinda feelin’ the NES RPG bug, and I mean hey… its sequel is right there, right? I had played FF1 before, a few times (though I had never beaten it). I had never played FF2, nor had I ever even seen anyone play it. I knew the main character cause of Dissidia, and I knew some horror stories about its mechanics… and also, I knew most people do not like it very much. This game suffers from what I call “NES Sequel Black Sheep Syndrome”. Games like SMB2 or Zelda 2 where the following game changes a lot of mechanics and tries something new, and people don’t like it. But usually with that, there’s a lot there that’s interesting, and some people really latch onto it. And people kinda have with FF2. There are absolutely FF2 fans out there, many who watched my stream. But they will also be the first to admit that while a lot of what FF2 came up with is cool, it was far, FAR improved down the road with other games that use its mechanics.</p>

<p>Since these mechanics ARE the most important part of FF2, lemme explain them. You have no levels in FF2, whatsoever. Instead, you gain stats after battles. These stats are, intrinsically, based on doing a thing. Cast more spells? Your intelligence goes up. Take more damage? You become sturdier and your health goes up. This makes sense, on its face. Practice a thing to get better at it. Unfortunately, a few times I found that I just had to grind, and grinding is slow and annoying, because stat growth is a chance-based system. Even if you attack a lot, your strength isn’t always going up, there are hidden algorithms determining what works. Fortunately, it is VERY easy to cheese. If you choose an action with a character then back out to reselect it, those algorithms count that move you didn’t actually do for some stats. You can’t gain health or mana this way, but you CAN gain strength, intelligence, and grind up your spell levels. This is VERY slow and boring. And if you don’t do it, your stuff will be low, ESPECIALLY spell levels. Spell levels are VERY important, and very, very boring to grind. But maybe the most egregious of these things is that, to gain health, have 1/9th lower health at the end of that battle, which makes going into a battle and having your characters beat the shit out of each other a viable strat that you’ll be doing, a lot. And it’s very funny when you’re doing this, because enemies run away based on the max health of your characters, so eventually they’ll run away cause you’re all being fucking weirdos. There’s also one other thing about this stat system though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iYtd58P.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>FF2 has got to be flat out the meanest and hardest FF game, if you go into it blind. If you don’t know the mechanics and are just playing it casually, you will get your ass beat in. This is because stats can raise, but they can ALSO go down! You attacking a lot? Your intelligence goes down. Casting spells? Strength goes down. This makes dual-classing kinda awkward. You’ve gotta plan out your characters before hand and not level them wrong. I did do some multi-classing with Firion, because Spirit, the white mage skill, cannot go down. Though attack CAN go down from casting white spells, so he was never quite as strong as I’d like. Statistically, it should only go down 1/6th of the time from a stat up, but y’know, bad luck is bad luck.</p>

<p>This isn’t the only reason this game is mean as hell. The dungeons have a lot of rooms we’ll call “trap rooms”. If you go into them exploring the dungeon, you’re put in the middle of the room, and the encounter rate is skyrocketed. So now you’re facing a lot of enemies and it’s annoying as fuck. I used maps, so I avoided all this. And since I knew the mechanics beforehand and had planned it all out, the game wasn’t very hard. But for a casual player? Yeah, this shit would be VERY frustrating, I understand why people didn’t like it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IbThEWf.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While this game is very weird in the context of FF, it introduces a lot of recurring themes and ideas in the series. While there are no moogles, there are Beavers that serve a similar purpose. There’s a Cid for the first time, with his airship. And of course, a plot. With like, characters. Your characters are their own people, and they’re not like… unique, or very interesting? You’ve got Firion, who’s a nice guy who’s kinda stupid. Maria, who is uh, a girl. Guy, who’s characterized as an idiot savant cause he talk like this, unga bunga, but he’s cultured and can speak beaver. And then a rotating cast of fourth characters, most of which die in wild ways, hopping in and out of the party. It feels very FF4 in that way. None of these characters are anything to write home about.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hy6FgqP.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, this game has a keyword system. You learn keywords and can say/ask about them to certain people and things, as well as using items in this menu. This is kinda cool in concept, but again, not utilized perfectly. It’s cool in some instances, but often times you’re confounded and there’s some really confusing nonsensical ways to progress, needing to ask one person something kind down the list, with no idea of knowing. Guides are recommended in this game.</p>

<p>This game is very interesting and cool and I don’t dislike it, at all. I quite enjoyed it. But I understand why it’s not universally loved. It has a lot of cool ideas, and those ideas would later be used, by the director of this game, for a series known as SaGa. This is basically SaGa 0, a test run. And I’m glad they tested it here first, before they ran with it. I am very glad I finally played it, but it’ll be a WHILE before I get the itch to try it again, tbh. And maybe just play the GBA version.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 56</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/21/OOCY56.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 56" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/21/OOCY56</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/21/OOCY56.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/irFkr4T.png" alt="&quot;Wel... is it me that you want? Because if so, you'll have to let me have you, too. Your beautiful, pale fingers, your cute, reddened cheeks. Your shining eyes, your beautiful, soft hair...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5SXJUxX.png" alt="&quot;and your heart, unsullied by this cruel world. But if I take those from you, even once, I may never, ever be able to give them back. Even so, would you give me all that you are?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yuki and the Authoress</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuki and the Authoress" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>