<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-14T00:03:30-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 175 - Newberry Winners - Bridge to Terabithia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/13/RA175-Terabithia.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 175 - Newberry Winners - Bridge to Terabithia" /><published>2025-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/13/RA175-Terabithia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/13/RA175-Terabithia.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YPKvZoP.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I don’t know if this is so much a thing anymore, but when I was a kid, computers were JUST starting to become bigger and bigger, and used for things that weren’t like, landing shit on the moon. And that included in schools. My media center was getting new computers, and they were trying to find ways to use computers for education. One of those ways was for testing. I remember one of the first times I really used the computer at my school for things that weren’t like, teaching how to type or playing games, was a book test. I don’t know if they still do that anymore, but that’s all this program is. It’s a test on a book that you’d teach in schools.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VMBUV6L.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I have never read Bridge to Terabithia. Not once. I knew absolutely nothing about it going in, except that I’d heard the name before. It’s a popular book from like, the 60s or 70s that they taught in schools, never taught it to me though. Anyways, the test is several parts, very simple, ranging from answering basic plot questions to putting events in order.</p>

<p>Like I said, I’ve never read this book, but I managed to do very well on the test. Why, am I psychic? Well, I DID go to school for literature. I know how books work. And this is a basic test for babies on a simple kids book. It appears to be a fucking DARK kids book, like, wow. But it’s still for younger audiences. So I know how basic story structure works, and I used context clues and judgement to guess how the story went, and y’know what, I got it right, pretty much every time. And even if I missed a question I could just redo the test, cause what was stoppign me?</p>

<p>This is a weird review, cause like, it’s not a game. It’s not a game at ALL. It’s barely even educational, it’s just a test, it doesn’t teach anything, it tests you on what you’ve been taught elsewhere. But this was a thing back then, and this was how I first interracted with computers, so it’s important to me for that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Bridge to Terabithia" /><category term="Text Adventures" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/12/LizstartrekVOY6-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 1-5" /><published>2025-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/12/LizstartrekVOY6-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/12/LizstartrekVOY6-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Tx1t43y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Equinox, Part II</strong> - VOY
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vhvdaMr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is still under attack by those nucleogenic aliens, after the Equinox ditched them. Chokie is hit by an alien and given a wild scar, but unfortunately he’s still alive. They kidnapped Seven, and also possibly the Doctor? They still have the Doctor’s emitter, but it’s filled with Evil Doctor instead.</p>

<p>Back on the Equinox, Captain Ransom talks to Seven, hoping that she’ll join them and help them. “You can be in the brig for a month until we get home, or join our crew. I’d prefer the latter.” “I would prefer the brig” “Janeway isn’t the ONLY person who can help you explore your humanity, you know”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fjMCKn9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>God DAMN, Seven. Anyways their stuff is locked by some codes, so they demand Seven do it. She refuses. So they bring the Doctor up and delete his ethical subroutines so he’ll do it. He agrees immediately. God, PLEASE make it so that he’s just faking. Sadly no, he doesn’t seem to be. But the thing about ripping out the memories would basically kill Seven.</p>

<p>Janeway wants to chase the Equinox to get Seven and the important Voyager parts they stole. Chokie wants to let it go and focus on Voyager, leaving Seven behind. Chokie, dude, they stole the part that makes you go vroom. He claims its all about revenge for Janeway, as it always is. What. “You’ve been known to hold a grudge” She has been?? THey focus way more on her want to stop Ransom than her want to save Seven, which disappoints the shit out of me. She has big Captain Ahab energy. Ugh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xbsBRPY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They chase after Equinox, but lose the fight. Which SEEMS stupid, but their systems are VERY taxed to hold off the aliens. Janeway feels really off this episode. They capture one of the members of the Equinox, and Janeway tries to get information out of him. When he refuses, she attempts to murder him by letting the aliens eat him. Chakotay comes in and saves him like “What the HELL Are you doing?!” This is REALLY fucked up of Janeway, and a very sudden 180. She’s doing the Ransom fall to darkness kind of thing, putting her morals away for a thing she feels she needs to do.</p>

<p>She ends up demoting Chokie and confining him to quarters, but follows his suggestion to meet the aliens who worship the extra dimensional aliens. She does, they’re like “we’ll stop attacking if you let us kill everyone on the Equinox” and she agrees, which disturbs Tuvok greatly. What the fuck is she doing?</p>

<p>And while Janeway has her 180, you know who else does? Ransom. He’s like “actually this is wrong and I need to do what’s right”. NOW? NOW YOU DECIDE THAT?! It’s too late though, when he tries to call them off and surrender to Voyager, he’s thrown in the brig by his second in command who takes control. The anxious ensign escorts him off. She’s just following orders, you understand. But actually she’s working with him and helps him break out to stop whatever the hell is going on.</p>

<p>Everything about this is stupid to me I’m ngl. What is it with Star Trek and not hitting the landing?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fvesr0m.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ransom shuts down their shields, and Max is now the bad guy. He refuses to go in Voyager’s brig, and would rather be stuck on a shuttle forever. So he fucking dies to the aliens, and the entire Equinox blows up, Ransom along with it. Everyone else is rescued. Everyone is sad about this. Janeway is like “He was still a Starfleet officer. He just forgot about it for a while.” YEAH, MY MAN. SO DID YOU??</p>

<p>They let the Equinox crew join them, but demoted and they’ll have to earn their trust. Janeway and Chokie are still tense. She acknowledged he probably should have mutinied against her. He says that would have been crossing a line. Then they hang the Voyager plaque back on the wall, which is poetic, I guess.</p>

<p>I want to quote one of the producer, Ronald Moore, about this episode: “The things that Janeway does in ‘Equinox’ don’t work, because it’s not about anything. She’s not really grappling with her inner demons. She’s not truly under the gun and suffering to the point where you can understand the decisions that she’s made. She just gets kind of cranky and bitchy. She’s having a bad day”. And it really just feel like that. This episode fucking blew. It RUINED what was an absolutely fantastic season finale and a great concept. Complete fuck up.</p>

<p><strong>Survival Instinct</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4y6pNHu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We have some scenes of Seven has a Borg with her unimatrix on a planet, then we jump back forward to the present. Voyager has docked at a pleasant location with a lot of alien traders, it’s nice! Seven is unhappy about this. Not cause it’s bad, just cause she’s bad with crowds. Her and Naomi try to eat quietly, but are accosted by a random guy who offers her some Borg implants he said he found for trade. They’re implants from her old unimatrix. She takes them then leaves to study it. The guy is then rude to Naomi, so clearly he’s not trustworthy.</p>

<p>We get more scenes of her and her unimatrix. They’re all acting a little weird. They’re y’know, talking, for one. But also they’re acting more like they’re already freed drones. Their vessel crashed, and they were the only survivors. The were seperated from the rest of the collective, and are now remembering who they were.</p>

<p>Back in the future, they’re trying to do SOMETHING to Seven as she sleeps. But are caught, and captured. But it’s pretty clear they’re not like, violent or evil in any way. They want to seperate the link between the three of them, as they are now seperate from the Borg fully not not each other. You’ve got three of them. The leader, some older guy, a Bajoran, and what looks like a stereotypical thug from a bad cyberpunk movie. Seven agrees to help them, but she’s concerned. She cannot remember what happened on the planet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LQw5BJk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They need to link Seven back up to the mini collective here to try and help them. There’s a chance she may get locked in the collective with them, turning it into a quartet, but she’s willing to do it. There’s a lot of stuff about family. They’re the closest thing she still has to family. Well, them, and Voyager. She has a moment with Naomi, telling her that she’s her family. It’s cute.</p>

<p>She hooks up, and we see more of what happened on that planet. They all became unique, their own people, but Seven was scared cause it’s basically all she knows. She ends up being the one who linked them all together, in fear of what would happen. When they find out Seven is the reason, they freak out and get pissed off, then go into neural shock.</p>

<p>The Doctor now announces they have a new problem. They’ll die like this. They can sever the link but they’ll live for a month. Or they could be returned to the Borg and live normal length lives, as drones. They also can’t be spoken to for their opinions.</p>

<p>It’s pretty clear what they’d want. They will happily live out shorter lives, as themselves, and Seven helps them with that. They accept Seven and don’t hold a grudge against her, wishing her well. Two of them leave to live out their days. But the Bajoran… stays on Voyager! She was Starfleet, and is happy to stay on Voyager, but she’s not able to forgive Seven. Things are tense, but she understands WHY Seven did it. She was a scared girl.</p>

<p>Seven spends some time with Naomi, her family. It’s a cute ending. Pretty good episode, good season premiere!</p>

<p><strong>Barge of the Dead</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sj9PaNX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Torres is trying a shuttle and crashes into the hangar bay, but she’s alive. Her hair is also all frizzy and curly! It’s cute. She risked her life to get a probe, but everyone is like “you are far more important than a probe. We care about you”. And she doesn’t try to bit their heads off!</p>

<p>Chokie shows her a thing that was lodged in her port nacelle. A shard of something Klingon. Some hunk of metal with the Klingon insignia on it, hundreds of years old. Neat. He gives it to her, and then it starts bleeding and screaming. That’s probably normal. It IS Klingon in origin.</p>

<p>She asks for scans of it, and they do, but find nothing. She orders more scans and Kim seems done with this shit. Usually I hate when people are like “come on you didn’t see the thign you saw, that’s wild” on Trek because Trek is finding new weird shit all the time. But in this instance, honestly I’m surprised Kim isn’t MORE done with everything. My mans gotta be exhausted.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nB4oHEi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At Tuvok’s weekly therapy, which is a thing Torres is doing now, he talks to her about her self hatred. She’s like “the hell are you talking about”. He then pulls out a batleth, wounds her, and tells her to leave, her and her dishonor. What the fuck</p>

<p>Neelix throws a party, a big Klingon inspired party. It’s partly cause they found that artifact, but also because it’s a piece of the Alpha quadrant so it’s a piece of home. She walks into the mess hall as they’re singing Klingon songs. It’s like a bunch of white people throwing a Diwali festival and the one Indian person walking in like “huh”. Anyways they celebrate, and then some Klingons come and murder everyone. Well then. Torres awakens on a bloody ship.</p>

<p>Turns out she’s on the Barge of the Dead. She’s dead. BEEN dead, in fact, and she’s being taken to Gre’thor, Klingon Hell. They just wanted to do a Klingon episode, and can you blame them?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QaKw9NJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They explain that she’s been in The Dream, something dying brains make up to think they’re still alive. The murderer was just waking her up. They can’t brand her though, apparently it is “still not her time”. She tries to fight the ferryman, Kortar, the First Klingon, and gets injured instead. And then her mother showsu p as another member of the dishonored dead, and suddenly she’s awoken in med bay. Apparently she almost died in that shuttle and was in a coma.</p>

<p>She’s now stuck on the memory of seeing her mother going to Hell, possibly for her sins and dishonor. She doesn’t believe in the afterlife, but a part of her still does, and she’s wondering, what if? This is a good “what’s real and whats not” episode.</p>

<p>She studies the Ancient Texts, and finds two things. One, her dishonor can in fact cause her mom to go to hell, cause of “the sins of the child”. Remember, Klingon Culture is fucked up and bad. And two, when people return from the dead, they have wounds that they got there come back. And she did keep the wounds given to her in the fight.</p>

<p>Torres is basically a born again Klingon. She has a plan. She’s going to simulate a near death experience and go back to the barge to try and bargain for her mother’s honor. Everyone is kind of belligerent about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MXjmTq9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Torres is really hot here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1ukH8tE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It works though. She finds herself back on the barge. She goes to find her mother, who’s kind of a bitch? Absolutely awful. She also refuses, she doesn’t WANT her to do this. “Cheat” her way into Sto-vo-kor. But in the moment, Torres ACTUALLY takes her place, and agrees to actually die. What’s her personal hell? Voyager. It’s just Klingonized Voyager. But no, actually she’s still on the Barge. No, she’s dying in the Med Bay. No, she’s on the Barge, arguing with her mother again, who is actually NOT in Sto-vo-kor, and refuses to tell her what she’s “supposed” to do, she has to find out herself.  What she’s “supposed” to be.</p>

<p>I’ll be honest, I also don’t know what she’s supposed to be. I don’t get this episode. I don’t follow the themes or what’s going on, exactly, but she throws away the Batleth while crying, and apparently that’s the right decision? Her mom says she’ll get into Sto-vo-kor. Maybe she’s just having an identity crisis and is suffering from a bad nightmare? I honestly have no fucking idea. Anyways she wakes up and is all good, and hugs Janeway first before her fucking boyfriend I guess. I have no idea.</p>

<p><strong>Tinker Tenor Doctor Spy</strong> - VOY
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/inhp8ll.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This might be the weirdest cold open in all of Star Trek. The Doctor is singing to a crowd, Tuvok has Ponfar, and the Doctor starts singing about him having Ponfar and needing a hypospray. He calms Tuvok down with it and ends his song to rapturous applause. We return to the REAL world to find out that the Doctor has invented a way for himself to daydream.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PTCcb3Z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Doctor why are you fantasizing about knocking out a horny Tuvok?</p>

<p>The doctor sends an official message to the Captain that he’s not being treated well enough by the crew, and that he wants a promotion, basically. She’s like “what the fuck” but hey, might as well draft a response. Meanwhile an alien ship is watching and scanning voyager.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sOLUAhe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They are the Onlookers, of the Hierarchy. They just spy on people and learn more about them so they can raid for supplies. Okay, sure. They view Voyager as an unacceptable risk, though. But one of them thinks they can hack into the computer to study them better. And it works! They get a live feed! But it’s a feed of… the doctor’s daydreaming. Oh my god what a FUNNY idea.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the doctor suggests for his promotion that he be given additional backup programming as a commander to help command when needed. The ECH: The Emergency Command Hologram. Janeway finds it interesting, but pushes it down the line, cause it’d be too much hassle for now. But that doesn’t mean he can’t be the hero commander in his own mind!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qWNLbL4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is all very exciting as he blows up a Borg Sphere by himself. The Onlookers are STUNNED, and are planning a raid, but only when he’s NOT in command. After all, the ship has riches upon riches inside!</p>

<p>The Doctor is walking down the hall, and is accosted by Chakotay, who congratulates him on blowing up the Borg. He’s confounded. Chakotay is in his quarters… uh oh. The daydreaming program is going off at all times. He tries to eject the core IRL, and they have to hold him back. They lock him in sick bay, but also hook him up to the holodeck so they can watch them. Everyone is excited, but Janeway is kinda disturbed. I mean, she promised him she’s treat him like any other member of the crew, and this is intruding.</p>

<p>Parts of this remind me of the first Barclay episode, but I like this a lot more. Some of the fantasies he has are a bit uncomfy, like romance fantasies, but like… a lot of us DO have those. We get it. He’d never act on them. Janeway sees one last fantasy where he’s so proud to be given the ECH program, because all he wants to do is reach his potential and help the people he loves. She feels a way about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BzAfzqc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The daydreams are fixed, but then they show back up. But it’s actually the Onlooker. His name is Phlox. He’s realized that what he’s been watching is NOT reality. And if his superior find out, he’ll be fired, or worse. He also wants to protect Voyager and the Doctor, because he’s formed a parasocial relationship over the past few days. I get it. I like the Doctor too. He offers to help them, but only if he ALSO pretends to actually be in command, so he doesn’t get fired. Oh boy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Tx1t43y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What commences is the ultimate bluff. The Doctor, anxious as fuck, talking to the Hierarchy leader, who demands surrender. The Hierarch actually could EASILY destroy Voyager, and take what they want, buuuut the Doctor has a secret weapon. The Photonic Cannon. A super weapon he built that blew up the Borg Sphere. And he WILL turn it on them. So they run the fuck away cause holy shit, they don’t wanna deal with THAT</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cPwF5ka.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor is given a promotion for his valor, and he will be given the ECH program after all. Wonderful, extremely enjoyable episode. I liked the Onlookers, they felt like Pacleds You Don’t Hate, and I love aliens learning about humanity from fiction. It was a combination of the Pacled episode and the Barclay episode, and it was way better than both.</p>

<p><strong>Alice</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kTF1XF9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is flying around when it detects a flotilla in front of them. Friendly or violent? Well, they get a hail, aaand it’s a junkyard. Abaddon’s Repository of Lost Treasures. They beam him on board, and he’s very interested to trade. He doesn’t have TOO much they need, but Paris sees a ship that looks VERY interesting. It has a “Neurogenic Interface”, which means it connects to the pilot through the brain, so you can control it directly. Seems weird, but sure. It needs a bit of fixing up! Good thing Kim is willing to help fix it up! “I am?”</p>

<p>Abaddon is sad to see it go, but is absolutely willing to trade. Paris names the new ship “Alice”, after a girl he had a crush on once at the Acadamy. He connects to it, but blows out some power relays and goes to bed. And theeen he hears voices in his head calling to him, calling him to the bay. Who is that? “It’s me, Alice”</p>

<p><em>cocks gun</em> ships haunted.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/svLwfyn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a montage of Paris fixing it up. He starts wearing a flight suit he found in her database. He gets REAL into it, missing hang outs with Kim. Stops shaving. Belanna and him have a date on there and she’s kinda weirded out by how he’s being. Aaaand then she starts manifesting as a thing he can see.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LEm4rhT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Alice. She has Overly Attached Girlfriend Eyes, she reminds me of Gifanny from Gravity Falls. She keeps wanting to leave and go elsewhere with him, tried to convince him to leave Voyager over and over. Also it seems like connecting with her is kind of… addicting? Brain washing? Bimbofying? One of those.</p>

<p>Everyone is watching Tom kinda become… less himself, and more distant as he’s working on this ship. It’s uncomfortable and kinda sad. He’s not SO far gone that he doesn’t at least try to save Torres when the ship literally tries to kill her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sX0gkAX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris at least realizes things are bad and tries to go to sickbay to get free of her influence, but it doesn’t go well. Alice causes him pain in his brain to force him to go back to the ship and fly away. He connects to the ship directly and they become “One”. It’s creepy. This entire episode is creepy. In a pretty entertaining way.</p>

<p>Paris and Alice manage to fly away. Voyager goes back to Abaddon to try and figure out what’s going on. He’s connected to Alice too, who tries to kill him for telling them anything. “I DID WHAT YOU ASKED I GOT YOU A PILOT-“ yeah, she’s nuts. They manage to save her, who tells them what we basically already know. She’s nuts, and wanted a pilot, for some reason. They find out where she’s going on scanners, a “Particle Fountain”, a kind of anomaly they know little about, because it ends up killing anyone who gets near it. Alice calls it “home”.</p>

<p>So either she’s an alien intelligence to some other universe, or she’s malfunctioning. Either way, Paris is probably dead. They can’t fire on the ship either, because he’s one with it, so hurting the ship will hurt him too. They need to shut down the ship by hacking it, while distracting Alice and Paris. So they hack into his neurogenic interface and hook Torres in there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XHzbPwN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s a Battle in the Mind, and he’s teleported out, just before Alice explodes. I guess she… got what she wanted? To explode in an anomaly???</p>

<p>Paris is extremely upset that he ever let it get that bad. “It was like I was sleepwalking. Thanks for being my alarm clock”. How romantic?? She also promises no more affairs with strange ships. But don’t worry about the Delta Flyer, they’re just friends.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 143</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/11/OOCY143.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 143" /><published>2025-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/11/OOCY143</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/11/OOCY143.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Etb1XfR.png" alt="Two girls on a train. 'You hungry?' 'How about we find food once we get there?' 'Sounds good! Actually, there's a place I wanted to check out!' Then a zoom in one the one chipper girl as she goes 'Ahhh....'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Etb1XfR.png" alt="That same chipper girl, side eying the other 'I WANT TO TOUCH HER. SOOOOOOOO BAD." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Girlfriend Limited to 7 Days</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Girlfriend Limited to 7 Days" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievements Unmastered 3 - Final Fantasy 8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/11/RAUM3-FF8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievements Unmastered 3 - Final Fantasy 8" /><published>2025-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/11/RAUM3-FF8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/11/RAUM3-FF8.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WGnZHeT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Final Fantasy 8 is a very special game that I had never played, once, in my entire life. I own it, though. It fascinated me, so I picked it up hoping to get to it, but it took me probably about 13 years. This is a special one in the Final Fantasy Ouvre, because it’s extremely divisive. There are a lot of people who love it, consider it their favorite in the entire series. There’s also a lot of people who haaate it. It’s a bit of a blacksheep, the one to skip. As I play games on stream, I also read contemporary reviews of games, and there were some scaaathing ones for this one. When I was an impressionable younger kid, reading those reviews but not playing the game, I agreed with them. This game is the worst in the series, I said, until 13 came out and I played that. Then it was the 2nd worst. But now I played it. I have formed my own opinions. And my thoughts?</p>

<p>I think I like Final Fantasy 8 more than 7.</p>

<p>With THAT controversial take out of the way, let’s get right into it!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v25cEbE.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Final Fantasy 8 is a very ambitious video game. It’s unique in Final Fantasy in many, many ways, all of which I will try to get to. Unique doesn’t neccesarily mean good, but you can respect the effort for a lot of them. There are a LOT of things to get to that FF8 does differently from both its immediate predecessor, and every other game in the series, but I think the first thing I want to talk about is mechanics.</p>

<p>Final Fantasy 8 introduces the Junction System. So, in universe, there are these things called GFs. Guardian Forces, I think, but we just kept calling them girlfriends, because it made for some very, VERY funny moments, like when the final boss exclaimed that they were using the MOST POWERFUL GIRLFRIEND. In game terms, this is a summon, essentially. These summons have their own levels and stats that they gain alongside you, and you “junction”, or equip, them to a character. The game has no other equipment aside from that, except for a minor weapon system that is less buying weapons and more crafting upgrades to them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/95QiDn1.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Each girlfriend also has their own abilities they can learn. These are things like stuff to help when they’re summoned, active abilities like Mug or Darkside, Cecil’s power from FF4. Passive abilities, like Encnone, allowing you to bypass all random encounters. Stat abilities, boosting stats or letting you gain stats when you level up, WE’LL GET TO IT. And finally, most importantly, magic junction abilities. These are ones called like “Mag”, or “Vit”. These will allow you to junction magic to a character in that stat if they have this GF junctioned. So, you equip the GF as armor basically, giving abilities, but also the ability to equip more things to increase stats. Make sense? You can equip magic you get onto these stats, increasing them based on the magic you choose, and the amount. Some magic is better for stats than others. Life and Cure spells are good for health and defense stats, while big damage spells like Flare and Meteor are good for Strength and MAgic.</p>

<p>How do you GET these spells though? Well, that’s where the Draw system comes into play. Each enemy has some spells that they have equipped. You can then select the Draw ability, which is equipped via GF like any other ability, and you can draw those spells from that enemy to your personal stash. You can ALSO just up and cast them, good in a pinch, but they’re weaker this way. The amount drawn depends on your magic stat, from 1 to 9. This means on average, with a cap of 100, you will be drawing about 20 times for one spell, but more than likely only 11. This can be tedious sounding, and it kinda is, but it’s extremely important to be able to do anything.</p>

<p>You may be going, wow Liz, this sounds confusing. And it kinda is! This is the biggest hurdle to getting into FF8, because this system is REQUIRED to do ANYTHING. FF8 doesn’t increase your stats as you level up as much as most FF games do, and it doesn’t matter too, because as you level up, so do enemies. You need to constantly be swapping out Junctions as you progress with better spells, so you can keep up. And when you get to points where you need to swap characters, it gets VERY clunky. This system is, straight up, jank. Not to mention that it disincentivizes using magic, as it’ll lower your stats. But it’s also kinda fun?</p>

<p>It makes it kinda like FF7 where any character can be anything. You have base stats, but then you can fit them however you want. This is cool, and really fun to break. But if you dunno what you’re doing, it’s kinda frustrating. And even if you DO know what you’re doing, the clunkiness can get to you. Over all I felt it was a plus, though, and I respected them trying something new with this system.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QFXsdAC.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I should also mention with the gameplay is the limit break system. In FF6, limit breaks happened randomly when you were low on health. They took that system and changed it completely for FF7, giving you a bar and once it filled up, forcing you to limit break. FF8 returns to the FF6 format. The more fucked up your character is, the higher a chance of their limit break happening, and the better it is. Lower health, more status effects. These use no magic, and aren’t super long winded, though they are y’know, long unskippable cutscenes, they’re not at bad as the summons, which I’ll get to. This is, by far, the best way to deal damage. But this also means you need to try and stay hovering at low health for a lot of fights to get em done faster, which is hectic.</p>

<p>I also wanna talk about the summons. A lot of reviews I read said that the best and only way to fight enemies, cause normal combat is so weak and slow paced, is to just spam summons. But summons have like, minute long summoning cutscenes. There’s no real reason NOT to use them, they’re just slow. You choose to summon one, then you have like, a backwards ATB meter that counts down, and a Summon health bar. If that health bar goes down, the summon doesn’t come out. Then you watch a long-ass cutscene, and then they deal like, okay damage. No cost, nothing. Now, I used summons maybe four times in the entire game. Once to see what they were like, twice for an actual effect (doom train reduces enemy defense), and once to see what the final summons animation was. It’s 30 seconds longer than Knights of the Round in FF7 and is absolutely fucking nuts.</p>

<p>The summon system feels unneccesary and not super great, and I dunno what all those magazines were whining about. I think they just didn’t get the Junction system and weren’t playing very well.</p>

<p>ONE LAST gameplay thing, and that’s mini games. So, Final Fantasy games love their little minigames. Small gameplay things that don’t make any sense and barely fit into the world. FF7 had so fucking many of them. You snowboarded down a slope after burying your dead friend. Does FF8 have anything like that? Well, only one, but it’s built into the entire game, and that’s Triple Triad. It’s a pretty fun and well made card game, I like Triple Triad. And you can abuse those cards you win by modding them into good magic and items, which is cool as hell. If you wanna min-max like crazy, you are going to be VERY familiar with Triple Triad. I just got all the cards. It was a lot of card games.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qyzcf59.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Next, let’s talk character and story. The main character of our game is Squall Leonhart. All my life, I heard the following. “It’s kinda public opinion that Cloud is an emotionless emo boy, but that’s not true. SQUALL is that, not Cloud”. I’ve now played this game and once again, much like Cloud, I feel like people only look at the surface and the first 10 minutes and decide that’s just what Squall is for the entire game. Now I’m curious to finish FF13 and find out if Lightning actually grows as a character.</p>

<p>Squall is a dork. He’s an anti-social teenager who responds “whatever” to things, but he’s actually just a fucking dork. It doesn’t help that we made his personality “extremely not into anything anyone else is doing, unless it fits his interests, which is card games” as a joke. He’s bad at communication, but is thrust into a leadership position rather suddenly, which he didn’t seem to want or care that much about. But he’s not emo, and he’s not emotionless, and he’s not a bad character at all. And by the end as you see him evolve, it’s great. In the final cutscene he calls out for his friends to help him. That feels like a minor thing, but that’s the culmination of his character development, it’s wonderful.</p>

<p>Squall is a child mercenary working for SeeD. SeeD is a special class of mercenary, trained by the three Gardens in the world. He’s joined by his fellow mercenaries from his garden, Quistis, one of the teachers who’s also a SeeD, his classmate Zell, a meathead who has Tifa’s moveset. They also meet Selphie, a slightly unhinged airhead from another Garden, and Irvine, the rootin’ tootin’ playboy cowboy from the last Garden, who’s actually extremely insecure and anxious about everything. It’s a good cast. But of course, we’re missing one more major character.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cZqtOt0.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is Rinoa, the plucky but kind of in-over-her-head leader of an underground resistance group fighting against The Evil Empire. She hires Squall and his group to help her fight against the Empire, and that’s one of the big things this game does differently to most other Final Fantasy games. This game IS about typical final fantasy stuff, fighting evil empires and stopping a world ending calamity. But at its core, it’s a love story. It’s about romance between Squall and Rinoa. And at first I was like “These two? Yeah right”. And it felt a little forced and heavy handed. But honestly? By the scene where they’re dying in space, stranded in space suits (yes really), I REALLY felt it. It was good. And Rinoai s a really cute character. She kinda looks like someone wanted to just make Tifa again, but has mild prosopagnosia, but that’s fine. Character wise she’s cute. Also her limit breaks use her dog Angelo! Angelo no joke has the most broken limit breaks, and he saved the galaxy by defeating the final boss with his “make everyone invincible for a minute” ability.</p>

<p>The villain is interesting too, as a comparison to Sephiroth. I really didn’t care for Sephiroth very much. Didn’t find him interesting, and he basically wasn’t in 80% of the game. Our villain here is a fun contrast cause she’s also kinda like that. Kinda. But not. See, the villain Ultimecia feels like a late game reveal of “this is the bad guy all along”, but her fingers and influence has been felt for the entire game in a way I appreciate. The final dungeon is Kinda Fucked, but over all I liked her presence. And she’s got a great final boss. Halfway through the game you name Squall’s lion he has on his ring, and I named it “Liony the Lion” as a joke. Anyways Liony the Lion became the final boss and it fucking floored me.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Os22yA9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Next let’s talk graphics. This game looks STUNNINGLY good for 1999 PS1. Like, yes, parts of it are chunky and look rough, like “best looking guy here” Squall up there. But over all, the in game graphics are quite good, and they move into FMV in a really seamless way that blew my mind multiple times with super cool sequences. And speaking of which, that FMV?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/heDfX8Y.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Really godo for the 90s. You can see some parts where it looks weird, or unnatural, but over all, it genuinely looks fantastic, and blew me away almost every time. Aesthetically, this game is on point. It’s also unique aesthetically. FF7 kinda mixed fantasy and sci-fi, but this is FULL on sci-fi, and it looks cool as hell.</p>

<p>The music is also really good. Not as good as FF7, I think, over all. But it’s got lots of great tracks. That final boss theme, The Extreme? Holy moly. Here’s the theme, by the way. It’s great cause it’s a surprise final boss phase after what seems like it was the last one, so it’s calm and peaceful as you’re like “Phew, it’s finally over”. AND THEN IT FUCKING KICKS IN. Head bangs the entire time.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WFjHWw_w91Q?si=kA5vAL34swUPd4fY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>One of those contemporary reviews I read about this game claimed that FF8 had the worst soundtrack of the entire series, and that it was a travesty, with no good songs at all. Look, no FF game has a bad soundtrack. Some have less standouts than others. But you cannot tell me the game with THIS SONG</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/orKgvGz2dHs?si=tX7aRK6mOOPtw_BQ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>is the worst Final Fantasy soundtrack out there. FF4’s soundtrack is way, way more boring. FF4 does not have a Shuffle or Boogie.</p>

<p>Anyways yeah, don’t have much more to add. I think FF8 is clunky, and kind of a mess, but in a way that I GREATLY enjoyed and had a lot of fun with. It’s a mixed bag, but I understand what people see in it now.</p>

<p>Really excited to play 9, because I know SO little about 9 over all.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PS1" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Unmastered" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Yuri Recommendation - Ouji-sama Nante Iranai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/10/OOCYSuggestion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Yuri Recommendation - Ouji-sama Nante Iranai" /><published>2025-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/10/OOCYSuggestion</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/10/OOCYSuggestion.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W3XYZqk.png" alt="Two women looking at each other in a very straight way." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I’ve been recently staying up till 3AM reading this manga, it’s called Ouji-sama Nante Iranai, and I finished it last night, so I wanted to talk about it. I don’t do recommendations as much as I should, so here, here’s one</p>

<p>Ouji-sama Nante Iranai is the story of two highschool students, Yukino and Nobara. They are 1st year students at this fancy school that has a weird gimmick. It has two divisions. See, it’s a school for both super fancy rich girls, and also hard working scholarship girls. These are the Botan and the Shakuyaku, respectively. Many years ago, this division was basically because the Shakuyaku were the Botan’s lackeys and personal servants, but at some point a Shakuyaku was elected to be student president, and managed to give the Shakuyaku more freedoms and rights in the school. But this ALSO means that the relationship between the two divisions is… bad. Lots of infighting, lots of catty bullshit.</p>

<p>But there’s two students here. Yukino, and Nobara. Yukino is Shakuyaku, Nobara is Botan. Yukino comes from an “ordinary” family, Nobara’s parents are wealthy musicians. Makes sense. In a normal setting, these two would never meet or come together, and even in this setting, they wouldn’t neccesarily get along, considering the bad vibes. But on the first day, Yukino meets Nobara in the greenhouse, and is entranced by how beautiful she is. But like, in a straight way, you know.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9OeOpcZ.png" alt="Nobara sleeping in the greenhouse" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Not only that, but due to a mixup, Yukino has to room with Nobara in the Botan dorms. Luckily, Yukino is a sweet young girl who just wnats to make people happy, and Nobara is a kind of emotionless doll who doesn’t really mind. They find each other fascinating, and what grows from their new friendship is something quite beautiful.</p>

<p>This story is, at its heart, the story of these two girls as they grow closer. Y’know, yuri. And it’s not like that “oh pure friendship between girls” kinda yuri, though the comic does address that at places, no, it’s pretty explicit. But not just that, but it’s about the political movings of this small school, the many students that inhabit it, and all of their personal relations. A school filled with students that hate each other slowly starts to come together, and it starts with Nobara and Yukino’s blossoming friendship.</p>

<p>This story has a lot of characters. Like, a loooot. And each of them has in depth backstories and character and motivations. Very minor characters who you wouldn’t expect get serious moments about who they love and who they want to be with. Like, for example, Yukino has a best friend from her old school. That best friend has a roomate, the ace of the school’s drama club. Okay, so she’s a minor character, but she gets a lot of indepth story is what you’re saying? Yes. But it’s more than that. We see this girl meet another girl and fall in love, but also at the same time, we get minor characters through THEIR connections. Later on there’s a school dance and they’re put into pairs, and the drama prince gets assigned a Botan who we’ve seen a few times as a background character. And she starts getting a crush, and suddenly it grows out from THERE. There’s a major love triangle between three minor characters. There’s a lot of things like this. You get like, 4 chapters for every minor character, showing their struggles and problems, with Nobara or Yukino (or both) helping them through it, as the school comes closer together.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Eg8oTBU.png" alt="Yukino waking Nobara up" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>At the center of it, though, there’s Yukino and Nobara. And it’s a cute sweet story. I like their characters. Yukino is a sweetheart who has MAJOR self worth problems, because she kind of tends to base her self worth on helping others and how much others like her. And Nobara is still suffering from the death of her parents a few years ago, which she blames herself for, and has walled herself off from the world. We watch them help each other through their problems and grow as people, it’s really heartwarming.</p>

<p>This is a rather long manga. 200 chapters. It’s in a long strip format, so it’s a LOT of reading. It took me several nights to finish, but I’m glad I did, it was really enjoyable, and I highly recommend it. If you like school drama, character drama, and of course social gap drama, you’ll like this one.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Ouji-sama Nante Iranai" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 142</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/06/OOCY142.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 142" /><published>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/06/OOCY142</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/06/OOCY142.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8SFUqan.png" alt="'A Prince is stared at by some girls. She just finished putting a sign up.. 'This should help us attract more attention' 'Y-yeah.... I think we're already attracting enough attention." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Love Yet To Bloom</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Love Yet To Bloom" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 173 - Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/06/RA174-Pooh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 173 - Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood" /><published>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/06/RA174-Pooh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/06/RA174-Pooh.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j5iduki.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Sierra On-Line was maybe THE Apple II dev. They made a lot of the most popular adventure games of the day, many of which you probably still know about, despite coming out almost 40 years ago. Games like King’s Quest, Space Quest, Police Quest, Leisure Suit Larry, Quest for Glory, Phantasmagoria, the list goes on. They were very, VERY big at the time. And around the growing height of their fame, in the mid 80s on their home town of the Apple II, they also made this.</p>

<p>It’s a simple text adventure with graphical components, mostly just a solid unmoving image. You move around a grid of a map, and sometimes into spaces on those grids like houses, in order to find items that are scattered around the Hundred Acre Wood. You then need to bring those items to their owners, who are scattered around, mostly in their houses. You are not Pooh in this, you’re just some random kid. There’s lots of spaces to explore, and every now and then the items move aroumd. They start randomized, and there’s a large pool of them but only 10 show up, so it’s technically different every time!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DcahVU5.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>For an Apple II game, I have to give credit, this LOOKS good. Compare this to a lot of the other games like this, text adventures which have an image at the top of where you are, and it’s night and day. I can actually recognize Owl!! They clearly put actual effort into the art, which is not a surprise since they probably had Disney breathing down their necks, and Disney will NOT let you do off-model art.</p>

<p>Over all, this is a very simple but kind of cute kids adventure game, where the adventure is mostly wandering aimlessly and occasionally running into a character you like. I was a HUGE Winnie the Pooh fan as a kid, so I had some sense of whimsy playing this, but there’s not a whole lot to it. There’s a reason that despite Sierra On-Line being one of the biggest game companies of the time, I could find very, very little about this game online. Sierra has a lot of great games I wanna check out sometime, and a wonderful history that was sadly cut short in the late 90s when it was bought by some big-ass firm that fell apart quickly, like all those big ass firms that buy companies do. It then lost all its talent and became a shadow until finally being devoured by Activision, because capitalism is garbage. But at least we can still look back on its classics, like <em>looks at notes</em> Winnie the Pooh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Winnie the Pooh" /><category term="Text Adventures" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sierra On-Line was maybe THE Apple II dev. They made a lot of the most popular adventure games of the day, many of which you probably still know about, despite coming out almost 40 years ago. Games like King’s Quest, Space Quest, Police Quest, Leisure Suit Larry, Quest for Glory, Phantasmagoria, the list goes on. They were very, VERY big at the time. And around the growing height of their fame, in the mid 80s on their home town of the Apple II, they also made this.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 141</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/05/OOCY141.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 141" /><published>2025-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/05/OOCY141</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/05/OOCY141.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rRb8eA8.png" alt="'That's right! It's times like these when you should consult the ultimate authority on love: romance novels!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Want to Make Black-Knight Fall In Love With Me!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="OI Want to Make Black-Knight Fall In Love With Me!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 21-26</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/04/LizstartrekVOY5-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 21-26" /><published>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/04/LizstartrekVOY5-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/04/LizstartrekVOY5-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KU4RpyL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>**Someone to Watch Over Me ** - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zg5Olxh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven is collecting research by staring at Torres and Paris. Torres asks her about it, and finds out she’s researching courting behavior. She reads the notes and is like “Why do you know when we’re having ‘intimate relations?’ Seven responds with ‘There is no one on deck seven who does not know when you are having intimate relations’ and almost gets her nose caved in.</p>

<p>Janeway suggests she just try to date instead. It’s maybe the gayest scene in Trek so far.</p>

<p>The Kadi are coming to visit! The Kadi are a species of conservative religious fundamentalists who lead an ascetic lifestyle. Their abbot dropps off one of them, a Kadi named Tomin. They have strict rules about what they can eat and do, but as soon as Tomin is alone he’s like “I’d like to try this spicy dish I heard about in your data files actually”. Yeah that makes sense.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iOHzNTG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Since the Doctor is Seven’s teacher in how to act like a person, he gives her dating lessons. At first it’s a little too narrow (she knows what sex is, doctor) to way too broad (Here’s a holographic guy, go flirt with him). It’s fun to see good actors try to be bad at things they’re good at. There’s no way Jeri Ryan wasn’t SWIMMING in dudes. Paris watches and comments that she’s a lost cause. Not that she couldn’t GET a date, half the crew apparently wants to jump her, but keeping a date is the hard part. The Doctor gets offended, and so they make a bet. Seven of Nine will show up to Tomin’s function with a date, and it will go WELL. I dunno about you, but I’m as into these stakes as all the ship blowy up ones.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OxS7KSn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Singing lessons! I dunno how this will get Seven laid, but the Doctor seems real into it. Real, REAL into it. He’s looking at her like… uh oh.</p>

<p>Kim got promoted from Person Seven Works With to friend! He offers her advice for some “candidates” she’s looking for for dating, based on her interests. “I didn’t know you had any interests.” “Neither did I, but apparently they include astronomy, physics, and music.” Funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CyXJdKA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We don’t have get to see Seven with her hair down very often, it’s nice.</p>

<p>She and this dude have a date. It’s a bit awkward, but certainly not TERRIBLE. They have a dance, and they’re both still awkward, but it gets better, until she gets a BIT too into it and tears a one of his ligiments, so he has to go home. Damn girl, how the hell did you pull that off? She laments that dating is a poor form of social interaction, it’s much better when it’s like it is with the doctor! When people just say what they mean. Did you know some people read Seven in an autism kinda way? No way, right? How strange.</p>

<p>Oh hey, remember Tomin? He’s fucking SMASHED on synthehol. Neelix didn’t even know you could DO that. He’s got holographic babes on each arm and is like “I’m thinking of leaving the convent and joining Voyager!!” Ohhh the alternate universe where they just kept picking up stragglers.</p>

<p>At Tomin’s party the next day, with Tomin still smashed beyond belief, Seven goes on a date with the Doctor. She’s doing well, and is almost the life of the party. Aaaand then Paris is like “well congrats doc, you won the wager” and she becomes, quite understandably, offended at the idea that the Doctor was just doing this for her for a bet. Which, yeah, fair.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NnlH5Rf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tomin is drunk as hell and super horny for Seven. He begs her to assimilate him. Get in line, dog.</p>

<p>The Doctor tries to smooth things over with Seven, and it seems to go alright, but he’s now coming to terms with the fact that he has in fact developed feelings for her. So now HE goes to PARIS for advice. Paris is like “Just tell her how you feel, duh.” “What if she doesn’t feel the same way back?” “Always the risk you gotta take.” So he does. He confesses, and theeen it turns out it was just a holodeck program. Understandable, gotta practice first. And then the real Seven comes in, and tells him that while she appreciates what he’s been doing, they no longer need these social lessons, as there are no potential mates on the ship for her to persue. The Doctor sadly plays Someone to Watch Over Me on piano as the episode ends. Poor Doctor.</p>

<p>Good episode, if a bit sad.</p>

<p><strong>11:59</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B9g40QH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I mis-saw this picture as Janeway with a rapier and got REALLY excited for a second</p>

<p>Neelix is infodumping about Earth to Janeway. Oh no he’s a Earthaboo. Apparently he’s been studying Earth and its many landmarks. Janeway asks him what he knows about the Millenium Gate (it’s some kind of self sufficient super building), and he lists the specifications of it, but she knows a bit more than that. Her ancestor is the person who built it, a woman named Shannon O’Donnel. And then it suddenly jumps to the past, the far off year of 2000, with Shannon O’Donnel. Wow, it’s a stealth Mrs. Columbo reboot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XvSKs4a.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s driving through Indiana and her car breaks down in the middle of nowhere. Every store in town is completely closed, except one, a book store run by a Henry Janeway and his son. He’s a curmodgeonly guy, a luddite, who’s making signs to stop The Millenium Gate. He calls it a “glorified shopping mall”, and that its forcing businesses to close. He’s kind of unlikable, I’m not gonna lie. She endears herself to them and and gets hired to help make the fliers and things, because he refuses to use computers. My dude, it’s 2000.</p>

<p>They try and push a romance between Shannon, who’s basically just Janeway but in the year 2000, and this dude who looks like Rick Berman’s self insert, and acts like him too. And then the theme of the episode appears to be how important ancestry and geneology is. The ONLY thing keeping me here is that I like Star Trek period pieces and seeing actors in cool outfits, but even here it’s just… normal-ass clothing.</p>

<p>Anyways turns out Shannon was a NASA engineer who got fired because it’s America and we don’t treat the people who actually do good jobs well. The guy who’s trying to build the Millenium Gate hits her up and offers her a job, if she helps him talk his dad down. Basically, he’s the last hold out, and if he doesn’t sell the shop by midnight, they’ll have to move the Millenium Gate, which is SUPPOSED to help the town a lot. Not that Alex Jones over here cares.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yaB7NAE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get into an argument about it, he’s as awful as he has been all episode. She later describes him as “listening to no one but himself” which is pretty accurate. And then we jump back to the future, where we’re talking more about family history and how important it is. But as she examines her history more and more, she starts to realize how malleable history is. Everything is biased by what people want to believe, so she’s digging through everything she can to learn more about Shannon, and she’s starting to realize that the family story of Shannon single handidly building the Millenium Gate and ushering Humanity into the future is pretty incorrect. She was just a consultant.</p>

<p>Shannon leaves the town, and then decides to come back and try one more time to convince him that he’s being a fucking idiot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xirah5M.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Why? WHY were you thinking about him? For the love of fucking GOD what do you see in this man? The fascist Janeway kissed from several episodes ago was more likable than this, because at least he PRETENDED to not be a piece of garbage. This is built on the romance, and the emotion of these two people but I can’t fucking stand him. His whole thing is “THIS IS MY SHOP I OWN AND I REFUSE TO MOVE IT” when they’re willing to help him move it, for free, into this new multiplex. Who the fuck gives a shit dude. This is like the “THIS IS OUR HOME” colonization episodes but way, WAY worse. Anyways he finally gives in at 11:59, and everyone lives happily ever after.</p>

<p>In the future Janeway is still disollutioned with everything, thinking Shannon not all that important in the grand scheme of things. But her crewmates convince her that it’s actually important, so okay, it’s important. There’s some stuff about “it’s not what she actually did, it’s her inspiration that rippled through time to you that’s important”, which I think is okay, that’s fine.</p>

<p>Over all though I really hated this. I didn’t really like any of its themes or think they were good, and then at its crux its a romance love story that is so, so, SO unpleasant. It’s not trash, but prolly my personal least favorite episode of Voyager so far, holy hell.</p>

<p><strong>Relativity</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JAGIXIX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Voyager being built in Utopia Planitia, and Janeway boarding it for the first time. Oh look at this crew, all bright eyed and bushy tailed, I can’t wait for them all to be alive. We see her walking around getting a tour from an admiral, and we see…. why, who’s that?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rwSzSzW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven of Nine is here in the past! She looks SO uncomfortable and unhappy to be here. She’s trying to find a “weapon” of some kind, and keeps calling in about how she has yet to find it, but keeps getting interrupted by y’know, the ship being a ship where people talk and exist on it. She finds the weapon, but can’t teleport it out, because it’s out of flux. Janeway catches wind of something happening in that space so she goes to explore, and whoever Seven is working with teleports her out, at risk of it possibly harming her. And it does, she dies in transport. Janeway also catches some chroniton readings, but that’s it.</p>

<p>The Captain of the Timeship is a man by the name of Braxton. Sound familiar? Maybe they’ll bring it up later. Anyways Braxton orders them to get a new one. We jump back to Voyager. Pretty chill day. Seven has hypochondria. There’s some cases of space sickness. Paris convinces Seven to join them for a ping pong tournament. Things get worse, as they find out it’s being caused by temporal distortions. They’re causing sickness, food spoilage, overall confusion as people call for help 7 minutes earlier than they need it. Oh also it’s starting to demolecularize the hull, that sounds bad. As the time cops show up, she catches wind of those same readings again. Janeway calls for an abandon ship, but it’s too late, as the ship explodes, just as Seven is teleported to the future.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zE9PukF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Braxton explains that someone at some point put a weapon on Voyager, and they need Seven to find it because she can actually determine temporal distortions with her ocular implants. Braxton also tells her to be careful of Janeway. She’s a loose cannon and cannot be trusted. She left him STRANDED in the past once, after he asked for her help! Yes, do you remember that? Braxton is, in fact, the guy who was FUCKING GOD AWFUL at time travel. He was the dude who almost killed Voyager for no reason, and then got stranded in the past, and became a hobo rambling about being from the future. The absolute fucking worst. His CO talks about how much he trusts his captain, but I have no fucking idea why.</p>

<p>They think the weapon might be planted during a battle with the Kazon, and they beam her in. Of course when Janeway senses the readings, she IMMEDIATELY goes hellbent on finding out what the fuck it is. They capture Seven, and Braxton in the future is like “GOD do not tell her anything” and of course Seven spills EVERYTHING.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KU4RpyL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They have a heart to heart. It’s Gay. They hunt down the ACTUAL sabateur and find out… it’s Braxton!! He’s suffering from temporal psychosis. He’s here to blow up Voyager because it destroyed his life. So, Temporal Psychosis is a thing that happens if they teleport you through time too much, you start to go a bit loony. Future Braxton is arrested for crimes he will commit, as futurer Braxton teleports away to another time, and Seven chases. She’s suffering from psychosis too, and after yet ANOTHER jump, she manages to destroy Braxton’s teleporter, before collapsing and asking Seven to help her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7jOsAg7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They eventually get him, but need someone to fix the timeline after its been contaminated so heavily. So they snatch Janeway and send her back to get Braxton at the start before this all even happened. Braxton’s CO explains after its all done that he’ll be reintigrated in tiem for the court date, as will they. There will only be one Seven running around. Aww, I was hoping there’s be a Future Seven for the fans and books to geek about. He also begs them to stop time traveling so much.</p>

<p>This was a really fun episode. I love goofy time travel.</p>

<p><strong>Warhead</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sCDEgJv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Harry Kim is on night duty, and is sitting in the captain’s chair. He gets to be in the CAPTAINS CHAIR but he won’t be promoted past Ensign? Poor Kim. They get a distress call, and Kim orders they head towards it. He wakes Chakotay up, who puts him on away mission duty to find the distress call. He goes down with a no name and the Doctor, and they find a weird metal tube who speaks in what Neli says is an old TOS robot speech. Only the Doctor can communicate with it, though it seems to be able to understand English. It asks why it can’t feel its arms and legs, and begs for help. It apparently does not realize it’s an AI.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N1O0X3c.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is an ensign on the bridge who we see a bit but doesn’t seem to be a major plot point. She’s very cute, I wonder if she’s single. ALSO, Chokie has barely been in any of these episodes. He shows up, people bounce jokes off him, and he stands there and looks pretty. Good use of your Chakotay.</p>

<p>They beam the thing back onto Voyager to find out what it is, and cause the Doctor wants to help it. He becomes very attached to this thing. He explains to it that it’s an AI, and tries to befriend it. They then discover what it is. A nuclear bomb, basically. A smart bomb. They need to get rid of it before it blows up. The Doctor begs them to just operate on it, put it in the holo emitters instead, and deactivate the bomb. They do, but then everything goes to shit. It gets angry at what they’re doing, and takes over the Doctor, angry that they were trying to dismantle it. It remembers who it is now, and its mission. Its mission is to fucking kill people, and it demands Voyager ferry it to its target so it can blow it up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hRpc8xB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Evil Doctor. Remember Evil Bashir from season 1 DS9? This is so much better. He’s willing to blow up if they stop him, and demands they help him. Kim and Torres are held hostage. Kim TRIES to talk it down, appeal to its better nature, but it doesn’t seem to work. It’s angry like, all the time.</p>

<p>A merchant they’ve worked with shows up, and offers to help. He’s like a smarmy used car salesman. Apparently the bomb was made by the Druoda, and he could sell it for a pretty penny. They’re uncomfortable with the ethics of it though and ask him to leave. His ship opens fire, but then the bomb sends an antimatter wave through the teleporter stream, a thing it can do I guess, and blows it the fuck up.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, other warheads lock onto Voyager and beam through space towards it. That’s prolly not good.</p>

<p>The bomb asks them to help it find out why its memory was jumbled, and they find evidence that the war is actually over, and HAS been for three years, and the bomb was recalled. It’s Very, VERY unhappy about this, because it’s so hellbent on doing what it was made to do, which is blow up these people. It refuses to learn any more about this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NCLs8Pe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>An attempt to stop him fails, just as more bombs show up, willing to tow him to his destination. But they manage to convince him to put his memory back in, aaaand yes, the war IS over. When he tries to convince the other bombs to stop, they’re like “lol no”. There’s some really good flexing with Kim and the Doctor here. I also like the parallels, with Kim like “you’re just regurgitating what you were told to think!” while earlier on, and for a lot of his character, he’s been regurgitating what he was told to think by higher ups and been afraid to think for himself.</p>

<p>The bomb sacrifices itself to blow up the other bombs. Superman. Neli called that this would be an Iron Giant situation, and it sure is. Before the bomb goes, it tries to tell them not to mourn it. Its still saving lives by being a weapon. It’s just that its target changed. Kim thanks for the Doctor for teaching him that AI can become more than its programming, and we see the cute ensign one more time, and then it ends. Good episode, very Trek.</p>

<p><strong>Equinox</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UfUUjOl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start by seeing a Starfleet vessel being attacked by Slimers. It’s brutal. They send out an SOS, whiiiich Voyager picks up! They chase after it and go to help. They get there, and the Equinox begs them to extend shields. They do, saving the ship, but no one responds to hails any longer, so they beam over to try and find survivors.</p>

<p>I’m a little surprised they’re so willing to jump into this ship considering I think things have pretended to be Starfleet out here… twice? For a trick? But I mean, any chance of finding others like they. And they do. There are life signs on board. They find a terrified ensign who’s like “But we’re the only Humans in the Delta Quadrant?” They find another who is kind of… numb to everything, and trapped under debris. He claims to have been there for two days. They find a third one who freaks out and thinks he’s under attack so they knock him out and beam him over. And finally, they find the captain on the Bridge. He says he was brought here the Caretaker. Well, turns out they weren’t the only ones then, huh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TGm3S2w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They welcome them all on Voyager, and try to help fix up the ship, while also figuring out what’s up with these aliens that are trying to kill them, some dimensional travelers. Half of the crew is suffering from PTSD. That girl they found refuses to go in elevators cause there’s nowhere to run in there, so she travels through jefferies tubes.</p>

<p>Their CO, Maxwell, makes some suggestions on how to capture the dimensional aliens. Build a net. They built a thing that brought them into our reality for several minutes. Oh my fucking god what the hell did you do to these aliens???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/90gNRTt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s pretty clear how this is going to go. Captain Ransom and his CO Max are whispering about not letting these bright eyed and bushy tailed lucky fuckers know what happened. Ransom and Janeway butt heads a bit, not sure who has authority, and Janeway explains that based on protocol, it’s her. But Ransom is like “Hmmmm, do those protocols even matter here in the Delta Quadrant?” Uh, yes, dude. Yes they do. Anyways there’s basically four Equinox members we need to care about. Ransom, his CO Max, the claustrophobic ensign, and the chill engineer Seven saved.</p>

<p>The Equinox crew plans to steal something from Voyager and return to Equinox, because they’re “going home”. Okay y’all. Meanwhile, Janeway assumes the worst. She’s sensing the Sus energy wafting off all of them, and determines that they intentionally made their science facility impossible to enter with radiation. So they just send the Doctor in instead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1wZyiQi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor finds some alien corpses. They’re turning the aliens into fuel. It was pretty clear what was going on, but damn, dog. That’s dark. Janeway confronts them, and we learn that in Equinox’s darkest day, they were saved by some aliens who blessed their travel by invoking spirits. These spirits were some nucleogenic lifeforms. They tried to study them, killed one by accident, and then realized what they could do. Janeway is diiisguuuusted, and relieves him of duty, and confines them all to quarters. They DO get the claustrophobic ensign to help them, cause she genuinely regrets ever having done any of this. But she just couldn’t ignore a command from her captain!</p>

<p>The Doctor activates the other EMH. Unfortunately, they deleted his ethical subroutines, so he takes out the Doctor. That’s not good. He infiltrates Voyager and goes to rescue Ransom. OH and the Clasutrophobic ensign is still working with them. Captains orders :).</p>

<p>They manage to get away, with Seven still on board, as the aliens attack. One charges at Janeway….</p>

<p>TO BE CONTINUED. Of course. You better watch out, Ransom. You stole Seven. Janeway hunted down the fucking BORG QUEEN for her, you ain’t shit.</p>

<p>This was very, very interesting, and I liked it a lot. I love the concept. I once was gonna do a Star Trek tabletop thing and suggested making a ship and thrusting them into what Voyager went through and seeing how they’d handle it. This is that. It’s nice to see as a mirror, and what could happen. But also what could happen if the people were weaker, weren’t giving it their all. Ransom kept talking about how Voyager was soft, how they didn’t go through what he did. Dog, it wasn’t called The Year Of Pretty Alright. And you follow that up by talking about how after a shitty time you met some friendly aliens who gave you food? Dude.</p>

<p>He’s awful, but refuses to accept it. He’s not even “what Janeway could be if she gave up her morals”, because she wouldn’t. She would never stoop to that level, because she’s who she is. He’s who he is. And he was not built for this, at all.</p>

<p>It’s also really fun to look into cause like, so, a lot of people hate Janeway and are like “WHY DIDN’T SHE JUST DO THIS AND THIS AND THIS TO GET BACK FASTER, JUST GIVE UP YOUR MORALS, YOU’RE IN THE DELTA QUADRANT NOW, WHO CARES”. Did they watch this episode? Are there “Captain Ransom Did Nothing Wrong” apologists out there? Can I hate them, because I already do.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 140</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/04/OOCY140.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 140" /><published>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/04/OOCY140</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/04/OOCY140.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2tHR7sl.png" alt="A butch wraps her arms around another girl'Aaaaya... san! Sorry for the wait...' and glares at two pickup artists, who recoil back. 'What...?! A hunk!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’d also melt and recoil if a butch looked at me like that, but not in the same way as those guys</p>

<p>source: The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn’t a Guy At All</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn&apos;t a Guy At All" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>