<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-15T22:47:30-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 51</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 51" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HdbAXcG.png" alt="&quot;Whether I'm a guy or a girl... nothing changes." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Boyfriend Sometimes Girlfriend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Boyfriend Sometimes Girlfriend" /><category term="genderbender" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 119 - Mario Paint</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/15/RA119-MarioPaint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 119 - Mario Paint" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/15/RA119-MarioPaint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/15/RA119-MarioPaint.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/za6MdG3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I didn’t own a SNES when I was a kid, but when I was like, 13-ish in the mid 2000s, my brother’s girlfriend gave us her childhood SNES. It had three games: Inspector Gadget, Super Mario World, and Mario Paint. Out of those three, Mario Paint was prolly my most played, even as a cynical and grumpy 13 year old. And as a cynical and grumpy woman in her 30s, it’s still one of my favorite SNES games. And it really didn’t need to be this good. Mario Paint was built to be a way that kids could play games that could be CONSTRUCTIVE, and usually attempts at that failed, especially with art, and especially back in the day, and <strong>especially</strong> on consoles.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ddzNaLL.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s literally just an art program. That’s it! That’s all it is! But it’s a… pretty good one? With nice AI. If you compare this to something like Art Alive on the Genesis, it’s stunning. That game is clunky with a dated AI. And don’t even get me started on Color a Dinosaur. But this has aged amazingly, it feels TIMELESS. And it’s smooth and has lots of tools to express your creativity.</p>

<p>You’ve also got the side content. I was really into the music maker in the mid 2000s, I loved watching Youtube videos of people making songs in it. Today, it’s still good, but I’m not as into it. And you’ve got the mini-game “Gnat Attack” too, where you swat gnats. Honestly, the worst part of the package to me? It’s not bad, at all, but if Gnat Attack didn’t exist, it wouldn’t effect my opinion of Mario Paint in any way. Ironically, Gnat Attack was like 70% of the achievement set for this. I had to beat a loop of it, which is pretty hard.</p>

<p>If you’ve never played the original SNES Mario Paint, you might not know it used a mouse. A lot of consoles back then had mice. I have lots of opinions about these mice, as I own a lot of them. The SNES one is one of the better ones, though it’s still clunky and rough, by today’s standards. But most mice were back then.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xlrdBxb.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mario Paint is beloved, and even today is 100% worth playing. There’s something really fun about using archaic art programs to try and make something actual artistic. Both of these works were made by me, by the way. Shout outs to Bob Ross. This and Kid Pix are the standouts of child’s paint programs. Today I guess they have like… Clip Studio Paint. Which is technically better in every way. But it doesn’t have Totaka’s Song.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Mario" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 50</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/14/OOCY50.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 50" /><published>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/14/OOCY50</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/14/OOCY50.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RTDyMEd.png" alt="A woman pinches herself as she wakes up in bed next to her wife" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>(By the way this is one of the best yuri manga ever and is highly recommended if you’ve never seen it before)</p>

<p>source: Yuki and the Authoress</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuki and the Authoress" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 118 - Mother 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/14/RA118-Mother3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 118 - Mother 3" /><published>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/14/RA118-Mother3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/14/RA118-Mother3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PfMlAEM.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It took me about a month before I picked up Earthbound and played through it, after Mother 1. After Earthbound, I picked up Mother 3 the following day. And after starting it, I did almost nothing else but play it, for a full on week. Mother 3 is one of those… very special games, and I had never actually beaten it before. I HAD played it, and got to chapter 5. But, much like how it had been with Earthbound, I kind of bounced off of it. Years later now, I gave it another try. Andyeah. This game is amazing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Za9RgR9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mother 3 is pretty much exactly what I wanted after Earthbound. It takes all of the improvements of Earthbound in the system, and SAYS something, and not only that, it says something new. As much as I like Mother 1 and 2, the characters aren’t really characters. And since the characters are the exact same from Mother 1 to Mother 2, that feels exhausting. Like, you’ve got baseball cap nice kid. Magic girl. Smart boy. These aren’t really characters. But the characters in Mother 3 <strong>are</strong> characters, and not only that, they are intentionally built to contrast with their previous counterparts. Ness was a baseball wielding tough but nice kid, a solid home life, and lots of friends. Lucas is a crybaby with a stick with a miserable home life, and is ostracized from his village. Paula is a sweet little demure magic girl with magic that can blast you into kingdom come, or gently smack you with a frying pan. Kumatora is a beartiger. She is a butch spellcaster who punches her enemies, and she cannot stop swearing. Jeff is a smart and competent nerd. Duster is a doofus with a limp who is here because it’s the right thing to do. And King, Ness’ dog, is a coward who refuses to join your party after the intro, while Boney is THE BEST BOY IN VIDEO GAMES, and will follow Lucas to the <strong>ends of the Earth</strong>. All of these characters are not only fun to play with, they’re fun to interact with, and they’re ACTUAL characters. They have goals, aspirations, emotions, and we see them, as opposed to in Mother 1 and 2, where they’re just implied.</p>

<p>The story of Mother 3 is rather simple, kind of. We start in an idyllic little village. They all live happily. There’s no one to even man the jail, because no one’s needed to be put in the jail. They have no concept of money, you just take what you need and leave what you don’t at the general store. They are at peace and one with the land. But then a strange force called the Pigmask army comes, starts changing animals into horrible mechanized hybrids, and lights the forest on fire. And after ruining Lucas’ life in chapter 1, we see them slowly and insideously corrupt the village in chapters 2 and 3 by introducing…. CAPITALISM.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TV7eHiI.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>YES. This game has some messages and themes it wants to tell, and one of those themes is that CAPITALISM FUCKING BLOWS. It corrupts and twists everyone in the town from people who are rushing out to find Lucas, his brother Claus, and their mother in the middle of the night after they’ve gone missing, to people who ostracize them because they still refuse to get a happy box (a tv), and upgrade their lives to modern society. This theme is apparant RIGHT in the logo of the game, and it handles this theme very, very well. It’s maybe heavy handed, but it makes you ANGRY, seeing how this society is corrupted and shifts, getting worse and worse with each chapter, and you can barely hang on, with no change of stopping the downward spiral.</p>

<p>The other theme this game tackles is, of course, the usual Mother series theme of Love and Family. I’m a bit worried talking about all of this, because this game’s story and plot is quite powerful and emotional, and I don’t want to spoil it. I’ll just say, it handles this topic quite well. It could maybe tackle the found family trope too, because by the end, Lucas, Kumatora, Duster, and Boney are BLOOD BROTHERS.</p>

<p>Also, the game improves on Earthbound’s actual gameplay in a lot of ways, which is impressive cause I only disliked a single thing about Earthbound’s gameplay, and that’s the damn item management. It’s still not perfect in this game, but it’s better. You’ve got item box guys all over the place, instead of having to call your sister and wait. That item box guy is the realest, btw. He’s just a hobo who believes in you. I love him. On top of that though, they did add in the rhythm mechanic. As you attack, you can tap A to the beat of the music to get up to 16 hits on an enemy. On emulator this is hard, but it’s a really cool extra little tihng, and it’s neat to get better at it and learn the songs. I don’t want to like, get 16 hits on every single song, cause some of them are fffffucked (some are very VERY fucked), but it’s still cool.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ORYW5t3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I should also mention that this soundtrack is fucking fantastic. Probably the best in the series, And that’s impressive considering it’s <strong>on the GBA</strong>, which is NOT a good system for music. But damn, they made this fucking thing sing.</p>

<p>Mother 3 is utterly fantastic. If there’s ONE thing that fell flat to me though, it’s the ending. I… don’t really want to talk about it, cause spoilers, but it feels like an anti-climax after everything that precedes it, and it confounds me. I don’t know what it’s trying to say, or imply, or mean. I have my own interpretation of it though, which I like. I’ll let you come to your own conclusions though.</p>

<p>In the end, I think Mother 3 is by far the best of the trilogy. However, I might still love Mother 1 more, for the nostalgia factor, and also what it’s TRYING to say. It fails at it a bit, ngl, it’s a very old school game and is held back by that. Can’t wait for that Mother 1 remake fans are making!!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="GBA" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Mother" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 49</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/13/OOCY49.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 49" /><published>2024-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/13/OOCY49</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/13/OOCY49.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SWAdvTK.png" alt="&quot;I NEED ROMANCE!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This would probably work on some people</p>

<p>source: El Goonish Shive</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="El Goonish Shive" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 48</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/12/OOCY48.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 48" /><published>2024-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/12/OOCY48</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/12/OOCY48.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/svW86Yn.png" alt="&quot;We're going to be the best fake girlfriends!&quot; &quot;BOOBS BOOBS BOOBS BOOBS BOOBS&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While you were dating girls in highschool, I was studying the kiss- wait.</p>

<p>source: Seven Days in Silverglen</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Seven Days in Silverglen" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 46</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/11/OOCY47.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 46" /><published>2024-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/11/OOCY47</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/11/OOCY47.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OLikiFp.png" alt="&quot;Master the way of the kiss, and take the first step to becoming a Great Kisser!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>While you were dating girls in highschool, I was studying the kiss- wait.</p>

<p>source: After Kissing Many Girls, I Became A Yuri Kisser…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="After Kissing Many Girls I Became A Yuri Kisser..." /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 11 - 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/10/LizstartrekDS96-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 11 - 15" /><published>2024-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/10/LizstartrekDS96-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/10/LizstartrekDS96-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vCTTDSl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Waltz</strong> - DS9
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NsVrj1L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Benjamin walking into Dukat’s jail cell. He’s being transported to a starbase, for a warcrime case. “You think I did warcrimes?” Uh, yes. I do. We all do. Because you did. Anyways he’s doing better! Psychiatric therapy is working, and he’s no longer… AS unstable. Just… kind of unstable. He accepts Ziyal’s death, and is trying to look forward, for his sake and for her’s. I like how this show keeps teasing and hinting that Dukat can and COULD be a good person… but he keeps making the worst decisions you possibly could.</p>

<p>Anyways this ship they’re on is attacked and blown up. There are known survivors, because they know that some shuttles and escape pods made it out, but… no one knows if Sisko is alive. I mean, we do. We see him and Dukat. JUST him and Dukat. Sisko is severely injured, shattered arm, sick, unhealthy. Dukat EASILY could have left Sisko, OR killed him. But he didn’t. He probably views Sisko as a friend, in that twisted Dukat way, and as a worthy adversary, this isn’t “fair”. So he’s taking care of Sisko, and doing what he can. He also has a general distress call out, neither Dominion nor Federation, “to make it fair”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2IXW5Lg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But also Dukat is clearly NOT doing as well as he says or seems. He’s seeing Weyoun, who’s mocking him and telling him to do murders. And Sisko isn’t making it easier, by basically insulting Dukat. I mean, y’know, he’s just being himself, but… there’s a huge fear and anxiety about whether Dukat will snap and kill Sisko, and Sisko isn’t really aware of it… At least, until Sisko finds out that Dukat never actually set up the distress call and was lying about it. So now he has to sneak around about it too, as Dukat is off discussing things with imaginary Damar. And keep in mind, again, he is very injured. And Dukat is eratic, and pops in and out all the time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bfRjHYw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>After Sisko realizes that Dukat is yelling at an imaginary Kira, he is far more willing to play the game, but Dukat is too far gone, and when he finds out that Sisko had fixed the distress signal, he lashes out, and hits Sisko with a pipe.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ztFoZoS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Now there’s no pretenses. Everything is out, and it’s a full on argument, a literal debate. Dukat wants, NEEDS Sisko to realize and tell Dukat that all of the deaths of Bajorans wasn’t his fault. So now it’s a nearly dying Sisko and a WILDLY unstable Dukat, explaining why he had to do fascism. He HAD to! HE WAS FORCED TO! HIS HAND WAS FORCED!!</p>

<p>This episode is fucking amazing. It’s also worth mentioning that this episode’s title with the developoment crew was “Dukat’s Head”. DUKAT’S BRAIN. I FUCKING LOVE IT. This episode, and this scene, has a LOT to say about colonialism, and fascism, and it’s… EXTREMELY heavy and loaded, and very, very good. When I talk about why I love Dukat and he’s a great villain, he’s acted so well, he’s FUCKING EVIL and VERY good to watch. It ends with him shouting about how he should have KILLED THEM ALL! Sisko hits him over the head, and escapes to the shuttle craft, but is caught again by Dukat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VEtSQCN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gul Dukat leaves in the shuttle, after declaring that “Bajor is dead”. Damn. This is going to be VERY important in the future. And Sisko declares, as he is rescued (they see Dukat leaving and find out Sisko was there), that it’s Dukat or him. He now knows what evil is. And he fears no evil. He will NOT let him destroy Bajor.</p>

<p>This episode is very very good, and is interesting a literal response to the fact that Trek fans liked Dukat. And I like Dukat, but fans liked Dukat in a different way. Like, they were defending his actions on forums. And the writers were like “oh no. Well, we did it. We made a good villain, but he might have gone too far”. And some people claim they went too far in the OTHER direction to fight that, and Dukat’s descent into an insane omnicidal maniac is off the wall, but uh, no. It fits. I am excited to see how it progresses from here, though.</p>

<p><strong>Who Mourns for Morn</strong> - DS9
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2gWzZ6g.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Odo comes in and yells at Morn about not doing a thing he was supposed to do, but Morn won’t even respond, which is wild, because Morn is such a little chatterbox. But no, it’s not actually Morn. Morn’s been on a business trip for two weeks, so Quark set up a hologram of Morn sitting in his chair, because Morn is “the mascot”, and when he’s not there, people wonder where he is, ask about him, are worried about him.</p>

<p>This episode, and Morn, is all a giant joke. He’s a background alien who was given a name. That’s it. And he was put in his spot every episode, a popular location for shootings, so he’s been seen a lot. And as he was seen a lot, people ended up liking him. And since they liked him, he was given some background information, and all of that information was meta jokes at the concept of him. He talks a lot (he never speaks a single time), he’s a big ugly alien but he is constantly SWIMMING in pussy. He seems to somehow be rich, even though he literally never leaves the bar. And this episode is just a giant addition to the joke, a large conclusion to the punchline.</p>

<p>Turns out Morn is dead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wsGbm3R.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone on the station shows up for the funeral proceedings. Quark makes a big talk about Morn’s seat, and sits a random person in the seat… who is Morn’s actor, out of makeup. This episode is filled with jokes like that. It’s a deepcut episode for huge nerds. I am a HUGE fucking nerd. We learn a lot of small fun things about Morn. Dax had a crush on Morn, but was turned down. IMAGINE. DAX, THE HOTTEST WOMAN IN SPACE, NOT BEING ENOUGH FOR MORN. Well Morn WAS a stunning bachelor.</p>

<p>Anyways, Morn left his entire estate to Quark. All the rotten beets he had in storage. His room, which just has a mud bath. But INSIDE the mud bath is Morn’s wife, who is here to explain that Morn had a shit ton of money hidden away somewhere, and she wants some of it. She comes on VERY strong.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7fcv1uL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We also start finding MORE people who are very interested in Morn’s assets. Two sleezy alien brothers who are VERY friendly and VERY threatening. And then an officer of some jurisdiction, who claims Morn was a prince of his planet, and all the money was the money he got as a gift from his parents. All of them are harassing poor Quark, who’s trying to get all of the money issues squared away at the same time.</p>

<p>Eventually it all comes to a head, ALL of it a lie. They were actually all bank robbers. Years ago the four of them, and Morn, robbed a bank. Morn betrayed them all and ran with the money. Now, years later, the statute of limitations was up, and they wanted their damn money. But they still need Quark to actually get the money from the bank delivery. But once he gets it open and shows off the latinum, they all turn on each other and start firing. Quark flees into the case of Latinum, and then Odo comes and bails him out. They’re all going to jail, and the latinum is ALL Quark’s, all 1000 bricks of it! He’s RICH! Oh, wait, no, it’s all just USELESS GOLD, someone sucked all the latinum out of them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QhgIu2m.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It also turns out that Morn is still alive! He faked is own death, and threw poor Quark under the bus, hoping he’d get the robbers taken care of. And well, he did. But Quark is PISSED. Morn is going to explain himself, but Quark doesn’t even want to HEAR him right now. But when Morn vomits up some liquid latinum, which he’s kept hidden in his second stomach for six years, Quark is okay with it. It’s practically 100 bricks worth.</p>

<p>This episode is goofy and fun. It’s a little slow around the middle, which is why it’s not an all timer, but it’s FILLED to the brim with fun jokes.</p>

<p><strong>Far Beyond the Stars</strong> - DS9
11/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iFVCRjQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is one of the big ones. Maybe the biggest one. This is possibly the most acclaimed Star Trek episode of all time. It’s certainly top 5. I’ve never seen it. Let’s go.</p>

<p>Sisko is overworked and stressed. Friends are dying in this dumbass war, and he feels like the entire alpha quadrant’s future is on his back. And he’s also going nuts. He’s starting to see visions, people walking around DS9 clearly out of place. After he has some kind of attack, Bashir explains he seems to be havign teh same effect as when he was having visions from the prophets last season. He’s looking into it, but then.. Sisko is in the dream.</p>

<p>Sisko is now Benny Russell, a struggling sci-fi writer in the 1950s. He’s a black man in the big city, and is struggling. His coworkers all like to tolerate him, but of course he’s harassed the cops. But the thing is, every other actor is an actor from DS9. Kira, O’Brien, and Quark are all co-writers of his. Odo’s his boss. Martok is the artist who writes things to help give them ideas. Dax is the secretary. Nog is the news boy. Worf is a baseball player after Benny’s girlfriend, who wants him to give up on being a writer and join her at the cafe. Dukat and Weyoun are cops who assault him for no reason. And Sisko’s father is a preacher on the street, talking to Benny directly. Telling him to write the story. Write the story.</p>

<p>What’s the story? Benny writes a story called Deep Space 9. It’s a bright future, a happy future. …It’s a future with a black captain. Odo, the boss, refuses to publish it. I mean, he’s SYMPATHETIC to the black cause, sure, but come on, Benny. He can’t publish this! It could cause race riots! RACE RIOTS! IMAGINE IT! What’s next, a black woman as the communication officer?!?! Quark’s actor is the best here, he’s the one who keeps sticking up for Benny, he’s a loud Jewish guy. Him and Kira are most vocal about it beign good, cause y’know, they’re minorities too. Others are sympathetic, enough, y’know. They don’t See Race :) You know how it is.</p>

<p>We get scenes from this man’s life. Him fighting for his story. Him trying, and failing, at trying to survive in a world that hates him. It’s very, very heavy, and EXTREMELY good and powerful. We see him win his story, but then the owner of the paper cancels the entire paper and fires him for even TRYING to <strong>write about a black character</strong>. I mean, come one, he was kind enough to even allow this colored man to work here, and he gets all UPPITY. This is after Benny is beaten near to death by cops for daring to cry about his friend getting shot and killed.</p>

<p>And then we get maybe the best scene.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ijrnOVX.png" alt="trek" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/vCTTDSl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I know people who mock this scene, and say that Avery Brooks is a bad actor. They need to shut the fuck up.</p>

<p>Benny is carried off after his nervous breakdown, and then Sisko wakes back up… he has a lot to think about. His vision from the Prophets is over, and now, where can he go from here? What if, instead… he IS just the figment of a man’s imagination? It says the quiet part out loud, it was always a theme and concept, a what if, but it puts it directly out there.</p>

<p>This episode is obviously one of the best. I don’t even have much to say about it. It stands on its own. It’s not an episode neccesarily for me, but I love it regardless.</p>

<p>I’m sure it was all the actor’s favorite episode too, because they didn’t need to sit in the makeup chair for hours.</p>

<p><strong>One Little Ship</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q69S1I1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey, we’re doing something NOT related to the Dominion for once! We’re doing some science! They’re testing an anomaly that SHOULD make the ship that goes into it tiny and smol. They tether onto it, holding it so it doesn’t fly into the anomaly. Dax, Bashir, and O’Brien are tiny and smol in the shuttle, and studying it. Unfortunately, things get bad. Yeah, I lied, the Dominion show up, beat the shit out of the Defiant, which is trying to keep the shuttle from falling into the anomaly so it can’t fight back, aaaand boom. The shuttle falls into the anomaly. They’re dead.</p>

<p>No, obviously not. They’re just tiny. They DID escape the anomaly, but they’re now tiny.</p>

<p>Anyways, the Jem’Hadar control the Defiant now. Something is new with the Jem’Hadar. They’re breeding a new race of Jem’Hadar, Alpha Jem’Hadar, who are “specifically bred for psychological profiles and combat readiness in this sector”. Whatever that means. But that ALSO means that they invented racism, because the Gammas and Alphas are kind of at each other’s throats. The Second, an Elder, is angry that the First, an Alpha, is the First now. And also not immediately killing Sisko. I dunno why he wnats to kill Sisko so damn bad, but they need Sisko to get the Warp Drive back online. So they get Sisko, Kira, Worf, and Nog to work on the Engine. The Second does not trust Sisko and his men to ACTUALLY work on the Warp Core…. and he’s right, they’re trying to get control of the ship from Engineering and hoping no one notices.</p>

<p>Someone does notice… The shuttle. They snuck in through the exhaust. I guess its just open to space, sure, and get into Engineering. So they’re going to basically act as the little angels trying to save the crew. They go to the bridge and sneak around, using clever tactics, like booping the door to distract the Jem Hadar like it’s fucking Skyrim.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RdAmPqV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They beam into a computer to change the circuits in there. This must have been very fun to shoot.</p>

<p>The shuttle manages to reroute control, and then goes in guns blazing, blasting Jem’Hadar with fucking photon torpedos. The ensuing chaos allows them to regain control. The episode ends with some fun jokes about being smol.</p>

<p>This one was a little goofy and fun. Weirdly, the Alpha and Gamma Jem’Hadar stuff will never come back.</p>

<p><strong>Honor Among Thieves</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/laWK7Z0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>O’Brien is undercover in a seedy bar in the armpit of the universe. Why is it O’BRIEN? Dunno. Just had to be. O’Brien is good at what he does, I guess. He’s not an INTELLIGENCE SPY, and he’s also kind of famous, but it’s fine. Anyways, he’s under cover, watching some Orion Syndicate peoples. He gets an in with them when he spikes one of their little brain connector thingies, and then saves them. Boom, he’s got an in.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on DS9, everything is falling apart. Y’know, cause O’Brien is gone. Yeah, as you’d expect.</p>

<p>O’Brien is playing the quiet, kinda awkward type. He’s almost playing Smiley. He gets in with Bilby, one of the small bigwigs in the Orion Syndicate. He’s an old, relatively pleasant guy. He’s kinda generous, has a sense of humor. Totally willing to work with O’Brien, who’s a genius who can fix anything, cause hey, he needs some stuff fixed. Who doesn’t.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PdAAJOp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode is as follows. O’Brien hangs out with literal gangsters, who are friendly, and then we see them blast a guy in the stomach for selling them shitty merchendise. And then he goes to a smoky alley and meets with his handler, giving him information.</p>

<p>It all takes a biiiit of a turn when Bilby covers for O’Brien. This means that if O’Brien is a rat (which he is), Bilby is dead. This IMMEDIATELY starts weighing on O’Brien. Bilby’s not a bad guy. Sure he’s doing bad, illegal things, but like, he doesn’t seem to really want to be in this life. He just can’t get out. He’s a sad man living alone in his apartment with his cat. He can’t see his wife and kids, cause of his work with the Syndicate, and if things go wrong, they’re dead, and it’s his fault. It’s a rough life.</p>

<p>O’Brien finds out a lot. He finds who the Orion Syndicate man’s on the inside is. He finds out the Dominion is working with the Syndicate. He finds out that the Syndicate is going to assassinate a Klingon, to cause instability. And when he finds that out, his handler takes him out. He’s in too deep, getting too sympathetic… so he decks his handler, and goes to warn Bilby.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rjw0nwo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But there’s nothing he can do. Bilby is in too deep. If he tells the Orion Syndicate its a trap, he’ll still be killed for sticking up for O’Brien. If he runs, his family will be killed. He could kill O’Brien, but he just… can’t bring himself to. So he asks O’Brien to look after his cat, and goes to die. O’Brien is shattered, but life goes on. He killed a man, but life goes on.</p>

<p>I really liked this episode, it was tense. The rest of the watch party didn’t, I was alone here. It does feel weird, a bit out of place. It’s not very Trekky. And parts of O’Brien feel out of character. But I still liked it, what can I say.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 46</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/09/OOCY46.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 46" /><published>2024-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/09/OOCY46</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/09/OOCY46.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UiNuWU0.png" alt="&quot;Kisses aren't something you can do in a half-hearted way! They're supposed to convey mutual feelings! They're supposed to make you feel good!&quot; &quot;Aren't you getting off topic?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If you come to my webbed site hoping for more than yuri, sorry, I haven’t really wanted to write lately lol</p>

<p>source: After Kissing Many Girls, I Became A Yuri Kisser…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="After Kissing Many Girls I Became A Yuri Kisser..." /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 45</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/08/OOCY45.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 45" /><published>2024-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/08/OOCY45</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/08/OOCY45.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wAerpKW.png" alt="&quot;And now we both have to live in a world where I've smacked you upside the head with a custom-made dakimakura of me.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Nishikino-san, low-key thirsty for Nico, left her Line background like that even after entering med school</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nishikino-san low-key thirsty for Nico left her Line background like that even after entering med school" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>