<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-09T23:10:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 15 - 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/09/LizstartrekEnt2-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 15 - 19" /><published>2025-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/09/LizstartrekEnt2-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/09/LizstartrekEnt2-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ldzddLn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Stigma</strong> - ENT
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a542LeL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are you ready for YET ANOTHER EPISODE with an alien of the week who’s REALLY horny for Trip for no fucking reason while he continues to be a dumbass at her? Oh boy, AM I!</p>

<p>The episode starts with Phlox telling her the treatment is no longer working and she might die, so they need to contact the Vulcans for help. What’s this for? Well, we’ll see. Meanwhile, one of Phlox’s wives is here to help them install a microscope or something. She’s friendly, and is CLEARLY attracted to Trip for, once again, reasons I do NOT understand. Oh wait, I do understand. Trip is Berman’s self insert character, and so all the women have to want to fuck him. She’s coming on strong, and I like a woman who knows what she wants, but it’s the fact it’s Trip, AND Trip has gotten SO MUCH action. He’s had like, 5 alien women want to bone down so far. We’re halfway through season 2. Riker had maybe that many women in seven fucking seasons, <strong>and he’s Riker.</strong></p>

<p>Phlox meets with some Vulcans, who make it clear that they do not want to discuss the disease, Pa’nar Syndrome. Phlox is doing some lies to obfuscate why he wants the info, but they’re pretty sus. They explain that the disease only affects a small subculture of Vulcans that they do not tolerate nor condone.</p>

<p>…</p>

<p>Is this the AIDs episode</p>

<p>I am going to fucking scream. I am going to Morb. NO ONE WILL BE SAFE FROM MY MORBING.</p>

<p>So I’m not against an episode about HIV in theory. It’s an important topic and one that should be discussed about how terrible the AIDs epidemic was, and how mistreated people were by people who decided they knew what was right and correct. But I do not trust Enterprise, and I do not trust Berman. And I am right to. Cause this already fucking reeks.</p>

<p>Cause, first of all, you do not write an episode about how serious and debilitating the AIDs epidemic was while also having the B-plot be how horny an alien is for your fucking self insert. Second of all, Berman is notably a raging homophobe. But it’s okay because it’s not like T’Pol is gay. INSTEAD, SHE WAS SEXUALLY ASSAULTED AND GIVEN THE DISEASE THAT WAY.</p>

<p>NO ONE IS SAFE.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W0eBAv8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Pa’nar Syndrome is contracted by improper mind melds. This is also introducing a lot of lore about mind melds. You know how we’ve had four series with a bunch of mind melding, and it’s always been a normal regular thing all Vulcans can do? Forget that. It’s disgusting behavior that no Vulcan tolerates, and only a small minority can even do it.</p>

<p>The Vulcans find out T’Pol has it, and when Archer finds out, he’s pissed he wasn’t told. Dude, you do know what doctor patient confidentiality is right? Phlox straight up calls him out on it and he ignores it. Lovely. But for his credit, he does clean his shit up once he finds out what’s up. She was sexually assaulted, given this disease, and if the high command finds out they might fire her. Cause intolerance. It’s not logical, by ANY means, and you cannot use logic to argue for this kind of intolerance. GOD I hate what they did with Vulcans in this fucking show, holy SHIT they are awful.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FyUI2Y1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A Vulcan sneaks some research to T’Pol. Why? Not cause prejudice is WRONG, of course. It’s cause he’s actually part of the minority. Of course. It’s only bad when you’re affected by it.</p>

<p>I really can’t stress how fucking awful the Vulcans are with this, they are so poorly written with no care for logic or consistancy. We need to start a temporal cold war, go back in time, and remove Rick Berman from power.</p>

<p>You may notice I’ve not been talking about the B-plot at all. That’s cause its bad. Trip is of course a fucking prejudiced idiot who doesn’t understand other cultures and is like “YOU CAN ONLY DATE ONE PERSON THAT’S WEIRD” and he refuses to talk with Phlox until WAY too late in the episode cause he’s a fucking idiot who refuses to talk to his friends or understand other cultures.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ldzddLn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>When he DOES talk to Phlox about it, finally, he’s like “I was told to never fuck another man’s wife and I can’t change that”. Of course, it’s all about the WOMAN in this. Phlox LITERALLY says “Your loss”, which is funny. Fucking conservative southern man hangups.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mRVlfs7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neli made this image which is good.</p>

<p>They get a hearing about the ethics of her being fired over this. T’Pol refuses to mention that she got it via rape, because she doesn’t want to contribute to stigmas against the minority that can do this. That’s fair.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I6le36f.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The only good scene in this entire episode is the one where Archer straight up says “WOW you all are bigoted, what the fuck is wrong with you”. He doesn’t call them out about how illogical it is, but of course it is. T’Pol is going to be fired anyway, but then the one gay vulcan on the council, the one who snuck info to her earlier, comes out and defends her. The others IMMEDIATELY turn on him, and then he lets slip that she was raped, even though she made him promise not to. So yeah, throwing gay people under the bus is bad, but a gay person can throw himself and his people under the bus, that’s fine. He’s fired, of course, but T’Pol is protected from being fired. The end.</p>

<p>Holy fucking shit I hated this so god damn much. 44 MILLION PEOPLE DID NOT FUCKING DIE FOR THIS.</p>

<p><strong>Cease Fire</strong> - ENT
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t5qRtFA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh thank GOD, Shran is here. The Andorians are fighting the Vulcans, and taking very heavy casualties. But the Vulcans say they want a cease fire. The Andorians, of course, do not trust them, because Vulcans are well known for being awful. But he has an idea. Someone who can be a good mediator. A Pink Skin, as he calls them. Which feels like a slur.</p>

<p>Archer gets the call. He thinks the Vulcans want him as the ambassador, and he IS basically the closest Earth has to an ambassador, which is weird. When he gets there, the Vulcan ambassador hates that he’s there, cause he’s fucking horrible. And he demands Archer take a spy down so that they can make the treaty go in Vulcan’s favor. Archer of course refuses to do that, and takes T’Pol instead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2BtDgsW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look, it’s Suzie Plakson, the actor who played K’Ehleyr, the hottest woman in space.</p>

<p>So what’s the problem here? Well, years ago, Andorians came and started to terraform this D-class planet, smaller than Earth’s moon. It has dangerous radiation and is a shitty awful rock. But the Vulcans saw them moving closer to their territory, and decided to claim it as well, for defensive purposes, and annexed it during a war years ago. So they’re obviously in the wrong, right? This is obviously Vulcan aggression.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3v7l3Tg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Andorians are testy and annoyed. They don’t trust Archer much, except for Shran, who is pretty okay with Archer by this point. Shran, for what its worth, is VERY willing to talk and try and work things out. His second in command is very aggressive, but he shuts her down. All he wants is the planet back, which they annexed in a war long ago. Archer agrees to try and get Ambassador Soval, the shithead he is, to come down and talk directly, not someone who can deflect and say “I’ll go to my superiors”. So he gets Soval to come down, and they’re shot down, not clear by who. It was almost certainly the Vulcans. Either that or the aggressive second in command.</p>

<p>Shran, for what its worth, thinks its his second in command. But he still gives her direct orders to go and recover them and keep them safe. Yeah, alright man.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Andorians have some reinforcements arriving in a ship. The Vulcans and Andorians move towards each other to fight… when Trip makes an order. Move the Enterprise between them. Holy shit, a <strong>good Trip moment??</strong> He goes “I will fire upon ANYONE who make an aggressive move. Let’s not start a war today, folks.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HGTaQpY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay, yeah, it was the second in command. A shame. Shran gets there, sees that Archer is fighting her, and after some talking, thankfully believes Archer and has her arrested. She’s like “There are many others who feel the way I do. We need to kill the Vulcans for what they’ve done”. Shran says he intends to make a stand, and prove himself as honorable. No more killing.</p>

<p>Shran has some VERY good lines. Archer: “I believe I’ve heard that compromises are what happens when both parties are disassisfied.” Shran: “Then these talks have been EXTREMELY successful. Welp, drink with me, to our mutual disatisfaction.”</p>

<p>This was just straight up a good episode. More of this please.</p>

<p><strong>Future Tense</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/81z02up.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise finds a random damaged ship out in the middle of nowhere. A stealth ship that bounces all scans, no engine, a fused hatch, and a dead human inside. Perhaps Zefram Cochrane, who canonically disappeared and reappeared in TOS? No obviously not, we know that. But who? Weirder still, the ship appears… bigger on the inside than the outside.</p>

<p>Holy SHIT, it’s a Dr. Who crossover.</p>

<p>While Trip and Reed are deep in temporal nonsense, the Suliban show up. Oh god dammit, it’s a temporal cold war episode. The Suliban demand the ship, Archer says “nah”, and they fight. But somehow some Suliban sneak on board and try to vent the launch bay, even while Trip and Reed are in there. But they manage to shake them off, for now.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Phlox finds out our dead friend is human, yes…. but part Vulcan. And also a few other things. MANY generations of interspecies breeding. Humans gonna fuck aliens, thats just what we do.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ChSjmnA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They look at some of the Future Notes they still have from whats his face, and find out its a future ship. Meanwhile, Archer and T’Pol are super hung up on the idea of Humans and Vulcans breeding, because of y’know, the sexual tension.</p>

<p>Anyways another ship shows up. It’s a ship that’s not immediately recognizable… but T’Pol knows what it is. A Tholian ship. Holy SHIT, the Tholians??? Been excited to see them! I know that Enterprise has some Tholians, and a Gorn, and I’ve been wanting that for ages. I doubt it’ll be as exciting as it is in my mind. The Tholian communicates with squeaks and squeals, and then a robot voice. It’s very Orz-y. It’s like “Archer, we are here to retrieve the vessel. It is dangerous for you.” and then when Archer says no, they try and tractor Enterprise, but fuck off unhappily when Archer threatens to destroy the ship. Archer is making NO friends today.</p>

<p>Good weird star trek moment where Reed and Trip are doing work on the ship, and then the scene keeps happening over and over, as soon as they open the hatch. They eventually realize it, and it’s kinda funny. At first I was like “Weird glitch in the video- oh”. The ship is releasing some unknown radiation, like the Tholians said. Whoops! Might be dangerous. T’Pol wants that ship gone, or destroyed. Archer wants to keep it so they can take a more active part in this temporal cold war. T’Pol says that is a very, very bad idea. I agree. That means we’d get more Temporal Cold War episodes.</p>

<p>They’re chased by some Suliban, but thankfully a Vulcan cruiser is nearby to help. They flee to them, injured and limping, aaaand the ship is damaged. By the Tholians. Uh oh. The Tholians make quick work of the Suliban, and Archer plans a surprise for them. He and Reed set up a fucking nuke inside the ship, though time keeps resetting so they have to get faster and faster at setting up this nuke. They send it out, aaaaand the warhead has been neutralized. So much for THAT plan. Then, all things related to the ship disappear, and the Tholians just dip.</p>

<p>The episode kinda just fizzles and ends, but not before Archer makes one more comment about Vulcans and Humans fucking. You just can’t get off this, can you man?</p>

<p>This was fine, I just don’t care about temporal cold war shit, or T’parcher, or whatever the ship is called. Archol?</p>

<p><strong>Canamar</strong> - ENT
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gCyELLG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The shuttle Archer and Trip (of course its more Trip) were using is found floating dead in space. Turns out they were abducted. Some aliens assumed Archer and Trip were smuggling and are sending them to Canamar, a notorious penal colony. The guards keep shocking them whenever they want cause they’re cops. The criminals aren’t much better.</p>

<p>Enterprise finds them, and gets them released. Unfortuantely, this happens RIGHT before a prison riot and the criminals take over the ship. Suddenly, its Con Air. Archer plays this new prison riot well, basically taking the role of “Yeah I was a smuggler all along”. The lead criminal here is a guy named Kuroda Lor-ehn. He used to be at this jail, Canamar, which they were all being taken to. He is not going back. Ever. He is NEVER going back.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1vVQ27r.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some ships find the transport vessel and try to take them out, but with Trips help, they manage to escape. Obviously, Archer and Trip are NOT happy they’re doing this, and when Kuroda orders Archer, at gun point, to blow up the enemy ships, he refuses. He’s only wanted for smuggling, not murder.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X4sSSkq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer gets on Kuroda’s good side. He offers to work with Trip and Archer, and tells his story. He was arrested even though he was innocent and thrown in a shitty jail for 5 years. That started him on his path to darkness. I wonder what this episode thinks about the jailing system. The answer is, not much. I don’t think they thought very hard abotu the politics of this at all.</p>

<p>Kuroda doesn’t plan to release any of the other prisoners. He’ll have the ship incinerated, while they get out scot free. Wow, what a dick. So now Archer has even MORE lives that he has to save. They just keep piling em up on this guy. Time to try and take the ship. Trip has the Nausicaan, Archer has the grizzled veteran murderer. Evenly matched, for sure. Obviously it doesn’t work, but the next attempt works, with Enterprise people bursting in to save everyone, just as the shuttle’s orbit starts to decay and kill everyone. Kuroda has one last Trekian fight with Archer. WHY is he? He could just go with them? Because this makes it easier to leave him to die in the ship, of course. Archer wins by using the tools of the oppressors to defeat him, and then Kuroda dies, rather dying than going back to prison.</p>

<p>Archer yells at the ambassador and tells him to fuck off, and he sits there sulking like “but our arrest first ask questions later policy always works ):”</p>

<p>This was… functional.</p>

<p><strong>The Crossing</strong> - ENT
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zySz1G9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise is unceremoneously eaten by a giant whale-shark ship. It’s very blue. They send a shuttle pod out to try and explode the inside of the ship. Inside are these weird floating ghost thingies. One of them possesses Trip for a few seconds, weirding everyone out. They take him back, and it SEEMS fine, but soon he’s acting very strangely. Getting confused, acting like others are his superior officer, wandering off.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gCUaAYV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find Tucker, who’s eating, and is like “Y’all gotta TRY this, have you?” “Uh, it’s called bread.” Turns out he’s been fully taken over by the wisps outside, which he is fine with being called. He says Tucker will be back, he just wanted to experience this. Archer is very, VERY aggressive about this. “I want my crewman back and I want my ship released!” I mean, dude, this is a first contact situation, and the wisps are NOT aggresive, they went “He’s having a good time and we just wanted to experience what it was like to have bodies”. But Archer is like “FUCK YOU GIVE ME MY CREWMAN”.</p>

<p>The worst part is he’ll be proven right by the end of this episode. And the moral of the story will be that it’s right to be xenophobic and not trust other cultures.</p>

<p>This series is the worst, and I think it can all be pointed to the politics of its era. 9/11 era USA. It’s dangerous. Archer is like “Maybe T’Pol is right and I’m being xenophobic because they’re so different”, literally a few episodes after he claimed that Humanity left bigotry behind long ago. But again, he’s proven right.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t1qXfgM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>More wisps move in and are less…. cooperative than the first. He’s also like “You should join the crossing with us and try to be male”. T’Pol is like “I’ve never thought about it”, because being trans doesn’t exist in the 22nd century. As more people are taken over, they need to find out who’s themselves and who’s not. So now its The Thing, but we know Phlox can’t be taken, he’s apparently incompatable. They find a way to scan for taken crewmen, and also find out, kinda by accident, that the Catwalk is a space they can’t get into, due to its plating.</p>

<p>T’Pol believes she can resist the wisps, and goes out of the Catwalk to try and stop them. They immediately try to take her, but she DOES resist. This also means she can read them, and knows their plan. Okay, why can’t Tucker… whatever. So, their ship is dying, and they need to move to hosts. They can’t just live in space. But uh, they’re not in the ship anymore?? They have to move from the ship to the vacuum of space. And apparently being in a corpse is the same as being in the vacuum of space. Hmm. I think this is dumb and poorly written.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEXufYp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At least this episode gives Phlox more to do, cause he’s the only one who can easily wander through the ship. Anyways it turns out that Tucker has actually been taken, and is now aware of their plan and is going to stop them. They have scanners that tell them if someone’s taken? What the fuck?</p>

<p>Tucker goes to fight Phlox, and it’s cool to see Phlox fight. He releases a gas which will apparently knock the wisps out of him. He succeeds and knocks the wisps out of everyone, who go to… space. This episode is dumb. They try to leave, but the ship persues them, ready to eat them again. So they blow the ship up, killing every single one of the alien wisps.</p>

<p>SUCCESSFUL FIRST CONTACT. But it’s okay, they were The Other, and were violent and trying to take over the ship.</p>

<p>This episode was fine from like, a watching sense, but its theming legit disgusts me, and I can’t read it as anything else. Star Trek is a political show that represents things. It’s not just a monster show with evil things that want to kill people. There are reasons, and in TNG, they would have found a way to communicate with the aliens and help fix their ship, or there would have been internal wisp conflict where they work with THEM. Not in this episode! They’re just all evil! We can kill them though and not think about it, because everyone who comes into conflict with us is an enemy that we can just forget is sapient!</p>

<p>Fuck this shit. I am really disliking Enterprise, a lot.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 9 - 14</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/02/LizstartrekEnt2-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 9 - 14" /><published>2025-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/02/LizstartrekEnt2-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/11/02/LizstartrekEnt2-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/arpI9Yz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Singularity</strong> - ENT
5.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/00vlP5K.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Interesting cold open here where we get T’Pol’s log as she crew is all passed out throughout the ship. She says they’re still moving, but might be debris by the time they get to their destination. Cool, good setup so far. And then we get the flashback to figure out what’s going on. Ah, in media res.</p>

<p>Enterprise is heading to a trinary system that has a black hole as a part of the system, which is weird. Also Archer makes Trip look at his chair, it’s very uncomfortable. I wish the entire episode was about his shittyh chair. Everyone takes turns sitting in the chair and getting knocked out like we saw in the intro. Also Chef is sick. I like Chef as a character, he’s very Morn-Coded. We NEVER see him (except for one time apparently, which my chat is upset about), but he’s fun.</p>

<p>Archer has to write a paper about his dad. He tries to make T’Pol do it for him. Do your fucking homework, Archer. Trip is an asshole about the captain’s chair, and Reed is developing Red Alert (He’s calling it Reed Alert, so they’re going to end up Han Soloing it, which is very dumb, because Red Alert is an actual Naval thing). Hoshi makes Oden while Chef is sick and everyone is a dick and kinda racist about it. How does THIS move into the intro??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZTvrw0s.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone is suddenly getting kinda ornery and grumpy for no reason. It’s all very unsettling… except Trip, because he’s really no more shitty and unpleasant than usual. He’s ALWAYS yelling about shit that doesn’t matter. Anyways this is all just uncomfy until Reed starts packing and becoming suspicious of everything. He basically says “I’mma coup the ship” Oh God, he’s turning into a Romulan, according to that stupid fucking SNW episode. Anyways this’d work better as a Naked Time style episode if this wasn’t how they all usually were. They’re all incompetent and focusing on the wrong things anyway.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5iLb5fd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Only one person seems actually immune to this. And that’s T’Pol. This episode is not beating the allegations that the entirety of the ship are babies that T’Pol is babysitting. Even Phlox is out of sorts, wanting to do brain surgery on poor Mayweather really REALLY bad. T’Pol ends up knocking him out to protect Mayweather, but the scans of Mayweather’s brain shows Shit’s Bad anyway. People start collapsing. Turns out there’s radiation from the black hole and it’s Bad. They can’t just turn around, cause the radiation would still be there. There’s a side of the blackhole where the radiation is minor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KAPCKxU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol wakes up Archer and forces him to be awake by shoving him in a shower and forcing him to drink coffee, which is kinda funny. He begrudgingly accepts helping her fly the ship through a debris field. They make it through and thankfully the radiation immediately wears off with zero lasting affects. Gee how lucky.</p>

<p><strong>Vanishing Point</strong> - ENT
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MJU5YTu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hoshi and Trip are on a planet exploring some ruins, taking pics and studying the language. Why the FUCK is Trip down there??????? Anyways a storm comes in and they decide they HAVE to go back up NOW even though they’re in a ruin, and it’d probably be fine. Anyways they use the teleporter. Holy shit, THEY REMEMBERED THE TELEPORTER EXISTS??? Hoshi is afraid of using the teleporter cause She’s Girl.</p>

<p>Hoshi is still uncomfy after her teleport, and the others tell her a Ghost Story about the first guy who died in a transporter incident. To be FAIR, Hoshi pushed them to tell her it, they didn’t want to. She’s VERY unhappy after the teleporter incident. She KNOWS something is wrong with her… molecules.</p>

<p>So, I suffer from hypochondria a lot. I get it. I don’t think they’re doing this WRONG really, and the transporter is a fucking thing. You wouldn’t catch me DEAD on that thing, hell no. I’ll take a shuttle, we have faster than light travel, why the hell do we need transporters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NXjN0nO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Berman has such a fucking fascination with making Hoshi take her fucking shirt off, the fucking pervert. At least she isn’t relegated to the kitchen in this episode.</p>

<p>Hoshi feels like she’s being ignored. Her alarm also doesn’t go off and she oversleeps, which is weird. Everyone doesn’t notice her at first and she’s becoming kind of paranoid. People are kinda treating her like shit. Also apparently there were aliens on the surface who are holding hostages, and Hoshi can’t translate their language. She’s dismissed, and then her replacement translates it no problem. It’s a Hoshi Must Suffer episode. Is that a thing? At least Phlox isn’t ignoreing her. Though he does kind of ignore her worries.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Z5MSLWn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>After a talk with Trip, she seems to fade out of reality entirely. She gets stuck in the exercise room, her hand is moving through the door controls. Why doesn’t she go through the door? Or the floor??? Anyways this is a repeat of the Ro and Geordi episode from TNG. We just keep redoing ideas but worse, don’t we? That one was enjoyable because Roe and Geordi were working together so they bounced off each other, AND they could actually do something to try and fix things. Hoshi doens’t have that expertise. Watching Hoshi be sad and ignored is not very pleasant to watch. ESPECIALLY with Trip VICTIM BLAMING HER? “Why didn’t I force you to go first? Why didn’t you LISTEN TO ME?” Then Archer calls her dad and he’s VERY slow on the uptake and real shitty. What the fuck is this episode</p>

<p>Anyways Hoshi finds some aliens on the ship planting bombs. She finds a way to make a light flicker and send an SOS, which Archer sees, accepts is an SOS, then ignored anyway, cause T’Pol tells him to ignore it. The ONE THING Hoshi can do, and it’s ignored. It’s FINALLY an episode where Hoshi gets to do something and it’s boring and bad.</p>

<p>In the end, Hoshi rematerializes and it turns out It Was All A Dream. She just had to be kept in the pattern buffer for 8.3 seconds. The end.</p>

<p>This episode can bite me.</p>

<p><strong>Precious Cargo</strong> - ENT
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RoMPUd7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Enterprise gets a distress call from a ship. They’re having some issues and need Trip’s help, fair enough. They’re transporting some girl in cryo freeze. Trip takes one look at her and falls in love cause of fucking course he does. Fucking Trip.</p>

<p>Anyways he accidentally wakes her, because of course he does, and she yells at him and tries to escape. One of the two alien dudes on the ship goes back after he gets an alarm (they were having dinner with the captain), knocks Trip out, and flies away, leaving his friend behind. lol whoops.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BrM2VHe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The frozen princess is, in fact, a princess. She claims she was kidnapped to be held for ransom. She has spots all the way down :o She’s a spoiled brat who is like “I’m too valuable to hurt, so I don’t try escaping, they’ll just pay my ransom and it’ll be fine”. She’s a shitty brat, but decides to go with Tucker anyway as he tries escaping through the escape pod. This turns the episode into Resident Evil 4 but Ashley is Unlikable. And so is Leon. Resident Evil 4 but Unlikable and Without Any Cool Zombies. Or maybe What if Spaceballs Sucked? They don’t get along at first, but after a while Tucker realizes she’s lonely and she realizes he’s rough but has a soft interior and uuhhhblhlblbl.</p>

<p>WAY more interesting is what Enterprise does to the guy they still have. They pretend he’s going to be executed if he doesn’t tell them where his partner went.</p>

<p>WHY DOES TRIP HAVE TO MENTION HE’S FROM FLORIDA EVERY 5 FUCKING MINUTES? NO OTHER TREK CHARACTER HAS DONE THIS. I GUESS maybe Worf but like, I hated it when he did it too. We fucking GET IT TRIP, You’re FROM FLORIDA. You’re a fucking Southern Boy. As a Southern Girl, shut up, it sucks shit down here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9KFUzoX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get into an argument and then fight and then make out and fuck, because that’s what it says to do in the hack’s guide to story writing. Then the alien captor finds them and Trip and him fight in the swamp. And then THEY kiss. No, not really, but that would have made this episode way more interesting. Enterprise comes and picks them up, the end. The princess is like “Come visit and we’ll fuck like rabbits” and then it ends. This was Rick Berman’s weird fucking fanfic for his stupid fucking self insert and I am unhappy I had to watch it.</p>

<p>This is literally the exact same plot as The Perfect Mate from TNG. It’s even the same race. But so much worse. Why do we keep just stealing previous episodes but poorly? This KEEPS HAPPENING.</p>

<p><strong>Catwalk</strong> - ENT
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oyhkKTB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This one looks like it could be good. PLEASE be good, god I need this.</p>

<p>Enterprise meets some aliens who are like “hey, we need your help, the storm will be here soon”. What storm? Well, turns out there’s a kind of storm that’s on the way, it’s VERY deadly and dangerous. And it’ll be here in four hours. They could outrun it at warp 7 but uh, oops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cmJ1l9S.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They have one place they can ALL fit which is properly protected. The proto-Jefferies tube, the “Catwalk”, the spot in the middle of the Nacelle. It’ll be cramped but they can prolly live in there for the time it takes. Which is, uh, 8 days. Oh boy.</p>

<p>AND the randos they invited in seem Kinda Sus and are keeping to themselves in a little tent they have set up.</p>

<p>I’m starting to get real tired of Reed. He’s either boring and like, a non-presence, or EXTREMELY annoying. Honestly? Maybe more than Trip. Trip is always grumpy and obstinant, but at like a 6/10. Reed is sometimes a 2/10, then he jumps to 11/10 ANY time something even SLIGHTLY goes wrong. Pissing and moaning cause there’s no shower, claiming Trip’s team is incompetent idiots cause of that. Trip is like “Dude, I had 4 hours, you’re lucky we have a toilet”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PL8GzEG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy shit, it’s Chef! Just off screen, but he’s here!!</p>

<p>Trip goes down to check some stuff out, in a space suit, where he finds a bunch of people just walking around on the ship, no suits. They’re Takarets, just like the aliens they invited onto their ship. Archer asks them wtf is going on, and although their leader refuses to admit whats going on, the others are like “Fuck that they have a right to know”. They’re desserters of the Takaret Militia, a thuggish military who are frankly evil. And that militia is now trying to take over the ship, cause why not? Also cause they think the desserters are on there somewhere.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/66zpQgz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer and T’Pol go to try and sneak control to the others. Archer sends him a message: “You’re in my chair”. A CLASSIC Trek captain line, like that line. He tells him very clearly “I will blow up my own ship if you don’t fuck off”, all the while they’re trying to turn off the thrusters (the people in them are currently cooking) and direct the ship into an eddy that’ll rip it apart.</p>

<p>The militia is like “oh shit fuck this” and run away. The bluff works, and Enterprise is safe.</p>

<p>That was just a good episode. Nice to have character moments and some fun stakes.</p>

<p><strong>Dawn</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/arpI9Yz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While looking at a gas giant (“Wow, this gas giant has dozens of moons” says Trip, not knowing what a gas giant is, I guess), Trip is attacked by a random ship and he crashes on a nearby planet. This happens to Trip a lot. This is like, the third time Trip has been stuck somewhere with a broken shuttle? He tries to get settled and get stuff fixed, but then he’s attacked by an alien and barely escapes.</p>

<p>Archer is contacted by the aliens, who explain that they’re the Arkonians, and this is their territory, leave. But also, they lost contact with THEIR shuttle. Archer suggests they work together to find their shuttles and then they’ll happily leave.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RA81mbo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This alien is a little animalistic gremlin. He steals the transciever, Trip tries to get it back, and is shot and stunned. Good job, Trip. The Arkonian holds him at gunpoint to try and force him to fix it, and it just goes back and forth like that. They can’t communicate, Trip doesn’t have his communicator for some reason. Maybe Reed left it on a planet somewhere. Reed and him kinda try to communicate but they’re very antagonistic? And any attempts to develop trust are bombed when Trip starts the fighting again. Enemy Mine this is not. Darmok this is not.</p>

<p>It keeps hinting that MAYBE they’d work together, but then they’re at each other’s throats. Over and over. This happens like three times. It is not good. They EVENTUALLY stop beating the shit out of each other, not because of any actual communication or desire to work together, but because the sun is rising and it’s getting hot and they’re suffering. This also unfortunately makes Trip take his fucking shirt off, so now I’M suffering too. Enterprise contacts them, but Trip refuses to leave without him. For some reason. But eventually they are rescued. The Arkonian leader is like “Thanks for rescuing my crewman. I hope your’s is okay, and if he was fired upon without provocation, he will be disciplined. But the alien is, at least, grateful he didn’t kill Trip, even when he meant to. I guess that’s the best we’ll get.</p>

<p>Got a little better at the end but still bad. Tonight was literally just better ideas from earlier shows regurgitated into bluh. Why do we keep doing this. Do we have NO good ideas?? Neli thinks this is one of the worst ever, because it’s very anti-Trek. Almost anti-communication as a concept, it’s saying communication can’t work. I don’t think it’s intentionally saying that, I just think this show was very poorly written in a very xenophobic time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 194</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/28/OOCY194.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 194" /><published>2025-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/28/OOCY194</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/28/OOCY194.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F2ud19y.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: #Gal and Gal Yuri</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Gal and Gal Yuri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 4 - 8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/26/LizstartrekEnt2-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 4 - 8" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/26/LizstartrekEnt2-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/26/LizstartrekEnt2-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mFGysyU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Dead Stop</strong> - ENT
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gBdeSD2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This show REALLY likes continuity! I’m not used to that with Star Trek. Our last episode had the Enterprise almost blow the fuck up, an entire chunk taken out of the poor thing. They’re safe, but dead in the water. They can go maybe warp 2 if they push the thing, but that’s still 10 years before they reach Earth. Luckily a Tellerite freighter catches them and goes “We’re not close enough, but there’s a repair station at these coordinates”, 3 days away. First ever Tellerites since they showed up ONCE in TOS! We don’t really see them though, they just speak, and even then their voice is fuzzy cause they’re so far away.</p>

<p>They reach the repair station, which appears to be automated. Not very friendly or well explained, but surely this will turn out well and not be too good to be true! Everything inside is in English, the station having scanned them. A pleasant robot voice is like “please choose payment type” and “the recreation area is now available, please enjoy your visit”. The inside of this station reminds me of kids toys for some reason.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7xAgzDY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This ship has some very advanced technology, including replicators. This is before replicators were common place, though some species seem to have them at the very least. And whoever owns this repair station is VERY advanced. I know that the other foot is gonna drop and things are gonna be Bad here, but I’d kinda like if this was just watching them get excited about advanced technology.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BLCrA2T.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy shit, it’s a fucking exocomp on its side. AN EXOCOMP, AS SEEN FROM ABOVE!! Making good use of old props they had lying around. Nanmo lives on EVEN NOW, like 12 years after anyone stopped caring about Dirty Pair.</p>

<p>Anyways, it all seems too good to be true, and Archer is the one really feeling this. Though tbf Reed and Trip are also sus and go sneaking around in the station’s cracks and crannies, and it teleports them off it. Mayweather is called by Archer somewhere and theeeen is suddenly killed. Rest in peace, Mayweather. No one knows why the fuck Mayweather went to a cordoned off area, it makes no sense. This is actually their first ever death. I can’t BELIEVE they’ve dodged so many deaths. They are really, REALLY hammering this in. This is like 10 minutes of them being sad about Mayweather’s death.</p>

<p>Obviously no, Mayweather’s not dead. It kidnapped him, replicated a fake dead body, and hoped they wouldn’t notice they just took one of their people and put them into slavery. So now they need to save him. While Trip distracts the program by huckstering it, the others sneak inside and try not to step off the alarm this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ek7HENE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Turns out it kidnaps aliens and then hooks them into the computer to use their body as processing power. I feel there’s easier ways to have a functioning computer like this… but whatever you say, random super powerful aliens we’ll never see or find out about. Maybe the writer had just seen The Matrix, it was pretty recent. They set off explosions in the warp plasma they were giving to the station. The station claims down on them but they manage to escape as it explodes. All those other aliens in there? They are VERY dead. But as they fly off… the station starts repairing itself. Oops we created the Borg. Too bad we’ll never see anything about this ever again.</p>

<p>This one was alright.</p>

<p><strong>A Night in Sickbay</strong> - ENT
1/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Km5ejJt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>You know, I didn’t know very much about Enterprise before watching this show. But the one thing I DID know is that it had a lot of decon scenes with half naked actors rubbing gel on each other. There’s been a lot less of it then I thought there’d be. But this is the one I’ve been waiting for.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mFGysyU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer rubbing gel all over Porthos.</p>

<p>You rememebr the Kreetassans? Prolly not. They were the aliens who got super offended cause Humans eat in public. Archer needed something from them so he groveled for 5 days, got another chance at an embassy, and immediately got kicked off the planet agian. Why? Cause he took Porthos and Porthos pissed on some of their sacred trees. Why the fuck did Archer bring Porthos to this diplomatic meeting? I guess he just assumed that the cute little Dog would make things go better.</p>

<p>Anyways they Kreetassans didn’t really try hard enough to make sure whether their planet was safe for Dogs, so it’s not. After Archer finds out that they might have killed his dog, he goes “They better HOPE they didn’t kill my dog, because if they did, I’ll be the one pissing on their trees”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NTtzhdt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Captain Archer, the first Captain in Starfleet history, one of the most historically important Humans ever, threatens to piss on some sacred trees out of anger.</p>

<p>Archer decides to spend the night in Medbay. Turns out Phlox is a very bad roommate. He’s cutting his nails and scraping his tongue in the middle of the night.</p>

<p>Archer’s being a little brat this episode. Yes I know his dog might die, and that’s very exhausting and emotionally a lot, but he really is being a fucking whiny bitch about the whole thing. I’ve often said that Enterprise is the most American Star Trek. It was mostly post 9/11 and has a lot of American jingoism and ideals baked into its writing and nature as American bullshittery reached a height. It is VERY America centric. But I think NOTHING shows how America centric this show is more than how Archer is acting in this episode. He’s being a fucking whiny bitch about needing to bend over backwards to fit in with some other aliens’ culture, when they SHOULD just bend over to HIS culture. And the Kreetassans are shown as extremely rude, self centered, and awful. So this episode 100% thinks Archer is in the right about this. I don’t care if it ends with him actually sucking up and doing the thing, the vibes are just off. Just compare how Archer is whining about needing to do some rituals to apologize for pissing them off to how Picard would act in TNG. I’m PRETTY sure I remember an episode where Picard learned an aliens’ language and did like a 2 hour long ritual just to make them feel welcome and they went “you really didn’t need to do all that”. THAT is how a captain acts. Not THIS. This alone is knocking Archer down several knocks on my tier list.</p>

<p>I’m kind of hating this episode but Phlox is fun in it at least. He has a lot of good moments. Him scraping his tongue. Him messing with a bat that sprays liquid all over him, and when Archer goes “is that dangerous?” he licks it and goes “Eh, probably not”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CseI4Vg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways Archer APPEARS to be really low on sleep and is having a lot of weird dreams about being sexually attracted to T’Pol, and it’s so awkward and uncomfortable. I think I hate this episode. It promised to be about ARcher’s love for his dog but then it’s filled with weird slapstick that has nothing to do with anything, Archer being VERY annoying, and then this. Star Trek often does romance awkwardly, and I KNEW they’d push a T’Pol x Archer pairing as like, the main canon pairing for this series, but for fucks sake, I was REALLY hoping they’d get it started with something BETTER THAN THIS. He even goes “I’m doing the breast I can- I mean the best”. This was written by a fucking hack. OH, WRITTEN BY RICK BERMAN? I’M FUCKING STUNNED. This has the energy of a really awkwardly horny, bad anime you watch 2 episodes of and then stop watching. This episode reminds me of DNA Squared. And that is a REALLY bad thing.</p>

<p>Even Phlox being cool and doing good lore doesn’t help with this. I’m learning a LOT about Dunobulans, and they’re all cool. I like Dunobulans, and I like Phlox. But I really can’t get over Archer in this episode, who frankly has been racist, and he does actually apologize for being racist and not understanding other cultures, but to me it’s a bit too little too late.</p>

<p>At least T’Pol straight up goes “you are my superior officer so we will never be a thing, have a nice day”. IT is as awkward as you can imagine it is. Anyways they get their thing and Porthos is fine. Fuck this episode.</p>

<p><strong>Marauders</strong> - ENT
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RDgTCvo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise lands at a Deuterium mining facility and offers to buy some  The people at the mining facility are ragged and anxious and extremely unhappy about anyone wanting to buy their deuterium being here, but they agree to sell some for a pretty harsh deal, and if they give some med supplies, AND if they fix some broken pumps. They’re evasive about everything. Trip meets a kid while working on stuff and makes friends with him.</p>

<p>We find what the problem is pretty fast. Some Klingons are on their way, and they get VERY grumpy because they think they have… a “mutual arrangement”. The Klingons don’t notice the Humans but beat the shit out of the settlers anyway, cause why the fuck not? They don’t have the Deuterium they want, even though they’re there early, so they beat them up for the “disrepect”. You know, bad Klingon stuff.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/82AhGdD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The leader of the colony just wants the Humans to leave, it’s not their fault, but everyone wants to help. They need to do SOMETHING, so they decide to teach them how to defend themselves. They eventually agree to help once Archer gives ‘em the old “teach a man to fish” line, which I have NO idea why that worked. They have 3 days. Time to montage.</p>

<p>We get them planning out traps, teaching guns, and martial arts. There’s a scene where T’Pol is like “I will teach you an ancient Vulcan technique”. That technique is getting the fuck out of the way.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lDND4mm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We then Bugs Life these grasshoppers. T’Pol even gets a scene where she beats the shit out of a Klingon in hand to hand combat. Berman must have been asleep. They successfully get the Klingons into the trap, and they go “HMPH, WELL WE DIDN’T WANT YOUR STUPID DEUTERIUM ANYWAY, YOU DOO DOO FACE!” and leave. It goes almost comically, sappily well. Even the kid lives. Trip gives him some schematics for the Enterprise, and all’s well that ends well. Frankly I’m stunned the Klingons didn’t bombard the colony from space out of spite.</p>

<p>This is, I believe, the first time we really fight Klingons. This kind of story is a little boring, and this is a very standard retelling of that idea.</p>

<p><strong>The Seventh</strong> - ENT
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y7x25Ej.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol is contacted the be High Command who say they’ve found someone named Menos. T’Pol then goes to Archer and is VERY out of character. She’s talking kinda stilted and awkwardly, and looks VERY unhappy, and tells him that she needs to do a mission and cannot tell him more. Archer is very bratty about this, as he usually is. When she comes to him and goes “I need your help” he’s EXTRA bratty. Archer, please.</p>

<p>She explains that she used to be a part of Vulcan security. There was a team of Vulcan spies who went rogue basically, years ago, and T’Pol could not apprehend one of them. They found him now, and she wants Archer to help her. He’s still bratty like “Pff, why ME?” and she’s like “Because I want to be with someone I can trust”, cutting it right to the bone. Get his ass, T’Pol.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Br9g5Up.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Trip is really excited to be acting captain while Archer is off the ship… at first. He uses Archer’s room to relax, eats nice food prepared specially for him. But then he has to make DECISIONS. AND the Admiral is currently asking for Archer, who was NOT supposed to go on the mission but did anyway. So Trip just…. freezes. And refuses to make any decisions. He is NOT made for captaining. He just pushes it down the way. I regretably relate to it, but I hate that I relate to Trip, cause he has big Rick Berman Self Insert character energy. Also, Trip is uh, a high ranking officer? He was 2nd in command until T’Pol came in. He trained for this. And here he is being a baby.</p>

<p>They capture their guy, who’s a Vulcan but has been surgically changed to look like a not Vulcan. He claims he’s not a villain, they just want to take him back because he decided he liked the life he’s living here. 
He doesn’t smuggle weapons like the reports say, he just didn’t want to go back home… which is technically against the law for an agent to do, so they’re trying to bring him back, and he’ll be tried guilty. “But the government wouldn’t do that!” Archer says, as if he didn’t find the Vulcans breaking a fucking treaty like a couple months ago and cause a diplomatic incident.</p>

<p>T’Pol is acting very weird. She’s remembering some things, their guy thinks she’s gonna kill him, and she’s acting very emotional.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iAd3zwf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Turns out she killed this guy’s partner years ago, then they did a Vulcan ritual on her that made her forget her memories and the emotions of the act, since killing others fucked her up a looot. Especially if he’s innocent, which he sure does claim he is. I mean, the guy she killed LOOKED like he was reaching for his gun. But also who knows. We can’t trust him, but we also can’t trust the high command, though Archer keeps saying we should. Dude.</p>

<p>This is very sloppily handled PTSD. Anyways he’s even more hard to trust when he sets the fucking bar they’re in on fire and runs away. He manages to get the drop on them, but Archer almost kills T’Pol to get into a fire fight.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uila8Sl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He tries to play to her guilty again, and Archer is like “You were here to apprehend him, not judge him”. Anyways it turns out he IS smuggling illegal biotoxins! We were justified! Never question orders :D</p>

<p>Rick Berman is a shitty writer, more news at 11. Brannon Braga is not much better.</p>

<p><strong>The Communicator</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CSRXflL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed, Hoshi, and Archer were exploring a pre-warp civilization. I want to note, Neli went “Oh good, he took competent people with him this time”. We then find out Reed just fucking forgot his communicator and left it down on the planet. Well so much for that!</p>

<p>They’re acting like this is a big deal. It is, of course, leaving technology behind in a prewar civilization is very bad. But can’t you like, call it to find out where it is and then teleport it back? You have teleporters. Fucking use them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b35NGff.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THey go back to the bar, get their communicator, and are immediately captured by some fascist-coded secret police. Welp, so much contamination of this prewarp civilization. This is why we probably shouldn’t just go down to them willy nilly, and when we do, WE SHOULDN’T MISPLACE OUR BELONGINGS.</p>

<p>I’m starting to agree with the Vulcans. They shouldn’t be out here. And frankly, that’s insulting to me, because the Vulcans in this show are fucking pretentious smug fuckheads and I hate them. But they’re right, and its the worst.</p>

<p>Half this show is Archer getting stuck in a chair and getting the shit beat out of him. It happens a lot. Anyways the secret police believe that Archer and Reed are here to assassinate Hitler, I mean Chancellor Kultarey. But when they beat the shit out of them, it becomes clear that the things on their foreheads are fake, and their blood is red. Oops, we made it worse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m7uidcS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Trip plans to use the Suleban cloak ship that they have from when they rescued Klaang… what? You still have that? It’s been A YEAR, dude. That’s just been sitting there?? Anyways he tries to get it working and then gets hit with a wave of energy which makes his arm cloaked. Trip sucks the fun out of everything, this should be a goofy fun scene. But I hate it.</p>

<p>The fascists are like “There’s no other option. These are space aliens.” Archer is like “That’s nuts. Come on, we’re just super soldier prototypes. Y’all are nuts.” Well, he helped hold back the cultural corruption, at least.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sALSyut.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer and Reed are about to be executed and dissected, and they had a long talk about “It’s good that the Enterprise is leaving us to die so we don’t make things worse down here”. And then their execution is interrupted by them showing up, cloaked, blasting, and then fleeing. Archer even goes to grab the weapons. There’s even a little “Ha ha, looking for this?” moment with Reed like “ha ha, you almost forgot your communicator”. Ha ha, we escalated a war that will kill millions.</p>

<p>T’Pol makes it clear, they fucked up, really, really bad. But she’s at least proud that Archer was going to sacrifice his life to protect them from more contamination… which is something.</p>

<p>Eh, no. Mostly annoying. Use the fucking transporter, or at least tell me there’s Fucktonium in the way. It’s good to show why the Prime Directive is important, Rick Berman is not that good of a writer.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 193</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/23/OOCY193.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 193" /><published>2025-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/23/OOCY193</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/23/OOCY193.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DEEgQAE.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: #Gal and Gal Yuri</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Gal and Gal Yuri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 212 - Luca no Puzzle de Daibouken!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/10/23/RA213-Luca.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 212 - Luca no Puzzle de Daibouken!" /><published>2025-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/10/23/RA213-Luca</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/10/23/RA213-Luca.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VoGvt6G.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This was a biiiiig one.</p>

<p>I like Sudoku quite a bit. Half a decade ago, I was in a really bad spot, and sudoku was one of the only things I could do to distract myself and calm myself down. I haven’t done much sudoku since then, but when this set came out, I decided I’d give it a try. This is Luca no Puzzle de Daibouken, a Gameboy Color game with a LOT of Sudoku puzzles on it. How many? 200.</p>

<p>I know the title screen says “2” by the way. I dunno why. It’s not the second.</p>

<p>The game has three modes. The first is 100 puzzles, each 20 of which unlock a new mini game in the mini game mode. These save and note as being beaten. After you beat all 100, you unlock 100 MORE puzzles. These are not the same puzzles but like, there’s nothing differentiating them basically. The ONLY difference is you can’t save in the middle of a puzzle, like in the other mode for some reason.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/183cTu6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Other than that, it sure is sudoku! It’s got a cute energy and alright music. I like the ocean and dolphins are adorable. There’s one problem, though. See this cute screen with all the fish in the background? Well yes, that’s the only screen for 200 puzzles, but most importantly, those numbers are WAY too small for me to read. Luckily, the game has a zoom in feature to make the entire screen the puzzle. But that also means… what’s the point. It’s JUST sudoku at that point.</p>

<p>I did 4 puzzles every day for months. It was very calming and pleasant for a while, just starting every stream with an hour and a half of sudoku. By the end I was ready to be done with it, to be honest. It was like 170 hours of fucking Sudoku. Even for someone who likes it, that’s a lot.</p>

<p>At least the dolphin is cute, though.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Puzzles" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 192</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/22/OOCY192.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 192" /><published>2025-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/22/OOCY192</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/22/OOCY192.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NW2CVsj.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Becoming Her Lover for the Sake of Love</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Becoming Her Lover for the Sake of Love" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 21 - 26</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/19/LizstartrekEnt1-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 21 - 26" /><published>2025-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/19/LizstartrekEnt1-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/19/LizstartrekEnt1-6.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v2t7Yb9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p>(these were 5 episodes from last week, and now 2 episodes to finish the season)</p>

<p><strong>Detained</strong> - ENT
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rpEEFIb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Mayweather wakes to find he’s in some kind of jail filled with Suliban. Holy shit, a Mayweather episode?! No way- oh, he’s here with the captain. Damn, okay, nevermind.</p>

<p>They’re taken to the warden who’s like “we found your shuttle near our military installation, and almost blew you up”. It was an honest misunderstanding, they were just studying the weird energy readings they found on it. No one is happy about this, but hey, it is what it is. Their hearing will be in 3 days and it should be fast. All they need to do is survive in the detention center for 3 days which is filled with Suliban POWs. Oh boy!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X3usRWW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh, maybe not POWs. That’s a child. Archer is like “Wtf you’re using KIDS for your war??” and he’s like “what the fuck no. You don’t know anything about us” and then he’s caught outside of curfew and is mistreated by the guards. Oh boy!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/igoh5oa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer finds the guy later and is like “Hey please tell me wtf is going on cause CLEARLY the Tandarens gave us a very biased viewpoint”. The Cabal attacked them 8 years ago, and the Tandarens put all the Suliban in their territory into internment camps. He thanks Archer for even listening, cause no one else will even bother. Archer is then taken to the leader of the internment camp, who WAS very friendly, but he’s not so much now that he knows Archer is talking to Suliban, AND he knows Archer knows things about Suliban. He threatens to keep him here indefinetely, and Archer is not at ALL willing to tell him anything cause holy shit, internment camps are evil, DID YOU KNOW THAT?</p>

<p>Good thing this is just fiction.</p>

<p>The Enterprise comes and is ready to sneak Archer and Mayweather out, but Archer refuses. Why? He’s going to save the Suliban, of course. He HAMMERS the fucking point by telling T’Pol about Japanese internment camps. Look, you need to be blunt for some topics. And this is one of em, I’m fine with it. It’s also VERY funny to me that they’re talking about this and how heinous it is, literally RIGHT when 9/11 happened and Freedom Fries were about to become a thing.</p>

<p>It IS unfortunate that we have ONE character in the Suliban group who’s a racist who hates the Humans cause they kinda look liek Tandarens. There’s racism on BOTH sides!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aVh4xId.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed beams down disguised as a Sulliban, while Trip goes in guns fucking blazing. It’s time for a prison break!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ETPmZrO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nice line. The general is like “THESE PEOPLE HAVE NO RIGHTS, AND YOU JUST GAVE THEM 80 MORE SOLDIERS! THEY’LL JOIN THE CABAL CAUSE WE TREATED THEM SO BAD”. Gee I WONDER WHY THEY’D DO THAT? But no, Archer is like “You’re a fucking idiot”. He doesn’t even talk to the Suliban as they blast off, they just go their seperate ways, with Archer going “I think they’ll be alright”.</p>

<p>A little on the noise, but this one was good.</p>

<p><strong>Vox Sola</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hip69J8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Enterprise insults some aliens in first contact and they run off. But not before some kind of goo moves from their ship to the Enterprise…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zgoSEBv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Alex Mack is invading Enterprise!! Oh no!</p>

<p>We find out that Archer’s favorite sport, that he’s obsessed with, is water polo. That’s so fucking funny.</p>

<p>Anyways Alex Mack is causing some tech fuckery. Power’s going out, screens are showing the wrong thing. An engineer goes to figure out why the lights went out on D Deck and finds milk, goop, and webbing. And instead of immediately leaving he just keeps investigating. Dude.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WAiKrm8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone goes to investigate and finds the crewmen in a web of some kind. You know, I just watched Alien. Anyways, it captures Trip and the Captain, and Reed has to run away, not before severing one of its tentacles. Phlox studies it and believes it MIGHT be intelligent. But they need to save those people so let’s go in blasting. Unfortunately, the alien has connected with their nervous systems so any amount of damage they do to it will hurt them. Apparently they’re all morphing into one creature in there. Weird.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FXanqFY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hoshi and T’Pol are working together to learn its language, which is almost math-like. Just fucking kiss, you two.</p>

<p>Very good scene between Reed and Phlox. Reed is going to torture the organism’s apendage that they cut off, and Phlox is like “No, it shows signs of being intelligent life”. “Who cares? It might hurt the captain” “I don’t care”. While I agree with Phlox over Reed, obviously, this is a good character moment for both of them. Reed is a lot more pragmatic. Phlox not so much.</p>

<p>They find the aliens who stormed off earlier, who are like “oh yes, we were at that creatures’ homeworld, sorry. But first, apologize. You ate in public which is very rude to us”. Merriweather apologizes but is kinda bad with it. Come on man, its not THAT hard to believe that they have a cultural tabboo about this.</p>

<p>Reed basically has to invent forcefields to try and get in so they can communicate with this thing. Kinda rude of the Vulcans to not teach them about forcefields though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PiIMm8Z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The creature sounds like its rubbing a bunch of balloons together. They communicate with it, tell it they’ll take it home, and it releases the Humans from its clutches. They take it to its homeworld, and alls good. It’s cute.</p>

<p><strong>Fallen Hero</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hip69J8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode starts in the most nutso way. T’Pol asks Archer if the Humans on Enterprise are getting enough sex. He’s like “what the FUCK?” “Well, I hear it eases tension for Humans.” To which Trip responds with “Not in MY experience”. Trip. Did you… just admit to being bad at sex??</p>

<p>Before they can go get laid though, they’re interrupted with orders to go pick up a Vulcan from a nearby planet. They HAVE to, NOW, then deliver her to a ship thats on its way in 3 days. She’s a famous ambassador. That’s all we know.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cH1jNcR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out fast that she’s being expelled for illegal activities. We don’t know what THAT is, but we’re still trying to be friendly and understanding. She’s SHOCKINGLY friendly for a Vulcan. She shakes hands, tries to understand Human culture, and is an ACTUALLY GOOD VULCAN ON EARLY ENTERPRISE. All the other Vulcans are weird assholes, she’s very friendly and understanding. But she IS an ambassador, this is how she SHOULD act. Though she’s also a criminal. T’Pol is extremely disappointed in her, and can’t hide her emotions about it.</p>

<p>They’re intercepted by a ship that’s like “Hi we’re here to take the ambassador back :)” and when Archer realizes he’s sus, they start opening fire. Enterprise is damaged but manages to run away.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4GW6cF4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rxxhIzc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer orders the ship to go back when the ambassador refuses to tell them wtf is going on. Vulcans are going to get VERY angry about this, but you know how he is with Vulcans. T’Pol and the ambassador have a talk about it. V’lar, the ambassador, is a very weird Vulcan. Her acting is different than any Vulcan I’ve seen.</p>

<p>She convinces T’Pol that it’s IMPERETIVE she not be sent back or she’ll be killed. Archer is still like “not enough” but when T’Pol BEGS, he relents.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/k81xThC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>To escape the attacks, they push the engines further than they’ve ever been pushed. The Ambassador is like “Alright fuck this, give me to them, it’s not worth you all dying” but Archer was given orders so he’ll carry them out. He’s an honorable dude even if he’s grumpy at times. The Vulcan Ambassador wasn’t sure if she could trust Humans, but she finds them fascinating… But Archer’s gonna show why he’s out here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jQgqTXC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Vulcan ships are very cool.</p>

<p>Anyways they get boarded and just have to buy ten minutes for the other ship to show up, so they pretend she gets put in the med bay, and they “kill her” (it’s a fake). Ha ha, gottem.</p>

<p>She announces that T’Pol and Archer seem to have a good burgeoning friendship, which poses well for their people, and then steps out. This episode was good too! Damn, good night tonight.</p>

<p><strong>Desert Crossing</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yHx0ruE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise is STILL heading to Risa when they’re interrupted by a distress call. They save Clancy Brown who sounds VERY Lex Luthory.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J7qHn7V.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He invites Archer to a party on his planet. It’s a desert planet, and they don’t really WANT to but they don’t want to offend him. MAybe they should invite the Vulcan, she’s from a desert planet- oh, no, Trip? Okay. Why not.</p>

<p>Trip and Archer have a good time. Eating blood soup and testicals, and playing Desert Lacross. It’s a very Top Gun scene. Everything seems good, but then T’Pol is contacted by a government official who’s like “you’re in danger. That man is a terrorist”. Uh oh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dV79Pay.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>When they find out, their host is like “Look, you’re being lied to.” They’re a lower class culture in this society and are being mistreated, and after ten years of trying to do it legally through protests and courts, are now attacking them and resorting to terrorism. “They call us TERRORISTS!” No, dog. You ARE a terrorist. Like, that’s the definition of it. You may in the right, but that doesn’t matter. It’s still terrorism.</p>

<p>Archer doesn’t handle this well. He was led here under false pretenses, and this guy wants him to help them fight a war. And why? Because he heard about Archer from the Suliban he released. A made up fictitious account that’s blown out of proportion, mind you. If there’s one good thing about Enterprise, they’re good at continuity. Anything can relate to anything else.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HosUVri.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The place they’re being kept at is being attacked, and they decide they’ll be safer in the desert. That seems…. I dunno. Deserts are scary. It doesn’t go well, especially since there’s also shuttles out looking for them, because the government has just decided they’re collaborating with the terrorists.</p>

<p>This episode has the longest unbroken shot in the entirety of the Star Trek franchise. Trip and Archer are hiding in an old abandoned shack, and Archer is trying to keep Trip awake so he doesn’t pass out with heat stroke, cause that’s bad for you. Almost four straight minutes of them acting tired and dying.</p>

<p>With the help of the original guy who got us into this mess, they manage to sneak a shuttle down to the planet and rescue the two of them. The episode ends with Archer admitting his cause is worth fighting for, but that’s not why they’re out there, and they go their seperate ways.</p>

<p><strong>Two Days and Two Nights</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cigexKX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Part three of the Journey to Risa trilogy, no joke, that’s what Memory Alpha says. But they FINALLY made it to Risa and are gonna be vacationing for two days. Archer is kinda unhappy he’s vacationing, but T’Pol is basically forcing him to. Plus they all drew lots. He needs a vacation. Thankfully, nothing bad is gonna happen at all while he’s down there! And back on Enterprise, Plox is starting his hibernation. Ohhh, let’s just STACK the Dangerous Situations on top of each other! Luckily, Archer is going down with Porthos in the shuttle, so we know nothings gonna happen to him. They’ll NEVER endanger Porthos.</p>

<p>I know this isn’t going to happen but please just let this be them chilling on the planet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/npy9zfG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol gifts Archer a copy of the teachings of Surak to “relax”, which is VERY funny. He also sees a girl with a dog in a villa across the way. Ooooh, romaaaance?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NSV9Ki0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Speaking of romance, we gotta keep pretending Reed is straight so he and Trip (who is actually straight, way, way too straight) standing around in a bar creepily oggling women. There’s jokes about “is that even a woman” which oh, what fun. Meanwhile Hoshi meets an alien with a weird language, and he offers to help her learn some of it. Okay, calling it. Hoshi is fucking that alien. Archer is MAYBE gonna fuck the girl he’s with, but might decide he would want something deeper. And Reed and Trip are going to desperately attempt to get laid but will absolutely not.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v2t7Yb9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Oh nevermind, they’ll just get robbed by some shapeshifters pretending to be call girls looking for sex. Why are they introducing so many shapeshifters?? I feel like this could create some problems for the lore.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sbrkpTP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Mayweather gets injured and has an allergic reaction to the medicine so they have to wake Phlox up. Phlox when he’s not gotten enough sleep acts like he’s drunk, and it’s actually VERY funny. He’s calling everyone captain, stumbling around, going “WE NEED BLOOD WORMS, MAXIMUM WARP”, it’s great.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0Ofjb3b.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer’s new girlfriend is very VERY insistant that Archer knows info about the Cabal. Archer is sus and scans her, turns out she’s a Tandaran. He assumes Grat, the Tandaran from that earlier episode, sent her. She knocks him out with a Spy Weapon, says she can’t have him “interfere”, and then leaves. They all make it back to the ship, Hoshi having gotten laid, Trip and Reed covered in gunk and exhausted from having to break out of bonds, and Archer pensive. And it just ends. PRetty good over all. A  bit glad it didn’t move into some greater bigger plot thread.</p>

<p><strong>Shockwave</strong> - ENT
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uQBARBa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While visiting a mining colony, they visit in a shuttle. The atmosphere is filled with shit that can explode, so they turn off their plasma ducts. Uh, but the atmosphere fucking explodes anyway. The entire colony is wiped out. 3600 colonists, dead. Everything shows that their stuff didn’t malfunction, but that doesn’t change the fact that there’s a bunch of dead people down there. They followed the protocols, hell they went above and beyond, but that doesn’t help either.</p>

<p>T’Pol is like “He is acting illogical” because Archer is EXTREMELY upset and blames himself for all thsoe deaths. Phlox is like “are you fucking kidding me”. Archer gets orders to go back home, the mission is cancelled. The Vulcans will use this as an excuse to delay Humans for another 20-30 years. Archer’s just letting it happen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qxdN6Mu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol is the person who knocks Archer out of his dispondency. It works because a VULCAN of all people is going “No, you Humans are ready. I’ll talk to my people. Will you talk to your’s?”. And then, when he goes to bed… he suddenly finds himself in the past. He’s EXTREMELY sus. Everything is EXACTLY how it was just before he boarded Enterprise, just before the first episode.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KESlahx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look, it’s Daniels! Remember him? He was fucking killed. That hasn’t changed. He’s like “Yeah that DID happen but hey, I’m fine now. Let’s not make a big deal out of this.” He took Archer back into the past so that he could tell him exactly what happened. Archer gets a crash course in temporal techno babble, and when he gets back to the present, he knows EXACTLY how to prove they’re innocent. Whoever temporally fucked with the timeline made it seem like Enterprise killed a bunch of people to try and get them out of the picture.</p>

<p>Archer then goes a mile a minute telling everyone EXACTLY how to fix things. No one questions things cause they trust him, but they’re all visibly weirded out. They raid a Suliban stealth cruiser and get proof that they’re innocent, and that it was the Suliban who did all this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WYKiNDT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Silik is still talking to this random shadowy dude, which is very, VERY Star Wars still but whatever. I sure hope we found out what thats all about soon :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7yBCzT1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On their way home, they find themselves surrounded by cloaked meatballs. Silik says “come with me or I blow everyone up”. Archer puts T’Pol in command, and goes with him. Archer basically does the Sisko “I’m going, but I’m not gone. I’ll be back soon” thing. But not quite as effective. He goes… and then disappears. No one knows where he went. Silik is not impressed, and orders Enterprise blown up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ThylDMW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Daniels grabbed Archer and took him to the 31st centry, like his bosses told him to. But uh… turns out that was a Bad Idea, and now the ENTIRE FUTURE IS DEAD because of this. And there’s no way to get back. They’re stranded. The End.</p>

<p>CLIFF HANGER TIME!</p>

<p>Interesting setup for a 2 parter. Let’s hope it ends well. I also wish I gave more of a shit about the Temporal Cold War.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 1 - 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/19/LizstartrekEnt2-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 2 episodes 1 - 5" /><published>2025-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/19/LizstartrekEnt2-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/19/LizstartrekEnt2-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ouHMzRZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Shockwave Part 2</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BHbF1JO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Daniels is NOT handling his world being blown up very well. Why do all these time travel cops snap and break the SECOND something bad happened with time travel? You’d think they’d be PREPARED for this shit. Remember the guy from Voyager who became a screaming raving hobo telling everyone about time travel after being stranded in the past? Idiots.</p>

<p>Enterprise is taken by the Suliban, who’re holding everyone hostage while they’re searching for Archer. Trip tries to fight them even thoguh they have guns on him and say “we will kill people if you resist”. I think I’ve realized what Trip reminds me of. He’s like a Chihuaha in a Human body. He yaps angrily at everything even though he knows it’ll do nothing and gets himself into danger trying to fight people he has no chance or hurting.</p>

<p>“We learned how to do time travel in high school” says Daniels. Why? Why did you do that? That seems very, very bad.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CnHX1Zm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Rick Berman, I’m gonna NEED you to keep your fucking “tie a woman up and torture her” fetish out of Star Trek for one fucking show, please, I FUCKING beg of you.</p>

<p>This is not beating the “part 2s are usually worse than the 1st part” allegations.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WqR5MD0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol is drugged out of her mind, when Archer manages to communicate with her. He’s doing a big Wizard of Oz thing with her, and needs her help, but she’s VERY zonked. But next time we see her she’s fine and working towards helping so I guess we’ll just forget that. Wow, there was no reason to have that “drug T’Pol and torture her” scene from earlier? No way! Rick Berman should be arrested.</p>

<p>They then force Hoshi to sneak through the shafts in a tanktop. Usually I’d love an episode of people Die Harding through the space ship, but this has the stink of Horny Berman all over it, as Hoshi moans her way through the engineering shafts, freaking out cause of claustrophobia. It’s way, WAY too Horny. And then she rips her shirt and gets naked. Rick Berman should be tried for war crimes.</p>

<p>Do you remember how Vulcans are super physically strong? Anyways cause T’Pol is a weak little girl she’s used as bait and dragged off easily by two big strong men. Rick Berman should be executed for war crimes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b8ZUkM5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed is captured while trying to take soemthing from Daniels’ locker, as the Humans sabatoge the warp core and prepare the ship to blow the fuck up. The Suliban take the thing from Reed but run away. Turns out they just faked a warp core explosion to get control back. Meanwhile, Silik is trying to use the thing he took from Reed to talk to Emperor Palpatine, and then turns out OH NO, IT’S ACTUALLY ARCHER, who jumps through time and decks him in the fucking face.</p>

<p>Archer takes Silik hostage and returns. Ambassador Soval, the Vulcan ambassador, still is like “You are a menace to this quadrant and must be stopped, I don’t care if you’re innocent”. Why did they assign an ambassador to Earth who CLEARLY hates Humans? Anyways, T’Pol speaks up and calls him out, defending Archer. Her speaking up STUNS everyone, and is probably what saved it. Enterprise continues.</p>

<p>Neli: “Okay. I didn’t hate the moments that weren’t offensive”</p>

<p>I couldn’t say it better myself. Good concepts and fun moments, especially the T’Pol bit at the end, is quite good. And then Berman’s spunk is all OVER this from him masturbating to it.</p>

<p><strong>Carbon Creek</strong> - ENT
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ouHMzRZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Trip, Archer, and T’Pol are celebrating her being on the ship for a full year. Impressive since the last longest time serving on a Human ship was 10 days. While having dinner, Archer asks why T’Pol was visiting Carbon Creek, a random mining town in Pennsylvania in 1957. She tells the story, and it becomes a Story Episode of her tlaking about her ancestors who crash landed on Earth hundreds of years ago. Her great grandmother, specifically. Her Gram Gram, T’Mir, is played by T’Pol’s actor, a classic just like when Voyager did it with Janeway’s ancestor. The seed is strong, I suppose.</p>

<p>Anyways T’Mir and another Vulcan go into town, steal some clothes, and try to blend in, just to try and get food, cause they’ll starve otherwise. They’re bad at blending in but it’s basically just two nerds with autism. Now it IS 1957, but people are taking it generally in stride. At least neither of the Vulcans are black, could you imagine?</p>

<p>T’Mir’s associate, Mestral, gambles on Pool and gets them some food. Trip feels like this is something out of the Twilight Zone but I’m kinda digging it so far. They get some odd jobs around town. T’Mir is annoyed at the situation, wants to avoid Humans, and thinks they’ll just blow each other up. Mestral appreciates the Humans, thinks them full of empathy and compassion, and expects they’ll do great things in the future. He’s also kind of a Humaboo, and is a fan of I Love Lucy. Also fun since I Love Lucy is so integral to Star Trek existing, its a cute reference.</p>

<p>Mestral also has very big Data vibes. This actor totally watched some Brent Spiner before this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Qpew3Hn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways turns out Mestral is sneaking out to have dates with a bartender in town. T’Mir is NOT happy and tries to stop him but like, what power does she have? Yes she’s his commanding officer, but y’know. But T’Mir eventually starts to come around. There’s a kid who’s a bright, friendly kid around town. She connects to him a bit.</p>

<p>Some Humans get trapped in a mine. Mestral steals a weapon to try and break them out. T’Mir is like “They only live at most 70 years so why even bother to extend their lives for a bit longer?” and he’s like “it’s called compassion? They’re my friends, and I’m going to help them.” T’Mir comes around and helps him though, guiding him through so he can do it safely without being caught.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I7DNuc0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get a message. They’re being rescued in three days. T’Mir’s young friend wishes her luck moving back home. Turns out he can’t go to college after all, he wasn’t accepted. He needs money, but they’re just a poor bar family. T’Mir spends the next few days taking a train into the city…. where she shows a big corpo bro fucking VELCRO, then donates all the money. Fantastic.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6gK2hEM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Mestral doesn’t want to leave. He’s fascinated by this species. And Maggie. And her breasts. But mostly their species. So they pretend he died in the crash, and then they blast off. Trip is like “omg he was around for 30 presidents afterwards and no one caught it???” Do you imagine 80 years later, Mestral was watching the TV and saw Trump won re-election and was like “I should have gone back to Vulcan”</p>

<p>Trip and Archer don’t believe her, but then she goes back to her quarters and pulls out a purse left by her gram gram.</p>

<p>This was fantastic. Best episode of Enterprise so far, absolutely. It had the Star Trek optimism, actually good well-written Vulcans, funny good writing. It was just… fantastic.</p>

<p><strong>Minefield</strong> - ENT
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vug49cO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed has a dinner with the Captain and is very awkward about it. The Captain is like “Dog, chill” then they’re called up to do some routine exploration when suddenly the fucking ship explodes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IYRaGLC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Something just up and blew up a chunk of the ship. 17 Casualties, including Hoshi, but no fatalities. I’m STUNNED honestly. Turns out they’re in a mine field filled with a bunch of cloaked mines. One latches onto the ship, and Reed goes out into space to detatch it. Meanwhile, a green ship uncloaks, shoots a warning shot, and yells in some language they can’t understand, because Hoshi has a concussion.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HgxLLpZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While Reed is trying to defuse the bomb, a spike comes and impales Reed right in the leg. Foam stops his suit from bleeding oxygen, but things aren’t lookin’ good. Archer goes out to help him, give him some anesthetic, and has to shut it down with Reed’s advice now.</p>

<p>Hoshi translates just enough t o find out… it’s some group called the Romalin Star Empire? T’Pol corrects her. It’s pronounced Romulan. Holy shit, actual first contact with Romulans? This is what we WANTED from Enterprise, not any of that Temporal Cold War shit.</p>

<p>Reed and Archer have some hearts to heart. Reed admits he just feels it’s not right to fraternize with a superior officer. He’s kinda a boring dude, honestly, right down to it. He’s also just kinda unhappy with Archer cause he thinks Archer should be a shitty, bad captain. Reed has bad opinions.</p>

<p>The Romulans, now that Hoshi can translate the language, are like “Get the fuck out of here. Just detatched that hull plating, kill your crewman, and leave.” Ahh, Romulans. As unforgiving of any others existing as always. Anyways the mine will explode if they try and disarm it like this. So Reed tries to kill himself so that they’ll just knock off the plate off. He’s like “JUST BE A GOOD (read: bad) CAPTAIN FOR ONCE AND LET ME DIE A HERO”. Reed is a fucking weirdo.</p>

<p>Archer comes up with a big dumb plan. He cuts the thing, and it explodes. They use plating as shields and protect themselves, launching away from the blast. Absolutely nuts. But it works, the end.</p>

<p>They probably should have just cut through his leg. Anyways, I found this mostly boring. Reed is just kinda boring.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 191</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/17/OOCY191.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 191" /><published>2025-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/17/OOCY191</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/17/OOCY191.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vkYvXpb.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Black Mixes Red</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Black Mixes Red" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>