<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-08T13:05:40-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 19" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FsOSYUN.png" alt="&quot;Oh shut up!! If it comes down to that, then we can just have an orgy together! I want to celebrate, right this instant!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: come rain or shine</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="come rain or shine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 6 - Mortol</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/08/UFO50-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 6 - Mortol" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/08/UFO50#6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/08/UFO50-6.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4tL6TaI.png" alt="Mortol" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mortol has a lot of interesting things about it’s backstory, so bear with me. We’ll start with the concept.</p>

<p>Benedikt Chun came up with the original concept of this game, but is notably absent in its credits, except for graphics. There are few hints as to why. Mortol 2’s description, and a hidden code that changes the way the game plays, explains that Chun’s original vision for the game was that you had to sacrifice your characters to continue, which the game still has, but you couldn’t gain back lives. I imagine the others played the prototype, or even talked him out of it really early, cause that shit is pretty rough and unfun (as you can tell from the code), and he kind of sat out development because of it.</p>

<p>The credits also show something else important. We’ve got another new worker at LX Systems! The first person other than Chun, Smolski, or Thorson who was brought on for actual game development reasons. Credited for graphics and level design, he’d go on to do basically every single possible job position at the company in his long, long tenure there. He is the protagonist of our story, in fact. His name is Gregory Milk.</p>

<p>Gregory Milk’s most important contribution to our story is that he literally made UFO 50. In the contexts of the world, he made the program UFO 50, which was later found years later by Mossmouth, and ported to PCs. His hands are all up in it, and while I WANT to call him a hero, he’s also an unreliable narrator. I’ll talk about that much, much later. But suffice to say, Milkdud is my man, and in my opinion a force of good in the company.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ha48kny.png" alt="Mortol" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Anyways, his first game he ever worked on, what was it?</p>

<p>An ancient evil has re-awakened and is laying waste to your country. How many men must lay down their lives to save Mortolia?</p>

<p>Mortol is a platformer. Kind of. One of the more traditional videogames in the company’s early catalogue, it of course has a weird twist that takes it in a different direction, the one that Chun original came up with. What if you had a game where, in order to progress further, you had to literally sacrifice people to get there? At the start, you have 20 men, and they each have three actions they can do, alongside running and jumping. Depending on what direction you press the D-pad as you press A, your character with either 1) Explode 2) Turn into a block or 3) fly directly forward and imbed your skull into any wall in front of you.</p>

<p>As you platform around, you’ll run into obstacles. Blocks you gotta blow up, enemies you gotta platform around, walls you gotta make a ladder of men with their skulls in the wall to proceed. Y’know, normal stuff. If you solve puzzles in the levels, like using a ritual explosion in juuust the right way, you can set up for picking up some of the lives that are scattered around each level. As your men give their lives for Mortolia, more will parachute out of the ship, which moves along as you make progress.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UqUVR28.png" alt="Mortol" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is certainly fun, and it’s pretty rewarding to retry a level and try to get through with as few deaths as you can. It’s like a puzzle, trying to figure out how to get all the life pickups, and get around obstacles with the fewest deaths. As I first played it I was a bity frustrated by the package, but after I beat it and went back to re-learn every stage and improve them, it got more and more fun. It was never BAD, but it did grow on me a little bit.</p>

<p>The music is also really nice, but unfortunately the last two levels completely remove the music. I guess for ambiance and vibes, but I’d prefer the music.</p>

<p>8/10</p>

<p>It’s worth noting that a lot of people REALLY like Mortol, so I’m a bit worried that people will be upset at my score. Remember that an 8/10 is still very good, people lol</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 18</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/07/OOCY18.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 18" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/07/OOCY18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/07/OOCY18.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3Bxcr2k.png" alt="&quot;CATS HAVE THE POWER! TO HEAL! JUST BY EXISTING!!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Demon Lord of “Yashiro”</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Demon Lord of &quot;Yashiro&quot;" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 5 - Magic Garden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/07/UFO50-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 5 - Magic Garden" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/07/UFO50#5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/07/UFO50-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ez864SS.png" alt="Magic Garden" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Something I haven’t quite mentioned about the history behind LX Systems is that they weren’t JUST a software company. While it’s never fully explained what the situation is, they seem to actually be producing the LX itself. I’m not sure if it’s a licensing situation, or if they actually developed the LX, but considering the name LX Systems, it makes sense that they invented it. I’m bringing this up because, at the turn of 1984, the LX was already a little long in the tooth. Technology was evolving considerably in the 80s, and yesterday’s top machine is today’s trash. Shit, not much has changed, but it was almost more pronounced back then. So in 1984, LX Systems released not only their next game, but an entirely new computer to go along with it, the LX2.</p>

<p>This wasn’t really anything new, and wouldn’t take all that much effort, all things considered. The MSX2 was something very similar to this. Same ol’ computer, but with some added ram, or a few added systems and boards, that kinda thing. I’m not a hardware specialists, I’m a Goblin who plays games on the internet. But anyways, the LX2 was created, and they hired a new specialist to help them develop it. Meesha Danry is our newest employee, and the first woman to work at LX Systems, which is cool. While she never will do a whole lot in the actual game development side, her effects are very pronounced on the company. She’s often considered a confidant and friend to those who work there.</p>

<p>So, what can the LX2 do? Well, it can display more sprites and colors per sprite, mostly. Typical upgrade stuff. And to show that off, we got our first game of 1984, Magic Garden.</p>

<p>And it’s one of the best games ever. This is my favorite game of the collection, hands down. I thought MAYBE Mini and Max would bop it, and it did for a bit, but after cherrying M&amp;M, I have to admit, Magic Garden is still better.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4iQuk6N.png" alt="Magic Garden" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Magic Garden, you play as a cute girl who’s tending to her garden, while the jealous witch Cloveranna tries to ruin your day. Magical slimes, named Oppies, grow and sprout out of the ground. You need to collect them then release them in the star squares, which move and shift around every 10 seconds or so. Meanwhile, angy Oppies are spawning, so avoid those. If you release oppies NOT on the star blocks, they’ll get angy. This can be useful, which I’ll explain later. Save 6 or more Oppies, and a potion will spawn, which will make all enemies vulnerable, except for the mushrooms. The mushrooms are only vulernable if you get a gold potion. You get gold potions by saving 10 Oppies at a time, OR by waiting, as potions will grow in strength if you leave them there. On top of the release button, there’s also a jump button, which should probably only be used as a last resort, cause it’s really hard to use. You gotta time it just right, and you can’t turn as easily after landing, so you gotta be careful, but it HAS saved my ass.</p>

<p>The goal of the game is to get 200 Oppies saved, after which the Gardener will tell the Witch that she’d be HAPPY to teach her how to garden, and then they walk off together. I assume to make out. THis game SCREAMS yuri, and I know I see yuri in everything, but no. This is yuri. Also I wanna note, early 1984, and a female protagonist? Ahead of the curve, LX Systems, good on you. Maybe Meesha made a suggestion. It’s certainly possible. Anyways, while saving those 200 Oppies, you can try to get a high score. Save more Oppies, or beat enemies in a row with the potion active to get more points. You can chain potions together to elongate the window of beating enemies, and ALSO to increase your score multiplier.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RmBsytE.png" alt="Magic Garden" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is so charming. I love the sprites. I love the art. I love how it changes color palettes as you reach different levels of Oppies saved. I love the style and design. The little cat yawning, so cute. The little trees with eyes. The oppies are WONDERFUL. THE YURI, OF COURSE. Also the music is FANTASTIC, this is Petters’ best work yet. Everything about this game works. Like, to be reductive, it really is just… Snake. But with a few extra steps. But it’s so extremely addicting. You take a hit, start all over, and it doesn’t feel bad, you just go “AHHH, okay one more go!” and then it’s 2 hours later. I seriously cannot overstate how good this game feels and is to play.</p>

<p>The ONLY thing that’d make this game better is an endless mode, which sadly it doesn’t have. This means there’s a theoretical cap to the socre, probably, as you can only get 200/6 potions, with which to beat Oppies. That’s where releasing Oppies and making them angry works out, btw. Fills the field so you can get a HUGE combo, which feels so satisfying. This game could also be improved with a multiplayer variant, which I feel it’s built very well for. Clears could send over more Oppies to the enemy field. Could end up with some really long lasting battles, but hard fought.</p>

<p>So, hats off to Chun. This game is fucking fantastic, and I have no bad things to say about it whatsoever. I’d buy UFO 50 just to play this game. Not a joke. 25 dollars for this game. It’s a BIT pricy, cause it’s such a short experience, but I do love it that much. At 50 cents its a god damn steal.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><category term="yuri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 4 - Paint Chase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/06/UFO50-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 4 - Paint Chase" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/06/UFO50#4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/06/UFO50-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N1c1zYS.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s nearing the end of 1983, and we’ve got a new game by LX Systems! This one is called Paint Chase, and it’s designed by Gerry Smolski. Up until this point it hasn’t been exactly apparent what Smolski or Chun brought to the table, but it’s made clear here. Smolski was not a game designer. He was the hardware specialist. LX Systems made the LX itself, as well, you see. And his job was to make sure everything worked on it. But he had an idea, and decided to branch out, and this was his first attempt. How did he do in his new role as game designer?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K9p9TvI.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Paint Chase is a racing action arcade game, though really less racing and more just themed around it. It’s more like Rally-X than a more modern idea of a racing game. You play as a little car that’s leaving paint behind it, and you need to paint as much of the ground as you can. At the end, you’ll be judged by how much of the arena is blue. Get above a threshhold, and more opnto the next level. There’s like 25 or 35 levels, and they get increasingly complex and difficult as you progress, throwing in new enemies and things. The enemies move around painting things pink. Pink or not pink doesn’t really matter to you, though, your main goal is just making EVERYTHING blue.</p>

<p>The game has some delightful music by Petterson, and it even has more cute cutscenes! A bit more expressive than what we get in Ninpek, these cutscenes are between every 5 or 10 levels or so, and introduce new enemies. It’s a welcome change.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VRUToz5.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, it doesn’t fix the game for me. When I first played Paint Chase, it felt kind of mid to me, and it’s only worsened as I’ve played it more. The conceit and concept is fun enough, and it doesn’t play poorly. Your car can’t turn around, which can make for some “ah fuck” moments, but it’s fine. The main issue is the enemies. This game is way too long, and it’s an RNG nightmare. I managed to beat it, with a few pretty good levels. I got a score of 350. What do you need to win? 550. Jeezus. Basically at the end, for every percentage you’re over the required percentage, you get a point. Good enough concept, but the enemies are WAY too numerous. They can spawn right next to you and easily be taken out, which makes a good score easy. Or more likely, they will spawn on seperate sides of the arena.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KbSYnnx.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>People watching me complain were like “oh, focus the gernades”. I did, then the slugs on the other side of the screen overwhelmed me. “Oh no, you need to focus the slugs.” So I did. Then the planes got me. “No, you need to focus the planes.” I CAN’T FOCUS ALL OF THESE THINGS, especially when they’re on seperate sides of the god damn map, and no matter what, I have to leave some of them alive, and some are <strong>faster than me</strong>. It’s an exercise in frustration, and no, I don’t like it very much at all. It’s just not very fun to play to conteract the frustration. I almost never feel like deaths are my fault, and that should never be how it is.</p>

<p>I’m sorry, Smolski. Maybe you’ll do better next time?</p>

<p>4/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/06/OOCY17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 17" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/06/OOCY17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/06/OOCY17.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IDuVQGR.png" alt="&quot;If that keeps going, I worry that 'dying because my wife was too cute' might become reality...&quot; &quot;That's it! And at the funeral, 'they both died because we were too cute...' WON'T THAT HAPPEN?! THAT'S BAD! I NEED TO KEEP LIVING!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yurikon</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yurikon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 1-7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/06/LizstartrekVOY3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 1-7" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/06/LizstartrekVOY3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/06/LizstartrekVOY3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xgK8LCx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Basics, Part 2</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0wsS1j5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We jump back to our crew, now a bunch of exiles on a planet. Things are looking up! Oh except one of them, a Maquis dude-bro, who’s eaten by some kind of lizard while trying to grab bones. And it’s all Neelix’s fault. Also they have to eat grubs. It’s gross and no one is happy. Understandably.</p>

<p>Oh hey, Paris is alive! His shuttle is on fire and struggling but he’s alive. And being kinda badass, still fighting off Kazon.</p>

<p>Seska comes in and talks to the Doctor, who’s been hiding, but can be good at deception! She actually asks him if he’s good at deception, and it’s like “No,” the Doctor lied. She wasn’t here for any of his character development. Anyways he informs her no, that is NOT Chakotay’s son. He just kinda looks Human. Who knows what a Kazon/Cardassian hybrid looks like?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1NbEwKd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor and Suder team up. Suder is willing to help take the ship back, and save everyone. Suder is like “Oh boy, here I go killin’ again!” He’s not happy. He’s been trying so hard.</p>

<p>Neelix and Kes are kidnapped by alien cave people. It’s a stupid scene. We already have die hard on the ship, and a survival situation, and Paris sneaking around space, do we ALSO need aliens trying to slave trade for Kes?? Also, when they couldn’t start a fire, Chakotay is like “We need SOME kind of kindling! Where could we find some?!” and they use hair, which would prolly would but wouldn’t be the best idea. You know what would be? ALL THE GRASS THAT’S ALL AROUND. INCLUDING THE ONES THAT THE ALIEN CAVE PEOPLE USE TO START A FIRE TO SMOKE THEM OUT.</p>

<p>This episode would be better without any of the stuff on the planet. If they just focused on the die-harding on the ship and we saw the crew at the end, broken and bruised, it’d be kinda interesting. Though maybe not. Maybe in that universe I’d be like “why did we not see any survival???” Anyways, horrible CGI beast that uses the same sound effect as a Hydralisk eats another crew member. They’re dropping like flies.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5ErvyTZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I think people might not like Suder? I find him very interesting. I am also chemically unbalanced and mentally unwell, and while I’m not like, unbalanced in a way I want to MURDER people, I respect and admire a character who’s internal demons are telling him to do things he doesn’t want to do, and he’s fighting against them. Even more so when he has to feed those demons to survive and help others. I LIKE that. Yes, calling him a sociopath, and 90s sensibilites are… a thing, but I like him, and he’s MOSTLY handled well.</p>

<p>Seska finds out about the Doctor sabatoging the ship, and though she thinks there’s another person on there. But the Doctor is VERY VERY good at deception, actually, and convinces her he did it all on his own and PRETENDED there was another on board, so they’d search him whoever that is. Genius. Seska buys the bait, but kills the doctor, blowing up his server. RIP Doctor, a real one. Suder’s all that’s left. The Doctor left a heartfelt message to him. He’s our only hope. He can do it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dlsyTfu.png" alt="trek" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/U2rFKcf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A full Uhura Maneuver later, and there are a dozen dead Kazon. He’s shot in the back by a dying one, but manages to overload the systems in time for Paris and his fleet to take Voyager. The resulting explosion kills a LOT of Kazon, and also kills Seska, who crawls for her baby. Culluh cries over her corpse and takes the baby, abandoning ship. They’ve lost. Paris and his allies board the ship and head back to rescue everyone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fo0UcYK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They mourn Suder as a hero, repair the Doctor, and Chakotay mourns Seska in his own way. I’d have thrown her out an airlock, but whatever works. They take off from their new home to the old one. They didn’t even get to take a shower, Paris is still covered in smudge lmfao</p>

<p>I loved half of this. The other half, not so much. It’s also worth noting that we will NEVER seen the Kazon ever again. With the Vidiians and the Kazons done, we’re almost at a soft reboot! We have no more bad guys. Gotta get some new ones.</p>

<p><strong>Flashback</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W7awxMD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things are okay on Voyager! They maybe found a new energy source and are going to pick it up. Suddenly, Tuvok has what seems to be a panic attack. He freaks out and leaves the room for sickbay, while having a flashback to something from his past. Young him, trying to save a girl from falling in a pit…. only issue is, it wasn’t a memory. It never happened. No one knows why this happened, could be so many reasons. While they study is, Tuvok Isn’t Doin’ Great. He goes back to active duty the following day, totally fine. But uh, he’s not. And he’s like “Well we should be wary about cloaked ships this close to Klingon space” and everyone is like “…what???? Dude” and then heh as another panic attack.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HzUn48E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Basically, in Vulcans, if they’re repressing a memory, it causes really bad things to their brain and causes them to die. How to fix this? A mind meld with a close family member, so they can bring that unconscious memory into the conscious memory, work through the trauma. Mind meld therapy session. Tuvok has no family on the ship obviously, so he mind melds with Janeway instead. She’ll basically be watching in a memory, no one reacting to her. He’ll take her back to his childhood…. and yet instead, we’re taken to the excelsior, 80 years ago.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EVjLUCA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So, Tuvok’s actor was on the Excelsior in Star Trek 6. They kinda retconned that that was young Tuvok, which is pretty great. We get to see some TOS characters! The last time we see… ANY of them, I’m pretty sure, until like, waaaay into Discovery. We’ll at least never see these actors again. (Technically Trials and Tribbleations aired after this, but there was no new  We see Sulu, who’s pretty great and fun here, and Rand! This is actually taking place DURING Star Trek 6, when Sulu goes to the Klingons to try and save Kirk.</p>

<p>Tuvok has another attack, and Janeway is forced out of his mind. After a bit they try again, and we learn some more Tuvok background. He was kind of a racist back then and didn’t even want to be in Starfleet to begin with. He eventually had a change of heart, “though heart had little to do with it. It was an entirely logical decision”. I’m sure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xMGAd08.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>KANG IS HERE! He politely tells Sulu to fuck off. Sulu does not fuck off. They give them a slip, but are attacked, and Tuvok’s roommate dies. This seems to do something to the meld, and the meld is falling apart, killing them both… but Janeway feels like they’re CLOSE. However, the disrupted meld causes issues, and everyone can see Janeway now. They need to restart the meld, with Janeway stealing Rand’s clothes. If I were a woman on the Excelsior and Janeway asked me to take off my clothes, I’d do it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TlHBfFD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back in the real world, the doctor finds out that a third memory engram is in there, some kind of virus. A viral memory. Weird. Anyways it had infected Tuvok’s roommate, and jumped to him. He wipes it out using radiation, the end. Feels like the actual things they were doing in the memory didn’t do anything and weren’t actually important? The Doctor just solved it with deus ex radiation. But it was fun to see TOS characters.</p>

<p><strong>The Chute</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3VyZYFq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>KIM</p>

<p>MUST</p>

<p>SUFFER!</p>

<p>Kim falls down the titular chute into some kind of jail, and is immediately beaten up by the prisoners there. Including Paris, who joins in on the beating. Computer, delete Paris. Paris makes up a story about a bombing and how Kim sold him out to get him away, and then they explain. The two of them were blamed for a bombing and thrown down here. It’s a prison 300 meters underground, in a hole. So it’s the prison in Batman Rises. but they also have been implanted with some kind of thing in their brains, and it’s making them itchy. Also it’s literally driving everyone insane.</p>

<p>We find out a bit more about what’s going on. These people, the Akritirians, are a fascist government. There was a terrorist bombing and they kinda arbitrarily decided it was Kim and Paris. They then declare that they will take Voyager and throw everyone on it in prison, so they attack Voyager. Of course, Voyager can handle it, but this is mostly extremely annoying for them. They NEED to get their people back. But how?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wnPcBeH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris is stabbed in a prison fight, because prisoners don’t play fair. They find a prisoner who’s SHOCKINGLY sane. He’s been in there for six years, and is handling it really, really well, writing alone in his little hut. Harry gets him to join them, as he’s possibly onto a way through the chute and back out of the jail.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mcG60lM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s writing a manifesto. He’s got it all figured out. He knows why they put the clamps in them. It’s not torture. It’s population control. This understanding kinda allows him to just… ignore its effects. It’s never clear if he’s ACTUALLY sane or not. Anyways, Harry does it, breaking through the chute, they can escape!! Except… nope. They’re not under the ground. They’re in space.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4sfs7hX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Well that’s not good.</p>

<p>Janeway finds the actual bombers, and has them dragged to the Akitirians. But the Akitirians refuse to release Kim and Paris, because it’s how fascism works. Isn’t it effective? :D Janeway gives the prisoners an ultimatum. Take us to the prison, or you’re going to the Akitirians anyway, even if we get nothing out of it. When he tries making demands about letting others out, she’s like “Nope.” It’s…. pretty hardass of her, especially after that one fucking episode where she was pretending to be the daughter of someone fighting against a fascist regime. LOTS of fascist regimes in this part of space? Anyways, they go to the prison, and Janeway dives down the chute, blasting everyone immediately. That’s so funny. And wonderful. Anyways they make it out, safe, and work through Kim almost killing him while they were both being driven insane.</p>

<p>It was tense and kinda good, but some things about it kinda annoyed me and felt flat.</p>

<p><strong>The Swarm</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0lU3yB9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Paris and Torres doing banter on a ship when some cool-ass aliens beam onto their ship. Paris is like “uh, hi, I’m Paris-“ and is IMMEDIATELY shot. I can only assume they went “OH FUCK, IT’S THAT GUY, FUCKING GET HIM”. They then beam off the ship. Guess they just wanted to kill Paris. My favorite new aliens.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Doctor is doing some opera in the holodeck. It’s nice that he has hobbies. Picardo is doing his own singing here, and it’s real good! But the Doctor is having some… issues. He forgets the lyrics. When he goes to treat Paris and Torres, he seems forgetful and distracted. But he doesn’t seem to notice. I’m sure he won’t have anything important to do- oh, looks like PARIS NEEDS SURGERY. With Kes’ help, they stabilize him.</p>

<p>So, since the Doctor has been awake for so long, his program is starting to fall apart, basically. They can just restart him to bring him back to normal, but that erases who he is after 2 years of experiences, and restarts him anew. Everyone thinks that’s bad, but the doctor is okay with it, because he can’t help people this way, and that’s his #1 goal. But Kes convinces them to at least TRY to save him. Torres is trying, but having trouble. So she calls on the one person who might be able to help them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7TnXXcl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They set up a holodeck of Dr. Zimmerman, the EMH’s creator. He is… awful. And his answer to the problem is “just erase his personality who cares”. Poor EMH is starting to become SCARED about his existence. Meanwhile, they’re trying to sneak through the bug people’s home, because otherwise it’ll add 15 months of time onto their travel. This is weirdly the B plot.</p>

<p>This feels like a response to Measure of a Man, but with a twist of talking about dimensia and alzheimers. Like, it has the “he’s just a machine, he doesn’t need friendships or hobbies” angle, but also a “he’s useless to us as he is.” Even KES starts to think they should just reinitialize him, after he doesn’t even remember who she is. What’s the point of those friendships and love if he can’t rememeber? Whoof. Keep in mind, this isn’t ME saying that, that’s a point the episode is saying. It’s really painful to even see the Doctor, my favorite episode here, fall apart like this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ek8IYQ8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode has a lot of treknobabble. They say the word “Interferometric pulses” a lot which is very funny. Anyways they stop the swarm, it’s a weird addition to this episode.</p>

<p>They sacrifice the Dr. Zimmerman diagnostic program in order to rebuild the EMH’s emgrams or whatever. No one knows if it’ll actually work, but after the fusion is complete, the EMH is here, and working, but doesn’t seem to know anyone ): Sad… but as he walks away, he starts humming opera to himself. I think it’ll just take a minute for him to warm up.</p>

<p>Pretty good episode all together.</p>

<p><strong>False Profits</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IMCXNDR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager comes across a wormhole that goes to the Alpha Quadrant. Oh boy, the show is gonna end, how lovely. They can’t quite get into it cause it’s so eratic, but they’re working on it. Meanwhile, a nearby planet shows scans of a replicator’s emissions, which is apparently a thing, so it seems someone from the Alpha Quadrant is here. Chakotay and Paris go down to a planet filled with totally-not-humans, and are IMMEDIATELY accosted by a bunch of money grubbing swindlers. They make their way to The Holy Temple, and get a look at the prophets.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/X6hpIlJ.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Do you remember that episode of TNG where they were trying to get the rights to a wormhole to the Delta Quadrant, but it was unstable and some Ferengi got stranded on the other side? HERE THEY ARE! This FINALLY pays off, an amazing brick joke in the works. And of course, they’re taken the replicator on their ship and are acting as gods who can summon anything they want.</p>

<p>Technically they can’t stop them, because the Ferengi are not Federation, and don’t have a Prime Directive… buuuut, technically, them being there IS kind of the Federation’s fault. Or at least, they can tell themselves it is. So they can interfere and fix their problem. Legally. The Ferengi argue that if they’re taken from this planet it’ll drive them into chaos, because their gods suddenly abandoned them. Janeway HAS to agree. So in order to save these people, they need to out Ferengi the Ferengi.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/HKhbjXW.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>They got Neelix pretending to be a Ferengi sent by the Grand Nagus. Beautiful. It works EXTREMELY well… until the ferengi decide to circumvent it by just trying to assassinate him. Neelix then freaks out and explains the whole thing. Shockingly they DON’T kill him and let him go, as a warning.</p>

<p>Instead, they just listen to the song that explains what the prophets to when they come out. And so they bring the NEXT prophet along (still Neelix) to announce its time for them to go home, on wings of fire. This works… until it turns out that they interpret that azs “BURN THE SAGES ALIVE”.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/iAlIVTs.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>They manage to beam them out in time. But even still, the Ferengi manage to FIGHT SECURITY AND BREAK OUT, getting into their ship and trying to get back to the planet. They ALSO destabilize the wormhole, because status quo is king. Voyager would have ended if they had more than one person guarding the Ferengi.</p>

<p><strong>Remember</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gBYq9WC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is near some nice friendly aliens who are helping to upgrade their systems. That’s pleasant. After a long day of work, Torres goes to sleep, and has a dream where she’s making out and fucking some dude. This dream is SO intense that it has her sleep through her duty shift. She seems to like these dreams, they’re vivid and fun. It’s like a living holo novel where she’s got a bad boy boyfriend her father doesn’t approve of.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, we find out that these friendly aliens are psychic! They have EXTREMELY laws about consent. Ohhhh no I know where this episode is going. By the way, this episode is a re-used episode concept from TNG, where the original idea was about this happening to Troi. YEP. IT’S ONE OF THOSE EPISODES. WHY DID THEY KEEP TRYING TO WRITE THESE EPISODES ABOUT TROI?</p>

<p>After a dream ends in her lover being burned and scarred, Torres decides that actually, this is probably something she should look into. She’s gonna ask one of the Inarans about it, but she passes out before she can get to anyone, so now EVERYONE knows about it. She wnats to keep exploring these dreams to learn more, something about it unsettles her, but it might be hurting her brainmeats.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7OlTR47.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Her dreams continue. Her boyfriend is a “Regressive”, basically amish. They don’t use technology, and living in the city, the “normal people” are worried because they might start a plague or something. So they’re just being… moved! They’re being relocated, it’s TOTALLY a thing they’ll agree with and like! And not forced at all! Yep! That’s right!</p>

<p>This is <strong>A genocide episode</strong>. These people are being genocided just behind the scenes. They’re transporting people away and just killing them. And when Torres wakes up again, she has a theory on who it is. It’s an old lady on the ship who’s dying, and she goes to save her, but the lady is like “No, I have to give you the rest of it, they’re trying to silence me”. Ruh roh.</p>

<p>Yeah there’s a lot of disgusting genocidal rhetoric that you see in this episode. It’s REALLY scary and fucked up. And she’s FORCED to join in on the genocide by her abusive family and the fascist regime she lives in. When it all ends, she has a GIANT speech about how disgusted she is by all of them for the cover up, interrupting a lovely party with talk of genocide. How rude??</p>

<p>She manages to pass the memories along to someone, just so that this memory isn’t lost forever. Even if nothing can be done.</p>

<p>This was SO much better than I expected. It’s not a mind-assault episode like I thoguht it’d be. Torres having agency, and trying to both push the puzzle forward and then spread the word helped a lot.</p>

<p><strong>Sacred Ground</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MNKcxIu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While exploring some alien’s holy shrine, Kes is electrocuted by a shrine and everyone is like “well clearly she pissed off the spirits, so there’s nothing we can do.” They can find no scientific paths to saving her, but there is ONE path. There’s an ancient story of a king who’s son did what Kes did, and the king did a ritual to speak to the spirits, and begged them to save his son. So that’s what Janeway is going to do. But she’s pretty… science-minded. How is she going to be able to handle this religious experience?</p>

<p>It’s an interesting setup. I like how it shows Janeway. She is very openly athiest, but extremely open towards religions and belief systems. Except in THIS case, where it’s killing a member of her crew. And the religious members are excited to help her with this. No one ACTUALLY wants Kes to die. So if there’s a way out that satisfies both parties.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XXJ2zvC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s some very fun like, ancient mystical monk rituals. Every so often we jump back to the ship where Chakotay is grumpy and wants to rescue Janeway and everyone like “Dude she went through this of her own volition, let the woman do her job”.</p>

<p>When she finally gets an audience with the spirits (the doctor, viewing her biometric levels, says she’s being given a psychative drug). The spirits in her dream tell her she has everything she needs to save Kes, that everything she went through was meaningless. Her guide says that too. And when she goes back, they try to use the info to save Kes, but it doesn’t work. And again the doctor repeats those words. Everything she did was meaningless. Her guide explains that yeah, all that was just cause that’s what she was expecting. The ritual isn’t even a real thing. She just has to believe in the spirits. She has to take Kes and walk into the “biogenic field”, aka the spirits, and trust them.</p>

<p>Chakotay is the voice of “this is stupid don’t do that” which is very weird? CHAKOTAY of all people like “HOW CAN YOU BELIEVE IN THESE FOOLISH BELIEFS”? Oochie Mama, we are far from the bones of our out of character. She takes her through anyway, and it saves Kes. The Doctor has a big scientific explanation for what happened, but Janeway is a bit… out of it. Her belief in science, what was a solid rock to her, is kind of broken.</p>

<p>While the concept was kinda cool and a few scenes were fun, it was a LITTLE boring sadly.</p>

<p><strong>Future’s End Part 1</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pVBz5PC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back in the 60s, something slams into a mountain as a hippie watches. Far out.</p>

<p>Back in the present, y’know, the 2300s, Voyager meets a Federation ship from the 2900s. It attacks Voyager, explaining that Voyager is causing a major problem in their future, and must be blown up. In the fight, they’re both sent back in time to 1996. Now they’re stuck in the past and need to find that “timeship”. They have reading to go off of. Los Angeles.</p>

<p>It’s always funny to see modern times in Star Trek.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MGcLarr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And also fun to see how the Trek crew try to fit in.</p>

<p>A SETI girl at an observatory catches wind of them in orbit, specifically based on a reading that some rich guy told her to look out for. He calls her up and he’s like “Do NOT contact them” and uh, she does anyway. It’s a very silly “standard greeting” for aliens. Very funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wNIXst8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find Braxton, the guy who was in the timeship, the guy from the 2900th century. He explains that his ship causes the timebreak in the future, so yeah, it was all his fault, it’s a paradox they have to carefully untie. He’s also a homeless raving lunatic who is very VERY bad at being a timecop. He’s a timecop from the future trying to stop time crimes, and in the past he tried to tell everyone he’s from the future and he’s treated like a raving lunatic, cause he’s acting like one. God how can you be this bad? He also explains that his ship was found by that rich CEO I mentioned earlier. Holy shit, the rich CEO was the hippie. That’s very funny.</p>

<p>They split into a few parties. Tuvok and Paris go to wipe the hard-drive of the cute dorky lady at SETI. At the same time, Janeway and Chakotay are going to break into the CEO’s house to find the stuff he stole. The CEO ALSO sends a goon to take out the dorky lady for sending that message to Voyager, and tells him to take “the weapon”, AKA a future phaser to kill him and the Voyagers.</p>

<p>I love this nerdy girl, I wish she’d join the crew. Voyager coulda been so much cooler if they just kept adding characters that they find. This show’d be better with her and Airheart joining the Voyager crew.</p>

<p>The rich CEO captures Janeway and Chakotay fiddlign with his systems, and even after being told he’s gonna blow up the future, he doesn’t seem to care. Like… dude? He’s trying to be a laughing maniacal villain, but like…. look I know he’s a rich guy and is thus evil, but it’s kinda stupid to be told, by people you KNOW are from the future, “you’re gonna blow up everything”, and then go “lol nah I know what I’m doing”. He’s being a fucking idiot.</p>

<p>Kim flies Voyager down to save them, teleporting them out. This ALSO makes it so EVERYONE sees Voyager. How are all of them SO BAD AT THIS?! The episode ends with the CEO stealing a lot of data from Voyager, including the doctor, who is now physically in his office. How is the CEO defeating Voyager with a DOS PC? How is the Doctor physically in his room? Again, with a DOS PC??? I don’t fucking know. And it’s very annoying.</p>

<p>It’s fine, but some of the things about it really bugged me. I’ll have to see how they wrap it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 16</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/05/OOCY16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 16" /><published>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/05/OOCY16</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/05/OOCY16.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UNf2ef8.png" alt="&quot;The hell?! Swimsuits are crazy!&quot; she says, staring at some tits" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Don’t Know Which One Is Love</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Don&apos;t Know Which One Is Love" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 3 - Ninpek</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/05/UFO50-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 3 - Ninpek" /><published>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/05/UFO50#3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/05/UFO50-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2TZ4O53.png" alt="Ninpek title screen" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Following Bug Hunter, the trio of Petters, Chun, and Smolski needed to make a new game. Their previous two games were a little… uncommercial, maybe? Bug Hunters was an interesting but kind of difficult to grok puzzle strategy game about mutant bugs, and Barbuta is… challenging. But there’s something big sweeping the nation in 1983… that’s right, NINJAMANIA! Ninjas are REAL in right now, let’s make a game about that! And so we get Ninpek. But is Ninpek just the trio selling out, or is it worth a look?</p>

<p>Ninpek starts off the bat with an extremely impressive innovation: scrolling. Scrolling to us today feels like a no brainer, like yeah, what about it? But in the early 80s, this shit was hard to get working. And ESPECIALLY on microPCs at the time. Smooth scrolling on DOS basically asn’t solidified and commonplace until the 90s, and the LX is no DOS. It wasn’t really commonplace in the home until… gee, Super Mario Brothers? And that’s after Ninpek. So Ninpek was MASSIVELY ahead of its time. It’s not choppy either, it’s smooth scrolling.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLp9426.png" alt="Ninpek" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Ninpek is a game where you play as a ninja, and your hoagie gets stolen. I call it a hoagie, it could be a burger. Anyways, you gotta get your hoagie back. That’s it. There’s a cute little intro, and then you’re off. The screen auto-scrolls to the right, and you run and shoot your way around. Very early arcadey platformer, the most obvious real life analogue might be SonSon, which in 1984 in arcades, was impressive. And this is 1983 in the home. I do feel this is a BIT of a temporal anomaly? Like, when I say it’s ahead of its time, it’s REALLY ahead of its time. It also for some reason reminds me of Chubby Cherub, but I have no idea why.</p>

<p>It’s not very complex. Run, jump, shoot. You move alongside the screen, so you constantly gotta fight against the screen in order to hit things in front of you and not run into them. It takes a little getting used to, but it’s mostly just weird to our modern sensibilities. For the time, it made sense. When enemies die, they drop little blobs that will give you points. You don’t get points until picking up the blob, incentivizing a bit of hectic and occasionally risky maneuvers to get your shiny points.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Muh7ETS.png" alt="Ninpek" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game ALSO has music for the first time! While no one is directly credited with anything in the game, Petters is credited in later games for sound and music, so assumedly it was his composition here. The music is pretty pleasant, IMO. It’s VERY Ninja-y. Which y’know, makes sense. This game feels very VERY Japanese, though it’s important to note I have no fucking idea what country this company is from. Parts of them feel British, American, and Japanese, all at the same time. And kinda nothing helps symbolize that more to me than a section in the game with little collectibles. They’re cherries, then you collect enough, and they become rice balls. Mmm, jelly donuts. Then collect enough of THOSE, and they turn into… coffee! Coffee is a pretty common sight in these games, these devs love their coffee.</p>

<p>Anyways Ninpek is nothing like, transcendent, but for an early 80s arcade platformer, it’s stunningly ahead of its time and quite enjoyable. I cherried it on my second ever attempt, which in this case means two loops through the game. Pretty challenging, but a good challenge.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 2 - Bug Hunter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/04/UFO50-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 2 - Bug Hunter" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/04/UFO50#2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/04/UFO50-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>The year is 1983, only a few months after Barbuta was unleashed onto the world. Thorson Petters, the artist, was nearly fired for making the game on company time, but that’s okay because he didn’t really seem to like working at Business Soft anyway. I mean, with a name like that, who would? So he and two of his coworkers and friends, Gerry Smolski and Benedikt Chun, break away Business Soft to form LX Systems, a fledgling game company making games for the LX. The LX, like most micro computers, was never really intended for video games, the industry was still so extremely new. But companies like this began to pop up all over the place, and while LX Systems was not the most creative name for a company focused on making games on the LX, it would soon prove itself with its next, and technically first, release: Bug Hunter.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6FJ8GMl.png" alt="&quot;Bug Hunter&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Bug Hunter, you play as a mercenary exterminator hired by a moon quarry to stop bugs that have been running rampant. Can you stop the bugs before they overrun the mine? To assist you, the owners of the quarry will drop energy blocks on you, which can be used to upgrade your weapons.</p>

<p>The game is an extremely interesting strategy puzzle game. You have slots for seven actions. You start with very simple actions, run, jump, shoot, and lob. As you collect energy, you can spend it to change out your actions for a new action. This also refreshes the action, so if you have the energy, you can keep cashing out to do more and more things in one turn. Each turn, bugs and energy will spawn, and your goal is very simple. Kill the bugs. If a bug is not killed in a turn, it will evolve into a new form of bug. These bugs all have different abilities, some way worse than others. You’ve got bugs that make holes when they die, bugs that turn energy into anti-energy near them, bugs that explode when they die, bugs that create fodder and can’t be killed unless you kill the fodder (the worst), bugs that take two hits (the OTHER worst). And after they evolve, then evolve again into scarier forms, they will become… take a guess… yep, that’s right.</p>

<p>An egg. Oh, Petters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4a8p0OE.png" alt="&quot;A screen of Bug Hunter&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And then if you can’t kill the egg, it will hatch and you’ll IMMEDIATELY lose. Eggs also don’t count towards your kills, so it’s best to not even let them get to that point. On top of needing 30 bug kills to win a round, you also need to finish in ten days. So an average of 3 bugs a day. Not too bad, right? Well, it can get pretty hectic, and it feels very RNG heavy. Some bug types feel like straight up run killers. It’s probably easier in multiplayer, and it DOES have one of those though I haven’t tested it, but the game is a real brain tickler. It also helps to remember you can mario stomp enemies by walking on them from heights, I kept forgetting that. Also, you can shoot energy to make it explode and kill enemies around it. But it can ALSO kill you, so be careful. For being a 1983 brain tickling puzzler, it’s shockingly kind, because if you’re targetting things, it’ll show where an energy explosion will reach, including all the chain reactions. Very pleasant.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A9TgS0z.png" alt="&quot;The bug threat has evolved!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Overall, Bug Hunters is an interesting game, but not one I’d go back to every much. I got my 6 runs in a row for the cherry, and that was probably good for me. It has no music, and the graphics are primative, but pleasant enough. It feels weirdly isolating and uncomfortable, which hey, that fits. It also introduces Benedikt Chun and Gerry Smolski into the story as the other two co-founders of the company. Though they don’t have a chance to really shine here, we’ll learn more about them later.</p>

<p>7/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year is 1983, only a few months after Barbuta was unleashed onto the world. Thorson Petters, the artist, was nearly fired for making the game on company time, but that’s okay because he didn’t really seem to like working at Business Soft anyway. I mean, with a name like that, who would? So he and two of his coworkers and friends, Gerry Smolski and Benedikt Chun, break away Business Soft to form LX Systems, a fledgling game company making games for the LX. The LX, like most micro computers, was never really intended for video games, the industry was still so extremely new. But companies like this began to pop up all over the place, and while LX Systems was not the most creative name for a company focused on making games on the LX, it would soon prove itself with its next, and technically first, release: Bug Hunter.]]></summary></entry></feed>