<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-06T12:37:09-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 141</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/06/OOCY142.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 141" /><published>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/06/OOCY142</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/06/OOCY142.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rRb8eA8.png" alt="'That's right! It's times like these when you should consult the ultimate authority on love: romance novels!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Want to Make Black-Knight Fall In Love With Me!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="OI Want to Make Black-Knight Fall In Love With Me!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 173 - Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/06/RA174-Pooh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 173 - Winnie the Pooh in the Hundred Acre Wood" /><published>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/06/RA174-Pooh</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/06/RA174-Pooh.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j5iduki.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Sierra On-Line was maybe THE Apple II dev. They made a lot of the most popular adventure games of the day, many of which you probably still know about, despite coming out almost 40 years ago. Games like King’s Quest, Space Quest, Police Quest, Leisure Suit Larry, Quest for Glory, Phantasmagoria, the list goes on. They were very, VERY big at the time. And around the growing height of their fame, in the mid 80s on their home town of the Apple II, they also made this.</p>

<p>It’s a simple text adventure with graphical components, mostly just a solid unmoving image. You move around a grid of a map, and sometimes into spaces on those grids like houses, in order to find items that are scattered around the Hundred Acre Wood. You then need to bring those items to their owners, who are scattered around, mostly in their houses. You are not Pooh in this, you’re just some random kid. There’s lots of spaces to explore, and every now and then the items move aroumd. They start randomized, and there’s a large pool of them but only 10 show up, so it’s technically different every time!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DcahVU5.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>For an Apple II game, I have to give credit, this LOOKS good. Compare this to a lot of the other games like this, text adventures which have an image at the top of where you are, and it’s night and day. I can actually recognize Owl!! They clearly put actual effort into the art, which is not a surprise since they probably had Disney breathing down their necks, and Disney will NOT let you do off-model art.</p>

<p>Over all, this is a very simple but kind of cute kids adventure game, where the adventure is mostly wandering aimlessly and occasionally running into a character you like. I was a HUGE Winnie the Pooh fan as a kid, so I had some sense of whimsy playing this, but there’s not a whole lot to it. There’s a reason that despite Sierra On-Line being one of the biggest game companies of the time, I could find very, very little about this game online. Sierra has a lot of great games I wanna check out sometime, and a wonderful history that was sadly cut short in the late 90s when it was bought by some big-ass firm that fell apart quickly, like all those big ass firms that buy companies do. It then lost all its talent and became a shadow until finally being devoured by Activision, because capitalism is garbage. But at least we can still look back on its classics, like <em>looks at notes</em> Winnie the Pooh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Winnie the Pooh" /><category term="Text Adventures" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sierra On-Line was maybe THE Apple II dev. They made a lot of the most popular adventure games of the day, many of which you probably still know about, despite coming out almost 40 years ago. Games like King’s Quest, Space Quest, Police Quest, Leisure Suit Larry, Quest for Glory, Phantasmagoria, the list goes on. They were very, VERY big at the time. And around the growing height of their fame, in the mid 80s on their home town of the Apple II, they also made this.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 141</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/05/OOCY141.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 141" /><published>2025-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/05/OOCY141</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/05/OOCY141.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rRb8eA8.png" alt="'That's right! It's times like these when you should consult the ultimate authority on love: romance novels!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Want to Make Black-Knight Fall In Love With Me!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="OI Want to Make Black-Knight Fall In Love With Me!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 140</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/04/OOCY140.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 140" /><published>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/04/OOCY140</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/04/OOCY140.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2tHR7sl.png" alt="A butch wraps her arms around another girl'Aaaaya... san! Sorry for the wait...' and glares at two pickup artists, who recoil back. 'What...?! A hunk!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’d also melt and recoil if a butch looked at me like that, but not in the same way as those guys</p>

<p>source: The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn’t a Guy At All</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn&apos;t a Guy At All" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 21-26</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/04/LizstartrekVOY5-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 21-26" /><published>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/04/LizstartrekVOY5-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/05/04/LizstartrekVOY5-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KU4RpyL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>**Someone to Watch Over Me ** - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zg5Olxh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven is collecting research by staring at Torres and Paris. Torres asks her about it, and finds out she’s researching courting behavior. She reads the notes and is like “Why do you know when we’re having ‘intimate relations?’ Seven responds with ‘There is no one on deck seven who does not know when you are having intimate relations’ and almost gets her nose caved in.</p>

<p>Janeway suggests she just try to date instead. It’s maybe the gayest scene in Trek so far.</p>

<p>The Kadi are coming to visit! The Kadi are a species of conservative religious fundamentalists who lead an ascetic lifestyle. Their abbot dropps off one of them, a Kadi named Tomin. They have strict rules about what they can eat and do, but as soon as Tomin is alone he’s like “I’d like to try this spicy dish I heard about in your data files actually”. Yeah that makes sense.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iOHzNTG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Since the Doctor is Seven’s teacher in how to act like a person, he gives her dating lessons. At first it’s a little too narrow (she knows what sex is, doctor) to way too broad (Here’s a holographic guy, go flirt with him). It’s fun to see good actors try to be bad at things they’re good at. There’s no way Jeri Ryan wasn’t SWIMMING in dudes. Paris watches and comments that she’s a lost cause. Not that she couldn’t GET a date, half the crew apparently wants to jump her, but keeping a date is the hard part. The Doctor gets offended, and so they make a bet. Seven of Nine will show up to Tomin’s function with a date, and it will go WELL. I dunno about you, but I’m as into these stakes as all the ship blowy up ones.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OxS7KSn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Singing lessons! I dunno how this will get Seven laid, but the Doctor seems real into it. Real, REAL into it. He’s looking at her like… uh oh.</p>

<p>Kim got promoted from Person Seven Works With to friend! He offers her advice for some “candidates” she’s looking for for dating, based on her interests. “I didn’t know you had any interests.” “Neither did I, but apparently they include astronomy, physics, and music.” Funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CyXJdKA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We don’t have get to see Seven with her hair down very often, it’s nice.</p>

<p>She and this dude have a date. It’s a bit awkward, but certainly not TERRIBLE. They have a dance, and they’re both still awkward, but it gets better, until she gets a BIT too into it and tears a one of his ligiments, so he has to go home. Damn girl, how the hell did you pull that off? She laments that dating is a poor form of social interaction, it’s much better when it’s like it is with the doctor! When people just say what they mean. Did you know some people read Seven in an autism kinda way? No way, right? How strange.</p>

<p>Oh hey, remember Tomin? He’s fucking SMASHED on synthehol. Neelix didn’t even know you could DO that. He’s got holographic babes on each arm and is like “I’m thinking of leaving the convent and joining Voyager!!” Ohhh the alternate universe where they just kept picking up stragglers.</p>

<p>At Tomin’s party the next day, with Tomin still smashed beyond belief, Seven goes on a date with the Doctor. She’s doing well, and is almost the life of the party. Aaaand then Paris is like “well congrats doc, you won the wager” and she becomes, quite understandably, offended at the idea that the Doctor was just doing this for her for a bet. Which, yeah, fair.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NnlH5Rf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tomin is drunk as hell and super horny for Seven. He begs her to assimilate him. Get in line, dog.</p>

<p>The Doctor tries to smooth things over with Seven, and it seems to go alright, but he’s now coming to terms with the fact that he has in fact developed feelings for her. So now HE goes to PARIS for advice. Paris is like “Just tell her how you feel, duh.” “What if she doesn’t feel the same way back?” “Always the risk you gotta take.” So he does. He confesses, and theeen it turns out it was just a holodeck program. Understandable, gotta practice first. And then the real Seven comes in, and tells him that while she appreciates what he’s been doing, they no longer need these social lessons, as there are no potential mates on the ship for her to persue. The Doctor sadly plays Someone to Watch Over Me on piano as the episode ends. Poor Doctor.</p>

<p>Good episode, if a bit sad.</p>

<p><strong>11:59</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B9g40QH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I mis-saw this picture as Janeway with a rapier and got REALLY excited for a second</p>

<p>Neelix is infodumping about Earth to Janeway. Oh no he’s a Earthaboo. Apparently he’s been studying Earth and its many landmarks. Janeway asks him what he knows about the Millenium Gate (it’s some kind of self sufficient super building), and he lists the specifications of it, but she knows a bit more than that. Her ancestor is the person who built it, a woman named Shannon O’Donnel. And then it suddenly jumps to the past, the far off year of 2000, with Shannon O’Donnel. Wow, it’s a stealth Mrs. Columbo reboot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XvSKs4a.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s driving through Indiana and her car breaks down in the middle of nowhere. Every store in town is completely closed, except one, a book store run by a Henry Janeway and his son. He’s a curmodgeonly guy, a luddite, who’s making signs to stop The Millenium Gate. He calls it a “glorified shopping mall”, and that its forcing businesses to close. He’s kind of unlikable, I’m not gonna lie. She endears herself to them and and gets hired to help make the fliers and things, because he refuses to use computers. My dude, it’s 2000.</p>

<p>They try and push a romance between Shannon, who’s basically just Janeway but in the year 2000, and this dude who looks like Rick Berman’s self insert, and acts like him too. And then the theme of the episode appears to be how important ancestry and geneology is. The ONLY thing keeping me here is that I like Star Trek period pieces and seeing actors in cool outfits, but even here it’s just… normal-ass clothing.</p>

<p>Anyways turns out Shannon was a NASA engineer who got fired because it’s America and we don’t treat the people who actually do good jobs well. The guy who’s trying to build the Millenium Gate hits her up and offers her a job, if she helps him talk his dad down. Basically, he’s the last hold out, and if he doesn’t sell the shop by midnight, they’ll have to move the Millenium Gate, which is SUPPOSED to help the town a lot. Not that Alex Jones over here cares.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yaB7NAE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get into an argument about it, he’s as awful as he has been all episode. She later describes him as “listening to no one but himself” which is pretty accurate. And then we jump back to the future, where we’re talking more about family history and how important it is. But as she examines her history more and more, she starts to realize how malleable history is. Everything is biased by what people want to believe, so she’s digging through everything she can to learn more about Shannon, and she’s starting to realize that the family story of Shannon single handidly building the Millenium Gate and ushering Humanity into the future is pretty incorrect. She was just a consultant.</p>

<p>Shannon leaves the town, and then decides to come back and try one more time to convince him that he’s being a fucking idiot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xirah5M.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Why? WHY were you thinking about him? For the love of fucking GOD what do you see in this man? The fascist Janeway kissed from several episodes ago was more likable than this, because at least he PRETENDED to not be a piece of garbage. This is built on the romance, and the emotion of these two people but I can’t fucking stand him. His whole thing is “THIS IS MY SHOP I OWN AND I REFUSE TO MOVE IT” when they’re willing to help him move it, for free, into this new multiplex. Who the fuck gives a shit dude. This is like the “THIS IS OUR HOME” colonization episodes but way, WAY worse. Anyways he finally gives in at 11:59, and everyone lives happily ever after.</p>

<p>In the future Janeway is still disollutioned with everything, thinking Shannon not all that important in the grand scheme of things. But her crewmates convince her that it’s actually important, so okay, it’s important. There’s some stuff about “it’s not what she actually did, it’s her inspiration that rippled through time to you that’s important”, which I think is okay, that’s fine.</p>

<p>Over all though I really hated this. I didn’t really like any of its themes or think they were good, and then at its crux its a romance love story that is so, so, SO unpleasant. It’s not trash, but prolly my personal least favorite episode of Voyager so far, holy hell.</p>

<p><strong>Relativity</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JAGIXIX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Voyager being built in Utopia Planitia, and Janeway boarding it for the first time. Oh look at this crew, all bright eyed and bushy tailed, I can’t wait for them all to be alive. We see her walking around getting a tour from an admiral, and we see…. why, who’s that?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rwSzSzW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven of Nine is here in the past! She looks SO uncomfortable and unhappy to be here. She’s trying to find a “weapon” of some kind, and keeps calling in about how she has yet to find it, but keeps getting interrupted by y’know, the ship being a ship where people talk and exist on it. She finds the weapon, but can’t teleport it out, because it’s out of flux. Janeway catches wind of something happening in that space so she goes to explore, and whoever Seven is working with teleports her out, at risk of it possibly harming her. And it does, she dies in transport. Janeway also catches some chroniton readings, but that’s it.</p>

<p>The Captain of the Timeship is a man by the name of Braxton. Sound familiar? Maybe they’ll bring it up later. Anyways Braxton orders them to get a new one. We jump back to Voyager. Pretty chill day. Seven has hypochondria. There’s some cases of space sickness. Paris convinces Seven to join them for a ping pong tournament. Things get worse, as they find out it’s being caused by temporal distortions. They’re causing sickness, food spoilage, overall confusion as people call for help 7 minutes earlier than they need it. Oh also it’s starting to demolecularize the hull, that sounds bad. As the time cops show up, she catches wind of those same readings again. Janeway calls for an abandon ship, but it’s too late, as the ship explodes, just as Seven is teleported to the future.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zE9PukF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Braxton explains that someone at some point put a weapon on Voyager, and they need Seven to find it because she can actually determine temporal distortions with her ocular implants. Braxton also tells her to be careful of Janeway. She’s a loose cannon and cannot be trusted. She left him STRANDED in the past once, after he asked for her help! Yes, do you remember that? Braxton is, in fact, the guy who was FUCKING GOD AWFUL at time travel. He was the dude who almost killed Voyager for no reason, and then got stranded in the past, and became a hobo rambling about being from the future. The absolute fucking worst. His CO talks about how much he trusts his captain, but I have no fucking idea why.</p>

<p>They think the weapon might be planted during a battle with the Kazon, and they beam her in. Of course when Janeway senses the readings, she IMMEDIATELY goes hellbent on finding out what the fuck it is. They capture Seven, and Braxton in the future is like “GOD do not tell her anything” and of course Seven spills EVERYTHING.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KU4RpyL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They have a heart to heart. It’s Gay. They hunt down the ACTUAL sabateur and find out… it’s Braxton!! He’s suffering from temporal psychosis. He’s here to blow up Voyager because it destroyed his life. So, Temporal Psychosis is a thing that happens if they teleport you through time too much, you start to go a bit loony. Future Braxton is arrested for crimes he will commit, as futurer Braxton teleports away to another time, and Seven chases. She’s suffering from psychosis too, and after yet ANOTHER jump, she manages to destroy Braxton’s teleporter, before collapsing and asking Seven to help her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7jOsAg7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They eventually get him, but need someone to fix the timeline after its been contaminated so heavily. So they snatch Janeway and send her back to get Braxton at the start before this all even happened. Braxton’s CO explains after its all done that he’ll be reintigrated in tiem for the court date, as will they. There will only be one Seven running around. Aww, I was hoping there’s be a Future Seven for the fans and books to geek about. He also begs them to stop time traveling so much.</p>

<p>This was a really fun episode. I love goofy time travel.</p>

<p><strong>Warhead</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sCDEgJv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Harry Kim is on night duty, and is sitting in the captain’s chair. He gets to be in the CAPTAINS CHAIR but he won’t be promoted past Ensign? Poor Kim. They get a distress call, and Kim orders they head towards it. He wakes Chakotay up, who puts him on away mission duty to find the distress call. He goes down with a no name and the Doctor, and they find a weird metal tube who speaks in what Neli says is an old TOS robot speech. Only the Doctor can communicate with it, though it seems to be able to understand English. It asks why it can’t feel its arms and legs, and begs for help. It apparently does not realize it’s an AI.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N1O0X3c.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is an ensign on the bridge who we see a bit but doesn’t seem to be a major plot point. She’s very cute, I wonder if she’s single. ALSO, Chokie has barely been in any of these episodes. He shows up, people bounce jokes off him, and he stands there and looks pretty. Good use of your Chakotay.</p>

<p>They beam the thing back onto Voyager to find out what it is, and cause the Doctor wants to help it. He becomes very attached to this thing. He explains to it that it’s an AI, and tries to befriend it. They then discover what it is. A nuclear bomb, basically. A smart bomb. They need to get rid of it before it blows up. The Doctor begs them to just operate on it, put it in the holo emitters instead, and deactivate the bomb. They do, but then everything goes to shit. It gets angry at what they’re doing, and takes over the Doctor, angry that they were trying to dismantle it. It remembers who it is now, and its mission. Its mission is to fucking kill people, and it demands Voyager ferry it to its target so it can blow it up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hRpc8xB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get Evil Doctor. Remember Evil Bashir from season 1 DS9? This is so much better. He’s willing to blow up if they stop him, and demands they help him. Kim and Torres are held hostage. Kim TRIES to talk it down, appeal to its better nature, but it doesn’t seem to work. It’s angry like, all the time.</p>

<p>A merchant they’ve worked with shows up, and offers to help. He’s like a smarmy used car salesman. Apparently the bomb was made by the Druoda, and he could sell it for a pretty penny. They’re uncomfortable with the ethics of it though and ask him to leave. His ship opens fire, but then the bomb sends an antimatter wave through the teleporter stream, a thing it can do I guess, and blows it the fuck up.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, other warheads lock onto Voyager and beam through space towards it. That’s prolly not good.</p>

<p>The bomb asks them to help it find out why its memory was jumbled, and they find evidence that the war is actually over, and HAS been for three years, and the bomb was recalled. It’s Very, VERY unhappy about this, because it’s so hellbent on doing what it was made to do, which is blow up these people. It refuses to learn any more about this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NCLs8Pe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>An attempt to stop him fails, just as more bombs show up, willing to tow him to his destination. But they manage to convince him to put his memory back in, aaaand yes, the war IS over. When he tries to convince the other bombs to stop, they’re like “lol no”. There’s some really good flexing with Kim and the Doctor here. I also like the parallels, with Kim like “you’re just regurgitating what you were told to think!” while earlier on, and for a lot of his character, he’s been regurgitating what he was told to think by higher ups and been afraid to think for himself.</p>

<p>The bomb sacrifices itself to blow up the other bombs. Superman. Neli called that this would be an Iron Giant situation, and it sure is. Before the bomb goes, it tries to tell them not to mourn it. Its still saving lives by being a weapon. It’s just that its target changed. Kim thanks for the Doctor for teaching him that AI can become more than its programming, and we see the cute ensign one more time, and then it ends. Good episode, very Trek.</p>

<p><strong>Equinox</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UfUUjOl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start by seeing a Starfleet vessel being attacked by Slimers. It’s brutal. They send out an SOS, whiiiich Voyager picks up! They chase after it and go to help. They get there, and the Equinox begs them to extend shields. They do, saving the ship, but no one responds to hails any longer, so they beam over to try and find survivors.</p>

<p>I’m a little surprised they’re so willing to jump into this ship considering I think things have pretended to be Starfleet out here… twice? For a trick? But I mean, any chance of finding others like they. And they do. There are life signs on board. They find a terrified ensign who’s like “But we’re the only Humans in the Delta Quadrant?” They find another who is kind of… numb to everything, and trapped under debris. He claims to have been there for two days. They find a third one who freaks out and thinks he’s under attack so they knock him out and beam him over. And finally, they find the captain on the Bridge. He says he was brought here the Caretaker. Well, turns out they weren’t the only ones then, huh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TGm3S2w.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They welcome them all on Voyager, and try to help fix up the ship, while also figuring out what’s up with these aliens that are trying to kill them, some dimensional travelers. Half of the crew is suffering from PTSD. That girl they found refuses to go in elevators cause there’s nowhere to run in there, so she travels through jefferies tubes.</p>

<p>Their CO, Maxwell, makes some suggestions on how to capture the dimensional aliens. Build a net. They built a thing that brought them into our reality for several minutes. Oh my fucking god what the hell did you do to these aliens???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/90gNRTt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s pretty clear how this is going to go. Captain Ransom and his CO Max are whispering about not letting these bright eyed and bushy tailed lucky fuckers know what happened. Ransom and Janeway butt heads a bit, not sure who has authority, and Janeway explains that based on protocol, it’s her. But Ransom is like “Hmmmm, do those protocols even matter here in the Delta Quadrant?” Uh, yes, dude. Yes they do. Anyways there’s basically four Equinox members we need to care about. Ransom, his CO Max, the claustrophobic ensign, and the chill engineer Seven saved.</p>

<p>The Equinox crew plans to steal something from Voyager and return to Equinox, because they’re “going home”. Okay y’all. Meanwhile, Janeway assumes the worst. She’s sensing the Sus energy wafting off all of them, and determines that they intentionally made their science facility impossible to enter with radiation. So they just send the Doctor in instead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1wZyiQi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor finds some alien corpses. They’re turning the aliens into fuel. It was pretty clear what was going on, but damn, dog. That’s dark. Janeway confronts them, and we learn that in Equinox’s darkest day, they were saved by some aliens who blessed their travel by invoking spirits. These spirits were some nucleogenic lifeforms. They tried to study them, killed one by accident, and then realized what they could do. Janeway is diiisguuuusted, and relieves him of duty, and confines them all to quarters. They DO get the claustrophobic ensign to help them, cause she genuinely regrets ever having done any of this. But she just couldn’t ignore a command from her captain!</p>

<p>The Doctor activates the other EMH. Unfortunately, they deleted his ethical subroutines, so he takes out the Doctor. That’s not good. He infiltrates Voyager and goes to rescue Ransom. OH and the Clasutrophobic ensign is still working with them. Captains orders :).</p>

<p>They manage to get away, with Seven still on board, as the aliens attack. One charges at Janeway….</p>

<p>TO BE CONTINUED. Of course. You better watch out, Ransom. You stole Seven. Janeway hunted down the fucking BORG QUEEN for her, you ain’t shit.</p>

<p>This was very, very interesting, and I liked it a lot. I love the concept. I once was gonna do a Star Trek tabletop thing and suggested making a ship and thrusting them into what Voyager went through and seeing how they’d handle it. This is that. It’s nice to see as a mirror, and what could happen. But also what could happen if the people were weaker, weren’t giving it their all. Ransom kept talking about how Voyager was soft, how they didn’t go through what he did. Dog, it wasn’t called The Year Of Pretty Alright. And you follow that up by talking about how after a shitty time you met some friendly aliens who gave you food? Dude.</p>

<p>He’s awful, but refuses to accept it. He’s not even “what Janeway could be if she gave up her morals”, because she wouldn’t. She would never stoop to that level, because she’s who she is. He’s who he is. And he was not built for this, at all.</p>

<p>It’s also really fun to look into cause like, so, a lot of people hate Janeway and are like “WHY DIDN’T SHE JUST DO THIS AND THIS AND THIS TO GET BACK FASTER, JUST GIVE UP YOUR MORALS, YOU’RE IN THE DELTA QUADRANT NOW, WHO CARES”. Did they watch this episode? Are there “Captain Ransom Did Nothing Wrong” apologists out there? Can I hate them, because I already do.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 172 - Pooyan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/02/RA172-Pooyan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 172 - Pooyan" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/02/RA172-Pooyan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/02/RA172-Pooyan.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wTP2VKz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Alright, this is much more my speed than the previous two Apple games. This is Pooyan, a very classic arcade game by Konami from the early 80s. We’ve actually got quite a few arcade ports on the Apple II. Name a game from that era, they prolly tried to make a port of it. Keyword being try.</p>

<p>Most arcade ports to the Apple II do NOT work, in my opinion. The hardware is just so limited that movement and control is stilted, awkward, and stiff. For fast paced action games, it feels AWFUL. I’m talkin’ things like Dig Dug, Mario Bros, Pac-Man, even arcade inspired games that require fast twitch movement, absolutely horrendous. But Pooyah is prolly the best of these I’ve played.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/54q1IM0.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Pooyan, you play as a mama pig trying to protect her kids from a straight up horde of hungry wolves. They come equipped with balloons, and are trying to get down to the bottom, or up to the top of a tree, depending on the round. You move up and down on an elevator, and are trying to shoot them down with a bow and arrow. Occasionally you can grab some meat, which allows your shots to kill instantly and pierce. You need to hit the wolve’s balloons, and not them, so it takes some tricky precise aiming, though you get plenty of chances, cause they need like 4 or more wolves to get through to win, and you can usually spam a bit.</p>

<p>The thing that makes Pooyan on Apple II better than its contemporaries is that you’re really only controlling up and down. It gets stuck and awkward sometimes, but it’s SO much better than anything else I’ve tried to play. And again, you can spam a lot, which helps. To get FAR and survive, you need to be precise, but you can get by with a little luck and spam.</p>

<p>In the arcades, Pooyan is a tricky but great forgotten gem. Here, it’s just a pretty okay port. I’d certainly NOT recommend this version, but it’s doing its best, and I respect it for that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Pooyan" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alright, this is much more my speed than the previous two Apple games. This is Pooyan, a very classic arcade game by Konami from the early 80s. We’ve actually got quite a few arcade ports on the Apple II. Name a game from that era, they prolly tried to make a port of it. Keyword being try.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 172 - Mind Castle I</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/02/RA173-MindCastle.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 172 - Mind Castle I" /><published>2025-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/02/RA173-MindCastle</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/05/02/RA173-MindCastle.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0KxyqMZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mind Castle is a 1984 text adventure by MCE where you’re exploring an abandoned mansion, which is said to contain treasures. As you enter, you are accosted by some kind of spirit that challenges you to a game. Solve his puzzles, and you can reach the top of the mansion and gain the treasure.</p>

<p>Along the way, you’ll explore the rooms in typical text adventure fashion, typing east, west, etc. Every room you enter has a new puzzle, usually based on that room you’re in, and you can ask for that room’s puzzle. Your host then gives you a puzzle, and it’s usually logic puzzles. And its USUALLY logic puzzles that are trying to troll you.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iFqUKLE.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Here’s an example. This puzzle says a Zebra is on its way to the river, and sees a bunch of other animals. How many animals in all were going to the river? Well, one. There’s a LOT of puzzles like that. Over all, the puzzles are trolly, but not bad. There were a few that stumped me, but not for too long. This IS a kid’s game, after all. There’s also nothing here that’ll make you scratch your head for hours. In terms of Text Adventures, this is one of the easiest. There’s no like, over arching puzzles, everything is held to each room, and you just need to solve all the puzzles to climb the stairs to the next floor.</p>

<p>While this game won’t sit with me forever, for what it is, it’s quite enjoyable. I also love the ugly Apple II art, as I always do. Look at that fucking Giraffe.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Mind Castle" /><category term="Text Adventures" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mind Castle is a 1984 text adventure by MCE where you’re exploring an abandoned mansion, which is said to contain treasures. As you enter, you are accosted by some kind of spirit that challenges you to a game. Solve his puzzles, and you can reach the top of the mansion and gain the treasure.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 139</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/01/OOCY139.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 139" /><published>2025-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/01/OOCY139</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/05/01/OOCY139.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VMdjMP8.png" alt="'What could have happened? She let out a sigh.' 'Perhaps there is something worrying her. She IS the only daughter of the Saionji family after all. She has many worries that we would not understand.' 'Ahh...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0GXRwt4.png" alt="Girl looking sad and forelorn at her lot in life. 'I want to eat a hand-made bento.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Ojou-sama wa Love Come no Shujinkou ni Naritai!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Ojou-sama wa Love Come no Shujinkou ni Naritai!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 15-20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/27/LizstartrekVOY5-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 5 episodes 15-20" /><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/27/LizstartrekVOY5-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/04/27/LizstartrekVOY5-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BtG8a04.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>The Disease</strong> - VOY
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XqpFEBS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Kim getting laid. Considering this episode is called The Disease and we see Kim getting laid with some alien, I’m real worried. Is this going to be the STD episode? On today’s Very Special episode, Janeway teaches Kim what a condom is.</p>

<p>Anyways it turns out the aliens of the week are some people Voyager are working with. They’re helping fix and improve their engines, in exchange for information and knowledge. These aliens are xenophobic and have been on this generational ship for… well, generations. They’ve been mistreated by aliens here, so try to avoid contact, but Voyager is xenophilic, and you know how extroverts are with introverts. This ALSO means that Kim fucking one of them is massively not allowed. It’s ALSO unfortunate for Kim because he is so, so, SO bad at lying.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JPhhemN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This gets out of hand when he’s showing some signs of a medical issue. He has to admit that he did, in fact, have sex with that woman. The Doctor is like “I’m sorry, I have to alert the captain about this”, who is livid. Apparently, it’s a rule that “before having sexual relations with any alien species, you need permission from your captain and medical officer”. This is nuts. Literally, but also this is wild. Are you telling me Riker got permission from Dr. Crusher all the time about fucking all those aliens he absolutely fucked? Or Kirk going to Bones like “Hey I’mma get some green pussy you okay with that”? Maybe they mean like, unknown aliens? Which y’know, fair, but also it feels so weird and gross you’d need permission for that, I dunno. Anyways, Kim gets reprimanded. Is THIS the reason he never gets a promotion? Cause he had sex once?</p>

<p>I do like how Janeway almost literally goes “I get why you did it, she’s really hot”. Not jumping the allegations there, Janeway. She’s being really harsh and bad about this though, and Chakotay asks her about why, and she’s like “He’s just an ensign, he hasn’t earned the right to try and push against my rules”. DUDE. HE’S YOUR OPS OFFICER. HE’S A SENIOR OFFICER.</p>

<p>There’s also talk of a disease that happens when people fuck. It fades as you stay away from them, but the more you’re with them, the more it grows. It’s love, they’re talking about love. That’s cheesy.</p>

<p>Also also, there’s some stuff about sabotage, some parasites that are causing hull fractured, caused by a faction on the alien ship that wants to break away from the authoritarian regime in control.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nalZXHm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kim and this girl, Tal, are actually kinda cute together? But obviously it’s not to be. They have different values, and those values come to a head when Tal is called in for questioning. They believe she’s in charge of setting up these parasites, and she comes clean. The parasites will cause the ship to break apart and become multiple ships. Dunno how THAT works but okay. Janeway also gets REALLY pissy about Kim disobeying orders, mostly out of a pissy “NO I’M IN CHARGE” kinda energy that I hate and don’t agree with, but I’m not exactly military now am I?</p>

<p>Voyager ends up almost risking its life to protect the Varro ship, and the dissidents go their seperate ways. Instead of trying to solve the virus problem they just don’t. Well that was easily solved. I guess. Janeway even lets Kim see his girlfriend one last time. Damn, aren’t you lucky that mom is letting you out of your grounding, Kim? Even after this, the episode goes on for like 7 more minutes because they really needed to drive home the fact that love bites, love bleeds, it’s bringin’ me to my knees.</p>

<p>This episode was mostly boring and annoying to me.</p>

<p><strong>Course: Oblivion</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/llxSAjT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Torres and Paris getting married! That might seem kinda sudden, and everyone agrees. Seven of Nine outright says she expected homicide before marriage, but hey, it works. It’s a cute scene. Also huh, Paris is lieutenant again! That’s interesting. I guess they just forgot to mention him getting re-promoted :). Everyone throws rice at them as they leave the room, which then sinks through the floor as it distorts and falls and bounces through the ship. That’s weird.</p>

<p>Everyone is going well on the ship! They’ve developed some new engine which shows that they’ll make it home in only two years. That’s great, what good news. Torres and Paris are going to go on honeymoon, which leaves Seven to be in charge of the new warp drive.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BtG8a04.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven confirmed for polyamory. Also, based based based.</p>

<p>They find that weird wibbly wobblyness in the jerrytube from the start. Turns out it’s some molecular unstableness from the warp drive, but even after they shut it down, it’s still happening. And then it hits the crew as well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xGCgFG6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They have a theory. Anything brought on board the ship within the past few weeks is not deteriorating, so it was something that happened to the ship within the past few months. They go back through their data logs to try and find out wtf the cause could be, citing a bunch of episodes we never saw. Of all the ones they go through though, there is one that we’ve seen. The episode with the Silver Blood.</p>

<p>Torres ends up dying. Paris does NOT take it well. Wow I can’t believe they killed off Torres. No, obviously. Chokie and Tuvok burst in and explain. They are not actually Voyager, they’re all copies. And something is causing them to disintigrate. Possibly the core, no one knows.</p>

<p>Janeway announces to the crew they’re all copies, but tells them that what matters if who they ARE, not where they ACTUALLY came from. Their memories, they’re thoughts, their beliefs. And they have an important goal that they have to stick to. Getting home. It’s causing the crew to fracture a bit. Paris is like “none of this is real or matters so it’s fine”, becoming kind of dead to the world. Chakotay BEGS Janeway to go home. Not to Earth, but to THEIR home, the Hell Planet. They find a nearby class Y hell planet, hoping that it’ll be enough. Unfortunately, that planet has some mining treaty which doesn’t allow people to go on it, so they open fire. They COULD blow up these people and kill them, but despite everything, they’re still Starfleet. They won’t kill people over a misunderstanding.</p>

<p>Chakotay dies, and Janeway hits a bit of a despair wall. They have no other choice. They bring the warp drive back online, and head back to the Demon Planet.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CN7FvC9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get a bit of a time jump. We’re in Lather That Shit On Me mode. Most of the senior crew has died. Neelix is now senior medical officer. “Morale is a luxury”. Janeway announces that they should make a time capsule, because they might not be able to survive, but none of them, or what they did, should be forgotten. Unfortunately, Janeway dies shortly afterwards. Things are not looking good.</p>

<p>KIM FINALLY GETS A PROMOTION. GOOP KIM IS CAPTAIN FOR A FEW DAYS. CONGRATS TO GOOP KIM. Kim can LITERALLY only get promoted if every other person dies first.</p>

<p>Neli described this episode as “like year of hell for for goo”. The Year of Gell.</p>

<p>The time capsule they make gets destroyed because of malfunctioning controls. But they have ONE last hope. They see a ship nearby. They have to drop out of warp and try to get its help. Unfortunately, ejecting the warp core causes the ship to tear itself apart, and everyone dies. No time capsule, nothing. Their history, everything they were, everything they did, forgotten. Might as well not have happened.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a32R54G.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile on Voyager, they’re chasing after a distress call. They arrive at the last known coordinates and find a bunch of weird debris floating through space. Cause unknown, no survivors. They make a small note in the ships log and move on.</p>

<p>This feels less Star Trek and more Twilight Zone tbh. It was very entertaining, at least!</p>

<p><strong>The Fight</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QbCO2z4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Chokie thrashing about in med bay screaming about voices in their head. Apparently he’s “ambassador” for some aliens they’re trying to contact? Torres says they’re in “chaotic space” but they’ll be in danger if they stay in it for much longer. Fascinating. The Doctor explains a bit better after the cold open. They are stuck in this space, and they need to get out. Chakotay is their only chance of getting out, communicating with the aliens who live here.</p>

<p>We get a jump back in time. Chokie was in a holodeck simulation, with Boothby as his guide through a boxing match. Boothy explains that boxing is not about trying to fight the other person, it’s about fighting the human urge to not get hurt. Interesting. Anyways Chokie sees a weird-ass fractal nightmare behind his opponent and gets the daylights knocked out of him. He explains this as the doctor sutures him up and makes fun of boxing as a concept, and then they get dragged into a weird ass goopy space nightmare.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PP2URcc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven explains they are in Chaotic Space. It’s a very dangerous space that jumps in and out of existence. Only one Borg Sphere has ever survived its encounter with Chaotic Space, which isn’t good odds. As they explore and try to find a way out, Chakotay starts hearing voices. They’re all based on boxing. After being sent to medbay, they find out Chakotay has a family gene that causes hallucination and insanity. He has the gene suppressed after his granddad went mad. Apparently Fluidic space might be causing it to come back.</p>

<p>Chakotay’s plan is to go into a vision quest. God fucking dammit can they not think of things to do with Chakotay other than getting him laid, or getting him to go on a vision quest???</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4mFetKa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Akoo-chee-moya, we are far from the bullshit of our fake native advisor. Oh wait no, We’re very close to it.</p>

<p>We get a lot of nonsensical fuzzy scene that are really hard to focus on or follow, because it’s SUPPOSED to be like that, where Chakotay is a pugilist running around Voyager, with Voyager stuff mixed up with pugilism. There’s also lots of stuff about his grandfather, talking about “them”, about how they’re so loud and talkative, but not so bad once you get used to them.</p>

<p>Eventually the Doctor drags him out of the hallucination, but he’s still like, half stuck in it. He claims that he needs to go back in the ring, he can “take them”, but also “Captain, when have we strayed away from first  contact”, “they’re about to ring the bell, I need to be there to meet the people who live here”. Kinda interesting. Janeway lets him go back into the hallucination fully.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TRRDXgq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He communicates with the aliens, who communicate through what I can only describe as “the prophets, but they communicate using clips of previous Voyager characters talking”. Chakotay is afraid to fully commit to communication, because they need to realign his mind and he’s afraid of losing himself completely to insanity, but he does to save the others. As the doctor says, even if he does go, he’ll be with friends. Which y’know, sacrifice for friends kinda thing. The aliens tell him out to get out, and he rushes to the bridge and gets them out of chaotic space just before they start to fall apart. The episode ends with Chakotay totally fine, and going back in to the holodeck for more boxing.</p>

<p>Eh. Parts of it were interesting I guess, but I kinda feel like I’m gonna forget this episode after tonight, and it kinda didn’t finish itself properly.</p>

<p><strong>Think Tank</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZgmEBu7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with an alien coming aboard a ship to meet a “Kurros”. Then George Costanza comes out and explains how happy he was that they could help. Apparently this guy’s planet was suffering debilitaing earthquakes. Unfortunately, the last quakes caused their payment to be buried under tons of rock…. or was it? George already accounted for this, and knows that they actually are hiding the payment. This alien’s people needs it for their replicators, to keep them fed, but if Costanza doesn’t get paid, he’ll just blow up their planet, causing the quakes to start again :) Hey, it’s only fair, they DID offer to pay him it in the first place! Oh, George.</p>

<p>Back on Voyager, Janeway is playing with what is essentially a Space Rubix Cube. She’s called out as they go to mine a planet of some minerals they need. As they approach, however, the planet fucking explodes, covering them in an explosive gas cloud as a Hazari ship comes to meet them. Seven explains what the Hazari are: They are basically bounty hunters with a work ethic. They were hired to get Voyager, and that’s what they’re going to do. Voyager barely escapes, but the Hazari are good at this. They’ve laid other traps. How do they know what is an escape route, and what’s a trap? Good thing GEORGE COSTANZA IS HERE TO HELP!</p>

<p>George uses a projection to put himself in Janeway’s room, and explains who he is. He’s Korros (I’mma keep calling him George), of a small group of aliens who study problems and help people solve them. Janeway calls them a Think Tank, which George likes. He offers to help them escape the Hazari. Okay, calling it now, George Costanza hired the Hazari. He’s making problems for people so that they’ll hire him to solve them. Which, tbh, is a VERY George Costanza thing to do. Very accurate.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m38JFUV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Holy SHIT Seven and Janeway are going on an aquarium date. This too is Yuri.</p>

<p>They meet all the members of the Think Tank, who SEEM pleasant enough. They HAVE done stuff with wars and stuff, but mostly they just try to help people, do not create weapons of mass destruction, and do not decimate populations. They find things for people, solve ecological problems, stuff like that. They RECENTLY cured the Vidiians of the Phage! Remember the Vidiians? You’d hardly recognize them now! Not that they will ever be seen again.</p>

<p>They give Janeway their price for helping them out. A recipe for soup, information on slipstream, an Olmec statue Chakotay owns (of COURSE he’s the one who own it), aaaaand also Seven of Nine. Ah.</p>

<p>So, not like, as a slave or something. They’re not BARTERING for Seven. They appreciate her and want her to join them as a member of the Think Tank. And Janeway is clearly disturbed by the idea, but it’s ultimately Seven’s idea, and she won’t stop her. Seven considers it. She wants to know more.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QTmX26Y.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But quickly decides she doesn’t really appreciate the way they live their life. Seven is like “How many people have suffered because they could not pay you?” Damn, Seven, I’d think you’d think that irrelevant, but you’ve got some good ethics on you. She rejects their offer, and George Costanza has some… unhappy energy about this. After another attack by the Hazari, they capture some and scan their computers to find who hired them. It was a Malon! But that makes no sense, the Malon are capitalists, there’s no profit in revenge. So they do some digging and yeah, it’s George.</p>

<p>Now the Hazari and Voyager have a common enemy. The Think Tank are infamous, and have a lot of enemies who’d want to capture them for a good bounty. There’s a good scene where try to outthink the think tank and it doesn’t work. Janeway is still fiddling with the Rubix Cube, and then gets sick of it and gives it to Seven. She solves it instantly. How? She scanned it. “That’s cheating!” “Cheating is efficient.”</p>

<p>THey learn from that. It’s time to cheat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KI6Q2Cx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Think Tank finds the Hazari attacking Voyager, who announces that they have Voyager but are upping the bounty 3x. George agrees to pay, and then Seven escapes Voyager to get to the Think Tank and offer herself to save Voyager. THey get her, but suspect a trap, so connect her to their telepathy thing to read her mind and determine Janeway’s plan. Aaaand the trap is sprung. They send a wave through the telepathy thing, disrupting it, and making it so none of the Think Tank can communicate with each other. The Hazari attack, Seven beams out, and Janeway gets in one last sass at the Think Tank before they leave them behind to their fate. Damn, cold.</p>

<p>This was an enjoyable one. Not great, just good.</p>

<p><em>**</em> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DSbHIfN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with a Malon ship having some problems. Their tanks are rupturing, and they need to eject them. The system they’re in is inhabited, but they have no choice. They send some people down to the tanks to try and force the ejection, sending them to die. Ahhh, it’s VERY Druuj.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Tuvok has been assigned to teach Belanna how to meditate. I dunno if that’s a good way to go about this??? I dunno if that’s even POSSIBLE? Also, they’ve written her so well recently. Now they’re intentionally writing her worse again, like she’s had no character progression, to make a point in this episode. It’s Flanderization, they’re Flanderizing her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YF9iiaL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find the Malon freighter, and the escape pods. Only two Malon have survived. They’re the most pleasant Malon we’ve ever met, but they don’t really want to go back, they’re ready to leave at any moment.Not that they really have anywhere to go, the ship is going to explode soon, and they can’t get away fast enough, apparently. Dunno how THAT works but sure. So they need to go onto the freighter and shut it down from inside. We’ve got our team. It’s Neelix, Belanna, and Chokey, and the two Malon, Fesek the leader, and Pelk, a young crewmember.</p>

<p>We learn more about the Malon. Fesek is a sculptor half the year. The other half he transports waste that will probably half his life span, and why? To keep his planet safe and tidy, to rid it of toxic waste. Sure that toxic waste goes elsewhere, but he does EVERYTHING he can to keep it safe, and make sure it gets to unpopulated areas. It’s just, y’know, things go wrong. Like this time. Torres thinks it’s disgusting. Yeah, I mean, we know they COULD clean it up and go green, but that removes profit.</p>

<p>Pelk is attacked by something. There are rumors of Theta wave creatures who live in the radiation. Pelk dies as he rambles about monsters. Hallucinations ARE a side effect of theta radiation. Was it real… or fake???</p>

<p>This episode is kinda cool and good, except for Belanna being overly belligerent to try and get her towards character development she’s already been through. She’s dying from theta radiation and is like “I REFUSE TREATMENT RAWR BRAGA BRAGA”</p>

<p>They detect an alien lifeform that’s cloaked by theta radiation, and detect its near them, and trying to stop them at every opportunity. It almost kills Chakotay, who’s beamed away safe, but hurt.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tOG3jo9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s a big fight in foggy smoke. It’s kinda hard to see anything. Belanna is sweaty, damaged, and hot in her tank top. She rips a pipe out and fight this guy in the smoke. He’s a horribly irratidated Malon. He was irradiated and left for dead, and now wants to kill everyone and hurt them for what they did to him. Destroy EVERYTHING, even innocents. So now Belanna has to talk him down, bringing it back to uh, her having a temper. I don’t think it’s super well handled. She fights him back when that fails, and they drive the thing into the sun.</p>

<p>Fesek is probably going to die young, due to his radiation poisoning. Occupational hazard. Everyone else gets out fine. We end with Belanna naked and sexy in a sonic shower as she has PTSD flashbacks of her attacking the irradiated guy.</p>

<p>I liked all the actiony stuff and solving the problem of the week, but it lost it trying to do a moral, and trying to give it a point. It’s okay if it’s not teaching anything and is just about solving a problem.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 171 - Frog Jump - Ordering Numbers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/24/RA171-Frog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 171 - Frog Jump - Ordering Numbers" /><published>2025-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/24/RA171-Frog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/24/RA171-Frog.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/E5StrMJ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If I thought the last game was a failure as education AND entertainment, this goes beyond that.</p>

<p>This is a game made by like one dude and published by Mindscape in 1985. It is MASSIVELY simple. You choose a difficulty, and then one or two players. Then, the game gives you a simple math problem. Depending on how fast you answer it, you hop around a board. Whoever reaches the end first wins.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AHr5BPh.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Even for a game for kindergarteners learning basic addition, I just don’t think there’s anything here. The colors and art are drab, the sounds are not good, the concept is boring and uninteresting. I’m sorry, this is one of the least games I’ve reviewed so far. It sure did count towards the event I’m doing on RA, though!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Apple" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Edutainment" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If I thought the last game was a failure as education AND entertainment, this goes beyond that.]]></summary></entry></feed>