<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-18T10:39:26-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 112</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 112" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cgmpP2V.png" alt="'So this is a date...' The other girl stares in confusion. 'Yes?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Voice First, Face Second, Hollyhock</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Voice First" /><category term="Face Second" /><category term="Hollyhock" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 11 - 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/16/LizstartrekVOY4-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 11 - 15" /><published>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/16/LizstartrekVOY4-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/16/LizstartrekVOY4-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KIXeBlw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Concerning Flight</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/S0bixIF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Janeway in the Leonardo Davinci holodeck again. He’s testing a flying machine, and they both test it, jumping off ab ridge, right into some water. She KNEW that machine would not work, but she jumped off the bridge anyway. Janeway’s here for a good time.</p>

<p>Anyways they’re suddenly attacked by some aliens who basically mug them, transporting stuff through their shields (don’t ask questions) and then running the hell away. They steal a bunch of things, including the main computer, and now Voyager has to limp along. THey manage to track the stuff down to a commerce planet, where it’s being sold off and whatnot. And then, as they’re investigating, they meet…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8X9D0Q2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>GIMLI! Look, if you get John Reese Davies, you use him for all he’s worth. It’s Davinci! He’s been downloaded into the Doctor’s emitter, and is walking around this planet. He’s very entertaining, and is also seeing things through his limited holonovel’s programming, so he thinks its America. The working title for this episode was “Davinci’s Day Out” which is very funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y00tcLD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We also find who did the stealing. His name is Tau, and he’s a consumate businessman. He’s totally willing to sell the computer back actually, all it would take is a small price. Like, a warship, maybe? Yeah there’s no way they’re affording this, it’s too valuable. Tuvok goes back to the ship while Janeway stays behind with Davinci to try and learn more, but once Tau learns who she is, he holds her captive, cause ooh, imagine the money he can make holding her hostage! Aaaand then davinci slams a tank into his head and knocks him out cold. Let’s fuckin’ go.</p>

<p>This is taxing and straining Davinci, who was NOT built for this. He gets shot and starts having an existential crisis, but Janeway plays to him well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bZxQVJX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Yes but not how you’re thinking.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oWBSqSQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They escape in a contraption Davinci’s been working on… a flying apparatus, based on things Janeway suggested to him. It’s actually a touching moment. They’re teleported out of the air and rescued, as Voyager makes its escape. This was just a cute episode.</p>

<p><strong>Mortal Coil</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EKRBa60.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got a Neelix episode! Neelix is being Ship Dad, helping take care of everyone, it’s actually super sweet. He helps the only kid on the ship (who’s suddenly like 8 years old don’t worry about it) get to sleep by telling her stories about his faith. His people believe in The Great Forest, a wonderful afterlife. He’s such a sweetheart, I don’t get why ANYONE wouldn’t like him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Pr3v7xy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyway, Neelix is killed abruptly in an away mission to collect Protoplasm, which I guess is the prototype of plasm. I can’t believe they killed off Neelix like that. Well, all that making us like him stuff at the start is just there to make us realize what we lost, huh?</p>

<p>No obviously, Neelix isn’t DEAD dead. Well, he is. He is very dead. He’s been dead for 18 hours by the time they get him back, cold and gone. But according to Seven, the Borg have techniques that could work, as late as 78 hours after death. Hot damn, I’m sure that’ll be super useful in the future! Oh nevermind.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7YLepdY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix is still his chipper friendly self… or so it seems. He’s still a sweetheart, and wants to do what he can to help out, though everyone is a bit worried about him, obviously. He volunteers to help Chokie look into what went wrong in the Holodeck. Chokie is like “are you SURE you’re okay?” but maybe he should have pushed a bit harder cause yeah, when Neelix sees his own fucking corpse, it kinda… snaps something in him. He realizes he was dead for 18 hours, and there was nothing. He was told all his life he’d go to an afterlife and be with his loved ones who had died, and it had carried him through so much. But now he can’t believe that. We’ll all just, poof, be gone. It affects him.</p>

<p>It’s also bad timing, because a Talaxian holiday is happening like, in a day. And it’s a day celebrating family and love and life, and Neelix is just straight up depressed. He has to tell another bedtime story to the kid, and she INSISTS on hearing about the Great Forest, his afterlife, and it’s… HEARTTBREAKING. I have to admit, Neelix’s actor is fucking KILLING it here. He’s the same, but he’s clearly lower energy, and it’s NOT easy to play a chipper happy character who’s depressed and trying to hide it from others and have it come across not hamfisted. He’s doing a FANTASTIC job.</p>

<p>Neelix is still dying, btw, he needs to be constantly upkept. He hates it, and snaps at Seven before almost dying again. He then, once revived, asks for help from Chokie. Neelix wants to go on a vision quest. Chakotay SAYS THE THING! :D He says “WE ARE FAR FROM THE BONES OF OUR ANCESTORS”! Thats a big meme in our watch group. Anyways the vision quest goes VERY poorly. His dead sister is like “there’s no afterlife so there’s no point to being alive.” and then she dies horribly in front of him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UFGqFvb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What the fuck Chakotay, did you really need to give him the BAD shit???</p>

<p>Neelix is back to his friendly self, kind of. He goes to apologize to Seven for snapping at her, and is very… cagey. Reverent, almost. He’s also avoiding telling Chakotay what he ACTUALLY saw, and Chakotay is unhappy, cause he can kind of tell. something is clearly wrong. Neelix goes about his time, doing the work he has to do, making sure everything is neat and tidy. Then he leaves notes for everyone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gjhwNdK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are they laying this on thick? Maybe a little. But like, as someone who has been suicidal, and has basically done EXACTLY this, planning things out and trying to leave neat and orderly? Yeah. It also hits. Poor Neelix. Chakotay pretty much talks him down from the edge of the bridge. He’s bad at it, and his actor is not doing a good job, but Neelix is doing his best. He has to stick around. People need him. He does good work here. He goes to tuck his goddaughter in, and tells her more stories.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7HDUrX1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She dreams of the Great Forest. And the positivity of faith continues.</p>

<p>This made me very emotional.</p>

<p><strong>Waking Moments</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VkdGtVc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with everyone having dreams. Harry dreams he’s making out with Seven. Tom is crashing a ship. Janeway dreams everyone died cause she took too long to get home. And Tuvok came to the bridge not wearing pants, which is VERY funny. Then all their dreams end with a weird alien just staring at them. Everyone quickly comes to the conclusion something is funny, cause they’re ALL eepy as fuck. Everyone is okay though… except Harry, who appears to be unable to wake up. And others quickly join him. So what can they do?</p>

<p>Get CHAKOTAY OF COURSE! God, they sure do love Chakotay in this part of the show. And what does he do? The ONLY THING HE DOES! HIS ONE CHARACTER TRAIT. Be vaguely native american!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JGqdIHy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay does some lucid dreaming, and converses with the aliens. They’re paranoid that people will hurt them, so they’re trying to keep people asleep. Seems a bit unneccesary, but okay. Chakotay promises to leave, and they get directions, and off they go. Well that’s a fast episode, huh?</p>

<p>Everyone wakes up, and things seem fine. Kim is awkward around Seven, it’s cute. Anyways they’re suddenly attacked by the aliens, who are super powerful and impossible to defeat. They’re now all trapped in the cargo bay as the aliens have full run of the ship. Eventually, however, Chakotay realizes… he’s actually still asleep.</p>

<p>He wakes up, and makes SURE of it this time. It’s just him and the Doctor, who can’t sleep. Everyone else was pushed into sleep. Chakotay theorizes: These aliens are always asleep, and keep others asleep where they’re the most powerful. He’s got to chase them down.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0p5y4dz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, back in the dream, chakotay just up and disappeared right aftter saying “oh I’m still asleep”. Turns out they’re all in a shared dream. Seven calls it “collective unconsciousness”. Janeway tests this theory by literally standing in front of an antimatter explosion.</p>

<p>There’s a good jump cut where we think Janeway woke herself up like Chakotay did, but then we find out, nope. He fell back asleep. The doctor wakes him back up chemically.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2C8yCFJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway gets to be a badass with a gun again, I love it.</p>

<p>Chakotay finds the sleeping aliens, has the Doctor target a nuke on them, and then falls asleep, and tells them “I will kill you all if you don’t stop immediately”. Chakotay was just about to wipe out an entire species.</p>

<p>Everyone is out, they think. They all have bad insomnia, understandable. And that’s it. The aliens’ like, real reasons aren’t explained, and uh, it feels kinda flat.</p>

<p><strong>Message in a Bottle</strong> - VOY
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VkdGtVc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven calls Chokie and Janeway into her Astrometrics Lab. Recently, she made a super long range scanner. Now, she found a relay network that goes a LONG way. It’s abandoned but functional… And at the other end, they see a Federation vessel. They try sending a message, but some technobabble stops them. But they CAN send the doctor!! Hopefully after he connects with them they can jsut send him back, but we’ll see. Good luck, Doctor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/liByn1e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s now on a ship called the Prometheus!! Unfortunately, everyone is dead. Some Romulans have taken over the ship. This is just a few months before the Romulans entered the war, I guess. This is an experimental combat ship, which is kinda neat. The Doctor manages to bluff his way into helping save a Romulan who gets injured. He needs help, though. So he summons THIS ship’s EMH.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/458iCim.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the new EMH. He fucking sucks. He’s also played by Andy Dick, who kinda sucks, which doesn’t help. He’s AMAZINGLY unlikable. He finds out they’re in a combat situation and just turns himself off. He refuses to help the Romulan, that’s “the enemy”. While the idea of a die-hard episode with the Doctor is very good, and one of my favorites, it’s uh… very annoying. New EMH is very unlikable, and Old Doctor can’t help but do a dick waving contest. He brags about having sex, among other things.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4TNp67O.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back on Voyager, the owners of the relay network realize whats going on and tell them to cut that shit out. Uh oh. Seven solves this problem by literally electrocuting this guy. Holy shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y3VLHqe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor is caught, but EMH2 saves him. He’s still annoying. He knocks all the Romulans out with nerve gas, and they try to stop the ship. Too bad they have no idea what they’re doing. They cause the warp core to fall apart, and then more Romulans show up. Things aren’t going well.</p>

<p>There’s also a C plot where Paris is sick of being back up doctor, so he asks Harry to make a new EMH. Harry tries, turns out its REALLY hard so he gives up cause fuck that shit.</p>

<p>This episode is weird cause it’s trying to be a hectic, tense thing with two doctors trying to recommandeer this ship, and yet its like half of a bad comedy, and the other half is the Doctor making actually good quips.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rjJjTnb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor succeeds, there’s a lot of dead Romulans, and then he beams back and lets them know that Starfleet now knows they’re alive, and are working to help. I found this episode kinda annoying, but it’s got some good stuff to it.</p>

<p><strong>Hunters</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v8XzwHP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Immediately following the last episode, Voyager gets a new message through the relays from Starfleet Command. Unfortunately, it’s cut off, but they can get the full message if they rescue it from a nearby relay or whatever. Meanwhile, the ACTUAL owners of the relay, who are unhappy about all this, the Hirogen, decide to do something about it.</p>

<p>Seven is hard at work trying to get the messages working. She’s like “this is important to the Captain, so I must work hard for it.” Oh she’d do ANYTHING for the Captain, wouldn’t she~</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HaIxumV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The next bit is them getting their letters. Some good news, some bad. Tuvok learns he’s a grandfather now. Janeway smiles then it slowly fades as she reads her’s. Chakotay goes to be alone after reading his. He learns all of the Maquis are dead, whoopsies.  Others are reacting differently. Paris hasn’t gotten any letters and doesn’t give a shit. Harry has gotten none and its KILLING him.</p>

<p>Seven and Tuvok go in a shuttle to fiddle with the relay so that they can get the messages more easily. They’re attacked by the Hirogen, and captured.</p>

<p>I’m actually liking how people are reacting to these letters. Paris is like “I want no part of this. What I have here is so much better than what I had back home.” I actually like this quite a bit. They made me like a PARIS MOMENT.</p>

<p>There’s a scene where Seven meets with JAneway, who is sad. And I was like “please, PLEASe, Seven, ask Janeway what’s wrong, so she can explain her husband married someone else to you, and NOT to Chakotay later on. And then you can go ‘I am sorry to hear that. But it sounds like you are available, can we go on a date this weekend’”. Unfortunately she just walked out the door and we pretty much just get that scene with Chokie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Nc1WTyl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>These are the Hirogen. They’re ALL about prey and hunting. They’re pretty much the aliens from the Tosk episode, but about EVERYONE, not just Tosk. They’re kinda cool tbh ngl. They’re not like, EVIL really. They just have very different morals. The Hirogen who captures Seven and Tuvok explains “You will probably die, more of my people are coming, these people I caught are my prize. Just leave so you don’t die too.” Obviously Janeway doesn’t just leave. They are, however, VERY scary, and fully intend to butcher the fuck out of Tuvok and Seven.</p>

<p>They weaken the relay, which is holding a black hole in it. The other Hirogen attack Voyager, which causes the ENTIRE relay to blow the fuck up. All the Hirogen explode, though they do save Seven and Tuvok, and manage to escape.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BYrisyt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, the explosion destabalized the entire relay system, so no more of that. They’re alone once more. But they got Harry’s message after all! I hope it doesn’t say like “Hey Harry, we got a new son. His name is John.”</p>

<p>We get one last scene with Janeway and Chokie where he shoots his shot. “I hope you like your boyfriends bland!”</p>

<p>Good episode all around, even if it has the Status Quo Curse.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 111</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/16/OOCY111.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 111" /><published>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/16/OOCY111</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/16/OOCY111.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y6Uz9yG.png" alt="'The tiny vibrations that give off body heat. What's going on? This feels good..... I want to hold her forever.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Apparently I haven’t hit live in 5 days? I’ve been uploading things. I SWEAR I have been. Huh.</p>

<p>source: Just Her in This Big Wide World</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Just Her in This Big Wide World" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 110</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/14/OOCY110.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 110" /><published>2025-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/14/OOCY110</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/14/OOCY110.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hXPjbqK.png" alt="'Matsuko-chan! Please accept this!' 'huh?!' 'I had a dream about you before. Since I woke up, the whole world has been sparkling. I really... wanted to meet you.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G59l8wH.png" alt="'....Meguru, you really... are an idiot, aren't you? This.... I sort of did at least half the work to make it...' 'Ah... ehehehe well it will definitely be delicious!' '...Then I will... indulge myself!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Happy Vamilumtimes Day!</p>

<p>source: The Two of Us and Apples</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Two of Us and Apples" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 109</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/12/OOCY109.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 109" /><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/12/OOCY109</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/12/OOCY109.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BIsXKxF.png" alt="'You said it! I knew you'd have fun!' 'Yeah.... but the customers get touched too? I didn't expect that.' 'what? They do?? ...I guess they could sense the powerful bottom energy that you put off.' 'WHAT DO YOU MEAN BOTTOM ENERGY?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 151 - Laser Blast</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/12/RA151-LaserBlast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 151 - Laser Blast" /><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/12/RA151-LaserBlast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/12/RA151-LaserBlast.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ki7uqpY.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I felt like playing random Atari games, so I did. This is Laser Blast, a relatively liked Activision game on the Atari 2600, and one I’d never even heard of before I picked it up to play. Like most Atari games, it’s a simple arcadey game. It’s like the inverse of Missile Command. You play as a UFO and you go around on the planets surface blasting turrets that shoot lasers back at you. You can move left or right, and shoot. If you’re moving as you shoot, you aim slightly left or right, otherwise you fire straight down. Your laser has some good width to it. Once you clear all the turrets, you move onto the next screen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Baesq1D.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is about rhythm. The enemy AI is easily manipulated if you do the same movements over and over, so it’s about finding those movements then committing them to a rhythm to quickly blow up all three turrets and move on, over, and over. To master this game, I had to get 100,000 points. At about 30 points per turret, that’s a lot of turrets. Apparently if you did this back in the day, you could send the picture in to Activision to get a patch for the Activision Federation of Laser Blasters? I want my damn patch, Activision.</p>

<p>The higher difficulties don’t change much, other than the turrets’ rate of fire and movement capabilities. It certainly gets more challenging, but you just need to find the right rhythm again. This game isn’t MUCH, but I had fun with it for about an hour.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Atari" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 150 - The Escape from Atlantis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/11/RA150-Atlantis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 150 - The Escape from Atlantis" /><published>2025-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/11/RA150-Atlantis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/11/RA150-Atlantis.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5jslN1W.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Color Dreams is at it again! This is a rather infamous one by them in some circles. It never got BIG attention cause it wasn’t covered by AVGN or anything, but for those who’ve played it, oh boy. This isn’t their worst game or anything, but it is interesting, because this game was never released! Yes, they decided Menace Beach was fine, but this was just too much for the market.</p>

<p>You play as Some Dude and you’ve got to escape Atlantis. A volcano is erupting and shit is bad. That’s it, that’s your story. You can run and you can VERY awkwardly jump. It’s kind of top down, but kinda isometric? It’s like a 3/4th view from a drone above.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CXZq9Py.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is nonsense. Each level requires you to do a new different thing to proceed, and this game is inscrutable. Cannot be scruted. Like it starts fine enough I guess? Beating enemies on the screen is a pretty simple puzzle, but by the end when you’re breaking down walls, but you have to break it in the RIGHT WAY, it’s just rough. If you die, you don’t immediately die, you get sent to Hades, where you need to collect hearts. If you get enough, you return to life. Get touched by Death, and you’re gone. Luckily this is VERY easy, so it’s practically infinite continues, and you’re gonna use ‘em.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/336Ou7m.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The music is rough, the art is VERY rough, I love that horrible little guy. Look at this AWFUL box art, why s his head so large, what the hell is going on with his facial hair?! This guy looks like a dude who’d be drinking little ales in a hipster bar. This game is bad, but if you’re following a guide, it takes like 30 minutes, and it’s fun to point and laugh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Color Dreams" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 108</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/11/OOCY108.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 108" /><published>2025-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/11/OOCY108</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/11/OOCY108.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OfwlrNB.png" alt="'You know, Annabel, for someone so intent in walking away from me, you never seem to get very far~'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Nevermore</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nevermore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 6 - 10</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/10/LizstartrekDS97-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 6 - 10" /><published>2025-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/10/LizstartrekDS97-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/10/LizstartrekDS97-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PeBe39g.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Treachery, Faith, and the Great River</strong> - DS9
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/D4tAwr6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got another a-plot and b-plot episode. Our A-plot starts with Kira naked and moaning while being massaged. I’m gonna like this episode. Odo tells her that news claims his best Cardassian informant is dead, buuuuut he just got a message that he wants to meet Odo, it’s urgent. Huh. Looks like a sussy trap. Good thing Odo is a puddle and can’t be hurt in any way. He shows up, and yeah, the informant has been dead for a while, but instead WEYOUN IS THERE! He claims he’s defecting. Odo doesn’t believe it. But hey, Weyoun could maybe help the Federation if he IS defecting, so worth a try.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8PHHOMi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, the b-plot is O’brien is overworked. What else is new? He needs to get a part, but the acquisitions officer can’t get it to them before like, 3 weeks from now. Nog believes he can use his Ferengi Wiles to butter up the officer and get them up on the waiting list. It’s a cute concept, and nice to show just WHY the Federation is good; it’s a combination of a lot of cultures and ideals, used to their effectiveness. Could be interesting.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on the Runabout, Odo and Weyoun get a call from… Weyoun! Turns out a month ago, the Weyoun we all knew and loved, Weyoun 5, was killed in a teleporter “accident”. This one here is Weyoun 6, who’s “defective” (he thinks the war is stupid), and Weyoun 7 here wants Odo to hand him over. Damar, instead, plans to just blow Odo up. Two birds, one stone, a good victory for the war. BOTH Weyouns are disgusted by the idea. But Damar insidiously worms his way into Weyoun 7’s brainmeats and convinces him that “oh, Odo doesn’t even consider himself a founder, so it’s not killing a founder!” Meanwhile, back on the roundabout, Odo is obviously not gonna give 6 up, and we get a lot of stuff about how Odo is still uncomfortable with being a God.</p>

<p>I love that this episode is just Nog doing a Zelda Trade Quest. Again. THis is like the third god damn time Nog has done a trade quest in this show and I love it every time. I hope we get a stem bolt reference. Unfortunately, this turns for the worst when he trades the captain’s desk to a dude… only for a minute, though. He was just borrowing it. This guy has a collection of images of himself sitting at famous captain’s desks. That’s fucking hilarious.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LvPUMYx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Weyoun 6 helps Odo blow up some Jem’Hadar. He feels guilty, but it’s for a good cause. There’s some interesting lore and talk about the Genetic coding of Vortas, which has always been a dark thing in the series.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the female Changeling ALMOST finds out that they’re trying to kill Odo, which would end with them being VERY dead. She also doesn’t look…. great. Uh oh. Weyoun 6 explains it to Odo with a good stinger. A sickness is spreading through the Great Link, and the Founders are dying. This… could be a good thing. Odo will be the only Founder left. And with him, he could save the Dominion. He could make them an empire of peace, understanding, and cooperation, not war.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LDOu7tO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, it’s not to be for poor Weyoun 6. He kills himself to save Odo, and they immediately call off the attack. He needs one thing though, just one thing before he dies.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sP6Fhzm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is very, very interesting to watch. Like, Weyoun 6 isn’t neccesarily a righteous or even GOOD character. He’s still brainwashed, he just decided he wants to help Odo, who’s his God. It’s great.</p>

<p>Also Nog gets everything settled, and O’Brien is now all in on it. It’s great.</p>

<p><strong>Treachery, Faith, and the Great River</strong> - DS9
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NsndL6E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got Kor back!! Kor was one of the original Klingons from ToS, I think the first one, actually. He visits Worf, and asks for help. He’s a Dahar Master, he’s been in the game for literal centuries, and he wants to leave the way he’s always lived. As a warrior, dying fighting. He asks Worf to help him get a command and a ship in the war, and Worf is like “Yeah of course, why wouldn’t you get one” then he goes to Martok who gets UNNATURALLY angry at the mention of Kor. What the fuck did Kor do, piss on his wife??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/T7iLTZv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We learn some background about Martok. His family was poor, but warriors. And Martok was VERY accomplished, so he was supposed to become an officer. But Kor was a member of some council that rejected him, seemingly just cause of his poor upbringing. Not a correct or valid reason, but what could Martok do? He crawled his way into serving anyway after getting a battlefield commission, but he’s been pissed at Kor for the last 30 years about this. Kor, for the record, does not even remember this, but he IS like “Oh you’ve been with this democratic rabble for too long. That’s how things are in the Klingon empire, I’m of noble blood, he is not. He should appreciate that”</p>

<p>And I love Worf’s response, just a very flat, “he does not.”</p>

<p>Kor also appears to be… significantly up there in years. I mean, he’s old. Like, very old. But he’s forgetting things.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g2IrmKq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Including some VERY important stuff.</p>

<p>Kor almost gets them all killed, because he thinks they’re fighting some Federation base from a century ago. He’s off his rocker, and they BARELY survive. Klingon senility is a little frightening, and also very sad and depressing to watch. Also Klingons are VERY bad at handling stuff like this so they just end up mocking him, which is also gross and uncomfortable to watch. However, luckily, IMMEDIATELY after, Martok is like “Okay no actually this is bad. I’ve been wanting to laugh in his fucking face and see him torn from his birthright for years, and now that it’s here, I get no joy from it.”</p>

<p>There’s also stuff here with Ezri and the Wanna Fuck Her Squad, and I hate this and I hate this squad and I hate this a lot.</p>

<p>Worf is going to sacrifice himself to save the fleet. Damn, I can’t believe they’ll kill off Worf like this. No, obviously, Kor takes his place, knocking Worf out with a hypospray. In a moment of clarity, Kor saves the day, all by himself. Die well, Kor.</p>

<p>Rough episode at parts, but not bad in the end.</p>

<p><strong>The Siege of AR-558</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/h86JXXO.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Rom singing. Poorly. I bet the actor ia amazing at it and was really playing it up. Did you know that on the Baseball episode, he had to act bad at Baseball, and apparently it was hard, cause he’s actually VERY good at baseball? It’s very Rom, though.</p>

<p>They’re going on a supply run to AR-558. Quark is going too, even though he really does NOT want to be there, cause the Nagus asked him to bring him a report. They beam down to give the supplies and help a bit and uh, shit’s bad. They’ve been there 5 months, they’re supposed to swap out every 90 days. There were 150 there. Now they’re 43. All of the leaders are dead, a Lieutenant is in charge now. Shit’s bad.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cVdB3NH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is going to be a dark episode isn’t it? Also literally.</p>

<p>Nog likes the soldiers who are left. Quark is like “Noooo no, stay away. If Humans are pushed against a wall, they are FUCKED.” We see one of them have a god damn freak out about someone he hated dying. Instead they have the counselor doing engineering stuff I guess. (They’re like “oh, your previous life, Tobin, was an Engineer? Perfect, you’re fired. Tobin was alive like 150 years ago. That’d be like hiring a dude from the 1800s to fix my laptop.) The enemy also rigged the base with “Houdini Mines”, mines that hide in subspace then randomly pop up to fucking kill you. What the shit. This place is very poorly run. You don’t leave 50 dudes to defend something, no wonder the Federation is getting their ass kicked.</p>

<p>Sisko decides to stay to try and help. So now it’s Sisko, Bashir, Dax, Nog, and Quark with these twitchy unstable soldiers, and they need to hold off a siege. The Siege of AR-588 has begun.</p>

<p>Nog goes off like a good little soldier and uses his hearing to find where the Jem’Hadar are. This ends with one soldier dying, and Nog losing his leg. Jeeze.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iXqqVmi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They manage to move those mines, setting a trap for the Jem’Hadar, but it doesn’t stop their advance, and there’s a full of siege. What proceeds is a long fight scene, with dramatic music, as people die left and right. Even Quark gets a shot off. (Which is extra interesting, because earlier in the episode, he’s like “You say you’ll kill for a good cause? It’s still killing, that’s bad”, and then he kills to save his nephew. A good moment.) But they manage to make it out. The ending is reverent about the lost soldiers.</p>

<p>I dunno how I fully feel about this episode. I think it handles the war story thing quite well. It’s very fucked up. I didn’t enjoy watching it very much. Very heavy. But still, good.</p>

<p><strong>Covenant</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MG4jOHR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s baaaaack!</p>

<p>An old friend of Kira’s shows up. He was a Vedek from when she was a kid, a very religious man. He gives her a gift, and whoops, it kidnaps her and teleports her to EMPOK NOR, which is now the base of operations of the Pah-Wraith cult, or “the followers of the True Prophets”, as they say. And their leader? It’s YA BOY, THE WORST PERSON IN SPACE!</p>

<p>All these Bajorans, willingly following and giving themselves up to a Space Fascist. This show is not subtle, and that’s a good thing. But don’t worry, They’re The Good Guys.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BJ2dGJ8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>LOL “Oh Nerys, you’re so misguided. You need to FORGIVE Dukat for what he did. I thought I taught you forgiveness is important”. YEAH, IF THEY ACTUALLY TRY TO CHANGE. If you stab me I won’t go “I forgive you” as you continue to fucking stab me. Put the god damn knife down. Also you all CALL HIM MASTER. WHAT THE FUCK IS WRONG WITH YOU?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5iRTBnT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s MASSIVELY on the nose. It’s also a fun example of the differences between Dukat and Sisko. THey’re both emmisaries. Sisko was hesitant, and stepped up when he had to. Dukat is… Dukat. Kira calls this out in an AMAZINGLY good way: this is just Dukat recreating the occupation. He’s the leader, the master, and these people “love” him, like he always wanted.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W3miUSd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is not holding back. They needed to ask Ducat permission to fuck, and he gave it. And guess what ELSE he did? He cucked this dude. “Oh it’s clearly a sign from the Pah-wraiths!” YEAH, TRULY A SIGN. IT’S A SIGN FROM THEM I SHOULD FUCK MORE OF YOUR WOMEN. YOU ALL SHOULD THANK ME!</p>

<p>Dukat, you have GOT to stop making half-Bajoran babies, for the love of God. And then when the mother is like “I think… if my husband asks, I’ll tell him you DID have sex with me”, uh, he tries to have her airlocked. Kira saves her. Looks like things might be falling apart for Dukat. He can’t keep this cult together…. so what’s he plan to do?</p>

<p>ITS TIME TO DRINK THE KOOLAID!!</p>

<p>Yes, LITERALLY, he makes them all drink poisoned drinks so they can “ascend and be with the prophets”. Jeezus. So yeah uh, he has no actual intention of drinking the koolaid with them. And when Kira knocks it out of his hands, one of them is like “Here master, here’s another one” and of course he refuses to drink it. As a mob forms, he teleports away. Good riddance.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zO3ButL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Vedek who brought Kira into this whole mess drinks the koolaid anyway. Why? “Faith.” Kira has NO clue what that means, and neither do I. Weird hill to die on, but at least you’re dead. I appreciated how this handled Kira, Kira is AMAZING, and I love her. The rest of the episode is fine, it’s just Cults 101, but that’s fine.</p>

<p><strong>It’s Only a Paper Moon</strong> - DS9
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HRvZubf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Nog returns home. He’s been in a hospital for a while cause, y’know, of his leg. Everyone gives him a loving return home, but uh, he seems… distant. Ezri tries to be a counselor at him. She is a very bad counselor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iB6xhpx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>His new leg is APPARENTLY fine. He thinks his doctor thinks he’s nuts, cause it APPARENTLY works fine, but it hurts Nog to walk on it, and so he uses a cane to help. He’s also constantly inundated with PTSD memories of the Siege. He also ONLY wants to listen to a specific song… A Vic Fontaine tune, “I’ll be Seeing You”. Why that one? Well, that’s the song Bashir played during the siege. He wants to play it, over and over. He plays the recording of it, but eventually his roomie, Jake, gets sick of listening to the damn song over and over, so Nog goes to listen to… THE SOURCE.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PeBe39g.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Vic sings him some songs, and Nog is… comfortable there. For the first time for months. So he asks if he can… stay. Stay in the holosuite, and become Vic’s roommate. Vic’s like “Yeah sure why not?” Vic is such a good character? He’s a GREAT guy. Nog is in his apartment with him and he’s looking over his checkbook, and Nog’s like “You know its not real money. I can just put money in your account.” “Nah, it’s real and important to me”. Y’know, just like Nog’s leg. HO HO. THE CONNECTIONS! Vic’s just a nice, chill guy. I know some people don’t like him but he’s EASILY one of the highlights of late stage DS9 to me.</p>

<p>Vic wants to help ween Nog off the cane, and back into his life. He gets him a new cane, a fancy replica of Errol Flin’s. But it’s more fragile, so he can’t put his entire weight on it. “Well, I don’t need to put my WHOLE weight on it.” It’s working.</p>

<p>Jake’s girlfriend calls Nog a hero and he gets angry and then slugs Jake and storms off…. without the cane. Good touch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ec3BQc7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ezri, being a bad therapist, thinks Nog should leave the holosuite now. I mean, what’s he doing? Improving? Pff, that’s too slow, he needs to feel better NOW, on OUR TIME! I know Ezri is like, a child, but fucking lord they are bad at writing her being a therapist. Instead, Nog basically becomes Vic’s boyfriend in the holosuite. It’s actually great. Like, okay, I think Nog retreating in the holosuite is FINE, actually, but he IS missing things out that his friends and loved ones are doing. Vic eventually gives Nog one last push, turning off the program. Nog basically has a freak out, and Vic comes back (he can stop himself from being turned on, Vic is Hologram God), and FINALLY Nog opens up.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZyC6lD5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s scared. He came face to face with his own mortality, and now he’s afraid to face it any longer. At least in the holosuite, he knows what tomorrow will bring. Vic gives him a good speech, and he finally heads out… He’s not okay. But he WILL be. He goes back to limited duty, and as a gift to Vic for all he did, he gives Vic a real life… he leaves the holosuite on, 26/7.</p>

<p>This was a very strong episode. Vic is so good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 107</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/10/OOCY107.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 107" /><published>2025-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/10/OOCY107</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/10/OOCY107.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AuZzXGB.png" alt="'Is it me, then? Do I terrify you?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xVdt3LK.png" alt="...Should you?' Eleanor smirks, then leans forward..." class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WHa1WRF.png" alt="...and chomps right in front of Annabell, who reals back in surprise 'Ah?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Nevermore is finally back, I’m super excited!</p>

<p>source: Nevermore</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nevermore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>