<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-02T12:11:16-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 101</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/02/OOCY102.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 101" /><published>2025-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/02/OOCY102</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/02/OOCY102.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8sRDv2Z.png" alt="A girl stares at another and then gets embarrassed. '...Even though it'd be fine if you looked more.' 'huh?!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Our Yuri Started With Me Getting Rejected in a Dream</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Our Yuri Started With Me Getting Rejected in a Dream" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 149 - Banishing Racer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/02/RA148-Anteater.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 149 - Banishing Racer" /><published>2025-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/02/RA148-Anteater</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/02/RA148-Anteater.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QD4t7kN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I already did a review on Anteater a while ago, for my “Games You May Not Have Heard Of” series. It’s an absolutely amazing maze game with almost perfect design, and while quite challenging, has a lot of room for fun fast paced strategizing of how you’re going to get that last egg.</p>

<p>I made this set, and people seem to like it, which is good. It came out on the 17th, like, a couple weeks ago, and already has more players than my other sets I’ve made…. except Pyramid, which has the most for some god forsaken reason.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KsWMi2p.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>If you’re interested in learning more about Anteater, including the skullduggery of the early PC market where they just stole games all the time, maybe look up my review of it. But either way, you should play Anteater. It’s very good.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Arcades" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Anteater" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 101</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/01/OOCY101.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 101" /><published>2025-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/01/OOCY101</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/01/OOCY101.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5W6oIwU.png" alt="A woman thinking with an arrow to them that says 'GAMER BRAIN'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Our Yuri Started With Me Getting Rejected in a Dream</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Our Yuri Started With Me Getting Rejected in a Dream" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 147 - Banishing Racer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/01/RA147-BanishingRacer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 147 - Banishing Racer" /><published>2025-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/01/RA147-BanishingRacer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/01/RA147-BanishingRacer.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZIkyy6t.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The first game I played this year was a random-ass Gameboy game no one’s ever heard of. Not even I had heard of this game before I played it. I was looking at Tryrush Deppy, one of my sets I made for Saturn, and saw someone added this game as a game that’s like it. Well shit! Tryrush Deppy can be a little frustrating at times, but I DO like it, lemme try this out! Guess what. This was ALSO frustrating at times. Minus the little.</p>

<p>Banishing Racer is essentially Opposite Tryrush Deppy. It was made by Jaleco, a company I’ve had mixed results with. You play as a car in a race across America, (driven by an angel who brings him back to life from the dump, which is wild) but instead of going from NYC to Sanfran, you go from Sanfran to NYC. Each of the levels is based off of where you are in the map. This means you get hilarious levels like the cow farm in the middle of the country, or a car factory near Detroit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9aUZjoV.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a platformer. You can jump, and charge. Your charge is a bit dinky, but it’s a good idea to learn how to charge jump, or charge in midair for tricky platforming. You can ONLY charge forward, so moving backwards can be dangerous. And that’s it. Platform your way across America, hopping on cars and shit. If you hop on like 6 cars in a row, you get a 1-up, which trust me, is EXTREMELY IMPORTANT. The final levels in this game are fucked beyond belief. There’s a 3 minute long auto scroller with no checkpoints, and a lot of trial and error. It was MASSIVELY rude.</p>

<p>In the end, Banishing Racer is…. fine. But it’s not really a forgotten gem. It’s a little too mean for its own good, and its conceit and platforming is FINE but not breathtaking. It’s like a 6/10.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Banishing Racer" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 100</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/30/OOCY100.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 100" /><published>2025-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/30/OOCY100</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/30/OOCY100.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ltSJoDh.png" alt="Two girls blushing like crazy 'What face should I make when I see her tomorrow...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Happy 100!</p>

<p>source: The Moon on a Rainy Night</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Moon on a Rainy Night" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 99</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/29/OOCY99.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 99" /><published>2025-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/29/OOCY99</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/29/OOCY99.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ZnMI7c.png" alt="Girl gets licked by a dog 'That tickles!' 'I WISH I WAS THAT DOG&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Be Happy in the Real World Too Okay?</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Be Happy in the Real World Too Okay?" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 146 - Trip World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/29/RA146-Tripworld.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 146 - Trip World" /><published>2025-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/29/RA146-Tripworld</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/29/RA146-Tripworld.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8MSnkgb.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I was playing a cult classic NES game called Gimmick. That game is hard as shit, and I didn’t really have it in me to grind it out right now, but I still wanted to play it. So I did the next best thing.</p>

<p>This is Trip World, a gameboy platformer by Sunsoft, and it’s a bit of a spiritual sequel to Gimmick. It’s not a perfect comparison, both games have their own things about them. But it’s a cutesy platformer with a bunch of scrimblos and you go through level to level, jump on enemies, and beat up bosses.</p>

<p>In Trip World you play Yakapoo, a Shabubu, TOTALLY not a Pikachu (this game predates Pikachu, they were onto something). Yakopoo lives with his grandfather, who protects the holy Maita Flower, which keeps peace over the world. One day shadowy creatures appear and attack grandpa, stealing the flower of peace. Now everyone starts quarreling and fighting with each other. Yakapoo must travel forth to find the flower!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/c1ioRF3.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Yakapoo can run, jump, and kick his way through five distinct levels. It’s a physics platformer, so you’ve got momentum to deal with when it comes to slopes, very much like Gimmick. You can also press a direction and kick to transform! Yakapoo can turn into a helicopter, which allows him to fly but it’s awkward, he can only go up while also moving forward, and if he hits anything he falls right the fuck back down. Down and kick turns you into a fish, good for the few water areas, bad everywhere else, you’ll flop on the ground. You can also find fruits through the level which can transform you into things like mini Yakapoo, a ball, and Yakapoo with a long club tail. If you COMBINE fruits, you get even MORE combinations! The fruits are in the same place every time, so you can route what powerups you want at what time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/garUi9f.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Trip World is a very charmingly cute platformer with amazing Sunsoft music, though it lacks a bit in a few ways. First, it’s short. You can beat this in like 15 minutes. Second, it’s really, REALLY easy… kind of. The first three levels are basically piss easy, the fourth level is normal difficulty, and the fifth level is really REALLY hard. There’s no continues. So you’ll be replaying the first four a LOT to get through the boss gauntlet at the end. Is that good? Ehhhh. It wasn’t unfun, at least! I managed to beat the game without dying, after some save state practice at the final boss gauntlet. Took some doing.</p>

<p>Trip World isn’t like, transcendent, but it’s charming and cute and prolly good for road trips. Yakapoo would be seen in a few other Sunsoft games, before fading off the face of the planet… though the game DID semi-recently get picked up for a re-release, with a modded “DX” port, which is pretty neat!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Trip World" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 98</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/28/OOCY98.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 98" /><published>2025-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/28/OOCY98</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/28/OOCY98.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/koT8yNg.png" alt="'Look, it's Ayanokouji-san! She's so cool...' 'She really is. I wish I was half as cool! She's like, the perfect woman. She's a bit hard to approach though...' 'the perfect woman, huh? What kind of... HOLD ON, ARE THOSE CUTESY SOCKS?! Oh, she seems like FUN!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: She’s Not What I Expected</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="She&apos;s Not What I Expected" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 97</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/27/OOCY97.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 97" /><published>2025-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/27/OOCY97</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/01/27/OOCY97.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NYSyRaO.png" alt="'Why do you think she came here?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/slsCDKO.png" alt="'Maybe she just wnated to see you?' After reading yuri manga, her brain is in yuri mode." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yuri Yuri Panic: An Extremely Precious Affair has Begun</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuri Yuri Panic An Extremely Precious Affair has Begun" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 145 - Barney’s Hide and Seek Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/27/RA145-Barney.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 145 - Barney’s Hide and Seek Game" /><published>2025-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/27/RA145-Barney</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/01/27/RA145-Barney.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yyZdVQW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>“Liz, why the hell are you playing this game for children?” Shut up, disembodied voice in my head.</p>

<p>God, remember Barney? I was the right age for Barney, and I grew up watching him. And then also, children my age were ALSO the EXACT perfect age to grow a little older, once they reached the “I’m too old for this” stage, right as they could start making flash animations on the early internet, so that instead of just going “Pff, Barney is for babies” in the school yard, they could instead take their aggression out and show how adult and cool they are by blowing his head off in a flash animation. God, the early internet was a time. ANYWAY.</p>

<p>Barney’s Hide and Seek Game for Genesis is a CLASSIC meme game, especially in speedrunner circles. It’s a simple kids game. You play Barney, move left and right around a map, and press A by presents and children to “collect” them. Barney says things in a pretty well digitized voice the entire time. You can also press A to interract with things in the environment, and they do things. You can blow hearts at animals, play with instruments, it’s a very “click on a thing and it does a thing” game. If it was just that, would anyone care? Prolly not. There’s 4 levels and that’s it, your done.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ztDmkYc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But its MORE than that. See, Barney’s Hide and Seek Game has a feature it advertises itself, directly on the box: It plays itself. If you set the controller down, Barney will walk along, and tell you what things you can interract with. He’ll walk by a kid and go “Press the button when you see a friend!” He then waits a minute, and just continues on. If you turn the game on with no controller plugged in, “you” can “beat” the game in about ten minutes. Just sitting there watching Barney walk around and talk about things. There’s some variance, but people legit speedran this. The WR holder for a while was a dog, which is great.</p>

<p>As a game? It’s y’know, it’s fine for very young kids. As a MEME GAME? Perfection.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Genesis" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Barney" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>