<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-04T13:08:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 6 -</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/04/LizstartrekDS96-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 6 -" /><published>2024-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/04/LizstartrekDS96-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/04/LizstartrekDS96-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9mxsRHI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Sacrifice of Angels</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gQkHIj5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tensions are high. In eight hours those mines are going down, and while Sisko is surviving, it’s just barely. So the rebels on DS9 need to do something, and fast. What’s their plan? A bomb. Too bad Damar arrests all of them on suspicions of them being rebels, which I mean, they are. So now it’s all on the last member of the resistance who ISN’T detained. And that’s Quark.</p>

<p>It’s literally all on Quark. We’re fucked.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/10EwmIN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Dukat is cocky. He knows what he’s doing, and he knows he’s going to win. What… IS he doing, anyway? He and Damar are like “once this war is done we’ll break off from the Dominion~” Uh fucking how? How do you EVER expect that of happening??? Cardassia’s best opportunity was siding with the Federation, and they betrayed them instead. Anyways Dukat is an absolute trashfire of a person, and there’s a good scene with him and Weyoun showing the differences between him/Cardassia and the rest of the Dominion. Weyoun is like “Welp, we’ll have to genocide everyone on Earth once we conquer the Federation, because they can’t be controlled” and Dukat is like “why would we do that??? What’s the point of fascism if people can’t see you do it? The point is the GLOATING and powering OVER people!”</p>

<p>Odo is still bimbo-pilled by the female Changeling, but she just lets it slip that Kira is being executed because they’ll trump up charges even though they can’t find anything. Welp. Good job losing the easily won war with ONE thing cause you’rE SO sure of your bimbofication process.</p>

<p>Quark saves the day, with the help of Dukat’s daughter. In the process, Quark kills some guards, almost certainly the first person he’s EVER killed.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uYjqb4K.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Odo breaks free of Bimbofication. “The link is paradise, but I’m not ready for paradise”. He and his guards blast away the people chasing Kira and the others, and they’re on their way to sabatoge the station. In the end though, they’re just SECONDS too late. The mines are taken down. Sisko goes into the wormhole, to meet the thousands of Dominion ships. Because of Kira, they can’t blow him up as his ship goes in.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TEQYPKT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Sisko argues with the aliens, who are like “You are about to kill yourself trying to fight these forces.” and Sisko is like “I am :)” so they just…. hold the Dominion ships. They just Get Rid Of Them. It’s basically a deus ex machina. The Dominion is strong, but the Wormhole Aliens are BASICALLY gods. As compared to the Changelings, who just ACT like they’re gods.</p>

<p>Welp, the Dominion are fucked. They immediately schedule a retreat, cause the Klingons are bolstering the Federation. Gul Dukat is SHAKEN, and wanders the halls looking for Ziyal. When she tells him “I’m not leaving, also I helped the resistance”, he’s broken even more, and THEN Damar fucking shoots her, cause she’s a traitor. Damar you FUCKING IDIOT. This COMPLETELY SHATTERS Dukat, who straight up goes insane. He can’t comprehend that Ziyal is dead and he lost and he’s also part of the reason. He just rambles about forgiving her, and forgiving Sisko.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rLkIkp6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It was a hard fought battle, but we did it. ALMOST a phyrric victory. So much of the fleet was lost. But we have the key to the Alpha Quadrant. There are cheers, and cries, and hugs. We did it.</p>

<p><strong>You are Cordially Invited</strong> - DS9
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zQFRAOm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things are going well on DS9 now that it’s back under the Federation. Alexander is about to be transfered away though, so Worf and Dax’s wedding is pushed up to happen on DS9, so he can be there for it. How sweet. This episode then splits into two things. 1) Worf, Martok, Sisko, Alexander, O’Brien, and Bashir are doing a goofy Klingon-ass bachelor party. And 2) Dax is being judged by Martok’s wife to see if she is worthy to enter the house. She’s a xenophobic rich bitch asshole, and Martok is FUCKING TERRIFIED of her, which is very funny.</p>

<p>This episode also has one of my absolute favorite quotes in the entire show. “You’ve gained weight. And your hair is growing grey.” “My… deterioration is proceeding apace.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BbNQLOF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>God Dax is hot. Worf doesn’t deserve her. Worf is actually pretty good here, I kind of hate DS9 Worf, but this is feeling more TNG-ish. Like he’s like “Y’all are being xenophobic, that is stupid.” Dax is EXTREMELY defiant of this woman. It’s hot as fuck. It eventually ends with her calling the entire wedding off, which she has the power to do cause Klingon tradition is dumb. Worf tells her to beg, and she’s like “what? No, she’s a fucking xenophobic asshole, I won’t do that”, so WORF calls off the god damn wedding too, like “she was right about you”</p>

<p>NO. NO YOU IDIOT. AND THEN WHEN THEY CONVINCE WORF, AND SHE’S STILL MAD, THERE’S SOME DUMB SHIT WHERE ONCE SISKO TALKS TO HER, DAX IS LIKE “guess I gotta grow you”. NO. NO, HE IS NOT GOOD FOR YOU, AND WANTS YOU TO PUT UP WITH PEOPLE TREATING YOU LIKE SHIT. They do the whole “groveling to enter the house” thing off screen, I guess the mother in law just allows it now. This episode has some fun moments but in the end, I do not like Worf x Dax because I can’t stand DS9 Worf, and this is a good example of why.</p>

<p>At least it has this moment, one of my favorites.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q_WMSqZDUkM?si=pzkAUm6a8hQcij8O" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p><strong>Resurrection</strong> - DS9
6.5/10</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/8cYbe65.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Dax and Kira are having a conversation about how Kira needs to get laid basically, she hasn’t dated anyone in months. She’s fine with it, but Dax is shovy. Dax if you want her to date someone that bad, divorce Worf and date her. Please. Please do that. For the love of God, please. Unfortunately no. Instead, we get someone beaming into Ops. It’s MIRROR UNIVERSE VEDEK BAREIL! You remember him? He was the failed pope boy who died because his brain was turned into a cyborg or some shit. I never cared about him much.</p>

<p>This Bariel starts his existence in our story by holding Kira hostage with a broken gun, and begging to be allowed to stay in the prime universe, because the mirror universe is fucking garbage and who’d wanna live there? He seems like he’s trying to just… become a part of it, now, once he realizes how much better it is. He goes to church, though feels weird that his counterpart here was nearly pope and well respected, cause he’s a thief who is NOT respected. He’s basically a han solo-esque thief. Very different from our Bareil.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/bHuGjXi.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Obviously the two of them start getting into it. Kira says it’s not cause he looks like Bareil. He’s nothing LIKE him. But it’s cause he’s who he is. I dunno if I believe that lol. Bareil goes and has an Orb Experience, which is what it’s called, and we’ve been making fun of that phrase a LOT. He has his Orb Experience and it seems to be bothering him, but you’re Not Allowed To Talk About Your Orb Experience.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/uHAHmTj.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Anyways, hot sexy bisexual Kira is here. Turns out it’s all a ruse. He’s here to steal the Orb. He seems conflicted though. Seems his Orb Experience, and making out with the Major, and ALSO everyone thinking he’s Vedek Bareil is getting to him. It’s funny how Kira catches on to this. It’s not cause he slips up, or anything. It’s cause QUARK sees him for what he is, and flat out warns Kira. “He’s gonna rob the orb”. Quark sees RIGHT through him.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/EdkxsC4.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Once again, Quark saving the day. There’s a standoff with Bareil, Kira, and Kira, and Bareil shoots Kira and then wishes Kira well. He saw them being happy and in love in the orb, but he knew, he’d fuck it up some day. Might as well fuck it up now. And then it ends. This episode was fine.</p>

<p><strong>Statistical Probabilities</strong> - DS9
2/10</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/8cYbe65.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>So, people who have been genetically enhanced in the Federation, against their will specifically, are sent to an institute. What that implies isn’t explained yet, we just know that at the start of this. There are four genetically enhanced individuals, and treatments by the therapists and psychologists there aren’t working. Why they’d NEED them again, isn’t explained. These people are supposed to be genetically enhanced, instead they’re introduced and shown as if they have mental disorders. You’ve got the one who won’t talk, the anxious wreck, the overly sexual nympho, and the manic violent one. They’re trying something new to treat them and make them “valued members of society”, by having Bashir work with them. Bashir, also being genetically enhanced, can maybe find common ground. Bashir explains later that the REASON they’re all like this is because the enhancement failed, in a way, and caused unintended side effects.</p>

<p>So I see what they’re TRYING to do. Y’know, saying things using this world to say things about OUR world. In this case, they’re using the genetically enhanced to talk about how we, as a society, treat people with mental disorders. First, I want to state I am not qualified to talk about this. I’m neuroatypical, myself, but like, I NEVER feel comfortable talking about something so broad. But this makes me VERY uncomfortable. The violence is uncomfy. And also there’s a thing here like, ascribing almost supernatural abilities to being neuroatypical. Like, it’s nothing built of malice. It’s built from liberal ignorance.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/pKCZTlL.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>ANYWAYS there’s plot. Damar is the new leader. He’s also Gul Damar, even though Guls are just planetary governors and not dictators, but Dukat kept Gul to appear humble so I guess Damar does too. The Dominion is looking for peace treaties, and are willing to give over a lot of land for that reason. The Neurosis Squad looks over the proceedings using a computer, scanning them, and use their Big Meaty Superbrains to determine what the dominion REALLY wants. They can also just tell what O’Brien is thinking by looking at him. They’re trying to go with a “they’re very analytical” but instead they’re just, psychic. And they can apparently use these powers to be able to read the future. Okay, whatever.</p>

<p>One thing I kinda like about this is that Bashir is VERY unhappy with the idea of being considered “one of the good ones”, and that’s fair. That’s a good, solid topic to talk about. It doesn’t handle it PERFECTLY, cause it handles nothing perfectly. But it’s an important topic, and it handles it… okay.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/ao8S0FJ.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>This episode gets very off the rails in a way I don’t like where they use their Future Calculations to determine that the Federation has absolutely zero hopes of winning this war, so it’s either surrender and save people, we just have to put up with fascism, or keep fighting and 900 billion people will die.</p>

<p>Anyways I hate how Bashir is here, a lot. It gets even MORE off the rails when the Super Brains determine that they can just send Federation secrets to the Dominion, who’d then win the war in weeks, and only two billion would die. MUCH better! Time to go betray the Federation! After all, we’re gods who can determine this!! They knock Bashir out and leave him with the mute one. She lets him go, because she likes the violent one, I guess, and Bashir convinces her that this will ruin her chances with him or some shit???</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/XqcbIrK.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Anyways, Jack didn’t anticipate that, and yes, that’s the point of this. One person derailed their plans, so you can’t just guess the future using algorithms. AND YES. DUH. OF COURSE. OBVIOUSLY. WHY WAS THIS EVEN THE QUESTION?</p>

<p>Anyways this episode sucks and I kind of hate it. But I don’t really wanna go into it too much cause again, it’s a topic I’m uncomfortable even talking about.</p>

<p><strong>Statistical Probabilities</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/iN39qZW.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>The episode starts with Quark being his Quarky self, when he gets some bad news from the Nagus. Moogie has been kidnapped by the Dominion. Why would she be kidnapped? Who knows, doesn’t matter. What matters is Quark needs to rescue her, and he needs to put together a crackpot team of the galaxy’s best Ferengi. We’ve got Nog, obviously, his Moogie is captured. We’ve also got Rom, who is talked into it easily by being told he’ll be given Worf’s job on Quark’s ship, basically. We’ve also got a very weird Ferengi, his name is Leck. He’s an “Eliminator”, who doesn’t care about latinum, but is VERY excited to possibly kill some Dominion. And finally, Quark pays his cousin Gaila’s bail, to get him out of jail to help out. And as they’re all bickering and arguing, Ex-Liquidator Brunt shows up and offers to help, cause it might help him get his job back. No one likes him, but he has a ship, so…</p>

<p>And thus we have our team. A bartender, an outcast, a psychopath, a failed weapons dealer, a failed traitor, and the smartest man in the Alpha Quadrant. But even Rom being with them isn’t going to help. All of their training is not working out. Leck keeps shooting Moogie after everyone else runs away, cause hey, putting her out of her misery. But Rom, again being the smartest person in the Quadrant, says they’re playing to their weaknesses. Time to play to their strengths. They put in some favors with the Federation to get Keevan, the Vorta who was captured a few episodes ago, to trade. And they meet up on Empek Nor, the DS9 clone. Cool!</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/88mshWk.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>This episode is VERY goofy and stupid, because the Ferengi are goofy and stupid, but in a great way.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/oxi6UAw.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>The talks begin. It’s very Magnificent Seven, because the Ferengi all studied the movie before shooting lol. We’ve got the Vorta they’re dealing with, played by Iggy Pop, and he is dry and flat and I LOVE him. He’s VERY funny. Everything seems to be going well, actually! They make some good deals, and plan to exchange prisoners in a half hour. Unfortunately, Rom lets loose that the others aren’t getting a fair share of the payment, aaaaand shots are fires. Keevan is killed, and his last words are “I hate Ferengi”.</p>

<p>With no prisoner, what else can we do? We have one last plan…. use cortical stimulators to weekend at bernies Keevan.</p>

<p>That’s right. This is Magificent Seven meets Weekend at Bernies.</p>

<p>It’s tense, it’s a very tense situation, but they make it out, and get the element of surprise. Leck gets to kill his Jem’Hadar, which he’s VERY excited about, and they capture Iggy Pop to give to the Federation as a gift. And they leave, happily, as Keevans’ corpse walks into a wall over and over.</p>

<p>This episode is VERY funny, extremely enjoyable.</p>

<p>….Next week we’re gonna do DS9 to get a cycle going correctly, and TOTALLY not because next week has several Episodes Of All Time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 42</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/04/OOCY42.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 42" /><published>2024-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/04/OOCY42</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/04/OOCY42.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xlzZCh0.png" alt="&quot;It's just the ruels of the game. I get it, I get it... a kiss between friends of the same gender isn't a big deal.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s no big deal for two girls to kiss!</p>

<p>It’s no big deal for two girls to kiss deeply, their tongues intertwining as they wrap their arms around each other, hearts beating hard and fast as one wraps a leg around-</p>

<p>source: Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 41</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/03/OOCY41.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 41" /><published>2024-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/03/OOCY41</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/03/OOCY41.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cr8Le7i.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Shit, now that people aren’t immediately being thrown in jail for being gay, you see gay people all the time. I wonder why that is.</p>

<p>source: Ayaka is in Love with Hiroko!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Ayaka is in Love with Hiroko!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 40</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/01/OOCY40.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 40" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/01/OOCY40</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/01/OOCY40.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sckDqCq.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>By the way I uploaded yuri yesterday too but I forgot to hit go live until like midnight lol oops, so go back and look at that yuri too</p>

<p>source: Questionable Content</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Questionable Content" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 39</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/31/OOCY39.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 39" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/31/OOCY39</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/31/OOCY39.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8hJG52L.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UvtaDgn.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bovsomU.png" alt="" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Moon on a Rainy Night</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Moon on a Rainy Night" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 38</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/29/OOCY38.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 38" /><published>2024-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/29/OOCY38</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/29/OOCY38.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OcFYC3x.png" alt="Soft and springy white bread with a gentle sweetness, or rough and hard black bread? Which do I like? It has to be white bread! That's why I love girls!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Princess of the Princess</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Princess of the Princess" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 38</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/28/OOCY37.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 38" /><published>2024-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/28/OOCY37</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/28/OOCY37.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oUPqony.png" alt="&quot;Ah! A pretty girl!&quot; &quot;Eh?! Where?&quot; *T-poses*" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Princess of the Princess</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Princess of the Princess" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 117 - Earthbound/Mother 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 117 - Earthbound/Mother 2" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m40cwUj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>A month ago, September 20th in fact, I mastered Mother 1, and made a post about it. I should go back and change that post. I feel like I was focusing a bit too hard on Mother 1 and comparing it to Mother 2, and didn’t talk enough about what I liked about it. I’ll try to do a little less of that this time, though some of that will probably come out anyway. These two games are VERY comparable, because they’re very similar, at least in how they present themselves.</p>

<p>Earthbound, or Mother 2 in Japan, is often considered one of the best RPGs of all time. It is HIGHLY influential. And it booooombed. It did NOT do well over here, though giving credit to it, it DID actually come out here, unlike its NES prequel, Mother 1, which got translated but was never released. When I was a kid, I played Mother 1 thinking it was this game, and didn’t learn that I was wrong for like, months. When I DID finally play this game, I got into it, and stopped playing prooolly around after Threed. And that’s about the way it was, for years. This is the best RPG ever, you HAVE to beat it, I’d pick it up, play until around Fourside, and then stop.</p>

<p>This year though, I FINALLY beat it. And yeah. It’s good. Pretty good! I do see why people like it. But some parts of it fall…. flatter than I’d hope.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y1CHXvR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Earthbound is about a young boy named Ness, who lives in the town of Onett in Eagleland. One day, he’s woken up in the middle of the night by a meteorite falling onto the hill near his house. After some shenanigans with his bratty neighbor Porky, a fly named Buzz Buzz comes out, claiming he’s a hero from the future who is here to warn Ness, the Chosen one, that evil is on the rise. An evil named Giygas has come to destroy the world, and Ness must gather three friends and stop him. And then Buzz Buzz is swatted like a fly and dies.</p>

<p>That’s kind of how I’d describe this game. It’s got a big plot about friendship and banding together to overcoming terrifying odds and circumstances, and then its also filled with very goofy funny moments. It’s maybe a little jarring? You’ve got funny goofy moments that are nonsensical, like oh hey, you need to move forward but there’s a big metallic pencil in your way. Well don’t worry, just get your handy dandy pencil eraser, which will erase any pencils! And then you have scenes like the one where Poo is meditating and a spirit comes to rip off his arms, legs, eyes, ears, and brain, violently, and horrifyingly.</p>

<p>It’s got a little bit of a tone problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q62vZen.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s not to say that either of these moments are bad. They’re both good. And this game is really quite funny. I love the little inconsequential dialogue, I went around speaking to everyone, cause it’s just funny and enjoyable. Everyone’s got something weird to say.</p>

<p>Let’s talk about gameplay for a bit. There’s no run button, which IS pretty painful. The first game didn’t have one either… except for the American Beta, which added a run button. So this is kind of a step back, actually. It’s slow and plodding, which is a little painful tbh. IMO the pacing of this game is off, and it’s not jsut with how slow it runs, the game REALLY drags in the middle, and then it doesn’t pick up for a while. But anyways, the gameplay is still a Dragon Quest-ish JRPG, though this time you can have up to four characters. The backgrounds aren’t all black now, you’ve got some really frekaing cool effects back there, I’m a big fan. Also a big fan of the new rolling health system. As you take damage, your health ticks down. If you win before it ticks to zero, you live, and your health stops falling! You can also do a quick heal as it’s ticking down to save yourself. IMO this is an ingenius invention, and GREATLY improves things. As you panic and quickly mash through menus to heal Paula for the millionth time, it keeps turn based combat exciting and fun!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y7AeldK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One of the things that feels a bit downgraded over the NES version is actually the world itself. The NES game takes place on one giant contiguous map. You go out, you explore the world. You see how places connect and move together. This doesn’t quite have that. It’s more like, a few dozen maps stitched together with doors to and from. I don’t think it’s a big deal for most, but for me, it feels like a downgrade. You know what’s also a biiiit of a downgrade? The music. I know, I know, I KNOW you’re booing, but look, Mother 1’s soundtrack is fucking fantastic, and while Earthbound’s is very, very good, and I like it a lot, it doesn’t have a Pollyanna, or a Paradise Line, or a Bein’ Friends, or an All That I Needed, and definetely not an And Fallin’ Love or a Mother Earth. Sometimes I heard tracks from Mother put in this game as a remix and I got VERY excited, but they’re few and far inbetween. You hear a relaxing heartwarming rendition of Polyanna in Ness’s house, and a great remix of Youngtown in Paula’s house, but that’s about it. again, this is not to say the soundtrack is bad. It’s very good. And it’s got a LOT of really interesting things about it, and a lot of references.</p>

<p>Okay, let’s talk theming. Mother 2 has, in my opinion, a bit of a theming problem. Like I said, it’s a game about friendship and banding together to overcome powerful odds, constantly pushing through even if it’s scary, because that’s what you have to do. That second part, I think the game handles quite well. The final area is really intimidating and scary, and it and the final boss emphasise this part of the theme very well, in my eyes. It’s the friendship part where IMO the game falls flat… I don’t think I can imagine these people as being the best of friends. Poo shows up randomly and says “I am your friend now” and then leaves with the exact same energy. Jeff leaves the game with a “Well, call me if you need some appliances fixed”. All of the characters talk about have a bit more character than their counterparts in Mother 1…. maybe. Honestly it’s about the same. There’s not a lot of character here, and because of that, I can’t really feel like they’re best friends who are banding together. They’re just random characters being shuffled together as fate decides, because a psychic child had a dream that said they’d be best friends.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hIMnDYG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This also leads me to one of my other major problems with Earthbound. It’s a big retread of the previous game, and yet it also has NOTHING to do with it. The only thing that links these two stories together is the main villain, Giygas, who might as well be a completely different character. The game does nothing to actually explain the connecting bridge between the two games, and if you didn’t even know Mother 1 existed, like kids didn’t in the early 90s, you wouldn’t expect anything is out of line. Ninten, Ana, Lloyd, and Teddy might as well not even exist. They’ve been replaced. Now we have Ness, who is just Ninten again, Paula, who is just Ana again, and Jeff, who is just Lloyd again. Teddy has been replaced ENTIRELY with Poo, who’s his own thing, at least. But there’s a LOT of retreat ideas. Area under attack by zombies? Yep. A desert filled with a monkey cave? Yep. Collecting 8 parts of a musical piece? Yep. Musical act scene? Yep. Gotta do a thing so that the pubic transit works and you can go through the tunnel? Yep. Like, the thing is, most of these would feel like references to JP kids who played both, or at least I think it was intended to feel that way, but it feels more to me like they were just trying to make Mother 1 again. There are plenty of unique ideas, and they’re all quite good, but a lot of the retreating feels like it doesn’t fit the themes and is just… there. And yeah, there’s no connection to Mother 1 despite all this. I know a lot of fan theories, like Giygas erased Ninten and his family from the timeline, which broke him because he also erased his mother. Or Ninten is Buzz Buzz. I’ve heard all these theories. But that’s all they are, theories.</p>

<p>This doesn’t actually make the game bad in any way. I’d give this game an 8/10, it is a very good game, and I totally get why parts of it are very influential. But people kinda ignore the most obnoxious forgettable moments, and especially the pudgy middle section, as they just re-do the same really interesting parts over and over, like the final Giygas battle, which is VERY influential, and yes, quite good.</p>

<p>Well, there’s Mother 2 done. I really only have one more thing to do…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Mother" /><category term="Earthbound" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 36</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 36" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B7NVOLu.png" alt="&quot;Hey Aya, when we kissed and did that lewd stuff, what exactly were you thinking?&quot; &quot;This rocks. I'm so glad I'm alive right now. Thank God my parents made me take aikido classes.&quot; &quot;Noooo don't think about your parents while we're doing it, dammit!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Yuri Story About a Girl Who Insists “It’s Impossible for Two Girls to Get Together” Completely Falling Within 100 Days</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Yuri Story About a Girl Who Insists &quot;It&apos;s Impossible for Two Girls to Get Together&quot; Completely Falling Within 100 Days" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 8-13</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/27/LizstartrekVOY3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 8-13" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/27/LizstartrekVOY3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/27/LizstartrekVOY3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JD9myCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Future’s End II</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P5ZqPsw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Aaand we’re back. Tuvok is getting some burritos, hes a big fan of tex mex. I guess the whole “the Voyager appeared in the sky aand everyone saw it” thing isn’t really important, okay. They hand wave it with a “people think it’s faked”. Sure, I guess.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JZ85vJB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay, the more I watch this villain, the less I like him. He legit feels like a fucking mary sue in a fanfic. Oh, he had holo-emitters set up in his office, of course. Also he already reverse engineered a holo-emitter device that allows the doctor to move around freely. And he can use an apple PC to outsmart Voyager. Yes he’s using 500 year technology on them but that’s not how technology works, and that’s not how this works at all. If you give a computer to a dude from the 1100s he would be able to use it to defeat a conquistador, is what I’m saying. This ENTIRE concept is completely out the window, none of them are selling it, and since it’s the entire basis of the episode, it makes it less and less likable the more they push it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JYKtC69.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They warp Elon Musk up, which they should have done ages ago, with Sarah Silverman helping them out now. But of COURSE Elon Musk has a fucking machine that makes it so he can disrupt transport, which seems like a BAD idea, but also he’s a fucking dumbass. It DOES make Chakotay and Torres crashland in Arizona though, where they’re found by anti-government farmers who capture them, accuse them of beign spies, and threaten them with SPAS shotguns. Where the mother fuck did these people get military grade weapons? Also they keep insulting Chakotay because he’s a native. I hate this episode, I think. I think they’re implied to be WACO? JFC.</p>

<p>Elon Musk is trying to go to the future so he can steal more technology and sell it. It’s “for the betterment of mankind”. Eat my ass. Anyways he escapes, there’s some chase scenes, they also get Chakotay and Torres out. And when Elon Musk tries to fly in the future, they just blow him up with a sneaky photon torpedo. Then Braxton shows back up and takes them to the future. This episode made the first part worse by comparison. All the worst parts of the first episode are the parts this episode focused on. I’ll just pretend the Doctor can walk around freely now cause they bought it from a merchant or something.</p>

<p>This episode was originally planned to be a FOUR PARTER. Thank the fucking lord. Also, they wanted to bring Silverman on as a main character. That would have been SO GOOD, and made the episode at least okay. But no. Apparently Berman heard their offers and went “Absolutely not &gt;:(“ Cause MORE WOMS ON MY SHOW? ABSOLUTELY NOT. Fuck Berman.</p>

<p><strong>Warlords</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/65RG1O3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Neelix in the holodeck getting a foot massage, which seems like it might be a sex thing for them? Foomox.</p>

<p>Anyway this episode has nothing to do with that. They rescue three people from an exploding ship, though one of them dies as Kes is working on him. Kes immediately starts acting kinda weird, and breaks up with Neelix in an awkward scene, and then when they go to drop them off, she and the two survivors hijack a shuttle and fly down. Turns out that the guy who died, Tieran, is a mind jacking virus basically, who swaps bodies when he host dies. 200 years ago he was the ruler of this world, and he’s been working on starting a rebellion to place himself back where he belongs. So now Kes is an evil psychotic bitch, and is very, very sexy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ZdV98s.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She also seduces the 2nd son of the Autarch, after murdering his father right in front of him. So like, Tieran is a man. He was a man in life, he’s still assumedly a guy at heart. But I guess for a mind swapping virus, gender means little. But like, still a guy. And here he is, seducing a guy. This is one of the gayest things ever seen in Star Trek.</p>

<p>Tieran stays in Kes’s body because she has psychic powers and he can use it to kill and coerce people. Kes being evil is very hot, btw. Have I mentioned that? This episode is a lot less interesting for its actual plot and more for the weird kinkiness of all of it.</p>

<p>They try rescuing her, sending Tuvok on a solo mission. Tuvok is caught. They plan more things, but it seems like they may not need to. Kes is starting to win out in a mental battle, there’s a big “fight inside the mind” scene, I love those.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EEHyF2K.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Eventually, Tieran focusing on the battle within and becoming unstable makes his empire crumble around him. His fortress is stormed, and the Voyager crew go and take him out using a medical thingy the doctor made, wiping him out first from Kes, then from a person he tried to jump to again. The episode ends with Kes having severe PTSD about all the people who died cause of her hands. Also, she and Neelix just aren’t together anymore. Even though Tieran is the reason they broke up, she had no control. It’s never really explained, and there’s no conclusion. That’s weird.</p>

<p><strong>The Q and the Grey</strong> - VOY
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vTrO6uc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Q shows up and asks Janeway to fuck him. Hey, remember when we saw Q last time? In that episode, he was a sexist pig who treated Janeway like shit. Now he’s like “you’re so hot, fuck me”. This is EXACTLY how I expect weird sexist assholes acting. Hating on women but god damn they wanna get in that pussy. Anyways, he’s really, REALLY pushy, and I kind of hate it. He’s like “oh I’ve been lonely, havign dated anyone for a billion years”. I guess Vash is nothing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zYvKjSh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey, a female Q! She’s apparently basically married to our Q. She’s also played by Key’lar, the half Klingon who fucked Worf, and one of the hottest people in Star Trek. She’s a haughty bitch who hates everything here.</p>

<p>Anyways Q teleports Janeway to a civil war representation and explains to her that he started a war in the continuum, based on Quinn’s teaching, the Q that killed himself earlier in Voyager. So now he needs Janeway’s help, because he thinks if they make a new species with a half Q and Human, it’d end the war. I don’t see it, but I dunno. He also talk about how this has never been done, Q are beyond sex, no Q has ever done it. Uh, you rememebr that TNG episode with the Q that had a kid who didn’t know she was a Q? Cause the writers did not!</p>

<p>Anyways, this war is causing stars to go supernova, so it’s actually VERY bad. The female Q is stuck in subspace, without her powers for some reason, and she works with the crew to sneak through a supernova, while Q and Janeway are in the Continuum, represented by the American Civil War. They try to get a cease fire, and the traditionalist Q are like “Nope. Time to kill you both :)” and are only stopped cause the Voyager crew somehow show up loaded up to the gills with the Q’s own weapons, somehow. Q and Q fuck, which makes this the first time completely uncensored sex was shown on screen, and Q has a baby. I still don’t get this plan, but it works, I guess. No more explosions.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V1kVfEy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode kinda blows.</p>

<p><strong>Macrocosm</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RUDGoWy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway and Neelix are returning to Voyager after a chat with some new aliens that Janeway pissed off. They scan the ship to find it’s floating dead in space, and some interference is making it so they can’t scan for life signs. They wander around, trying to find out what happened, but find no one, like the crew just disappeared in the middle of what they were doing. Systems are failing all over the ship, including environmental controls. And they find signs of Goop burning holes in the hull. Yep.</p>

<p>We’re doing an Alien.</p>

<p>Neelix gets gooped and feels sick. Janeway leaves him to grab a medkit, and he screams, disappearing shortly after. Now it’s just Janeway, a missing crew, and an unknown alien. What does she do? That’s right.</p>

<p>Go full Ripley.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JD9myCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is legit one of the best fucking things, already.</p>

<p>The episode now becomes Alien meets Die Hard. It’s actuallty badass. She sneaks around, sending out an SOS. Meanwhile, some weird bugs are floating around, and they sting Janeway. Uh oh. She continues to go around, and finds the crew all piled up, alive, but barely, sick with something.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3EXS5z0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway blows away a buzzing alien whatever it is, and then makes it to Medbay, where the Doctor is, of course, still alive. Thankfully he hasn’t shut down yet. He tells a story about how they were called to help some miners on a nearby planet suffering from an outbreak. When he beams back, they accidentally spread the virus, and it gets out of hand. The Doctor can’t explore, because his holo emitter gives off infrared, which the viruses use to track their victims.</p>

<p>The Doctor and Janeway work together to release the cure onto the ship, as the aliens from the start come to “purify” them, cause the only cure is to blow them the fuck up :) Janeway convinces them to hold off for an hour, as she tricks the viruses into the holodeck in a very funny scene, and then fucking bombs it with a grenade.</p>

<p>Good episode, big fan. And not JUST cause Kate Mulgrew is hot as fuck.</p>

<p><strong>Fair Trade</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TTAsYI3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix is acting weird. He’s trying to get In with all the people on the ship, trying to get more jobs on, and he’s kinda just getting in the way. I wonder what that’s about. Meanwhile, they come across The Nekrit Expanse, a vast uncharted section of space. To go in prepared, they go to a local trading depot. The person who owns it takes 20% of all deals and is a grumpy guy, but he’s fair, and willing to help Voyagert get supplies. While on the station, Neelix finds an old friend, Wix, who he parted on bad terms with. Apparently Wix basically took a bullet for him years ago. Neelix feels awful and wants to help his old friend, who tyells him to not worry about it. Seems HIS life is going better, but Neelix explains how worried he is. He’s never been past the Nekrit Expanse. His job, as a guide, will soon be moot. So that’s why he’s trying to get more jobs. It’s understandable. He wants to stay on board.</p>

<p>Things get a biiiit worse. Wix wants Neelix’s help (using Voyager’s tech) to help him covertly secure a deal. Yep, it’s drug. He’s smuggling drugs. And after Neelix has to defend himself, with a phaser, he’s now implicated in all this, as they realize that the phaser was from Voyager, and are searching for either someone on the crew smuggling drugs, or someone who stole a phaser.</p>

<p>Neelix is now caught in a hard place. He has a friend, who he feels indebted to, and also the crew he’s a part of. It’s a bunch of awkward situations. Especialyl as the episode devolves with Neelix asking the crew about their histories, and what they’d do in a situation like his, basically. And all the guilt weighing on him. It’s not at all bad, in any way, but I don’t personally like it. Those kinda things just get to me and make me very upset.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FYNeT99.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He has to steal some warp plasma to pay off the drug dealers. I guess they’re gonna like, snort it? Warp Plasma Challenge, let’s gooooo. But he doesn’t do it. He can’t. I mean, he asks what did Paris in, and Paris responds with “I think my biggest downfall was I didn’t tell the truth”. Like, how can you fight that? That was set up way too well. It’s like they all KNOW Neelix is actually doing it.</p>

<p>Neelix and Wix manage to confess, but strike a deal, turning in the drug dealers in exchange for them not being charged.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QzZWEU3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some REALLY good alien designs in this episode. Anyways, Neelix outsmarts the drug dealers with a clever venting plasma scheme.  The episode ends with Janeway giving Neelix a “I am very disappointed in you, but we are family. We’ll get through this” speech. It’s a good Janeway moment. And now Neelix’s job as guide is done, and we’ll move on. This is good, in a way. One of the issues with the first two seasons was the feeling we kinda weren’t going anywhere.</p>

<p>This episode was fine. It did have “very special episode” energy, but not nearly as bad as that one TNG episode.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>