<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-28T09:59:55-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 117</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/28/OOCY117.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 117" /><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/28/OOCY117</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/28/OOCY117.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xd9VWbe.png" alt="Someone asked the other if they're a lesbian, and she just smiles and puts her hand on the other's surprised face." class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OK2zXjN.png" alt="The first, in surprise, explains that she's male, and the other shakes her head, kissing her hand and hair, stating the female symbol each time" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cuEjL5t.png" alt="She says one more female symbol, on the first's heart, and the two of them move together for off screen lesbian makeouts" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Childhood Friend Yuri(?)</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Friend Yuri" /><category term="trans" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 154 - Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchi Enji</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/26/RA154-Madou-Monogatari.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 154 - Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchi Enji" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/26/RA154-Madou%20Monogatari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/26/RA154-Madou-Monogatari.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UqwMby6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is the only Madou Monogatari game that has an achievement set on RA at the time of writing, so it’s actually my first game in the series I’ve ever played. Uh, kinda. I’ve actually played a LOT of Madou Monogatari! And you probably have too, or at least you’ve seen it a lot. But you probably have never heard that name before, unless you’re a massive turbo nerd, like I am. What IS it? Well, Madou Monogatari is an early 90s dungeon crawler series by Compile about a very young girl named Arle. Most of them are that like, first person dungeon crawler style that was popularized by Wizardry. They were good, but never came out over here, so no one in America knows a single thing about the series.</p>

<p>Except. The series DID come out here. The series had a spinoff, a little puzzle game called PUYO PUYO. You might have heard of it.  This series became MASSIVELY successful, and HUGELY popular. They greatly outstripped Madou Monogatari, to be point where the original series is very nearly just dead (there was a new one that came out last year, apparently, the first in 11 years, and 9 years before that one for the third most recent one). But these original games are still there. The Madou Monogatari series though, has a thing about it. It doesn’t really get new games in the series very often. What it DOES do is do remakes of the first game, over, and over, and over. This is one of those!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f5XMkpS.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is an RPG that is NOT a dungeon crawler, the first in the series like that. It’s more of a traditional JRPG, though a very weird one, and a retelling of the first game, though extended. I’d say it’s the plot of MM1 with 80% of the game taking place right before MM1, and the last dungeon is MM1. The plot is you’re Arle, a kindergartener, and your final exam is coming up. You need to travel the world, collecting items so you can make a wish for your exam ticket, and then take the exam to graduate! Along the way you’ll help people and meet a bunch of wacky characters, all of whom you’ll recognize from Puyo games, if you’ve played those, which you probably have.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hnV1rvt.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Most of the game is played in a top down style, where you’re running around, talking to people, exploring dungeons and the like. And the other half of the game is the random encounters and combat you get into. First you get a little dialogue between characters that is straight up the dialogues from Puyo games, then it’s KIND of traditional JRPG combat? This game series is actually quite weird, and the way I’d describe it, is it runs 100% on vibes. You don’t know your health. Or your MP, which all spells take. Or your opponent’s health. Or ANYTHING. That is gauged by the very extensive and quite good animations of Arle, and the opponents. And after attacks you’ll be told a little thing, like “The Puyo is not feeling so good!”. There are like, 10 different levels of damage, and you’ll need to learn a general idea of how hurt an enemy is, and how hurt YOU are.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JuYvnwV.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>On the main field, you can gauge your health by Arle’s big-ass face that’s always right there at the bottom, at all times. There’s also some orbs down there, that’s your EXP, when all those fill up, you level up. You can view your stats on your report card, and it gives a general description of you, ranging from “A wimp” to “Kind of scary”, which is a very funny way to describe a 4 year old.</p>

<p>So yeagh, I described the JRPG mechanics of this game as “baby’s first JRPG”. It’s entirely run on vibes, not hard to pick up, and very simple. Unfortunately, the rest of the game doesn’t hold up quite as well. Random encounters are very common, so it’s slow paced, and the dungeon design in this game is honestly just kind of bad. This game is half of the same rooms pasted over and over, honestly, in giant door mazes. It’s really disappointing.</p>

<p>While there’s a lot to like about Madou Monogatari: Big Kindergarten Kids, as it’s translated, there’s also a lot to detract from it. I think its style and presentation is utterly FANTASTIC, it is a GORGEOUS Super Famicom game. Which it should be, It’s a 1996 SFC game, that’s pretty damn late. I’d really only recommend this if you’re really curious, a huge puyo fan, or a Madou Monogatari fan who’s somehow never played this, but I dunno how many of YOU read my blog.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Madou Monogatari" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 116</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/25/OOCY116.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 116" /><published>2025-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/25/OOCY116</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/25/OOCY116.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zQXHULq.png" alt="'I had two or three love affairs with girls myself when I was young &lt;3 So I totally get the way you're feeling! Don't tell your dad.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Concerto</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Concerto" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 11 - 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/23/LizstartrekDS97-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 11 - 15" /><published>2025-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/23/LizstartrekDS97-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/23/LizstartrekDS97-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/taINSsm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Prodigal Daughter</strong> - DS9
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mOuLab4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>O’Brien is missing! He was hunting down the widow of Bilby, the gangster he befriended last season, and is now missing. I can’t believe we’re STILL doing Bilby episodes, for an episode I just kinda liked, it sure does get mentioned a lot.</p>

<p>Ezri’s mom basically helps run the area where he was last seen, so Ezri is sent there to try and get any leads. Unfortuantely, Ezri has a pretty rocky relationship with her mother, who seems a bit controlling. And that was BEFORE she became joined. Now she’s basically a new person, so it’s gotta be even weirder.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4BKgx2K.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ezri’s family is very VERY uncomfortable to watch. Like, her mother is the worst. Very controlling in that “I’m offended if you think this is bad” kind of way. We also find out pretty quickly that things aren’t on the up and up here. They’re clearly doing some kind of business with the Orion Syndicate, who if you remember, are the guys Bilby worked with in that older episode.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Q8j1GyY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Watching this woman on stream is agonizing.</p>

<p>Anyways, some cops drag O’Brien in during an argument with mommy dearest. He’s beat to shit, both by the cop and also by some Orion thugs. He found Bilby’s widow’s corpse in a river, and is CONVINCED the Syndicate killed her. Usually the Orion Syndicate doesn’t kill its own people like that, unless something is up. I mean, that deranged loyalty is the thing that allows them to control their operatives, but O’Brien is CONVINCED. Ah well, not much he can do about that now, so he’s going to at least help out around the house with some engineering problems they’re having.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Ezri’s youngest brother is having a nervous breakdown, ripping his art up. There’s stuff about how he hates his art, it’s not good enough, but his mother keeps forcing him to like, put it up on the wall and shit, and it’s embarassing him and making him feel powerless. Ezri is doing that Counseling thing where she’s analyzing everything and everyone just by looking at them for three minutes.</p>

<p>Anyways we start to see some stuff. This slimy smarmy mother fucker has been sabatoging their mining equipment, because they fired an Orion operative, and he wants him reinstated. He also warns the older brother, who seems to be in on the executive side of the business, that O’Brien is with Starfleet Intelligence, and is looking for a Morica Bilby, which seems to worry the brother. Ahhh, he knows something… O’Brien is also VERY good at discovering things, and is getting closer to figuring out The Truth, so the older brother wants him gone. He finds out what happened before he leaves, though, and Ezri confronts the family about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6Zici3f.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Shockingly, the mother is kind of on our side about this. She had nothing to do with the syndicate. The older brother got them hooked up in it out of fear, and cause he had this job forced onto him by his mom. Bilby was basically forced upon Ezri’s family. Widows like her are given cushy jobs with no actual job to do, so she was here, but she was unhappy with her pay, so she argued with them, aaaand the younger brother killed her. He cracks and confesses very easily, and Ezri convinces the older brother to also just… leave. And when her mom is like “This isn’t MY fault is it???” uh, yeah, it was. Ezri leaves, the murder is solved, nothing of value is gained.</p>

<p>Someone in chat called this “a sketch of a Murder, She Wrote plot”. Yeah, basically.</p>

<p><strong>The Emperor’s New Cloak</strong> - DS9
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/slqLwGL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Zek’s gone missing! Quark assumes he’s just sluttin’ and fuckin’ with the bad bitches on Riza, but then Ezri shows up and pulls a knife on him. It’s hot. Quark finds it hot too, but Ezri is disgusted. Turns out The Grand Nagus went to the Mirror Universe to open business relations with them. Instead, he got captured, and they’re demanding cloaking technology, or he’s dead. And Quark’s the only one who can help. Quark? Of all people? Huh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1k7v4z1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They steal the cloaking device from the Klingon ship, and then cloak it, and we get a scene of Rom and Quark pantomiming carrying a heavy thing down the hall which is very funny. Ezri’s actress does a lot of flexing here, it’s great to watch. Quark and Rom follow her to the mirror universe to make sure that they get the Nagus back, cause they can’t trust the regent, and they immediately see Mirror!Bashir shoot Mirror!Vic. We get to see Mirror Vic JUST to watch him die, damn. Smiley is still nice and chill, but Mirror!Bashir is a lunatic. He’s especially grumpy because Mirror!Jadzia apparently died recently. Just couldn’t let ANY version of Jadzia escape unscathed, could you, Berman???</p>

<p>Zek, to Mirror!Kira: “You have such nimble fingers, my dear…”
Mirror!Kira: “How many times have I heard that??”</p>

<p>Mirror!Kira is ALWAYS the top. Anyways she’s being her terrible self at Zek, it’s great. She’s ALSO been captured, and is in jail with Zek.</p>

<p>Mirror!Brunt saves them. He’s a pleasant nice guy. He also loves Mirror!Kira, but Mirror!Kira is gay, so he just… sticks with her. Not at ALL like our Brunt. They bring the cloaking to Worf, who is like “what? Why would I give you the Nagus?” It was a setup. A setup for THIS!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rhSKp4p.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ezri’s been with the Regent all along! And she had a deal with Worf to get out scott free, if she gets Ezri, her new toy, to bring a cloaking device. They gay kiss and everything. This is the first gay kiss on Star Trek that can’t be hand waved by “Actually one of them was once a guy when they were married so it’s not gaaaay”. Nah, these bitches gay. Unfortunately for the Regent, she gets all Nutso and stabs Brunt, when Brunt tries to suggest that they should let the Ferengi go, cause why not, and Ezri actually LIKED Brunt. So is she going to help them escape? She offers to help them escape if Rom installs the cloakign device but uh, yeah, that was also a trick. They’re not letting them go. Rom is REALLY starting to hate this universe.</p>

<p>Also there’s a good gag where Mirror!Kira is whispering in Mirror!Worf’s ear, and he goes “I never thought about doing that THERE” “oh, most men don’t but they all love it after I put it in”. Holy shit she’s suggesting pegging him. Oh my fucking god this episode is so funny. There’s ALSO more really funny lines where they distract Garak by telling him how much better THEIR Garak is. And then it turns out, Rom was SMART and sabatoged the ENTIRE ship! So the rebels beat the shit out of them, and Mirror!Ezri shows up to rescue them. Turns out she got a conscious after all. She kills Mirror!Garak, sadly, and then lets Mirror!Kira go.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V9kwkd0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Quark shoots his shot at Mirror!Ezri and is immediately turned down as she starts flirting with Mirror!Leeta. Welp, you tried Quark. Zek is like “wow this universe is great”, as if lesbians don’t fucking exist in the Prime Universe.</p>

<p>And that’s it! That’s thje last time we’ll see the Mirror Universe. Well, until Enterprise, but this is the last one for a very long time, and in this timeline. It sets it up nicely for more stuff, there’s a big paradigm shift, but Mirror!Kira is still out there. Good for books I guess? Also, Mirror Leeta is here for like 5 seconds, has three lines, and becomes a MASSIVE force and antagonist in Star Trek Online which is very funny.</p>

<p>Good note for the Mirror Universe to go out on.</p>

<p><strong>Field of Fire</strong> - DS9
5.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xBGnph2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Yet another Ezri episode. They’re trying to get her caught up to speed as much as they can, I guess. I don’t MIND it, I don’t hate Ezri. I just wish she had better material.</p>

<p>Our episode starts with this new guy, Liutenant Ilario, who everyone is like “Oh it’s ILARIO, OUR BEST BUD!” He’s chill and flirts with Ezri. I can’t wait to see this character for episode to c-</p>

<p>Yeah, he’s dead. Ezri wakes up the following day and finds that he’s been killed, by being SHOT. Guns?? Turns out it looks like it was the TR-116, a prototype rifle that the Federation was working for when phasers don’t work, dampening fields and stuff. Ezri takes his death pretty hard, and then has nightmares the following night, with Joran Dax.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R2TQnXl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>If you don’t remember Joran, he’s the host who did murders, and then got written out of existence. But he’s still there. Still in Dax, his memories still very alive. The nightmares involve Joran explaining that he can help, because he knows the murderous mind so well. The dream is in like, shit-FPS, but it’s inconsistant. Good effect. She wakes up to find another guy dead.</p>

<p>They find out how these people keep getting killed by point blank range from a bullet, alone in their rooms. The rifle has a transporter stapled onto it, which allows them to fire through walls and teleport a bullet rIGHT next to the target. This is the perfect assassin weapon. And ALSO, notably, the perfect anti-Borg weapon, so I guess we’ll never see it again, huh?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UADeoXE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She summons Joran, and he explains the conceit of the episode very clearly. “If you wnat to catch a serial murderer, you have to think like one.” It works for a time, she puts on the weapon and scans through the docking ring for people to kill, aaaand then he’s like “GOOD NOW DO MURDER”. Oh no, I can’t believe this backfired. But she keeps working with him anyway. Even after she almost STABS someone under his guidance. Everyone is like “Ezri is cracking, oh no.”</p>

<p>She finally sees a connection between all the victims, after a third one shows up. They all have one thing in common. They have pictures in their room of someone laughing. With that, she decides it’s someone who hates emotion, and decides its a Vulcan. That’s a weird leap, but whatever. And when a Vulcan steps into the elevator with her, Joran is like “oh thats our killer. KILL HIM NOW”. This actor is trying his best but the serial killer who wants to kill everyone around him energy is getting old.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AJwOUvf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She watches him in the rifle scope, and turns out he’s actually about to shoot her. So she shoots him first. Joran is like “YES, DO IT”, like he’s fucking Palpatine, and then she calls for medical team instead. When asked why he did it, he explains “because logic demands it”. Uh. Okay. She then sends away Joran, and we’re done.</p>

<p>I mostly this one just kind of eh.</p>

<p>Apparently this serial killer, Chu’Lak, shows up again in Prodigy as Janeway’s chief science officer?? Weird.</p>

<p><strong>Chimera</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N6wjjSF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode starts with Odo being a Wife Guy and bringing Kira two gifts from a trip. O’Brien forgot to get one for Keiko so he offers to buy one. And then suddenly they’re overtaken by some wibbly thing in space that then disappears, and blorp, out of the vents comes a fucking Changeling.</p>

<p>Turns out he’s one of the 100 Changeling babies that was sent out years ago. He sensed Odo and wanted to meet him, he’s been searching for more Changelings for years. He’s NOT a Founder, they’re all infected right now and he’s fine. His name is Laas. He’s been around for 200 years, far more than Odo’s 30. He never quite connected with the people who found him, and now he’s been searching for others like him. He doesn’t HATE humanoids, but he distrusts them, cause they’ve treated him pretty poorly. Apparnetly he also had a wife but she wanted kids, so they seperated. This leaves insidious thoughts in Odo. Odo, y’all can just adopt, it’s fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K66b4zp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the first gay sex on Star Trek, yay</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xdo2RLB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Odo introduces Laas to his friends. Laas insults them all by being a racist. And then when Odo refuses to link with him right in the middle of the Promenade, he’s like “Ah, you’re afraid of making anyone think you’re a Changeling, you’re hiding your true nature”. Dog, I don’t walk around town with my tits out, this ain’t rocket science. We don’t fuck other people in public, that’s just a rule of society. I’m sorry you seem to think that’s wrong, but like, my man, that’s how our society works.</p>

<p>I mostly find this guy insufferable tbh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NTGbY5u.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kira is bothered by the fact that she can’t link with Odo, and is also afraid he’s just going to leave with this random shmuck. He thinks Odo is just patronizing her. I mean, it’s understandable. Remember when Odo was fuckin’ the female changeling and he was SO bimbofied he almost let the entire Alpha Quadrant die?</p>

<p>Laas turns into fog into the promenade. This freaks out some Klingons who attack him, and Laas kills one of them in a T-1000 style. Now Odo is surrounded by people who are suddenly distrustful of him, and it’s bother him, very deeply. He’s realizing their tolerance only goes so far… <em>Cause he’s one of the good ones</em>. Quark literally tells him this isn’t the time to throw a pride parade on the promenade. I… don’t THINK it’s an LGBT metaphor, but considering there was canonical gay sex on screen just earlier, y’know.</p>

<p>Christ the longer we watch this, the more I think, it IS an LGBT metaphor. Like, maybe not intentionally, but it feels like it. “I need to be able to exist! As MYSELF! Without judgement!”</p>

<p>All of the people being like “HE MUST BE PUT ON TRIAL, HE’S A MURDERER” about this are being fucking idiots and it’s weirdly out of character. Worf is \hard on this, cause he’s a racist in this episode, because Worf is always the resident conservative racist when he wants to be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ccFGgC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Odo tells Kira he wishes he was out there with him instead, and so Kira lets Laas escape, because she loves him and wants him to be happy. And not feel like he has to be here out of a sense of obligation. It’s quite sad. But Odo goes to tell Laas, yes, he’s staying. Because he doesn’t understand. He doesn’t understand what it is to LOVE someone, especially love them enough to let them go. He’s staying for one reason. And that’s Kira. Laas tells him love is just fake nonsense to distract from the loneliness without the Link. Odo’s like “Nah,” and thats that.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/s04LgJD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kira apologizes to Odo if he ever felt he couldn’t be himself around her, and then she basically bathed in him as she turns into aurora borealis around her. It’s a cute ending.</p>

<p><strong>Badda-Bing, Badda-Bang</strong> - DS9
10/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CV5gbsg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>YAY MORE VIC!</p>

<p>Vic is doing a show for O’Brien and Bashir, when suddenly the holosuite just fucking changes to a completely different club, and some mobster guy shows up, announces he bought the casino, and is throwing Vic out. Bashir and O’Brien can’t freeze the program or delete these new characters. It’s a “Holodeck gone wrong, but the holodeck knows it went wrong” episode which is cute. Though these new characters aren’t self aware like Vic is.</p>

<p>They could turn it off and reset the program, which will reset Vic’s memory and erase him, basically, which uh, that’s bad. It also turns out it’s a Jack in the Box, which is a thing in a holosuite program that changes it up as a bit of a surprise. Everyone on DS9 bands together to try and save Vic. Oh, except Worf and Sisko. Sisko is like “Why aren’t you working??”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CpRLzDU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Vic gets roughed up, so O’Brien and Bashir help him out and help him stay low, while Odo and Kira investigate into this new villain, Franky Eyes. They are VERY good at this. Kira just has to be hot, which isn’t hard, and she gets in with Frankey, and Odo gets in with his thugs by doing bar tricks (he extends his arm and grabs a drink). Everyone is EXTREMELY good at this. Their plan is hatched: THey need to rob the casino, so Franky can’t pay his mob boss.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/su4t0R3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out the reason Sisko is annoyed by everyone shillin’ for Vic. He’s annoyed because Las Vegas 1962 was a racist time, but the program ISN’T racist, and it’s not accurate. Kinda weird, Sisko, but whatever. His girlfriend asks him to try and come to grips with it. So he does. They need ONE more man for the plan, to be the high roller who distracts. That will be Sisko. We’ve got our plan. It shows it all, heist movie style. It’s great. Lots of distracting and set ups so that Nog can open the safe with his Ferengi ears, and Odo IS THE SERVING TRAY, TAKE A DRINK!!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/taINSsm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is one of the best shots in all of DS9. Except for all the shots that has Ezri with her spots all the way down in that amazing god damn outfit holy hell in a handbasket.</p>

<p>The plan starts. Things don’t go nearly as well as they hoped, but it never does in heist movies, does it? Everyone has to improvise on their feet. The safe is a different kind of tumbler lock than Nog expected. A patron knocks into Ezri as she’s delivering the martini. They need a distraction? Sisko makes it rain. Just tosses money into the air randomly yelling “EVERYONE’S A WINNER!” It’s great.</p>

<p>It works out. They manage it, with a few messes, but Vic’s is back, baby.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1CtF7QL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get one last scene in the end with Sisko and Vic doing a duet. It’s great.</p>

<p>Why don’t people like the Vic episodes? What is WRONG with them???? Vic is legit the best part of late era DS9?!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 115</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/23/OOCY115.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 115" /><published>2025-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/23/OOCY115</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/23/OOCY115.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2KtJJKG.png" alt="'My hand really outdid itself when I needed it to! You're such a gifted hand!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class’s Green Tea Bitch</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class&apos;s Green Tea Bitch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 114</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/22/OOCY114.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 114" /><published>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/22/OOCY114</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/22/OOCY114.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLrthkI.png" alt="'come to think of it... how DOES it happen between girls...?' - INADEQUATE THEORETICAL KNOWLEDGE" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Please Bully Me, Miss Villainess!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Please Bully Me Miss Villainess!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 153 - Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon - Another Story</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/22/RA153-SailorMoon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 153 - Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon - Another Story" /><published>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/22/RA153-SailorMoon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/22/RA153-SailorMoon.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lsBIgxe.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Still playing a bunch of RPGs, trying ones I’d never really seen or played before. Double Moon Densetsu and Ghost Lion kinda burned me by being just okay, but SURELY this one will be good right? I mean, it’s SAILOR MOON! I like Sailor Moon! I’m a girl in her 30s who grew up watching it, of COURSE I like Sailor Moon, that’s like, the law. Uh, no. Sadly, no. This one is pretty damn mid.</p>

<p>This Sailor Moon game is an RPG for the Super Famicom, and it is the most fanfictiony thing I’ve ever seen in my god damn life. Basically, the plot is there’s an evil powerful shaman who gains control over time, and she sends her bad guy five-girl squad into the past to change history, so that the Sailor Scouts are defeated and she can rule. Simple, and quite fitting for Sailor Moon, right? That’s pretty typical stuff. What makes it fanficky is that they’re changing the fates of characters we know, EXPLICITELY so that the Sailor Scouts (you can tell I’m from the 90s, they’re not called that anymore) can fight enemies from their past. We get retreads of all the villains from season 2 and 3 of Sailor Moon. We DO also fight Beryl, though her five goon squad are actually good guys in this game. I guess the writers liked them too much.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/U1TNO42.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a time travel timey wimey plot, and like true fanfiction, it makes NO fucking sense. It has no care for scale, or plot, or consistancy. It falls apart under the SLIGHTEST scrutiny. I’m not about to sit here and tell you that this sailor moon game is bad though because it has plot holes, that’d be dumb. If anything, it helps. It’s VERY fun to point and laugh. What the fuck is this weird cult-like town that’s in the middle of Canada that you visit? Why did it exist thousands of years ago during the Silver Era???? Where are the natives? Oh it doesn’t matter. Like I said, it’s fun to laugh at.</p>

<p>The one thing I REALLY did not like in the plot was the decision to take the Goon Squad from the second half of season 2 (in other words, the good half), and change their fate. Unlike EVERY other villain in the game that we fight, these are the actual same normal girls. Like, for example, you fight Sailor Saturn’s dad, who was brought back to life and back to the moment where he was a villain. That’s like an AU version of him dragged here. But the Spectre Sisters are EXPLICITELY the same Spectre Sisters from our universe. They settled down and quit being villains and are living a happy life…. except now that time travel fate changing powers are in play, they join in and get themselves killed pathetically, throwing themselves at you one after another in one on five boss fights, just for the chance of maybe grasping victory again. It’s a slap in the face from their story conclusion in Sailor Moon R &gt;:(. I’m angy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cWWI4St.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Goon Squad this go-round are the Oppositio Senshi, who are basically just evil-sailor scouts. They’re all assigned a Sailor Scout to be the opposite of, and they’re kinda like that Scout, taken to an extreme. They’re also all named after Mesopotamian gods. Nabu is Mars’ counterpart, she’s cold and calculating, but to an extreme, with little empathy. Ishtar is Venus’ counterpart, she’s aloof and goofy, but taken to an extreme. You get the idea. Sin is the leader, and she’s focused on helping and saving her friends and family… <strong>No matter what</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oWgMaw0.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So that’s the story. How’s the gameplay? It’s uh…. it’s boring! In this game, you mostly walk through hallways, and occasionally open mini-dungeons and door mazes, fighting random encounters that will NOT threaten you, because Sailor Saturn is UNBELIEVABLY BUSTED. And if you have Sailor Pluto on your side, good fucking luck to the opponents. She can freeze time for 3 turns, heal her MP, then cast it again, and stun lock you down. This works on EVERY boss. But what if you don’t have them on your team, due to story reasons? Well, then you grind. This game is VERY grindy, and unbalanced. Poor Sailor Mars gets the short end of the stick, she’s basically useless. Which is really a shame, because she’s my favorite Scout. The first chapter is the Scouts all splitting up, and you do a small mini chapter with each of them. Mars’ chapter is agonizing, because she does NO damage, and is made of paper. She has heals and support stuff, but that doesn’t help when its just her. Oh also, these mini chapters with all the scouts alone? The mini-plotlines in them all have the Scouts fall in love with some random OC made for that mini-chapter. Uh, Ami has a boyfriend, game. He’s even brought up and mentioned.</p>

<p>The art is really nice. It’s cool that they have all the Scouts in there. They have this team up system where you can learn skills with Scouts fighting together. You have this menu, plop two Scouts together, and if they have a teamup skill, you learn it. It takes like 5 minutes to plop them all together. The music is forgettable. All in all, this RPG is just extremely mid, which is a shame. It’s very interesting as a fan of Sailor Moon, but for ANYONE else, it’s not worth it at all. It’s also interesting because the game was made AS Sailor Moon S was being worked on, so they had to look at the notes for what the Outer Senshi were going to be like, but had no idea who the hell they were cause the devs hadn’t watched that part of the anime yet. That’s kinda funny.</p>

<p>Anyways, meh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Sailor Moon" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 152 - Math Gran Prix</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/20/RA152-Math.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 152 - Math Gran Prix" /><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/20/RA152-Math</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/20/RA152-Math.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0YVOeuW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing my random “I want to play Atari Games” kick, this is Math Gran Prix. This is also the only game I’ll prolly post with only ONE picture cause uh, that’s it. It’s just this screen. You control one of the two cars. You choose to move 2 or 3 spaces, then do a math problem. If you do it right, you move that number of spaces. Some of the spaces on the board change how you move, like letting you move ahead random spaces, or letting you choose again. If either of you land on each other, it stuns the other.</p>

<p>It’s basically a REALLY shitty math board game. There’s no strategy, it’s dead simple, and the AI is a shithead that cheats, ALWAYS staying right behind you and knocking you away at the worst point. It’s very annoying. I THOUGHT this game would be a goofy little fun time with a bad game, but it was mostly annoying.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Atari" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 113</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/20/OOCY113.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 113" /><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/20/OOCY113</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/20/OOCY113.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F8jX2h9.png" alt="'It's a bit embarassing to have Kanata look straight at me like this...' *They're dating and live together." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: My Love for My roommate Was One-Sided</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="My Love for My roommate Was One-Sided" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 112</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 112" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cgmpP2V.png" alt="'So this is a date...' The other girl stares in confusion. 'Yes?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Voice First, Face Second, Hollyhock</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Voice First Face Second Hollyhock" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>