<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-11T13:20:36-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 21</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/11/OOCY21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 21" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/11/OOCY21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/11/OOCY21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YCcHDX7.png" alt="A woman holding up a smart phone. &quot;We need to get rid of this oppressive symbol of reality.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Futari Escape</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Futari Escape" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 12 - Avianos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 12 - Avianos" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50#12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-12.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uEJP5VD.png" alt="Avianos" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the most out there games of the entire collection, just showing that despite LX Systems not really having much commercial success in this period, they were making some REALLY out there and fascinating games. And, frankly, EXTREMELY uncommercial. Fuckin’ look at this thing.</p>

<p>This is also the first game in a bit with some new members of the crew, joining the team with the start of 1985. Y’all, meet Ester Mac and Shayn North. Ester is a programmer, and did the AI here, and Shayn is a graphics guy. We’ve also got KC Levin on testing, and Smolski’s nephew, Boby Smolski, who helped with dinosaur fun facts around the office. The office is getting pretty packed! It’s also worth noting that of the 9 different staff members, 3 are women. That’s <em>unheard of</em>. I mean, there were LOTS of women in tech in like the 50s 60s and 70s, but they had pretty much been kicked out of the profession by men by that point. LX Systems was a very progressive studio, in a lot of ways.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tP7S01s.png" alt="Avianos" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Avianos is a 4x game. In 1985. It’s the far future, Humans blew each other the fuck up, and now it’s the reign of the birds. But they’re going down the same dark path as the mammals, and waging war, worshipping ancient Dinosaur gods. In this 4X strategy game, your goal on each map is to keep and hold 4 or more fortresses. You do this by praying to your gods, which each do three things when you pray to them. These things range from moving units to another square, taking ownership of it, gathering resources based on your buildings, building new buildings, recruiting units, or using magic spells like freezing enemy units or spying on how many units are in a space. Every two times you worship an ancestor, their favori will increase, allowing you to upgrade one of their three actions to a better form. This results in a LOT of variance and strategy.</p>

<p>Seriously, this game is pretty deep, and I bet multiplayer is WICKED.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nwOFhZJ.png" alt="Avianos" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When your units collide, the game enters an auto-combat mode. The only things you can tell your units to do are to attack, hold, run, or destroy your own buildings if you know you’re going to lose and don’t want the enemy taking it. It’s shockingly deep. A lot of my strategy WAS just to build a Giant Murderball, but hey, what works works, y’know? There’s a lot of good strategies that work.</p>

<p>This game is some wicked fun, and is SUPER interesting. But also very intimidating, and you’ll have NO clue what you’re doing at first. It’s like a little boardgame more than a video game, but hey. I like board games.</p>

<p>8.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 11 - Kick Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-11.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 11 - Kick Club" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50#11</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/11/UFO50-11.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/crDGaLM.png" alt="Kick Club" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This one is one of my favorites of the collection. Kick Club is a single screen action arcade game, in the same vein as Bubble Bobble. Games like this, inspired usually by Bubble Bobble, were quite commonplace back  in the day, especially in arcades. They were tough as nails, and fun as hell with friends.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4vxVSBO.png" alt="Kick Club" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Kick Club you play as either a guy or a girl running through sports themed worlds. You’ve got net sports, olympic sports, ice sports, and ball sports. Your only defense against the denizens of these worlds is your trusty soccer ball, which you can kick, aiming with the d-pad, to defeat enemies. As they’re defeated, you’re awarded junk food. Quite fitting for a fitness themed game, obviously. You can chain enemies to get better junk food. Go for the high score!</p>

<p>It’s a simple game. Ten levels for four worlds, the last level being a boss fight. There’s not much to it and it’s not too long, but it is a tricky little game. Quite challenging. You’ve gotta learn all the enemies and their patterns! It’s a really fun one though, and the music is REALLY catchy. I wake up some days with this in my head.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QIFnFYX.png" alt="Kick Club" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I don’t have much more to say about this one. The credits give special thanks to Chun and Smolski’s childhood coach, and the local burger joint, but it’s still made by the core team. It’s just a cute and very fun game. Apparently there was a VS mode that was planned, but didn’t make it in in time. Honestly, the game is fine without it. The co-op is prolly loads of fun, too.</p>

<p>9/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 20" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R0AaJwj.png" alt="&quot;A woman kabedoning another with her leg&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Black &amp; White</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Black &amp; White" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 9 - Attactics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 9 - Attactics" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50#9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-9.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EUTyCA2.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>We’ve got the core team for LX Systems, there won’t be too many changes for at least a little while, so there’s not much to say about this game other than to talk about the game itself.</p>

<p>Attactics is a strategy action game that’s pretty different from anything I’ve played. It’s a realtime turnbased game. You’ve got a 5x8 grid, and units will spawn randomly on each side of it. Those units will then move every single turn, depending on what kind of unit they are. Turns go automatically, every few seconds. However, you can grab and shift your units, moving them up and down, or back. You can shift and swap units this way, as well, for maximum strategy. When a unit kills another, it gets a promotion and deals extra damage. The goal is to just get enough units to the enemy’s side, to knock down all their flags, and you win!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/McWFLo1.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got a bunch of unit types, each with different strengths and weaknesses. Grunts will be immune to melee damage if they’re in a column of 3 or more units. Archers will shoot from afar if a unit is in their sight, instead of moving. Shieldmen are tanky as fuck and can block arrows. Cavalry move twice, good for sneaking through weak spots and getting quick damage in. Spearmen attack two spaces instead of just 1, through units, good for hiding behind shieldmen. Assassins will throw daggers up and down as they walk. Sappers will explode when they die, which blows up the enemy, but can ALSO blow YOU up. Aaand then there’s heroes, unique units that happen every 5 promotions on certain stages, and they move twice as far, pierce two stages, and start promoted like, 5. They’re good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9TJpbvh.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And that’s it! Battles are tense and hectic. The AI can’t move at all, so it usually gets like, 70% more units to compensate. I imagine multiplayer is WILD. The description of the game explains that the game was delayed cause the devs just wouldn’t stop playing it, and the credits show that “Chiffon the Strong” was the office champion. It just shows how the vibe was in those days at the office. Their games aren’t selling… amazingly, but they’re loving what they’re doing.</p>

<p>This one was pretty alright, and then grew on me a bit more. It’s nothing amazing, but it’s fun for what it is. And not super long.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 10 - Devilition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 10 - Devilition" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50#10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-10.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tInZkFa.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Devilition has an interesting IRL story behind it. So I’ve been talking about the in-universe characters who supposedly made these games, and are credited as such, but there’s a REAL actual team of actual people who made them, and they kinda split up the work, each person creating a few different games. I’m not sure who created what, exactly, except for a few of them where it’s obvious (Hello Velgress/Upwell). In this case, it’s obvious, because in 1999 Derek Wu created a game called Diabolika. That game was repurposed for UFO 50, with some touch ups and changes. Apparently in the original, the little devils had big swinging dongs. They don’t got that here. There’s a few other changes, too, I’ll get into those.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EjakEoN.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Devilition is a puzzle game where you play an alchemist trying to keep a town of puritan-esque settlers alive from a horde of Demons. Each round, devils are placed randomly about the board, and then you can place your pieces anywhere on the grid. When these contraptions explode, they explode in different directions, signified by the colors emenating from them. So you’ve got ones that explode in a cross, an X shape, you’ve got ones that blast out further, ones that blast all around, ones that do 3 spaces in front of them, ones that only do side to side, aaaand the rocket, which will blast up then fall on a space, blasting all around. Your goal is to try to kill as many Devils as you can this way, while avoiding the settlers. At the end of a round, if the settlers outnumber the devils, you move on. If not, you lose, start over. If you get rid of ALL the demons, you get an extra settler. You can kill your settlers all you want, which is fucked up, all that matters is that they are equal or outnumber the demons. After ten rounds, you fight a boss, who’s actually extremely easy, and you’re given a score based on your time, pieces used, and settlers left.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a0Lz65u.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And that’s it! It’s not a very complex puzzle game, and while it seems okay at first, it falls a bit flat to me on repeat plays. I acknowledge I’m not very good at this game. It is not kind to those with ADHD. I get distracted and suddenly forget an entire third of the board is there, or think I planned out a way to deal with THAT ONE devil, and nope, I forgot about it again. But the real thing about this is that it’s a bit of an RNG fest. The game can absolutely give you unwinnable situations, especially if it clumps a bunch of the devils together that take two hits to kill, with no room to put anything near them. I had that once. It tends to spawn things away from your already set up contraptions, and I had one left over by accident, and whoops, giant clump in the corner :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dIyrft7.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s FINE, it’s a fine game, but the music, setting, idea of it, all of it just doesn’t really speak to me. It’s notable though that this setting of all settings will be re-used later, far, far down the line, and for MUCH better effect.</p>

<p>5.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 8 - Planet Zoldath</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 8 - Planet Zoldath" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50#8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-8.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dmAIsML.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’m gonna make more of these a day so this doesn’t take me literally 50 days.</p>

<p>This is one of the more important games in the canon of LX Systems, because it is the first appearance of Zoldath, a major setting for their games, the little red UFO that will become their trademark symbol down the way, and its pilot, named… Pilot. Neither the UFO nor Pilot are actually named here. Writing is credited to Gregory Milk, so we can assume he came up with Zoldath and this world, though I think it’s implied it’s also in the board game Smolski and Chun made years ago? Unsure. Anyways, what is Zoldath actually about?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zchLX5O.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game starts with you landing on Zoldath in your UFO. You are not given any goals. You are not given any information. All you immediately know is there’s three spaces for… papers? And four different resources of some kind, and you’re being timed. You can’t do anything but run around and explore screens that shift and move like Zelda 1.</p>

<p>Zoldath is incredibly confusing on your first play, but as you actually learn what it’s about and how it works, you’ll find that it’s actually… really shallow, and uninteresting. So basically, you need three pieces of an intergalactic map that are hidden in this world. They can be hidden in a number of ways, and you’ll need different items to obtain them. Often times these items are just lying around, and there’s like 5 of them. Once you discover what every item does and how it can be used to open up the map for more exploring, it all falls into place. Like, using the transmogrifier to turn crystals into meat so they can explode and NOT kill you, or using the transmogrifier to turn yourself small and go through holes, or using the boots to go over acid, or using the boomerand to grab things across pits, or using meat to lure out enemies so you can sneak past them. Lots of options, but none of them are super interesting past that initial “Oh that’s what the game wants me to do” moment.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z4jUCZq.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Each time the game starts, a world is generated. There are like 8 different alien species, and out of those, two are friendly. One needs a translator to talk to. They can give little fun lore tidbits, or trade you items for resources you can find lying around the map. One of the maps will ALWAYS be traded for, so you’ll need to find who trades for what, so you can get good amounts of what the map is traded for, cause they’ll want like 30 of them for it. Also, out of those aliens, a few are chosen to shoot bullets, and one is chosen to fucking EXPLODE when it dies, so you always gotta be careful until you know how every enemy acts.</p>

<p>There’s also a little dungeon, which has a map at the end. The third map piece is usually sitting somewhere in the world, either behind a big invincible enemy, or over a pit. And uh, that’s it. You get those three, blast off, and the game is over. Do it as fast as you can.</p>

<p>I find Zoldath kind of boring and unfun. It’s not BAD or HORRIBLE, I just never have any interest in playing it again. It’s kinda like a VERY mini Zelda, with less fun exploration and worse combat. This world, its characters, and even the ideas within it will be done much better down the way.</p>

<p>4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5sJvf5t.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 7 - Velgress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 7 - Velgress" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50#7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-7.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ODhzsfp.png" alt="Velgress" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’m gonna make more of these a day so this doesn’t take me literally 50 days.</p>

<p>Still in early 1984, we’ve got a game that’s pretty important for two reasons. One is that it introduces yet another staff member to LX Systems! Her name is Chiffon Bola, and while I don’t hear much talk about her from fans who discuss the meta narrative of UFO 50, she is EXTREMELY important. She’s notable for being y’know, another woman, and a programmer this time! She’s the lead programmer on this project, alongside Benedikt Chun, who directed it. Chiffon seems like a cool lady, she’s big into bikes and her effect on the company was a positive one, for sure. It’s absolutely possible that her suggestions are what truly made this game, as it is yet another game with a female lead, and one that would become a major part of the company’s character lineup: The Space Pirate Alpha. She’s a lady in green space armor with a rifle, and she’s got a LOT of Samus Energy going on.</p>

<p>Velgress is about Alpha, who is captured by the Demon Princess Chakras and thrown into a deep pit known as Velgress. It’s a deep pit filled with traps and monsters, and now Alpha has to escape alive! The best way I can describe this game is by calling it “Upwell”. Notably, the creator of Downwell IRL worked on this game, so like, makes sense? You can run, jump, double jump, and shoot, and your goal is to move up a shaft. As the camera moves, so does a spike pit at the bottom. All floors crumble and break underneath you as you land on them, so you have to CONSTANTLY be on the move. The only thing that actually kills you is the bottom of the pit, everything else wil lstun and throw you, and will PROBABLY end with you landing in the spike pit, but maybe not! You might be able to jump out of it. But you’ll probably die.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UkadO8i.png" alt="Velgress" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You die a lot in Velgress. But it’s built with that in mind, it’s VERY replayable. You die, press A, and with an animation of you being thrown into a pit, immediately jump back into the action. It slams you back to the first stage, which after the first time of getting to level 2 and dying being jarring in a “AGH DAMMIT, MY PROGRESS” kinda way, you get over it fast. The game is like 5 minutes long. It’s VERY short. Only the four levels, the last one being mostly a boss, and a shop inbetween.</p>

<p>Along the way, mini bosses will show up. They barely even try to attack you, but if you kill all three in each of the levels before they run away, you get the good ending. I never got the bad ending, they’re not hard to kill.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HTyvGZ9.png" alt="Velgress" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another cool thing about Velgress is that it uses random generation. That wasn’t unheard of back then, but it’s a cool addition, and fits this gameplay very well. Its is also notable for having more than one musical theme! The other games would have one track, and then maybe an ending theme, but Velgress has different music for each level. I like level 1’s theme a lot, the others are just okay.</p>

<p>I didn’t super love this the first time I played it, but after sitting down to beat it, it really grew on me. But I can’t deny the game is very, VERY short. Also, I dunno why, but it reminds me of Kid Icarus even though it’s nothing like it. Maybe it’s the music.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>

<p>ALSO, important to note, I got the early lore of LX Systems completely wrong. I’ll edit my earlier posts and fix it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/09/OOCY20.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 20" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/09/OOCY20</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/09/OOCY20.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tMhmxgz.png" alt="&quot;Even if she ends up choosing someone else, I...&quot; &quot;You're thinking something stupid again, aren't you? &lt;3&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I wonder what it’s like to NOT have anxiety about relationships</p>

<p>source: Yurikon</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yurikon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 19" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FsOSYUN.png" alt="&quot;Oh shut up!! If it comes down to that, then we can just have an orgy together! I want to celebrate, right this instant!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: come rain or shine</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="come rain or shine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>