<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-08T12:22:28-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 158 - Catrap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 158 - Catrap" /><published>2025-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/08/RA158-Catrap.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JS9Pthf.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I played a homebrew NES game called Witch n’ Wiz recently, and it was a cute little puzzle game. As I was playing it someone in chat went “Huh, this is kinda just Catrap”. And then I played Catrap and uh, yeah. It’s the same game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Mx3p01H.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Catrap you play as two people cursed to become cat people. Oh no, uh, how horrible. They can ‘break’ the curse though, by defeating all the enemies! It’s 100 levels, infinite lives, and it saves. This game is shockingly ahead of its time for 1990. Anyways, you can play as either the catboi or the catgirl, and they play exactly the same except for ONE thing I’ll mention later. You can defeat enemies by walking into them, but only from the side, otherwise they’re platforms. And with that, push blocks and use sand effectively to make your way through 100 levels!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ty0mfwO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Catrap is a fantastic puzzle game, with great puzzle design, and I’m frankly stunned by how ahead of the curve it is for 1990. It’s got a few fun gimmicks too, like some levels have you control both girl and boy, and swap between them with select, making for fun twisty levels. The one thing that got me though, is that the set has some “beat this level as fast as you can” achievements. Which y’know, is fine. You can basically buffer your inputs, so as long as you remember where to go, it’s honestly easy. The DIFFICULT part was that, in one of the challenges, I just couldn’t do it. I was like 2 seconds off. I watched a TAS. I was following it EXACTLY, still couldn’t get there. Why? What was I doing wrong? Then, I found out…. the boy is faster. Their climbing animations are different, and the boy’s is much faster than the girl’s. That’s it. It CONFOUNDED me. So I had to play as the boy for those levels, sadly.</p>

<p>The only thing the actual GAME has against it, IMO, is the music. It’s pretty rough, even for 1990 Gameboy standards. Like, we’re quite a ways off from Pokemon TCG, sure, but this is honestly kinda bad.</p>

<p>But yeah, fantastic game, and if you like puzzlers, you should check it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Catrap" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 120</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 120" /><published>2025-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/07/OOCY120.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7Axr1s3.png" alt="'I was going to let you take control today, but in the end you still backed down. I think that side of you is cute, but... I also have my limits...' 'E-eh?! Wait, hold on!' 'I'm done waiting.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Day I Tried to Go on the Offensive</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Day I Tried to Go on the Offensive" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 119</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/04/OOCY119.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 119" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/04/OOCY119</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/04/OOCY119.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/liwD1AY.png" alt="'There... there are still holes?' A girl awkward says as another clings to her" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yumimi Mix</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yumimi Mix" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 157 - Fisher Price - I Can Remember</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/04/RA157FisherPrice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 157 - Fisher Price - I Can Remember" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/04/RA157FisherPrice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/04/RA157FisherPrice.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wlvqHTE.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I was hanging with a friend and for SOME DAMN REASON I decided this is the game we should play. I don’t know why I thought that was a good idea. This is Fisher Price: I Can Remember, an obscure NES game, licensed by Nintendo, with that Nintendo seal of quality, and it’s an “educational” game. It’s not. There’s no educational value at ALL in this, as there probably couldn’t be on the NES for a game for 2-3 year olds. This game is, instead, fucking product placement advertising, in a way that kind of pisses me off.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OTp1rjm.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The “game” is simple. You flip over spots to reveal all the WONDERFUL FISHER-PRICE TOYS YOU SHOULD ANNOY YOUR PARENTS TO BUY YOU, and then if you match the same one, you get a point! Pretty hard, huh? There’s a point system that’s nonsense, it’s VERY slow paced and boring, and there’s like 5 rounds of this. You can play VS others, or with a computer. And that’s it. I thought this would be goofy and fun but it kinda just annoyed me in the end.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NEs" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Fisher Price" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 16 - 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/02/LizstartrekVOY4-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 16 - 19" /><published>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/02/LizstartrekVOY4-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/02/LizstartrekVOY4-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oPqZ08e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Prey</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2kQtuQz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s the return of both the Hirogen AND Species 1234569. We start with the Hirogen hunting a Species ship, talking to each other about how the prey is reacting. One of them is played by Kurn’s actor, and his voice is very hot.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Voyager, Seven needs some compassion classes. This might be one of those episodes.</p>

<p>A Hirogen ship suddenly comes up on Voyager, one life sign, eratic, so they beam over to help. Seven is like “This is stupid, the Hirogen won’t accept your compassion”. Janeway SHOULD have responded with “ weird, it worked for you”, but instead she just goes “I’mma do it anyway”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CboMGs6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They rescue the Hirogen, who is pretty against working with who he views as his prey, but eventually agrees to let them treat him, albeit in a grumpy fashion. Yay for me, the Hirogen who’s still alive is the one with the sexy voice. They also learn more about the Hirogen, which seems to go against what we learned LAST EPISODE. They had a communications network, what do you mean they have no worlds and are nomadic. More Hirogen are also on the way, but before they can deal with THAT, the Species breaks its way into the fucking hull and into the ship. It sneaks around in antimatter injection ports and then attacks the Engineering team. It does NOT appear to  goo them like they did, with Harry.</p>

<p>Okay, so I guess Seven’s “compassion classes” are she thinks they should just kill the species, and Janeway goes “No”. No? NO? People are dying and WILL die, Janeway, I get it, but Seven is ACTUALLY right this time. She ALSO releases the Hirogen from his containment after he says he wants to finish the hunt. My girl, do you think this guy ISN’T GOING TO KILL THE SPECIES???? What the hell is wrong with Janeway in this episode.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9zQ556t.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode then becomes Aliens. Chakotay is in charge of keeping an eye on the Hirogen, which I would TOTALLY trust him with. Shockingly, the Hirogen attempts to kill the Species, and has to be shot to be stopped. No way, what a surprise. Also now that Kes is gone, it’s telepathically communicating with Tuvok instead. It tells Tuvok that it’s just trying to get home, and Janeway wants to do everything she can to get it home. She’s like “this isn’t a hunt, it’s a slaughter”. MFer that’s what a hunt is? Janeway is REALLY holding the idiot ball this episode. when she gives her reasoning and position, like, I get it? But it’s poorly written, and clearly written by people who have NOT been in a life or death, or even leadership position before.</p>

<p>Janeway stands by her ideals and refuses to give the prey, or the hunter, to the Hirogen. This is a very stupid idea because they’re up against six ships that can easily blow them the fuck up. They blow off TWO NACELLES. THAT’S BAD?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2zkTGC0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Hirogen breaks out and attacks the Species. Seven takes matters into her own hand and teleports both of them off the ship (a bit weird since it’s been stated they can’t be targetted but okay). Everyone is enraged by Seven about this, and Janeway removes her access and rights as a member of the crew over this. How DARE she SAVE THE CREW??? WHAT A FUCKER.</p>

<p>This is the dumbest thing I’ve EVER seen Janeway do. Stupid as fuck. Seven rightfully calls her out it, but god. I can’t tell if they’re trying to make Janeway or Seven the one in the right here, it’s open ended, but it SHOULDN’T be. Janeway should get her comeuppance.</p>

<p><strong>Retrospect</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qLdpujc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A weapons dealer is on Voyager, selling them a cannon. Janeway deigns to let Seven work with him, because they “work well together”, apparently, even though Seven states she does not like him (he is inneffecient). During installation, he pushes her out of the way, and she immediately decks him in the face. Everyone is like “what the fuck”, and she can’t really explain herself. She also freaks out when the Doctor tries to scan her. The doctor notices something strange in her brain. He does a hypnosis thing to try and figure out what the issue is. In the hypnosis flashback, she sees the weapons dealer, Kovin, performing surgery on her and extracting Borg technology. She uses the word “violate”, which is rough.</p>

<p>This could go okay, or very, vERY poorly.</p>

<p>It explains, in long excrutiating detail, her memory of what happened. They drugged her and harvested borg technology from her, before setting her back where she was and explaining it was a weapon overload that stunned her. Tuvok is skeptical, not for any BAD reason, just because this kind of memory recovery has been unreliable in the past. He intends to investigate. And to Janeway’s credit, she’s like “this is very important, and I will do what I can to get to the bottom of it”. When the trader is like “You’d risk trade negoations for the possibily her delusions are true?!” Janeway is like “Yes. I would.” Good on you for that. The Doctor is EXTREMELY in on this. He’s DISGUSTED by the concept of what Kovin did, and is fully behind Seven. Possibly to a… pushy degree? Like, making shit up. Hmm.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ae9F5YD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get a local Magistrate to investigate with them, for an impartial investigation. It’s not impartial enough for Kovin, so he pulls a gun on them and beams out. When they chase, he hits them with a pulse and disappears. They chase. Everyone is like “The investigation HAS been impartial, but we all had our preconceptions about him”. Hmmmmmmmm.</p>

<p>They find evidence that proves Kovin is probably not guilty. Seven is so SURE of what she saw, and they all agree she believes what she believes. She doesn’t react to this well, especially not when the Doctor “turns” on her about it, basically. They find out it’s some stuff playing with her borg implants and making her think things were happening when they weren’t. They catch up to Kovin, tell him “We know you’re innocent, don’t worry” and he just shoots at them without saying anything. His weapons overload and he blows himself up. And everyone is beating themselves up over this. No, he was being a fucking asshole. This episode FEELS like it’s a “THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS WHEN SEXUAL ASSAULT ALLEGATIONS ARE TAKEN TOO FAR, YOU’LL HURT INNOCENT PEOPLE”, but no, he’s being a fucking dumbass. I hate this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gDvO76k.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This all blows.</p>

<p>And the Doctor feels the most guilty cause he was the MOST cancel culturey, and so asks to be turned back to factory standard. This is such a weird leap. What the hell?</p>

<p>This episode is just Male Victimhood Fantasy and I wish it didn’t exist.</p>

<p><strong>The Killing Game</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qLdpujc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Is that a Hirogen in a fucking nazi uniform???</p>

<p>Yes, actually, it is. The Hirogen appear to have taken control of Voyager, and are putting the crew through simulations to test them. They’re rewriting their memories about who they are. First they make Janeway think she’s a Klingon warrior, which is hot, then they do THIS to her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bouDVW9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway dons her best Lesbian Suit, like holy HELL. This is basically Casablanca. Janeway is a resistance member in France who owns a bar. Seven sings at the bar and is secretly their munitions expert. Tuvok is Janeway’s friend and ally. The other Hirogen seem very confused about what they’re even doing, but the one in charge views this as a game. The others are like, seemingly kinda pissed they even gotta put up with this.</p>

<p>Neelix is riding around town with baguettes in his bike, as if you didn’t already know this was France.</p>

<p>LOL okay the Hirogen think the Nazis suck. When even your Space Predators think Nazis suck, maybe your Nazis fucking suck. He chokes out a nazi and tells him “You’re superior to no one, and if you think you are, you’ll die when the hunt turns back on you. Pathetic.” I hate that I love that.</p>

<p>We learn a bit more when one of the Hirogen get bored and shoot Seven of Nine and Neelix. The Doctor is still normal, and treating who he can. This seems like it could maybe be a deal they put together so more of them don’t die (though some of them ARE dying). Kim is outside the simulations, working on the ship at the Hirogen’s demands. He’s also forming a resistance cell within the ship, which is a fun dichotomy alongside the resistance cell happening INSIDE the simulations.</p>

<p>We learn more of why the Alpha Hirogen is doing this. He’s a progressive! Y’know, for a Hirogen. He believes that in order for his people to survive, they must adapt, and reform an actual civilization. Of course, the hunt is still important. They’ll just adapt. They’ll use this holodeck technology to continue the hunt, in a new society. It’s some SWEEPING changes he wants to make, and it’s fascinating. The other Hirogen seem to be more traditionalists.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gLJkicW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On the eve of the Americans re-entering the city, Seven is put back in the simulation. The doctor made is so she remembers who she is… unfortunately this means she doesn’t know wtf World War 2 is, and she’s an important part of the simulation, so that’ll be… worrying. This is a tense situation, but she manages to interface with the holodeck and release the prisoners JUST as soon as Janeway is about to shoot Seven, thinking she’s a nazi. Unfortunately, they know she’s free, and immediately go to recapture her. But everyone fights back. For the resistance!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hpBc0kA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We see a Nazi building explode and they do a sick-ass dive. The explosion blows its way into other decks, releasing the simulation. I mean, they DID turn off the safeties, makes sense that a fucking missile would do that. Holographic soldiers and real soldiers (our crew members) break their way out of the simulation… TO BE CONTINUED…</p>

<p><strong>The Killing Game, Part II</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3Ab58ON.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>…right now! Enjoying the commonality of two parters mid season now. Janeway and Seven are moving around the ship, beating up holographic nazis where they can. But they’re going to need help. Time to get the French Resistance to help. Janeway plays the simulation well. She knows her World War 2.</p>

<p>There’s some stuff with Paris and Torres’ characters in the simulation being in love, which is kind of unimportant and distracting from the actual plot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5gLnG2M.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway and Chakotay, still thinking he’s an American soldier, go to meet Janeway’s “contact”. But first they need to “go through caves”. These caves are the other holodeck, which has the Klingon simulation, and Neelix drunk off his ass as a Klingon. She contacts the Doctor, and gets her plan. She heads to sick bay ,but not before placing some charges on the thing that keeps their neuro transmitters in check. Janeway is shot, and the others are recaptured JUST as soon as they’re freed from the neurotransmitter.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Th5Sxao.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway is brought to the alpha Hirogen, and explains to her WHY he’s doing what he’s doing. With the holodecks, they can continue the hunt without killing others, and themselves, as readily. And he appreciates Humans. He and Janeway come to an agreement, and decide a cease fire. Janeway will give them Holodeck technology, and they will leave. Remember season 1 where they refused to give those aliens replicator technology?</p>

<p>He calls for a cease fire to his hunters, but one of the nazis in the simulation convinces him to continue. The more conservative, traditionalist hunters connect with the fucking nazis, over the progressive, who connects with the allied forces. This episode knows what its doing. The Nazis break the cease fire. Man, if you can’t trust the Nazis. The 2nd in command, the one who listened to the nazis, kills the Alpha Hirogen, and then chases Janeway around. Janeway STILL has a bullet in her leg. Now we have an injured Janeway in a sexy outfit running from a Nazi Hirogen and outsmarting him, it’s great.</p>

<p>Things are looking grim. The Nazis have our heroes up against the wall… and then!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oPqZ08e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE KLINGONS ARE THE BIG DAMN HEROES! Klingons killing nazis NOT something I knew I needed, but I did need it.</p>

<p>Janeway kills her hunter, and the remaining Hirogen agree to the truce again. She gives them the technology after all. Their leader’s ideals were unconventional, but maybe things can get better. Heavy casualties on both sides, the Voyager continues, freed.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 156 - Chrono Trigger</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/02/RA156-ChronoTrigger.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 156 - Chrono Trigger" /><published>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/02/RA156-ChronoTrigger</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/02/RA156-ChronoTrigger.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OfRXBcI.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I do a thing on my stream called RPG Night. I hang out with my friends and play RPGs and we all do silly voices as I play. We usually try to 100% the games, and get a mastery (though some games make that very hard, lookin’ at you FF7). I’ve done lots of games already for this. But this one is special. This GAME is special. Chrono Trigger has the distinction of being probably the best RPG ever made. I do not say that lightly, and I’ve played a lot of games trying in vain to find any others that could topple it. Some come close. But none succeed. I feel like a sheep saying this, but yes, Chrono Trigger is essentially infallible. I’ve played it several times in my life, and each time, I’m kind of blown away.</p>

<p>So if you come into my reviews with NO knowledge, somehow, of Chrono Trigger, sit down and buckle up. I’ll give a brief review.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yMQP0eF.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chrono Trigger was an RPG made by Squaresoft in 1995, at the end of the SNES’ library, and it’s basically a sendoff of the console. All the biggest minds at Square at the time basically converged to make this one game. A lot of Final Fantasy people especially, which makes sense, because at one point this was slated to be a Final Fantasy game. FF5, I think? The SNES era of FF is nuts with stuff like that. There were like, 4 RPGs that were at one point going to be a Final Fantasy game that did not end up being a Final Fantasy game, or got cancelled. Anyways, it had a lot of people working on it. Three directors, most namely Sakagushi, the lead FF guy. Four different writers, most namely Yuji Horii, the creator of Dragon Quest. Four artists, most namely Akira Toriyama. And two composers including Yasunori Mitsuda, most famously, in his first actual composition role, instead of just sound effects. This game would rightfully launch him. Oh, I’ll get into the music later.</p>

<p>So yeah, this team was internally known as “The Dream Team”, which is very funny. It was the super group of JRPG teams. But could they live up to their hype? Uh, yes. Fuck yes, they could.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xC9lyoN.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Chrono Trigger, you play as a young man named Crono. All of the characters are like, 17-19, which sets it apart from a lot of other RPGs where the characters are 13 year olds fighting God. Anyway, Crono lives in a pleasant Fantasy Kingdom in the year 1000AD, near his childhood friend Lucca, a brilliant inventor. It’s the Millenial fair, and you decide to go visit! While there, you bump into a young woman who calls herself Marle, and she asks you to show her around the fair. The two of you have a good time, then visit Lucca’s show, where she’s showing off a teleporter she made. However, the teleporter goes wrong, reacting to Marle’s necklace, and she’s sent into the portal, disappearing to somewhere. You pick up the necklace she dropped and hop right in after her to rescue her, sending yourself back 400 years, into your kingdom’s past, to the middle ages.</p>

<p>This is a time travel story that sends you aaaalll over the place. This game can kinda be described as a bunch of smaller stories and plot points that converge on one singular main point and plot. Like, you go back in time and find out that Marle, your time’s princess, was mistaken for this time’s princess. Unfortunately this causes a paradox, because they stopped looking for THEIR time’s princess, and Marle ceases to exist. You have to go rescue the REAL princess before something bad happens to her! Or later on, where you’re going back in time to prehistory to find a valuable rock that doesn’t exist anymore. After partying with the local people, your time travel device is stolen by local reptile people, and you need to get it back. Stuff like that, that’s all connected by one singular thing, and that’s Lavos. Most of you probably already know what Lavos is but I don’t want to spoil it for those who don’t.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/r2HLTCx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chrono Trigger to me, is characterized by its utterly fantastic writing, story, and characters, and the vibrant and beautiful world that it takes part in, which you feel you NEED to save. There are 7 major characters, and one of the game’s major flaws is you can only use 3 of them, because ALL of them are good and you’ll like all of them by the end. You’ll use all of them by the story’s end, as some are required for different points in the story, but by the end my main party was Crono, Marle, and Ayla for this playthrough. I usually use Lucca or Robo, but I wanted to give Ayla some love this time. Anyways, I seriously can’t overstate how well crafted this game is.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZarmyFK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But how’s the GAMEPLAY? Chrono Trigger uses a typical ATB battle system, which was very common place at the time, where everyone in a battle has gauges that fill up based on a speed stat, and then once it fills up, they can move. It’s semi-turn based, in that way. On top of that, Chrono Trigger has a system for proximity. Enemies and characters are on the field, and enemies will wander around. Their attacks, and your’s, will vary based on how close the target of their attacks are. You also have special tech attacks that care about things like proximity, or even attacking in a straight line. While it’s still, at its heart, a traditional JRPG combat system, it’s one of the more engaging ones from its time period. I tend to find combat systems from this era to be a bit dull, and often mash through them without thinking, and that can happen a bit in Chrono Trigger, but it’s okay, not everything can be Panzer Dragoon Saga. I’ve often said if there was a game with PDS’s combat system and Chrono Trigger’s story and characters, it would be the best game ever made.</p>

<p>Oh, and of course, I’d be remiss if I didn’t talk about the soundtrack. This was Mitsuda’s first actual soundtrack he worked on, and it is fucking fantastic. In my opinion he’ll outdo himself soon with Chrono Cross, the best video game soundtrack of all time, but seriously, this one is so good. It’s so good it coined a term called “The Mitsuda Lick” which I hear people talk about legitimately during musical discussion. Here, have a cover of some really damn good music to close out this review.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IAzPRupcTjQ?si=rMqkaHQ8PYoIbPZn" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>All together, Chrono Trigger is the real deal. I know public consensus says its one of the best games ever made, and so people go “pff, public consensus is always wrong, it can’t be that good”. I get it. I can be a bit of a hipster too. I JUST mentioned Panzer Dragoon Saga in the last paragraph for fuck’s sake, I LOVE my obscure shit no one cares about. But no, Chrono Trigger is actually really that good. Public consensus got it right. If you’ve never checked out Chrono Trigger, I highly advise you to. It’s worth at LEAST a try.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNEs" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Chrono" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 118</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/02/OOCY118.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 118" /><published>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/02/OOCY118</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/03/02/OOCY118.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SZVw4h1.png" alt="A girl throws some yen into a new years shrine. 'I wish my little brothers won't catch the flu... I wish for my thighs to lose some fat... and also...' An image of her hot friend pops in her mind" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn’t a Guy At All</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Guy She Was Interested in Wasn&apos;t a Guy At All" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 155 - Inventory Full</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/01/RA155-InventoryFull.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 155 - Inventory Full" /><published>2025-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/01/RA155-InventoryFull</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/01/RA155-InventoryFull.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/99H0hDd.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Inventory Full is a homebrew Gameboy game by megamittz, and you can find it on itch.io for free. IT was made in GB Studio, the usual go-to for Gameboy homebrew these days. It’s a short little game, prolly about 6 to 7 minutes. The plot is that you’re the leader of a group who just explored a dungeon and found the legendary sword at the end, but your inventories are full, so you take your comrade’s equipment and sell it on Ebay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fxp9atX.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The rest of the game is a very simple actiony arcade game, where you try and sneak past your allies to grab their stuff. They’re blocking your way, as well as other hazards, and you need to move left and right, then press A to charge forward. Three hits and you’re out. It’s not very complex, but the art is very nice and cute, with big full cutscene art that’s pleasant.</p>

<p>This isn’t anything special, but I like checking out homebrew now and then, there’s a lot of great homebrew on the Gameboy and the NES.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="homebrew" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 117</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/28/OOCY117.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 117" /><published>2025-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/28/OOCY117</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/28/OOCY117.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xd9VWbe.png" alt="Someone asked the other if they're a lesbian, and she just smiles and puts her hand on the other's surprised face." class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OK2zXjN.png" alt="The first, in surprise, explains that she's male, and the other shakes her head, kissing her hand and hair, stating the female symbol each time" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cuEjL5t.png" alt="She says one more female symbol, on the first's heart, and the two of them move together for off screen lesbian makeouts" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Childhood Friend Yuri(?)</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Friend Yuri" /><category term="trans" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 154 - Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchi Enji</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/26/RA154-Madou-Monogatari.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 154 - Madou Monogatari - Hanamaru Daiyouchi Enji" /><published>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/26/RA154-Madou%20Monogatari</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/26/RA154-Madou-Monogatari.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UqwMby6.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is the only Madou Monogatari game that has an achievement set on RA at the time of writing, so it’s actually my first game in the series I’ve ever played. Uh, kinda. I’ve actually played a LOT of Madou Monogatari! And you probably have too, or at least you’ve seen it a lot. But you probably have never heard that name before, unless you’re a massive turbo nerd, like I am. What IS it? Well, Madou Monogatari is an early 90s dungeon crawler series by Compile about a very young girl named Arle. Most of them are that like, first person dungeon crawler style that was popularized by Wizardry. They were good, but never came out over here, so no one in America knows a single thing about the series.</p>

<p>Except. The series DID come out here. The series had a spinoff, a little puzzle game called PUYO PUYO. You might have heard of it.  This series became MASSIVELY successful, and HUGELY popular. They greatly outstripped Madou Monogatari, to be point where the original series is very nearly just dead (there was a new one that came out last year, apparently, the first in 11 years, and 9 years before that one for the third most recent one). But these original games are still there. The Madou Monogatari series though, has a thing about it. It doesn’t really get new games in the series very often. What it DOES do is do remakes of the first game, over, and over, and over. This is one of those!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f5XMkpS.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is an RPG that is NOT a dungeon crawler, the first in the series like that. It’s more of a traditional JRPG, though a very weird one, and a retelling of the first game, though extended. I’d say it’s the plot of MM1 with 80% of the game taking place right before MM1, and the last dungeon is MM1. The plot is you’re Arle, a kindergartener, and your final exam is coming up. You need to travel the world, collecting items so you can make a wish for your exam ticket, and then take the exam to graduate! Along the way you’ll help people and meet a bunch of wacky characters, all of whom you’ll recognize from Puyo games, if you’ve played those, which you probably have.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hnV1rvt.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Most of the game is played in a top down style, where you’re running around, talking to people, exploring dungeons and the like. And the other half of the game is the random encounters and combat you get into. First you get a little dialogue between characters that is straight up the dialogues from Puyo games, then it’s KIND of traditional JRPG combat? This game series is actually quite weird, and the way I’d describe it, is it runs 100% on vibes. You don’t know your health. Or your MP, which all spells take. Or your opponent’s health. Or ANYTHING. That is gauged by the very extensive and quite good animations of Arle, and the opponents. And after attacks you’ll be told a little thing, like “The Puyo is not feeling so good!”. There are like, 10 different levels of damage, and you’ll need to learn a general idea of how hurt an enemy is, and how hurt YOU are.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JuYvnwV.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>On the main field, you can gauge your health by Arle’s big-ass face that’s always right there at the bottom, at all times. There’s also some orbs down there, that’s your EXP, when all those fill up, you level up. You can view your stats on your report card, and it gives a general description of you, ranging from “A wimp” to “Kind of scary”, which is a very funny way to describe a 4 year old.</p>

<p>So yeagh, I described the JRPG mechanics of this game as “baby’s first JRPG”. It’s entirely run on vibes, not hard to pick up, and very simple. Unfortunately, the rest of the game doesn’t hold up quite as well. Random encounters are very common, so it’s slow paced, and the dungeon design in this game is honestly just kind of bad. This game is half of the same rooms pasted over and over, honestly, in giant door mazes. It’s really disappointing.</p>

<p>While there’s a lot to like about Madou Monogatari: Big Kindergarten Kids, as it’s translated, there’s also a lot to detract from it. I think its style and presentation is utterly FANTASTIC, it is a GORGEOUS Super Famicom game. Which it should be, It’s a 1996 SFC game, that’s pretty damn late. I’d really only recommend this if you’re really curious, a huge puyo fan, or a Madou Monogatari fan who’s somehow never played this, but I dunno how many of YOU read my blog.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Madou Monogatari" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>