<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-05T23:15:12-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 17 - 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/05/LizstartrekEnt1-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 17 - 20" /><published>2025-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/05/LizstartrekEnt1-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/05/LizstartrekEnt1-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ssVkiCl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Fusion</strong> - ENT
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sqridOn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Enterprise is exploringa far nebula when they’re contacted by a Vulcan ship. The captain is all smiles, which is IMMEDIATELY weird. They ask for some assistance, explain they’re civilians, and when the captain meets for dinner, he happily eats meat and is all smiles. The Captain is nice, but his 2nd in command is a smarmy asshole. They explain they’re V’tosh ka’tur, Vulcans without Logic. That name MIGHT be familiar… that’s Sybok. These guys are Pre-Syboks. T’Pol is not amused.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/klbapEf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This guy has the most punchable face in space, and every second he’s on screen I’m afraid he’s about to sexually assault someone and then say it’s “just a joke bro”. He tries to chat up T’Pol and I’m expecting him to force a mind meld with her by the end of the episode. He explains that they’re not REJECTING Surak’s teachings, quite the opposite. It’s more that they’re a heresy that believes the teachings are misinterpreted, and he wanted Vulcans to “MASTER” their emotions. Whatever that means.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/M2GxlhM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We basically have two stories here. T’Pol with the smarmy guy, Tolaris, and this guy, Tor, the engineer. He’s a friendly guy who likes making pals on the ship. Tor’s dad asks Archer to try and convince Tor to contact him, since he’s dying, and Tor refuses to talk to him. Emotional manipulation time?</p>

<p>SPEAKING OF EMOTIONAL MANIPULATION, HEY, I CALLED IT. T’Pol has a sex dream about Tolaris. Creeps Invading Psychics With Sex Dreams is not a new phenomena in Star Trek, but I hate it every time it happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5qqhnXX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This dude’s body language is rancid, just HANGING over her with that fucking smirk. I dunno why she’s humoring him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vmqLPtL.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look, I called it. I hate being psychic.</p>

<p>Archer finds out what happens, basically tricks Tolaris into throwing him across the fucking room, and kicks him out of the ship. Good, fuck that guy. Trip helps Tor talk to his dad, and it goes better than expected. So while sometimes the emotional vulcan experiment doesn’t work, it can. Tor seems like a good guy.</p>

<p><strong>Rogue Planet</strong> - ENT
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wZd1v9l.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While flying through space, Enterprise finds a rogue planet. Wow, title drop. This is a real phoenomenon where planets are just… floating in space. It’s not COMMON but it’s a thing. They find a ship on it, but it ignores their hails.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2VVOqZu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The planet is actually habitable, due to thermal vents, which is kinda nuts. The crew quickly finds the aliens here, the Eska, who are hunters hunting some dangerous game that lives on this planet. Reed offers to join them for a hunt, but the others are kinda disturbed by the idea of hunting. As Archer says, hunting went out of favor on Earth a century ago, but they do still appreciate the hunters’ hospitality.</p>

<p>That night, Archer senses something out in the forest, and goes after it. A bit wild to do that after hearing the hunters explain all the dangerous animals that lurk in the dark. He finds a young human woman with long blond hair, wearing a night gown. She calls Archer by name, and then disappears into the foliage. Interesting :o</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EKdA3n3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The others are like “Sir, there’s no Humans on this planet but us, don’t be nuts, you’re hallucinating”. Everyone thinks he’s being a fool, which is really funny and shows this really IS Early Trek, since after being in space for 200 years, Starfleet goes “You saw something weird? Got it, time to do all the tests we can”, while here they’re like “Silly Captain, weird things don’t happen in Trek”.</p>

<p>She appears again and is like “Hey, I’m contacting you SPECIFICALLY because I need help. And I’m taking this form because you’d be reticent to it”. This is pretty obvious, I think, where this story is going. But that doesn’t make it BAD. It looks like its a Devil in the Dark situation, a non-humanoid is being hurt and wants to reach out for help. Also this girl is played by the super sexy Trill from Insurrection. Yay!</p>

<p>After some more shenanigans, Archer gets to talk to her again, and she explains that the Eska are hunting THEM. The Eska, for what its worth, seems to not realize there’s anything sapient on the planet. Archer finds out more by talking to the hunters, learning about beings called the Wraiths, animals that are able to psychically read minds. Ah, I see.</p>

<p>The Eska sense them by reading a pheremone they give off when scared. Phlox develops something to help mask it, and all’s well. The Eska are pissed and suspicious, but can’t prove anything.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ICxl0v3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>SLUG MOMMY!</p>

<p>Pretty good episode for Enterprise, honestly.</p>

<p><strong>Acquisition</strong> - ENT
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XlElzh9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THE FERENGI ARE HERE! We know Starfleet had SOME interractions with the Ferengi before TNG, none good, but it’s fascinating to see them. They do something to gas Enterprise and then make their way in to rob the place, not without weirdly sexually harassing T’Pol. Ohhh, Ferengi. Never change (?)</p>

<p>One of these Ferengi is played by the same actor as Neelix. It’s nice to see him! Is this the first time a main actor character has come back in a cameo role? I can’t remember any others happening. I know a few in reverse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UQWjlr0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone is knocked out… except for one. Of COURSE it’s Trip. OF FUCKING COURSE IT’S TRIP. I swear to God, he gets more love than Archer does. He was stuck in decon, so he gets spared. Now he’s gotta Die Hard around the ship. All the while the Ferengi are going about their business, taking the things they personally like. One has big colorful socks and are stealing shoes. Another is gathering all the women. Oooof course. I miss DS9, when their weird sexism was mocked more openly.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KzzlHiQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They wake Archer up, and he tries to play them pretty well after a little bit. Tries haggling, talks up the weakest one, kinda befriends him. He doesn’t have the lobes. He sees Trip is awake, and sneaks a message to him about how to wake up the others like he got wake up. We get T’Pol up, but none of the others for some reason.</p>

<p>T’Pol plays the other three Ferengi against each other, doing things with some remote control scanners that makes them stop trusting each other. Very smart.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1SfLtjG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>T’Pol AND Archer are actually both very good at this. I guess Trip’s job is to run around half naked. Though honestly when he’s put on the line, he does a VERY good job faking a fight with Archer. “THEY’RE GONNA TAKE MY WIFE, YOU GREEDY SON OF A BITCH”, then promises to show them where the Gold Vault is.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MTgbFf8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re all so shockingly good at this. T’Pol seduces the weaker one and then knocks him the fuck out. This episode is filled with a lot of great character moments, holy hell. Trip lures them into a trap and T’Pol shoots them, knocking them out. They then force them to put EVERYTHING back.</p>

<p>Archer lets Krem, the weaker one, take control of his ship while the others are tied up, and they fly off, while Archer puts the Ferengi in the database as dangerous. Anyways this is absolutely fantastic, the best episode of Enterprise so far prolly. Grading on the Enterprise scale, it’s like a 10/10. Grading on the NORMAL scale, prolly a 9 lol</p>

<p><strong>Oasis</strong> - ENT
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/t4N9qO0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Enterprise meets a trader who tells them of a planet not far from here that has a crashed ship that he couldn’t scrap for parts, because “the crew objected”, even though nothing is alive there. Ooh, scary, interesting~</p>

<p>They go down to explore the ship, even though there’s a MILLION red flags. It’s weird for them to like, try to scavenge a ship. The only time I can think of that ever happening was Terok Nor, and that was a special case.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2MaVJkB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Obviously no, they are not alone. There ARE people living there. These are people on a supply vessel that was shot down by raiders. They’ve been hiding here now for three years, unable to get the ship flying. And yes, that IS Odo! I know I literally JUST last episode went “I can’t remember a main actor coming back for a cameo” and here he is. Hi Rene, it’s so good to see you. Archer agrees to try and help them get their ship flying again.</p>

<p>These aliens, the Kantare, are not UNFRIENDLY, but are a little standoffish. And they don’t want the younger Kantare to really interract with the crew. There’s a girl called Liana who’s a little standoffish too at first, but is friendly to Trip after he tries to open up with her. T’Pol is like “of COURSE you’re trying to sleep with her too”. Trip claims he’s not. Oh please.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zBKXV2W.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some things the Kantare are saying aren’t really making sense. Scans show their ship has been there for a VERY long time. Over 20 years. Meanwhile, they also find a corpse of one of the Kantare that they saw on the ship, alive, an hour ago. When Trip confronts Liana about this, she’s like “OKAY I GOTTA GO BYYYEEE” and dips. Sussy.</p>

<p>The Kantare capture Trip and T’Pol and force them to fix the ship. Trip goes “You’ve got a LOT to learn about making friends” and Odo says “I’ve made all the friends I need”, which I think gives the game away.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/T6CKUn3.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Yeah, so only Odo and his daughter survived the original crash. Odo blames himself for killing the rest of the crew and made holograms of them to try and deal with the trauma and guilt. He left his station during the crash to save his daughter, which is why he blames himself. Poor guy. After learning exactly what happened, they agree to help fix the holographic systems, if that’s what they REALLY want. But they need to be sure of that.</p>

<p>They convince Odo to fix the ship and head back home. He’s happy there, but his daughter isn’t. Trip and Liana kiss, and that was about it. This was okay, but it feels like a retread of previous Trek ideas</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 3 episode 6-8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/05/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 3 episode 6-8" /><published>2025-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/05/LizstartrekSNW3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/10/05/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nVITuMH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Through the Lens of Time</strong> - SNW
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N8mQara.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This season is going really hard on the romance drama, which is starting to get mostly tiring for me. But it’s ALSO pushing this new nurse guy, Dana. He’s SO excited and happy to be here. This guy is SO fucking dead. He’s got the voice over and it’s really pushing him, he’s so fucked. It also seems like he was brought in secretly as a third wheel so that thigns aren’t TOO awkward between Spock and Korby as they do some kind of dig.</p>

<p>Ortegas’ brother is also here! He’s recording stuff for a documentary, it seems, and is also invited to this mission, which SEEMS to be an archaeological dig on a sacred site. He’s also getting romance vibes with Uhura. They’re really trying to hook EVERYONE up this season aren’t they? Though Pelia the Warpcore Witch also seems to be real into him. And I like that, cause it’s funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5JfYBa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They all enter some kind of temple, after Chapel does some kind of thing to gain entry. They IMMEDIATELY find corpses and Spock is like “okay, protocol tells is we need to leave now”. Korby gets pissy and refuses, and Chapel, who’s in charge of the mission, sides with him cause he’s her girlfriend. There’s also a lot of tension cause of the whole Spock x Chapel thing. See, this is why everyone shouldn’t just fuck. Use the holodeck to fuck- wait. We already had an episode about how that’s a bad idea at this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ypNSSmn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>New Kid, who’s name is Gamble, acts like a TOS red shirt and randomly touches shit. Anyways, woah, New Kid gets his fucking eyes exploded cause things are actually super dangerous in here! Looks like Spock was right, what a mother fucking shock! The native living with them sees something else, freaks the fuck out, and tries to run away, and is vaporized. But we have so many things we could learn here!!! Korby was ABSOLUTELY going to just fucking die because he wasn’t being careful enough if others didn’t die before him, frankly. Why was he SO SURE that he had to do this dig RIGHT THE FUCK NOW? “I’ve waited all my life for this!” Yeah dude, but you’re like, 33. This temple isn’t going anywhere. Put down that fucking idiot ball, right now, mister!</p>

<p>They get split up, as if it couldnt’ get any worse, and are in different rooms, but able to communicate. This now turns into a split room puzzle game escape room. Seems to be the same room but also not, seperate dimensions. They can still communicate though. Why? I dunno, bad writing?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x4jYCCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Eyeball Regenerator, which apparently exists, is not working. New Kid’s brain is also registering as braindead. New episode name: Gamble’s Brain. Gamble is also acting Kinda Sus now. Hmm.</p>

<p>Ten minutes ago, Gamble’s eyes exploded. Now, Spock is saying how Korby is not being safe enough and not taking any precautions, and then he TAKES A FUCKING VISOR OFF OF A DEAD ALIEN AND PUTS IT ON HIS EYEBALLS AND USES IT TO LOOK AT THINGS. WHAT THE FUCK, SPOCK? I’m starting to think this episode might just not be well written.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLyV7Ze.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel, who I remind you is now half Gorn, meets Gamble, and starts speaking in tongues. Gamble does the same, and they proceed to beat the shit out of each other. Gamble also murders someone in the scuffle. After he’s captured, he just breaks through the force fields and kills more red shirts. Damn, this episode has a body count.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hp0x8tF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Pelia shoots Gamble in the back, releasing the ancient dimensional alien inside of him. Scotty then captures it in a Pokeball and tosses it up into the transporter. He locks it in the transport buffer, until they can figure out what to do with it. There’s no WAY that’ll backfire!!!</p>

<p>Pelia has a big discussion about ancient evil, which turns out to be her mugging for the documentary. Okay, that was funny. I was like “wow that’s very on the nose- oh okay, that’s good”. I do like Pelia. As M’Benga calls Gamble’s parents to tell them about their son, the Enterprise computer screens flash alien text. Wow, I knew it’d backfire but THAT fast.</p>

<p>I think my judgement of this will depend on if and when it goes anywhere, but I feel it was poorly written. Something was off and the pacing was bad.</p>

<p><strong>The Sehlat Who Ate Its Tail</strong> - SNW
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iXkfagX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What a weird episode title.</p>

<p>Anyways, Kirk is on the Ferragut, and he’s bored as fuck. His captain, V’rel is a hot Vulcan bitch who does everything By The Book, and Kirk wants a shakeup. Be careful what you wish for, Kirk. They disturb a disturbance in the crust of a planet they’re observing, which turns out to be the planet fucking exploding. The captain and a lot of the crew is taken out. Comms are down, so there’s no way to communicate.</p>

<p>Enterprise comes to help out, a team beaming over to try and help. Kirk is in charge, V’Rel is alive but injured. Turns out there was some kind of gravitational beam that blew up the planet, though it’d take a ship so much larger than anything else on record. Uhura sets up comms with the Enterprise, who orders everyone to evacuate. Fair. La’an and some of the critically wounded beam over first. Before they can do anything else though, THIS happens!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nV2aKch.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A giant fucking thing comes and literally eats the Enterprise. La’an explains she thinks it’s the Eater of Worlds. A giant ancient scavenger ship. Ghost story. Interesting. You’d think something like this would be more than just a Legend, but whatever works. Kirk refuses to leave people on the ship, and demands Scotty make miracles. This is actually the first time Kirk and Scotty are even working together. Since Spock is here too, as acting 2nd in command, with Uhura too, it’s practically a TOS reunion party. Just like, a pre-union.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2J7mGnt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The things in charge of this giant Scavenger ship appear to have boarded the Enterprise, and are just fucking Big Daddies.</p>

<p>Kirk is making bad decisions. He ignores all his advisors, and the ship explodes. Not like, fully, it’s just dead in the water. He ignored Scotty, and he’s pushed it too far. He gets angry and refuses to listen to any other advices. He storms off. They decide he needs someone to help him through this, someone with a less emotional style to calm him. Time for the start of Spock x Kirk!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FJxOfv8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get to see Pelia’s quarters. It’s absolutely incredible. She digs in a box for some ancient junk. She pulls out a mother fucking Atari. Holy hell. I want to see her video game collection. Communications are being jammed, so her plan? Wire the enterprise with ancient cables and use old-ass phones. That’s honestly fantastic.</p>

<p>We learn what the title of this episode means. The Sehlat that Ate Its Tail is a Vulcan idiom, similar to “the dog that caught the car”. Someone hunting after a thing, then… now what? Kirk, going after leadership, now he’s stuck and frozen. It’s cute. Anyways, Spock and Kirk have a heart to heart, and it helps. He comes back with a new plan. Make their ship look REAL tasty to the scavengers so they’ll come biting, then make them regreat it.</p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, the Big Daddies refuse to kill Pike after it knocks his helmet off. Weird. Strange.</p>

<p>“I haven’t done this since I was a roadie for the dead!” “…Your species can communicate with dead people?” Holy shit, I LOVE Pelia. When they actually do things with her she’s so funny.</p>

<p>This episode is not doing a LOT with Pike, but it’s doing more than the rest of this season’s done. He’s the CAPTAIN, and he’s barely got any love this season. He’s the best character on this show. Very fun moments with him. “Take a step back, this might blow up.” “Captain, if it does, it’ll blow up the entire engineering section.” “…A very large step back, then?” I love you, Pike.</p>

<p>Spock manages to hit the aliens where they hurt and blow them upm just as the Enterprise escapes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lQm5m80.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out the Scavengers were Human. On the side of the ship, they find “XCV-100”, which is a reference to a classic Ship concept. Apparently many years ago, some Humans built a ship to escape an environmental collapse of Earth. But then the ship disappeared, never to be heard from again. But how did they go from THAT, to whatever they became? It’s not explained.</p>

<p>I’m not really sure I like the ending all that much? The big twist? But the lessons Pike imparts to Kirk in the end are good, at least, and the action and jokes are good. It’s like, a solid season 1 or 2 episode.</p>

<p><strong>What is Starfleet</strong> - SNW
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hb6jfUp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So for the past season, we’ve seen Beto, Ortegas’ brother, recording a documentary about Starfleet. And now this episode IS that documentary. We get to see this guy’s documentary he made about what Starfleet is. And you know what? It kinda sucks.</p>

<p>We’ll see if, by the end of this, it’s… intentional. But it feels like a first year film student trying to Do Something. To Say Something. But it’s honestly stunning how bad the editing is. That HAS to be the intention, but I don’t care if something is intentionally bad if it’s bad to watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ePXmjB1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It jumps between scenes with weird camera angles and bad shots. None of the scenes flow together, with the different members of the crew talking about random inane bullshit. Apparently we get a Spock Self Harm backstory. When he was a kid he tried to carve the human half out of him with a knife. Joy. Glad THAT’S canon now.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J9er1s6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Whatever this thing is, it’s pretty.</p>

<p>We see them go do… something in some war. It’s not super well explained. Every character feels weirdly out of character. I THINK that’s the point? They’re being misrepresented for some kid’s school project. Pike is angry and lashing out about the cameras being around. M’Benga is represented as a violent shady war criminal. He tells Uhura her friend is dead, just so he can get her reaction on camera. Oh yeah, just ask your sister on camera, who’s knee deep in PTSD, how her hand is doing after 3/5ths of it was dissolved in Gorn Goo.</p>

<p>Neli, the friend I watch these with, describes it as “them trying to do ‘Faranheit 911’. A kind of shockcumentary that is so up its own ass and full of itself. Yeah.</p>

<p>Also the camera shakes around so much this is so extremely hard to follow and hurts to look at. Beto is… bad at being a documentarian. I’ve said that a lot, but his camera work is ass, as ass as his editing. Why was THIS GUY given full open access to record anything on the flagship of the Federation?? It’d be like giving Uwe Boll unlimited access to do whatever he wants.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sqdG641.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Is he RECORDING PEOPLE WITHOUT THEIR KNOWLEDGE for this documentary??? I doubt that’s legal in the Federation. At least it seems like everyone on this ship is kind of sick to death of Beto. Uhura tells him to fuck off after he asks her some self pretentious shit about colonizers. At least we know where THAT romance plot is going. I swear, if they STILL try to push a romance with them after this episode, it’ll be even worse than the Worf x Dax bullshit.</p>

<p>So there’s some kinda plot about a society at war with another society, and they’re doing some kind of project to make this giant space amoebas into beasts of war. The neural implant they’re using is torturing it, and it breaks so it can’t be controlled anymore, and it lashes out. They communicate with it telepathically, find out it can’t control itself, and they help it commit suicide. That’s the plot. Honestly, not terrible? I would have liked to watch a normal-ass Trek episode about it. Because the first half is whatever hte fuck was going on there, weird propaganda shit, and this second half is actually Trek-like and kinda okay, but it’s COMPLETELY ruined because I was so extremely checked out. Also the editing and camera work are still fucking ass.</p>

<p>And it just ends. Here’s some comments from a video that put the ending out there clearly:</p>

<p>“The space moth killed itself and that was sad. But is war bad? Well at the end of the day: it is what it is. But most importantly: we are a family. The End” - robstein1313</p>

<p>“Is Star Fleet a military colonizing force? I think the real Star Fleet is the friends we made along the way.” - CouncilofGeeks</p>

<p>All of this was done to give character development to a character that I didn’t really care about and thought was just a little annoying at best, and now I kind of hate him. And this episode.</p>

<p><strong>Four and a Half Vulcans</strong> - SNW
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/04GBE4L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Something about this title feels insulting</p>

<p>We’ve got more relationship troubles cause that’s all this show does now. La’an is ALREADY making shit awkward with Spock, and Pike’s girlfriend wants to get back to work, and needs Pike’s help making her old boss happy about it. But before we can do ANYTHING like that, we have to do some shenanigans.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gMfQRpe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s a very flimsy reason that they need to do this, but they need to all become Vulcans through the reverse of that serum they gave Spock to make him Human for a bit. It doesn’t work on Pelia, who continues to be the best character in this season. The serum makes them all extremely annoying and theyre IMMEDIATELY working overtime to be weirdly racist towards Spock for being a half Vulcan. They go down to do the job they had to do, do it super fast, and then dip back up. But oops, the Vulcan serum doesn’t work and they can’t turn back.</p>

<p>Everyone is handling being a Vulcan Very Poorly. This is just badly written Vulcan things. Yes, logic can be used to justify bad things, like racism, or apparently in La’ans case BECOMING A SPACE CONQUERER? Yeah that’s a thing. Yes, you could justify all that with logic. If you’re a bad person who wants to come up with any reason to be bad you can do that. It’s very easy! But these are not bad people. These are good people who want to do good things. But they are not now, because of bad writing.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SPXpIT9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They decide to stay as Vulcans (though La’an is clearly actually a Romulan, which could be VERY bad), because it’s so much better for everyone. Obviously. I say this is grounds for IMMEDIATELY locking them up and mutinying, but even Spock is like “maybe we should not do that”, and he’s being shafted so hard. All the Vulcans do horrible things, like Uhura LTERALLY brainwashes Beto. Hmm. They need help, so Una seeks help from her ex, Doug.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CZKI7VS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is Doug. He’s a Vulcan who is fond of Human cultures and when he and Una are nearby each other they want to make out with each other violently. It’s comedic in a way that does NOT fit. Doug agrees to help them connect with the Vulcan’s katras, which they, no joke, do off screen. Just, cut to black, come back in, “Anyways we solved it”. Are you shitting my dick????</p>

<p>Only one person is resisting being brought back, and that’s La’an. Spock talks to her inside her mind, and he straight up says “Your sadistic and untrusting and violent, that’s because you are related to Khan”. WE LITERALLY HAD AN EPISODE ABOUT THIS, ABOUT HOW BIO-ESSENTIALISM ISN’T REAL AND SHE CAME TO ACCEPT THAT PART OF HERSELF. BUT NOW NO, BIO ESSENTIALISM IS REAL. YOU’RE EVIL, LIKE ALL IN YOUR LINE.</p>

<p>They fight, then dance, and then she goes “okay yes change me back”. The rest of the episode is like 10 more minutes of everyone going “holy shit I’m so sorry for being awful” and then it ends. This episode kinda sucked. The writing was DRASTICALLY uneven. There were some fun moments and a lot of really bad ones.</p>

<p>At the end though you have Spock giving Doug a How To Be A Human lesson and I kinda like that.</p>

<p><strong>Terrarium</strong> - SNW
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/btQTDWc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is something I’ve wanted since Strange New Worlds first came out. We’re FINALLY getting it. An Ortegas central episode. Ortegas has always been around and good with snarking in the sidelines, but she’s never gotten her own centric episode. Everyone else has gotten like, 3 each. So why am I worried?</p>

<p>Because the writing has been pretty bad this season, AND they have this “Ortegas has PTSD” side plot. I can think of a MILLION ways they could fuck this up.</p>

<p>Ortegas is sent out in a shuttle to do a simple solo mission to release a subspace relay, when suddenly a wormhole pops up RIGHT on top of her and she’s sucked into it. Enterprise sees her disappear, with her last line being “I’VE GOT IT! I’VE GOT-“. And then boom, she’s gone. Damn, rest in peace, Ortegas.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zFOXC4C.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>No, obviously not. She manages to release the buoy before crash landing. Her rations get burned up in the crash, I dunno why you’d put the rations next to the explodium. So she goes about preparing to survive on a hostile alien world.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LoVVWiI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Okay, props to the writers of this so far. If you asked me how Ortegas would handle being stranded on an alien planet, it’s EXACTLY this. She’d talk to herself a lot and be sassy. Honestly, they don’t even need writers. Point a camera at a good actor and let her adlib for 45 minutes, and you’ve got an Ortegas episode. Fantastic. She’s doin’ shit like building a condensor and going “Hello Mr. Condensor, please Condense” like, I love it?</p>

<p>Back on Enterprise, they gotta go meet Captain Decker of the Constellation soon so they don’t have time to stick around for a rescue. If you don’t remember, Decker is from the episode of TOS where they fight the Planet Eater. Or as I call it, The Windsock, and as I call him, The Windsock Guy. Uhura is DETERMINED to get Ortegas back, and fights for them to stay.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dpfOrtm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ortegas finds a Gorn living on the moon she’s stranded on. At first it seems like they’re gonna fight, but the Gorn is actually… not very aggressive? It kills something and gives Ortegas some of it. It’s a disgusting bug, but hey, shockingly friendly Gorn. The Gorn is injured, though, and Ortegas obviously doesn’t trust it, so she basically robs the Gorn and tries to run away back to her shelter. She sees a light in the sky, aaaand the shuttle falls into a sinkhole. Whoops. Ortegas is then attacked by more bugs, but is SAVED by the Gorn! New Gorn Best Friend :o</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QHOWVNj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ortegas can’t really communicate with the Gorn easily, but fashions a communicator that can give yes or nos, basically. The Gorn can actually understand her, because “you want to understand your enemy?” “Agree”. The Gorn and Ortegas spend time getting to know one another. It’s a girl Gorn, so it’s “a couple of girls having a slumber party”. Ortegas teaches her Chess, she teaches her some kind of game. They actually get along rather well. New Gorn GIRLFRIEND?!</p>

<p>The Gorn is too injured, and if it’s rescued, that’s a death sentence. The Gorn blow up their own ships if they’re too weak. Ortegas is like “Well, then come with us, and show my people that you’re as wonderful as you showed me!” The Gorn doesn’t seem very happy about that. All the while, Ortegas feels like she’s being watched, and there’s these weird lights in the sky. I think I know what’s going on.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qaesgzY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ortegas and the Gorn work together, Ortegas convincing her to TRY and stay alive, and they have one wild plan. Light a GIANT explosion that’ll hopefully alert Enterprise they’re there and get them teleported out. Ortegas risks her life to light the flare, getting the attention of Enterprise… but also something else. And when Enterprise comes and immediately blasts the Gorn, killing it, Ortegas goes NUTS. Screaming out at whatever’s watching her. And it’s…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rdScTg6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I FUCKING CALLED IT. The Metron is like “We need more data to determine if the Gorn and the Humans can ever find peace.” AKA, Arena. The Metron says Ortegas isn’t ready to meet them, erases her memories, and then they’re sent back. And the Gorn? Still dead. Still very, very dead. Fucking god dammit. My Gorlnfriend &gt;:(</p>

<p>This was FANTASTIC until the bad feeling at the end. It’s just a shaggy dog story. And the Metron being there actually doesn’t add much, it prolly would have been better without it. Weirdly nostalgia bating for nothing to add to it. This WOULD have been a 9/10, maybe even higher, if they had stuck that landing. But right now it’s just…. kinda anger enducing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 188</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/04/OOCY188.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 188" /><published>2025-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/04/OOCY188</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/04/OOCY188.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rcngdeP.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Girlfriend Limited to 7 Days</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Girlfriend Limited to 7 Days" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 210 - Amazing Tater</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/10/04/RA210-Tater.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 210 - Amazing Tater" /><published>2025-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/10/04/RA210-Tater</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/10/04/RA210-Tater.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tTngzrQ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So the other day I reviewed Kwirk, which is a cute little Gameboy puzzle game. This is the sequel to that. You might think that means that means its pretty similar. You’d be correct!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ePpYQH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Amazing Tater, also known as Puzzle Boy 2 in Japan (frankly, I think both names are bad), plays almost exactly like Kwirk. You push blocks around, push em into holes, and move around spinners which can be blocked. Move to a goal. It’s frankly a simple and fun little puzzle game. All new puzzles, go give it a whirl, not much more to say, right?</p>

<p>Well, there IS one new mechanic. In some levels, you have multiple characters! There’s a, like, collection of characters made for this game. Kwirk himself is nowhere to be seen. And sometimes, multiple are in a level at once. You can swap between them with select, which honestly is a fun addition to sokoban that increases the complexity by quite a lot.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8sAAswB.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The other new addition is a race mode, of sorts. It’s a little weird. You have two versions of it, one where it’s a race, and one where you’re lost in the woods. You get a random selection of puzzles, and you need to solve them. If you solve them fast with no resets, you continue onwards with the race. If you fuck up too much, you fall back in place, or get more lost. It’s a weird system, but I kinda get what they were going for.</p>

<p>All in all, this really is just more Kwirk. If you like that kinda game, then you’ll like this. Not much more to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Platformer" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 187</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/02/OOCY187.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 187" /><published>2025-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/02/OOCY187</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/10/02/OOCY187.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Mc6XvDB.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Under One Roof</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Under One Roof" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 13 - 16</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/28/LizstartrekEnt1-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 13 - 16" /><published>2025-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/28/LizstartrekEnt1-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/28/LizstartrekEnt1-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ssVkiCl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>IT’S BEEN A LOOOOONG ROOOOOAAAD</p>

<p><strong>Dear Doctor</strong> - ENT
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NUKFOp8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>YAY A PHLOX EPISODE! Phlox is so extremely the best character in this show its not even funny, so giving him an episode ABOUT him should be great! Right?</p>

<p>Phlox has a wide collection of animals he keeps in his lab, which he takes care of lovingly. He’s wonderful, I love him. He’s been getting messages from a Human friend who helped him get accustomed to life on Earth, and they’re doing a penpal thing. So he’s basically writing to him about his day to day life. Phlox is very good with living on a Human ship, but he’s NOT Human, and it’s easy to kinda forget that. But he gets along very well. There’s also a crewman with a big crush on him. I don’t blame her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gtrUykj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They meet some aliens who are dying from a disease, and Archer conscripts Phlox to help cure them. Phlox is like “Obviously I want to help but I’m worried that he’s putting 4 billion peoples’ lives on my shoulders”. It becomes worse when he finds out the disease is actually genetic, and that makes it MUCH harder to stamp out.</p>

<p>There’s also some stuff about how this planet has two species with seperate cultures, that did NOT kill each other. Rare. One are the Valakians, one are the Menk. The humans view it as bad, the “lesser advanced” species is kinda kept in camps and used for manual labor, but the species is happy and safe and fed so they’re happy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/j0iZl9i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The aliens, the Valakians, ask for ftl technology so they can go meet more aliens and ask for more help. Archer is like “they are NOT ready” and kinda hates he’s being put in the spot of the Vulcans. It’s interesting, actually.</p>

<p>Phlox is like “I’ve made a cure but I don’t know if it’s right to save these people, cause it could effect the future of the Menk”. Archer literally goes “one day we might make a doctrine about what to do in a situation like this. We might call it a Prime Directive, even. But that’s not this day, so we have to decide now not to play god”, and decides not to cure the disease but help nudge them in the right direction and give them medicine to ease the symptoms so they can develop a cure themselves.</p>

<p>This was just straight up a good Trek episode. Interesting moral and setup, said well cause of the Phlox narration, doesn’t give you the answer but lets you kinda sit on it.</p>

<p><strong>Sleeping Dogs</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L9Mzu37.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While lookin’ at a class 9 gas giant they find a damaged ship sinking into the atmosphere, with some life signs on board. They go down to try and help out, but they only have an hour before the ship sinks too far. T’Pol, Hoshi, and Reed are going to help them, and Reed has a bad cold.</p>

<p>They get on the ship and quickly find out, whoops, it’s Klingon. Reed wants to save them, T’Pol is like “they would not want you to do that, and if they wake up and find us, we’re dead.” Well, one comes out, finds them, beats the shit out of Reed and then steals the shuttle and runs off, leaving the others stranded on her ship. Rude. The Enterprise captures her quickly, and heads into the Gas Giant themselves to rescue them.</p>

<p>That plan falls apart quickly, as the ship starts groaning. It’s a Submarine episode, yay! Enterprise backs out, and now they really have one plan Get the Klingon to help them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hPwJ5rZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>That’s not gonna be easy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WEeq2gk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hoshi has a freakout, understandable, and T’Pol holds her hand and tries to meditate with her. I did not expect to ship these two but damn, they got chemistry. Of course I’m over here shipping the ONLY TWO WOMEN ON THE ENTERPRISE TOGETHER but look, it works.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hKouaO8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer starts thinking like a Klingon, and uses that knowledge to play the Klingon against herself. He convinces her, and they go down JUST to find that they’re LITERALLY blowing themselves up to try and move upwards in the Gas Giant. They rescue the Klingons, who IMMEDIATELY prepare to open fire for the indignity of being saved. Archer punches him right back in the nose, metaphorically, and he runs with his tail tucked between his legs. The episode ends with the three of them, T’Pol, Hoshi, and Reed, sitting in decon, relaxing.</p>

<p><strong>Shadows of P’Jem</strong> - ENT
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b2I0hbr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve FINALLY got a sequel to the Andorian episode! Admiral Forrest is talking with a Vulcan about the situation from that episode. Forrest is like “Dude no offence but you DID literally break a treaty” and the Vulcan is like “truly it is a shame you are too EMOTIONAL to understand it’s fine to break treaties when we do it”, then announces the Vulcans are pulling out of Earth.</p>

<p>Archer gets the news and delivers it to T’Pol. P’Jem got blown up by the Andorians, and the Vulcans are coming to pick T’Pol up. He tells T’Pol this is CLEARLY an emotional reaction from the High Command, who just wants to punish someone. And T’Pol is the easiest target.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JANne01.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer takes her on one last mission, to go exploring a nearby system and meet the people there. They are IMMEDIATELY attacked and captured by what appear to be rebels. The government of this place is “propped up” by the Vulcans, so they immediately assume T’Pol is the captain. She lies and claims she is to get heat off of Archer. I think I’m sensing a theme.</p>

<p>Trip throws a hissy fit and is angry about what’s going on. I don’t like Trip, why is he here and in charge so often? It’s like if season 1 Paris replaced all his horniness with more idignant insults and was also the 2nd in command. Anyways, the Vulcans show up, declare they are taking over the situation, are gonna go in guns blazing so that they, quote “discourage this kind of behavior in the future”. The Vulcans are, as usual, fucking awful in this, but Trip being Trip really really doesn’t help. It’s a really dick vs assholes situation over here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/whrfCr1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Trip and Reed are IMMEDIATELY captured while trying to rescue T’Pol and Archer. Of course. But it’s NOT from the rebels… it’s the Andorians!!! They’ve been listening and watching and are like “Yeah you were being led into a trap, and also if you DO go through with the hostage demands they’ll just kill your captain anyway. But we know these people, and we repay our debts”. Thy’lek Shran is here! I might just keep calling him Jeffry Combs.</p>

<p>Any attempt to resolve this with subterfuge with the Andorians is shot when the Vulcans come and Uhura Maneuver the whole thing, killing everyone they can. T’Pol is shot and injured diving in front of a bullet meant for the Vulcan leader, and Shran straight up tells him “YOU should be dying, not her”. Damn, he’s kinda fucking awesome???</p>

<p>The Vulcan Captain begrudgingly agrees to talk to the high council about letting her stay.</p>

<p>There’s a thing I realized here. There’s good Vulcan writing, like T’Pol gently going “Oh, I cannot leave. It would be violating doctors orders” at the end. Writing where the Vulcan is a hardass, but in a way that hints at the humanity inside. And then there’s bad Vulcan writing, where the Vulcan is a racist.</p>

<p><strong>Shuttlepod One</strong> - ENT
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gOCwnAN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed and Trip are doing some exploration and find something weird on an asteroid… the Star Ship Enterprise, wrecked and crashed.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, ON the Enterprise, they area talking aobut how there was a recent problem where a launch bay door got blown off, but it’s all fine :) Oops, Reed and Trip think the Enterprise blew up cause they found a single door. Unfortunately a lot of their systems are down due to other problems. They can only move at impulse, and have ten days of air. They set a course for the closest base, though they’re not gonna get CLOSE before they die. So they’re kinda just preparing for death.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xQkY1eG.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed is getting morose and depressed and spending his last 9 days writing apocalypse logs. Trip is pissed off about how cynical he is and how he has to be his room mate for 9 days here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ipQblHU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Reed wakes up and finds himself in the med bay, where T’Pol professes her love for him for all his selfless acts to save Trip or whatever the fuck. Yeah, keep trying to imply Reed is straight, y’all. Obviously it’s a dream. But even for a fake dream, it is SHOCKINGLY unromantic. Reed keeps saying “stinky” as if thats romantic. What the fuck? Is this a gay man thing?</p>

<p>Anyways this episode is just these two men BARELY hiding their contempt for each other, arguing as they’re about to die. I’m reminded of other episodes that have this dynamic, like the DS9 one with Odo and Quark, and this is nowhere NEAR close to that, because Reed is okay but not super interesting and I straight up do not like Trip.</p>

<p>They turn off the heat to conserve air. Did you know that the cold isn’t the problem in space, it’s the heat? Anyways, they get a message from Enterprise who say “hey we found you, we’re on our way” but they’re moving at warp 2 cause they think it’s fine. It’s not fine. I think this episode would hit bigger if we didn’t know the Enterprise was fine right at the start, and we were unsure? I mean obviously it was fine, cause thats how a show works, but you know. They blow up their engine to light a flare to hint “hey come here faster”</p>

<p>ACTUALLY good Trip moment? He tries to kill himself to double the oxygen for Reed. Reed holds a fucking gun at him, on stun, refusing to let him. They go together, or they go alone.</p>

<p>Obviously they go together, saved. Reed makes a pass at T’Pol. She shoots that shit right down. She has a date to go to with Hoshi, after all. This episode wasn’t bad but eh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 186</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/27/OOCY186.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 186" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/27/OOCY186</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/27/OOCY186.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fi1O3J5.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Silent Hill f Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/27/SilentHilf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Silent Hill f Review" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/27/SilentHilf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/27/SilentHilf.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7yLJLIT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Silent Hill is back. Apparently.</p>

<p>I wouldn’t call myself a Silent Hill superfan. Silent Hill 3 might be my favorite horror game of all time (though it might be SIGNALIS, I’d have to think on that), and 1 and 2 are fantastic as well. 4 is okay, and everything after that you can basically just leave. Though I did unironically like Shatmem, maybe even more than 4.</p>

<p>The series was re-awakened after a decade about two years ago now. Let’s ignore the pachinko, they do not count. Konami announced THREE new Silent Hill games at the exact same time. The first was one stupid AI thing or something that no one liked and everyone already forgot. The second was the Silent Hill 2 remake, which a lot of people liked. I didn’t enjoy what I saw, but I am a Bloober Team hater. And then they announced Silent Hill f.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y1ueDE4.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There were a lot of thoughts about the trailer. The most prevelant ones I heard was “how is this a Silent Hill game”. It DID look more like Siren to me, but there were a lot of other things that set Silent Hill f apart. It takes place in Japan, the first Silent Hill game NOT taking place in America. And it’s VERY Japanese. It’s so extremely culturally Japanese, it feels like Mega Man 6 where they made Wily’s castle extremely Japanese for some reason. It’s also the first Silent Hill game produced in Japan since…. fuck, The Room? Silent Hill 4? That was a long-ass time ago. According to interviews, the reason this game is so extremely Japanese is cause they were afraid the series has become too Americanized and lost its Japanese roots. Which again, is interesting, since the series ALWAYS took place in America.</p>

<p>There’s another important thing about this game that there was a lot of talking about before its release. It stars a woman, and is very, VERY explicitely about feminism and the way women are treated, specifically in 1960s Japan. A lot of people were angry about that, and I heard lots of the funniest shit I’ve EVER heard, like someone going “I hate that they’re shoving this woke shit in there. Why couldn’t it be like Silent Hill 3, where it’s feminist, but you can easily ignore it cause it doesn’t shove it in your face”. THE GAME WHERE YOU LITERALLY ABORT GOD? So yeah, THAT made me interested. As I said, Silent Hill 3 is an utter masterpiece to me, and anything TRYING to invoke the ideas and themes of that is something I will at least be slightly interested in.</p>

<p>So I played it. And it’s…</p>

<p>alright. It’s alright. Not bad. It’s the best Silent Hill game we’ve gotten in a while. And it IS a Silent Hill game. I saw a lot of people claiming it doesn’t feel like one, but it IS. It’s a different setting and got some different vibes, but it has a lot of nods to the original games. “This is just a Fatal Frame” game was the funniest thing I saw from people who stepped in and watched for two minutes. Yes, they are both very Japanese. Fatal Frame is ghosts and spiritualism. This game is VERY meaty. AND flowery!</p>

<p>The thing this game REALLY reminds me of is Higurashi. In many ways, it feels almost like a retread of Higurashi. But that makes sense, they’re both written by the same person. This game was written by Ryukishi07, a guy I don’t know a lot about, but I respect a lot because his name is a reference to Final Fantasy V, and like respects like.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WTnP6lG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Silent HILF you play as Hinako, a Japanese school girl in 1960s Japan. She has an argument with her family one day and goes to spend time with her friends, when suddenly Horrible Shit starts happening around town. One of her friends dies, monsters come, a fog monster is killing everything, Shits Bad. Hinako is an ordinary enough girl, though she’s always been a bit of a tomboy and prefers playing with boys. She always strained against her alcoholic father for being a failure of a woman, though her sister always protected her…. until she left to get married.</p>

<p>This game is not subtle about its themes. That’s not a bad thing. I will once again point to how we saw a character abort god earlier in this series. I have no problems with that. And the things its saying ARE good… but I dunno. It’s hard for me to explain, but I don’t think it hits as hard as it, or I, want it to hit. Yes, women are forced by incompetent and failed societies to place all the burden on themselves, that does suck. What’re we gonna do about it?</p>

<p>There is ONE thing about the story, though, that kinda floored me. So, I looked at a lot of reviews of this game before I got it, and they all said the same thing. 9/10, very good, and it also has a scene in it that’s possibly the most haunting, upsetting thing in any Silent Hill game, or even horror game, so heed the content warnings. I think it’s more a 7/10, but that warning? They uh, they were not kidding. That shit was upsetting. It’s not what I expected (I expected sexual assault, which thankfully is NOT a thing in this game, except for the one monster inspired by it), but it really blew my mind. I liked it, it was good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YoJT6tn.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I do like the monster designs. Silent Hill has always had good monster design that fit in with the themes of the game, and this is no exception. You’ve got creepy dolls, women who are beaten and abused and lash out at those they CAN lash out at, horrifying sex predator monsters, big pregnant monsters who’s only job is to breed, school children scarecrows who watch and strike when you don’t expect it, it’s good.</p>

<p>The story, vibes, and themes are all fine, but didn’t blow me away. The gameplay, on the otherhand, was outright annoying. Silent Hill combat has never been good. Ever. And that’s fine. I don’t mind that. The issue is, uh, this game has the combat be MUCH more important. There’s no guns or anything, what the fuck do you expect, this is Japan, not America. Instead, Hinako uses exclusively melee weapons, and it IS cool to play this school girl beating the shit out of monsters with axes and naginata.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TMGei5z.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But the combat is very clunky and annoying, and filled with required counter attacks, and I never liked counter attack combat. The first 70% of the game was rather good, because I could fight when I felt I needed to, but avoid combat a lot of the time, like all the other Silent Hill games, and only really have to engage 25% of the time, or for bosses. But then uh… the last 30% of the game is Not like that. The last 30% of the game FORCES you into a lot of combat. You have a LOT of combat arenas in a row, and nothing else. No real exploration. No puzzle solving. JUST combat arenas. All the enemies are damage sponges, ESPECIALLY the fucking breeder enemies. AND the game has a weapon durability mechanic. Yes. That DOES suck, I agree!!!</p>

<p>It frankly ruined my enjoyment of the game. It doesn’t help the game runs like shit on my computer, and I have a new, strong computer. I was just happy for it to be over by the end, I could barely enjoy the ending. And then I learned another rough thing about the game. It has like, 5 endings. 1 bad, 2 neutral, 1 good, and a UFO ending. You can ONLY get the bad ending on your first playthrough. Then you need to get both neutrals on New Game plus, then fiiiinally you can get the good ending. So you need to play this game four times to get the best ending.</p>

<p>No thanks. It wasn’t long, or anything. It took me 11 hours. But I can’t be assed to play again.</p>

<p>Do I recommend Silent Hill f? I do. But not for 70 dollars, and ESPECIALLY not for the 80 dollars I paid for it for the special edition. Though the art book IS nice. For 40 dollars, this is a good deal. But I know what world we live in now, so like THAT’LL ever happen.</p>

<p>So, is it a return for Silent Hill? I’m not certain. It’s a step in the right direction, at the very least. But maybe if you’re looking for a modern Silent Hill game that’s as mindblowing as the classics in the series, just play SIGNALIS or Sorry, We’re Closed.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Horror" /><category term="Silent Hill" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 209 - Kwirk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/27/RA209-Kwirk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 209 - Kwirk" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/27/RA209-Kwirk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/27/RA209-Kwirk.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z5Wq4HV.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing my random early Gameboy exploration, we got KWIRK! Kwirk is a rather classic gameboy game, though I don’t think it ever really hit that eschalon of anything above cult classic. But when I played this, I did have lots of people in chat go “oh man I played this a lot in the car back in the day”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VxylGws.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also known as Puzzle Boy, this is the second game I’ve played in this series. The first was on PCEngine, and it blew. It was a buggy broken mess and was missing a lot of cool mechanics. This is so much better, it’s not even funny. In the Puzzle Boy franchise, you play as a lot of different veggies and fruits. In this one, you’re a little tomato boy who doesn’t appear in any of the other games.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wpg5Xcy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The goal is extremely simple. In normal mode, you’re dropped into a screen with an exit. Get to that exit. Between you and that exit are blocks and spinners. The spinners take a bit of getting used to how they work, it’s a bit hard to spatially grasp them, but those are really the only two mechanics. You’ve got blocks, which you can move around and push into holes to fill them, and spinners, which can be blocked depending on the shape of the spinner and whats around it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9z5ZE7K.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There’s also a challenge mode, where it gives you a number of rooms and you have to go through them as fast as you can. You decide the number of rooms before it starts, and you get points on how fast you clear each room. There’s only so many rooms the game has in store for each difficulty, of course, but it likes to do mirrored rooms to keep things fresh, and you’d be surprised how much that works to remove the previous room from your brain.</p>

<p>Kwirk is a very simple puzzle game, but one that stands tall. If you were in 1989 and had a gameboy, you could do so much worse than this. Kwirky little puzzle games on the Gameboy you can pick up and do a few puzzles in were the bread and butter for this system, and this is really one of the greats. At least, until we get to the sequel~</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Platformer" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 185</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/25/OOCY185.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 185" /><published>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/25/OOCY185</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/25/OOCY185.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mvOsIFp.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Useless Princesses</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Useless Princesses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>