<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-22T13:33:25-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 114</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/22/OOCY114.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 114" /><published>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/22/OOCY114</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/22/OOCY114.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLrthkI.png" alt="'come to think of it... how DOES it happen between girls...?' - INADEQUATE THEORETICAL KNOWLEDGE" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Please Bully Me, Miss Villainess!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Please Bully Me Miss Villainess!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 153 - Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon - Another Story</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/22/RA153-SailorMoon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 153 - Bishoujo Senshi Sailor Moon - Another Story" /><published>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/22/RA153-SailorMoon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/22/RA153-SailorMoon.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lsBIgxe.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Still playing a bunch of RPGs, trying ones I’d never really seen or played before. Double Moon Densetsu and Ghost Lion kinda burned me by being just okay, but SURELY this one will be good right? I mean, it’s SAILOR MOON! I like Sailor Moon! I’m a girl in her 30s who grew up watching it, of COURSE I like Sailor Moon, that’s like, the law. Uh, no. Sadly, no. This one is pretty damn mid.</p>

<p>This Sailor Moon game is an RPG for the Super Famicom, and it is the most fanfictiony thing I’ve ever seen in my god damn life. Basically, the plot is there’s an evil powerful shaman who gains control over time, and she sends her bad guy five-girl squad into the past to change history, so that the Sailor Scouts are defeated and she can rule. Simple, and quite fitting for Sailor Moon, right? That’s pretty typical stuff. What makes it fanficky is that they’re changing the fates of characters we know, EXPLICITELY so that the Sailor Scouts (you can tell I’m from the 90s, they’re not called that anymore) can fight enemies from their past. We get retreads of all the villains from season 2 and 3 of Sailor Moon. We DO also fight Beryl, though her five goon squad are actually good guys in this game. I guess the writers liked them too much.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/U1TNO42.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a time travel timey wimey plot, and like true fanfiction, it makes NO fucking sense. It has no care for scale, or plot, or consistancy. It falls apart under the SLIGHTEST scrutiny. I’m not about to sit here and tell you that this sailor moon game is bad though because it has plot holes, that’d be dumb. If anything, it helps. It’s VERY fun to point and laugh. What the fuck is this weird cult-like town that’s in the middle of Canada that you visit? Why did it exist thousands of years ago during the Silver Era???? Where are the natives? Oh it doesn’t matter. Like I said, it’s fun to laugh at.</p>

<p>The one thing I REALLY did not like in the plot was the decision to take the Goon Squad from the second half of season 2 (in other words, the good half), and change their fate. Unlike EVERY other villain in the game that we fight, these are the actual same normal girls. Like, for example, you fight Sailor Saturn’s dad, who was brought back to life and back to the moment where he was a villain. That’s like an AU version of him dragged here. But the Spectre Sisters are EXPLICITELY the same Spectre Sisters from our universe. They settled down and quit being villains and are living a happy life…. except now that time travel fate changing powers are in play, they join in and get themselves killed pathetically, throwing themselves at you one after another in one on five boss fights, just for the chance of maybe grasping victory again. It’s a slap in the face from their story conclusion in Sailor Moon R &gt;:(. I’m angy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cWWI4St.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Goon Squad this go-round are the Oppositio Senshi, who are basically just evil-sailor scouts. They’re all assigned a Sailor Scout to be the opposite of, and they’re kinda like that Scout, taken to an extreme. They’re also all named after Mesopotamian gods. Nabu is Mars’ counterpart, she’s cold and calculating, but to an extreme, with little empathy. Ishtar is Venus’ counterpart, she’s aloof and goofy, but taken to an extreme. You get the idea. Sin is the leader, and she’s focused on helping and saving her friends and family… <strong>No matter what</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oWgMaw0.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So that’s the story. How’s the gameplay? It’s uh…. it’s boring! In this game, you mostly walk through hallways, and occasionally open mini-dungeons and door mazes, fighting random encounters that will NOT threaten you, because Sailor Saturn is UNBELIEVABLY BUSTED. And if you have Sailor Pluto on your side, good fucking luck to the opponents. She can freeze time for 3 turns, heal her MP, then cast it again, and stun lock you down. This works on EVERY boss. But what if you don’t have them on your team, due to story reasons? Well, then you grind. This game is VERY grindy, and unbalanced. Poor Sailor Mars gets the short end of the stick, she’s basically useless. Which is really a shame, because she’s my favorite Scout. The first chapter is the Scouts all splitting up, and you do a small mini chapter with each of them. Mars’ chapter is agonizing, because she does NO damage, and is made of paper. She has heals and support stuff, but that doesn’t help when its just her. Oh also, these mini chapters with all the scouts alone? The mini-plotlines in them all have the Scouts fall in love with some random OC made for that mini-chapter. Uh, Ami has a boyfriend, game. He’s even brought up and mentioned.</p>

<p>The art is really nice. It’s cool that they have all the Scouts in there. They have this team up system where you can learn skills with Scouts fighting together. You have this menu, plop two Scouts together, and if they have a teamup skill, you learn it. It takes like 5 minutes to plop them all together. The music is forgettable. All in all, this RPG is just extremely mid, which is a shame. It’s very interesting as a fan of Sailor Moon, but for ANYONE else, it’s not worth it at all. It’s also interesting because the game was made AS Sailor Moon S was being worked on, so they had to look at the notes for what the Outer Senshi were going to be like, but had no idea who the hell they were cause the devs hadn’t watched that part of the anime yet. That’s kinda funny.</p>

<p>Anyways, meh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Sailor Moon" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 113</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/20/OOCY113.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 113" /><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/20/OOCY113</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/20/OOCY113.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/F8jX2h9.png" alt="'It's a bit embarassing to have Kanata look straight at me like this...' *They're dating and live together." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: My Love for My roommate Was One-Sided</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="My Love for My roommate Was One-Sided" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 152 - Math Gran Prix</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/20/RA152-Math.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 152 - Math Gran Prix" /><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/20/RA152-Math</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/20/RA152-Math.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0YVOeuW.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing my random “I want to play Atari Games” kick, this is Math Gran Prix. This is also the only game I’ll prolly post with only ONE picture cause uh, that’s it. It’s just this screen. You control one of the two cars. You choose to move 2 or 3 spaces, then do a math problem. If you do it right, you move that number of spaces. Some of the spaces on the board change how you move, like letting you move ahead random spaces, or letting you choose again. If either of you land on each other, it stuns the other.</p>

<p>It’s basically a REALLY shitty math board game. There’s no strategy, it’s dead simple, and the AI is a shithead that cheats, ALWAYS staying right behind you and knocking you away at the worst point. It’s very annoying. I THOUGHT this game would be a goofy little fun time with a bad game, but it was mostly annoying.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Atari" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 112</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 112" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/18/OOCY112.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cgmpP2V.png" alt="'So this is a date...' The other girl stares in confusion. 'Yes?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Voice First, Face Second, Hollyhock</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Voice First Face Second Hollyhock" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 11 - 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/16/LizstartrekVOY4-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 11 - 15" /><published>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/16/LizstartrekVOY4-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/02/16/LizstartrekVOY4-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KIXeBlw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Concerning Flight</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/S0bixIF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Janeway in the Leonardo Davinci holodeck again. He’s testing a flying machine, and they both test it, jumping off ab ridge, right into some water. She KNEW that machine would not work, but she jumped off the bridge anyway. Janeway’s here for a good time.</p>

<p>Anyways they’re suddenly attacked by some aliens who basically mug them, transporting stuff through their shields (don’t ask questions) and then running the hell away. They steal a bunch of things, including the main computer, and now Voyager has to limp along. THey manage to track the stuff down to a commerce planet, where it’s being sold off and whatnot. And then, as they’re investigating, they meet…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8X9D0Q2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>GIMLI! Look, if you get John Reese Davies, you use him for all he’s worth. It’s Davinci! He’s been downloaded into the Doctor’s emitter, and is walking around this planet. He’s very entertaining, and is also seeing things through his limited holonovel’s programming, so he thinks its America. The working title for this episode was “Davinci’s Day Out” which is very funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y00tcLD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We also find who did the stealing. His name is Tau, and he’s a consumate businessman. He’s totally willing to sell the computer back actually, all it would take is a small price. Like, a warship, maybe? Yeah there’s no way they’re affording this, it’s too valuable. Tuvok goes back to the ship while Janeway stays behind with Davinci to try and learn more, but once Tau learns who she is, he holds her captive, cause ooh, imagine the money he can make holding her hostage! Aaaand then davinci slams a tank into his head and knocks him out cold. Let’s fuckin’ go.</p>

<p>This is taxing and straining Davinci, who was NOT built for this. He gets shot and starts having an existential crisis, but Janeway plays to him well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bZxQVJX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Yes but not how you’re thinking.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oWBSqSQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They escape in a contraption Davinci’s been working on… a flying apparatus, based on things Janeway suggested to him. It’s actually a touching moment. They’re teleported out of the air and rescued, as Voyager makes its escape. This was just a cute episode.</p>

<p><strong>Mortal Coil</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EKRBa60.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got a Neelix episode! Neelix is being Ship Dad, helping take care of everyone, it’s actually super sweet. He helps the only kid on the ship (who’s suddenly like 8 years old don’t worry about it) get to sleep by telling her stories about his faith. His people believe in The Great Forest, a wonderful afterlife. He’s such a sweetheart, I don’t get why ANYONE wouldn’t like him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Pr3v7xy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyway, Neelix is killed abruptly in an away mission to collect Protoplasm, which I guess is the prototype of plasm. I can’t believe they killed off Neelix like that. Well, all that making us like him stuff at the start is just there to make us realize what we lost, huh?</p>

<p>No obviously, Neelix isn’t DEAD dead. Well, he is. He is very dead. He’s been dead for 18 hours by the time they get him back, cold and gone. But according to Seven, the Borg have techniques that could work, as late as 78 hours after death. Hot damn, I’m sure that’ll be super useful in the future! Oh nevermind.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7YLepdY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Neelix is still his chipper friendly self… or so it seems. He’s still a sweetheart, and wants to do what he can to help out, though everyone is a bit worried about him, obviously. He volunteers to help Chokie look into what went wrong in the Holodeck. Chokie is like “are you SURE you’re okay?” but maybe he should have pushed a bit harder cause yeah, when Neelix sees his own fucking corpse, it kinda… snaps something in him. He realizes he was dead for 18 hours, and there was nothing. He was told all his life he’d go to an afterlife and be with his loved ones who had died, and it had carried him through so much. But now he can’t believe that. We’ll all just, poof, be gone. It affects him.</p>

<p>It’s also bad timing, because a Talaxian holiday is happening like, in a day. And it’s a day celebrating family and love and life, and Neelix is just straight up depressed. He has to tell another bedtime story to the kid, and she INSISTS on hearing about the Great Forest, his afterlife, and it’s… HEARTTBREAKING. I have to admit, Neelix’s actor is fucking KILLING it here. He’s the same, but he’s clearly lower energy, and it’s NOT easy to play a chipper happy character who’s depressed and trying to hide it from others and have it come across not hamfisted. He’s doing a FANTASTIC job.</p>

<p>Neelix is still dying, btw, he needs to be constantly upkept. He hates it, and snaps at Seven before almost dying again. He then, once revived, asks for help from Chokie. Neelix wants to go on a vision quest. Chakotay SAYS THE THING! :D He says “WE ARE FAR FROM THE BONES OF OUR ANCESTORS”! Thats a big meme in our watch group. Anyways the vision quest goes VERY poorly. His dead sister is like “there’s no afterlife so there’s no point to being alive.” and then she dies horribly in front of him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UFGqFvb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What the fuck Chakotay, did you really need to give him the BAD shit???</p>

<p>Neelix is back to his friendly self, kind of. He goes to apologize to Seven for snapping at her, and is very… cagey. Reverent, almost. He’s also avoiding telling Chakotay what he ACTUALLY saw, and Chakotay is unhappy, cause he can kind of tell. something is clearly wrong. Neelix goes about his time, doing the work he has to do, making sure everything is neat and tidy. Then he leaves notes for everyone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gjhwNdK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Are they laying this on thick? Maybe a little. But like, as someone who has been suicidal, and has basically done EXACTLY this, planning things out and trying to leave neat and orderly? Yeah. It also hits. Poor Neelix. Chakotay pretty much talks him down from the edge of the bridge. He’s bad at it, and his actor is not doing a good job, but Neelix is doing his best. He has to stick around. People need him. He does good work here. He goes to tuck his goddaughter in, and tells her more stories.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7HDUrX1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She dreams of the Great Forest. And the positivity of faith continues.</p>

<p>This made me very emotional.</p>

<p><strong>Waking Moments</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VkdGtVc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with everyone having dreams. Harry dreams he’s making out with Seven. Tom is crashing a ship. Janeway dreams everyone died cause she took too long to get home. And Tuvok came to the bridge not wearing pants, which is VERY funny. Then all their dreams end with a weird alien just staring at them. Everyone quickly comes to the conclusion something is funny, cause they’re ALL eepy as fuck. Everyone is okay though… except Harry, who appears to be unable to wake up. And others quickly join him. So what can they do?</p>

<p>Get CHAKOTAY OF COURSE! God, they sure do love Chakotay in this part of the show. And what does he do? The ONLY THING HE DOES! HIS ONE CHARACTER TRAIT. Be vaguely native american!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JGqdIHy.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay does some lucid dreaming, and converses with the aliens. They’re paranoid that people will hurt them, so they’re trying to keep people asleep. Seems a bit unneccesary, but okay. Chakotay promises to leave, and they get directions, and off they go. Well that’s a fast episode, huh?</p>

<p>Everyone wakes up, and things seem fine. Kim is awkward around Seven, it’s cute. Anyways they’re suddenly attacked by the aliens, who are super powerful and impossible to defeat. They’re now all trapped in the cargo bay as the aliens have full run of the ship. Eventually, however, Chakotay realizes… he’s actually still asleep.</p>

<p>He wakes up, and makes SURE of it this time. It’s just him and the Doctor, who can’t sleep. Everyone else was pushed into sleep. Chakotay theorizes: These aliens are always asleep, and keep others asleep where they’re the most powerful. He’s got to chase them down.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0p5y4dz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, back in the dream, chakotay just up and disappeared right aftter saying “oh I’m still asleep”. Turns out they’re all in a shared dream. Seven calls it “collective unconsciousness”. Janeway tests this theory by literally standing in front of an antimatter explosion.</p>

<p>There’s a good jump cut where we think Janeway woke herself up like Chakotay did, but then we find out, nope. He fell back asleep. The doctor wakes him back up chemically.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2C8yCFJ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway gets to be a badass with a gun again, I love it.</p>

<p>Chakotay finds the sleeping aliens, has the Doctor target a nuke on them, and then falls asleep, and tells them “I will kill you all if you don’t stop immediately”. Chakotay was just about to wipe out an entire species.</p>

<p>Everyone is out, they think. They all have bad insomnia, understandable. And that’s it. The aliens’ like, real reasons aren’t explained, and uh, it feels kinda flat.</p>

<p><strong>Message in a Bottle</strong> - VOY
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VkdGtVc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven calls Chokie and Janeway into her Astrometrics Lab. Recently, she made a super long range scanner. Now, she found a relay network that goes a LONG way. It’s abandoned but functional… And at the other end, they see a Federation vessel. They try sending a message, but some technobabble stops them. But they CAN send the doctor!! Hopefully after he connects with them they can jsut send him back, but we’ll see. Good luck, Doctor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/liByn1e.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s now on a ship called the Prometheus!! Unfortunately, everyone is dead. Some Romulans have taken over the ship. This is just a few months before the Romulans entered the war, I guess. This is an experimental combat ship, which is kinda neat. The Doctor manages to bluff his way into helping save a Romulan who gets injured. He needs help, though. So he summons THIS ship’s EMH.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/458iCim.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is the new EMH. He fucking sucks. He’s also played by Andy Dick, who kinda sucks, which doesn’t help. He’s AMAZINGLY unlikable. He finds out they’re in a combat situation and just turns himself off. He refuses to help the Romulan, that’s “the enemy”. While the idea of a die-hard episode with the Doctor is very good, and one of my favorites, it’s uh… very annoying. New EMH is very unlikable, and Old Doctor can’t help but do a dick waving contest. He brags about having sex, among other things.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4TNp67O.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back on Voyager, the owners of the relay network realize whats going on and tell them to cut that shit out. Uh oh. Seven solves this problem by literally electrocuting this guy. Holy shit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y3VLHqe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor is caught, but EMH2 saves him. He’s still annoying. He knocks all the Romulans out with nerve gas, and they try to stop the ship. Too bad they have no idea what they’re doing. They cause the warp core to fall apart, and then more Romulans show up. Things aren’t going well.</p>

<p>There’s also a C plot where Paris is sick of being back up doctor, so he asks Harry to make a new EMH. Harry tries, turns out its REALLY hard so he gives up cause fuck that shit.</p>

<p>This episode is weird cause it’s trying to be a hectic, tense thing with two doctors trying to recommandeer this ship, and yet its like half of a bad comedy, and the other half is the Doctor making actually good quips.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rjJjTnb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor succeeds, there’s a lot of dead Romulans, and then he beams back and lets them know that Starfleet now knows they’re alive, and are working to help. I found this episode kinda annoying, but it’s got some good stuff to it.</p>

<p><strong>Hunters</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/v8XzwHP.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Immediately following the last episode, Voyager gets a new message through the relays from Starfleet Command. Unfortunately, it’s cut off, but they can get the full message if they rescue it from a nearby relay or whatever. Meanwhile, the ACTUAL owners of the relay, who are unhappy about all this, the Hirogen, decide to do something about it.</p>

<p>Seven is hard at work trying to get the messages working. She’s like “this is important to the Captain, so I must work hard for it.” Oh she’d do ANYTHING for the Captain, wouldn’t she~</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HaIxumV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The next bit is them getting their letters. Some good news, some bad. Tuvok learns he’s a grandfather now. Janeway smiles then it slowly fades as she reads her’s. Chakotay goes to be alone after reading his. He learns all of the Maquis are dead, whoopsies.  Others are reacting differently. Paris hasn’t gotten any letters and doesn’t give a shit. Harry has gotten none and its KILLING him.</p>

<p>Seven and Tuvok go in a shuttle to fiddle with the relay so that they can get the messages more easily. They’re attacked by the Hirogen, and captured.</p>

<p>I’m actually liking how people are reacting to these letters. Paris is like “I want no part of this. What I have here is so much better than what I had back home.” I actually like this quite a bit. They made me like a PARIS MOMENT.</p>

<p>There’s a scene where Seven meets with JAneway, who is sad. And I was like “please, PLEASe, Seven, ask Janeway what’s wrong, so she can explain her husband married someone else to you, and NOT to Chakotay later on. And then you can go ‘I am sorry to hear that. But it sounds like you are available, can we go on a date this weekend’”. Unfortunately she just walked out the door and we pretty much just get that scene with Chokie.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Nc1WTyl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>These are the Hirogen. They’re ALL about prey and hunting. They’re pretty much the aliens from the Tosk episode, but about EVERYONE, not just Tosk. They’re kinda cool tbh ngl. They’re not like, EVIL really. They just have very different morals. The Hirogen who captures Seven and Tuvok explains “You will probably die, more of my people are coming, these people I caught are my prize. Just leave so you don’t die too.” Obviously Janeway doesn’t just leave. They are, however, VERY scary, and fully intend to butcher the fuck out of Tuvok and Seven.</p>

<p>They weaken the relay, which is holding a black hole in it. The other Hirogen attack Voyager, which causes the ENTIRE relay to blow the fuck up. All the Hirogen explode, though they do save Seven and Tuvok, and manage to escape.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BYrisyt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, the explosion destabalized the entire relay system, so no more of that. They’re alone once more. But they got Harry’s message after all! I hope it doesn’t say like “Hey Harry, we got a new son. His name is John.”</p>

<p>We get one last scene with Janeway and Chokie where he shoots his shot. “I hope you like your boyfriends bland!”</p>

<p>Good episode all around, even if it has the Status Quo Curse.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 111</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/16/OOCY111.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 111" /><published>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/16/OOCY111</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/16/OOCY111.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y6Uz9yG.png" alt="'The tiny vibrations that give off body heat. What's going on? This feels good..... I want to hold her forever.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Apparently I haven’t hit live in 5 days? I’ve been uploading things. I SWEAR I have been. Huh.</p>

<p>source: Just Her in This Big Wide World</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Just Her in This Big Wide World" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 110</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/14/OOCY110.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 110" /><published>2025-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/14/OOCY110</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/14/OOCY110.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hXPjbqK.png" alt="'Matsuko-chan! Please accept this!' 'huh?!' 'I had a dream about you before. Since I woke up, the whole world has been sparkling. I really... wanted to meet you.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G59l8wH.png" alt="'....Meguru, you really... are an idiot, aren't you? This.... I sort of did at least half the work to make it...' 'Ah... ehehehe well it will definitely be delicious!' '...Then I will... indulge myself!'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Happy Vamilumtimes Day!</p>

<p>source: The Two of Us and Apples</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Two of Us and Apples" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 151 - Laser Blast</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/12/RA151-LaserBlast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 151 - Laser Blast" /><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/12/RA151-LaserBlast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/02/12/RA151-LaserBlast.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ki7uqpY.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I felt like playing random Atari games, so I did. This is Laser Blast, a relatively liked Activision game on the Atari 2600, and one I’d never even heard of before I picked it up to play. Like most Atari games, it’s a simple arcadey game. It’s like the inverse of Missile Command. You play as a UFO and you go around on the planets surface blasting turrets that shoot lasers back at you. You can move left or right, and shoot. If you’re moving as you shoot, you aim slightly left or right, otherwise you fire straight down. Your laser has some good width to it. Once you clear all the turrets, you move onto the next screen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Baesq1D.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is about rhythm. The enemy AI is easily manipulated if you do the same movements over and over, so it’s about finding those movements then committing them to a rhythm to quickly blow up all three turrets and move on, over, and over. To master this game, I had to get 100,000 points. At about 30 points per turret, that’s a lot of turrets. Apparently if you did this back in the day, you could send the picture in to Activision to get a patch for the Activision Federation of Laser Blasters? I want my damn patch, Activision.</p>

<p>The higher difficulties don’t change much, other than the turrets’ rate of fire and movement capabilities. It certainly gets more challenging, but you just need to find the right rhythm again. This game isn’t MUCH, but I had fun with it for about an hour.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Atari" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 109</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/12/OOCY109.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 109" /><published>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/12/OOCY109</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/02/12/OOCY109.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BIsXKxF.png" alt="'You said it! I knew you'd have fun!' 'Yeah.... but the customers get touched too? I didn't expect that.' 'what? They do?? ...I guess they could sense the powerful bottom energy that you put off.' 'WHAT DO YOU MEAN BOTTOM ENERGY?'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Asumi-chan Is Interested In Lesbian Brothels!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>