<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-06T23:31:06-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 1-7</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/06/LizstartrekVOY3-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 1-7" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/06/LizstartrekVOY3-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/10/06/LizstartrekVOY3-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xgK8LCx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Basics, Part 2</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0wsS1j5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We jump back to our crew, now a bunch of exiles on a planet. Things are looking up! Oh except one of them, a Maquis dude-bro, who’s eaten by some kind of lizard while trying to grab bones. And it’s all Neelix’s fault. Also they have to eat grubs. It’s gross and no one is happy. Understandably.</p>

<p>Oh hey, Paris is alive! His shuttle is on fire and struggling but he’s alive. And being kinda badass, still fighting off Kazon.</p>

<p>Seska comes in and talks to the Doctor, who’s been hiding, but can be good at deception! She actually asks him if he’s good at deception, and it’s like “No,” the Doctor lied. She wasn’t here for any of his character development. Anyways he informs her no, that is NOT Chakotay’s son. He just kinda looks Human. Who knows what a Kazon/Cardassian hybrid looks like?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1NbEwKd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Doctor and Suder team up. Suder is willing to help take the ship back, and save everyone. Suder is like “Oh boy, here I go killin’ again!” He’s not happy. He’s been trying so hard.</p>

<p>Neelix and Kes are kidnapped by alien cave people. It’s a stupid scene. We already have die hard on the ship, and a survival situation, and Paris sneaking around space, do we ALSO need aliens trying to slave trade for Kes?? Also, when they couldn’t start a fire, Chakotay is like “We need SOME kind of kindling! Where could we find some?!” and they use hair, which would prolly would but wouldn’t be the best idea. You know what would be? ALL THE GRASS THAT’S ALL AROUND. INCLUDING THE ONES THAT THE ALIEN CAVE PEOPLE USE TO START A FIRE TO SMOKE THEM OUT.</p>

<p>This episode would be better without any of the stuff on the planet. If they just focused on the die-harding on the ship and we saw the crew at the end, broken and bruised, it’d be kinda interesting. Though maybe not. Maybe in that universe I’d be like “why did we not see any survival???” Anyways, horrible CGI beast that uses the same sound effect as a Hydralisk eats another crew member. They’re dropping like flies.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5ErvyTZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I think people might not like Suder? I find him very interesting. I am also chemically unbalanced and mentally unwell, and while I’m not like, unbalanced in a way I want to MURDER people, I respect and admire a character who’s internal demons are telling him to do things he doesn’t want to do, and he’s fighting against them. Even more so when he has to feed those demons to survive and help others. I LIKE that. Yes, calling him a sociopath, and 90s sensibilites are… a thing, but I like him, and he’s MOSTLY handled well.</p>

<p>Seska finds out about the Doctor sabatoging the ship, and though she thinks there’s another person on there. But the Doctor is VERY VERY good at deception, actually, and convinces her he did it all on his own and PRETENDED there was another on board, so they’d search him whoever that is. Genius. Seska buys the bait, but kills the doctor, blowing up his server. RIP Doctor, a real one. Suder’s all that’s left. The Doctor left a heartfelt message to him. He’s our only hope. He can do it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dlsyTfu.png" alt="trek" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/U2rFKcf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A full Uhura Maneuver later, and there are a dozen dead Kazon. He’s shot in the back by a dying one, but manages to overload the systems in time for Paris and his fleet to take Voyager. The resulting explosion kills a LOT of Kazon, and also kills Seska, who crawls for her baby. Culluh cries over her corpse and takes the baby, abandoning ship. They’ve lost. Paris and his allies board the ship and head back to rescue everyone.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fo0UcYK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They mourn Suder as a hero, repair the Doctor, and Chakotay mourns Seska in his own way. I’d have thrown her out an airlock, but whatever works. They take off from their new home to the old one. They didn’t even get to take a shower, Paris is still covered in smudge lmfao</p>

<p>I loved half of this. The other half, not so much. It’s also worth noting that we will NEVER seen the Kazon ever again. With the Vidiians and the Kazons done, we’re almost at a soft reboot! We have no more bad guys. Gotta get some new ones.</p>

<p><strong>Flashback</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W7awxMD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things are okay on Voyager! They maybe found a new energy source and are going to pick it up. Suddenly, Tuvok has what seems to be a panic attack. He freaks out and leaves the room for sickbay, while having a flashback to something from his past. Young him, trying to save a girl from falling in a pit…. only issue is, it wasn’t a memory. It never happened. No one knows why this happened, could be so many reasons. While they study is, Tuvok Isn’t Doin’ Great. He goes back to active duty the following day, totally fine. But uh, he’s not. And he’s like “Well we should be wary about cloaked ships this close to Klingon space” and everyone is like “…what???? Dude” and then heh as another panic attack.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HzUn48E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Basically, in Vulcans, if they’re repressing a memory, it causes really bad things to their brain and causes them to die. How to fix this? A mind meld with a close family member, so they can bring that unconscious memory into the conscious memory, work through the trauma. Mind meld therapy session. Tuvok has no family on the ship obviously, so he mind melds with Janeway instead. She’ll basically be watching in a memory, no one reacting to her. He’ll take her back to his childhood…. and yet instead, we’re taken to the excelsior, 80 years ago.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EVjLUCA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So, Tuvok’s actor was on the Excelsior in Star Trek 6. They kinda retconned that that was young Tuvok, which is pretty great. We get to see some TOS characters! The last time we see… ANY of them, I’m pretty sure, until like, waaaay into Discovery. We’ll at least never see these actors again. (Technically Trials and Tribbleations aired after this, but there was no new  We see Sulu, who’s pretty great and fun here, and Rand! This is actually taking place DURING Star Trek 6, when Sulu goes to the Klingons to try and save Kirk.</p>

<p>Tuvok has another attack, and Janeway is forced out of his mind. After a bit they try again, and we learn some more Tuvok background. He was kind of a racist back then and didn’t even want to be in Starfleet to begin with. He eventually had a change of heart, “though heart had little to do with it. It was an entirely logical decision”. I’m sure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xMGAd08.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>KANG IS HERE! He politely tells Sulu to fuck off. Sulu does not fuck off. They give them a slip, but are attacked, and Tuvok’s roommate dies. This seems to do something to the meld, and the meld is falling apart, killing them both… but Janeway feels like they’re CLOSE. However, the disrupted meld causes issues, and everyone can see Janeway now. They need to restart the meld, with Janeway stealing Rand’s clothes. If I were a woman on the Excelsior and Janeway asked me to take off my clothes, I’d do it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TlHBfFD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back in the real world, the doctor finds out that a third memory engram is in there, some kind of virus. A viral memory. Weird. Anyways it had infected Tuvok’s roommate, and jumped to him. He wipes it out using radiation, the end. Feels like the actual things they were doing in the memory didn’t do anything and weren’t actually important? The Doctor just solved it with deus ex radiation. But it was fun to see TOS characters.</p>

<p><strong>The Chute</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3VyZYFq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>KIM</p>

<p>MUST</p>

<p>SUFFER!</p>

<p>Kim falls down the titular chute into some kind of jail, and is immediately beaten up by the prisoners there. Including Paris, who joins in on the beating. Computer, delete Paris. Paris makes up a story about a bombing and how Kim sold him out to get him away, and then they explain. The two of them were blamed for a bombing and thrown down here. It’s a prison 300 meters underground, in a hole. So it’s the prison in Batman Rises. but they also have been implanted with some kind of thing in their brains, and it’s making them itchy. Also it’s literally driving everyone insane.</p>

<p>We find out a bit more about what’s going on. These people, the Akritirians, are a fascist government. There was a terrorist bombing and they kinda arbitrarily decided it was Kim and Paris. They then declare that they will take Voyager and throw everyone on it in prison, so they attack Voyager. Of course, Voyager can handle it, but this is mostly extremely annoying for them. They NEED to get their people back. But how?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wnPcBeH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris is stabbed in a prison fight, because prisoners don’t play fair. They find a prisoner who’s SHOCKINGLY sane. He’s been in there for six years, and is handling it really, really well, writing alone in his little hut. Harry gets him to join them, as he’s possibly onto a way through the chute and back out of the jail.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mcG60lM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He’s writing a manifesto. He’s got it all figured out. He knows why they put the clamps in them. It’s not torture. It’s population control. This understanding kinda allows him to just… ignore its effects. It’s never clear if he’s ACTUALLY sane or not. Anyways, Harry does it, breaking through the chute, they can escape!! Except… nope. They’re not under the ground. They’re in space.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4sfs7hX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Well that’s not good.</p>

<p>Janeway finds the actual bombers, and has them dragged to the Akitirians. But the Akitirians refuse to release Kim and Paris, because it’s how fascism works. Isn’t it effective? :D Janeway gives the prisoners an ultimatum. Take us to the prison, or you’re going to the Akitirians anyway, even if we get nothing out of it. When he tries making demands about letting others out, she’s like “Nope.” It’s…. pretty hardass of her, especially after that one fucking episode where she was pretending to be the daughter of someone fighting against a fascist regime. LOTS of fascist regimes in this part of space? Anyways, they go to the prison, and Janeway dives down the chute, blasting everyone immediately. That’s so funny. And wonderful. Anyways they make it out, safe, and work through Kim almost killing him while they were both being driven insane.</p>

<p>It was tense and kinda good, but some things about it kinda annoyed me and felt flat.</p>

<p><strong>The Swarm</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0lU3yB9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Paris and Torres doing banter on a ship when some cool-ass aliens beam onto their ship. Paris is like “uh, hi, I’m Paris-“ and is IMMEDIATELY shot. I can only assume they went “OH FUCK, IT’S THAT GUY, FUCKING GET HIM”. They then beam off the ship. Guess they just wanted to kill Paris. My favorite new aliens.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the Doctor is doing some opera in the holodeck. It’s nice that he has hobbies. Picardo is doing his own singing here, and it’s real good! But the Doctor is having some… issues. He forgets the lyrics. When he goes to treat Paris and Torres, he seems forgetful and distracted. But he doesn’t seem to notice. I’m sure he won’t have anything important to do- oh, looks like PARIS NEEDS SURGERY. With Kes’ help, they stabilize him.</p>

<p>So, since the Doctor has been awake for so long, his program is starting to fall apart, basically. They can just restart him to bring him back to normal, but that erases who he is after 2 years of experiences, and restarts him anew. Everyone thinks that’s bad, but the doctor is okay with it, because he can’t help people this way, and that’s his #1 goal. But Kes convinces them to at least TRY to save him. Torres is trying, but having trouble. So she calls on the one person who might be able to help them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7TnXXcl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They set up a holodeck of Dr. Zimmerman, the EMH’s creator. He is… awful. And his answer to the problem is “just erase his personality who cares”. Poor EMH is starting to become SCARED about his existence. Meanwhile, they’re trying to sneak through the bug people’s home, because otherwise it’ll add 15 months of time onto their travel. This is weirdly the B plot.</p>

<p>This feels like a response to Measure of a Man, but with a twist of talking about dimensia and alzheimers. Like, it has the “he’s just a machine, he doesn’t need friendships or hobbies” angle, but also a “he’s useless to us as he is.” Even KES starts to think they should just reinitialize him, after he doesn’t even remember who she is. What’s the point of those friendships and love if he can’t rememeber? Whoof. Keep in mind, this isn’t ME saying that, that’s a point the episode is saying. It’s really painful to even see the Doctor, my favorite episode here, fall apart like this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ek8IYQ8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode has a lot of treknobabble. They say the word “Interferometric pulses” a lot which is very funny. Anyways they stop the swarm, it’s a weird addition to this episode.</p>

<p>They sacrifice the Dr. Zimmerman diagnostic program in order to rebuild the EMH’s emgrams or whatever. No one knows if it’ll actually work, but after the fusion is complete, the EMH is here, and working, but doesn’t seem to know anyone ): Sad… but as he walks away, he starts humming opera to himself. I think it’ll just take a minute for him to warm up.</p>

<p>Pretty good episode all together.</p>

<p><strong>False Profits</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IMCXNDR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager comes across a wormhole that goes to the Alpha Quadrant. Oh boy, the show is gonna end, how lovely. They can’t quite get into it cause it’s so eratic, but they’re working on it. Meanwhile, a nearby planet shows scans of a replicator’s emissions, which is apparently a thing, so it seems someone from the Alpha Quadrant is here. Chakotay and Paris go down to a planet filled with totally-not-humans, and are IMMEDIATELY accosted by a bunch of money grubbing swindlers. They make their way to The Holy Temple, and get a look at the prophets.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/X6hpIlJ.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>Do you remember that episode of TNG where they were trying to get the rights to a wormhole to the Delta Quadrant, but it was unstable and some Ferengi got stranded on the other side? HERE THEY ARE! This FINALLY pays off, an amazing brick joke in the works. And of course, they’re taken the replicator on their ship and are acting as gods who can summon anything they want.</p>

<p>Technically they can’t stop them, because the Ferengi are not Federation, and don’t have a Prime Directive… buuuut, technically, them being there IS kind of the Federation’s fault. Or at least, they can tell themselves it is. So they can interfere and fix their problem. Legally. The Ferengi argue that if they’re taken from this planet it’ll drive them into chaos, because their gods suddenly abandoned them. Janeway HAS to agree. So in order to save these people, they need to out Ferengi the Ferengi.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/HKhbjXW.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>They got Neelix pretending to be a Ferengi sent by the Grand Nagus. Beautiful. It works EXTREMELY well… until the ferengi decide to circumvent it by just trying to assassinate him. Neelix then freaks out and explains the whole thing. Shockingly they DON’T kill him and let him go, as a warning.</p>

<p>Instead, they just listen to the song that explains what the prophets to when they come out. And so they bring the NEXT prophet along (still Neelix) to announce its time for them to go home, on wings of fire. This works… until it turns out that they interpret that azs “BURN THE SAGES ALIVE”.</p>

<p>&lt;img src=”https://imgur.com/iAlIVTs.png” alt=”trek”</p>

<p>They manage to beam them out in time. But even still, the Ferengi manage to FIGHT SECURITY AND BREAK OUT, getting into their ship and trying to get back to the planet. They ALSO destabilize the wormhole, because status quo is king. Voyager would have ended if they had more than one person guarding the Ferengi.</p>

<p><strong>Remember</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gBYq9WC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is near some nice friendly aliens who are helping to upgrade their systems. That’s pleasant. After a long day of work, Torres goes to sleep, and has a dream where she’s making out and fucking some dude. This dream is SO intense that it has her sleep through her duty shift. She seems to like these dreams, they’re vivid and fun. It’s like a living holo novel where she’s got a bad boy boyfriend her father doesn’t approve of.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, we find out that these friendly aliens are psychic! They have EXTREMELY laws about consent. Ohhhh no I know where this episode is going. By the way, this episode is a re-used episode concept from TNG, where the original idea was about this happening to Troi. YEP. IT’S ONE OF THOSE EPISODES. WHY DID THEY KEEP TRYING TO WRITE THESE EPISODES ABOUT TROI?</p>

<p>After a dream ends in her lover being burned and scarred, Torres decides that actually, this is probably something she should look into. She’s gonna ask one of the Inarans about it, but she passes out before she can get to anyone, so now EVERYONE knows about it. She wnats to keep exploring these dreams to learn more, something about it unsettles her, but it might be hurting her brainmeats.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7OlTR47.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Her dreams continue. Her boyfriend is a “Regressive”, basically amish. They don’t use technology, and living in the city, the “normal people” are worried because they might start a plague or something. So they’re just being… moved! They’re being relocated, it’s TOTALLY a thing they’ll agree with and like! And not forced at all! Yep! That’s right!</p>

<p>This is <strong>A genocide episode</strong>. These people are being genocided just behind the scenes. They’re transporting people away and just killing them. And when Torres wakes up again, she has a theory on who it is. It’s an old lady on the ship who’s dying, and she goes to save her, but the lady is like “No, I have to give you the rest of it, they’re trying to silence me”. Ruh roh.</p>

<p>Yeah there’s a lot of disgusting genocidal rhetoric that you see in this episode. It’s REALLY scary and fucked up. And she’s FORCED to join in on the genocide by her abusive family and the fascist regime she lives in. When it all ends, she has a GIANT speech about how disgusted she is by all of them for the cover up, interrupting a lovely party with talk of genocide. How rude??</p>

<p>She manages to pass the memories along to someone, just so that this memory isn’t lost forever. Even if nothing can be done.</p>

<p>This was SO much better than I expected. It’s not a mind-assault episode like I thoguht it’d be. Torres having agency, and trying to both push the puzzle forward and then spread the word helped a lot.</p>

<p><strong>Sacred Ground</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MNKcxIu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While exploring some alien’s holy shrine, Kes is electrocuted by a shrine and everyone is like “well clearly she pissed off the spirits, so there’s nothing we can do.” They can find no scientific paths to saving her, but there is ONE path. There’s an ancient story of a king who’s son did what Kes did, and the king did a ritual to speak to the spirits, and begged them to save his son. So that’s what Janeway is going to do. But she’s pretty… science-minded. How is she going to be able to handle this religious experience?</p>

<p>It’s an interesting setup. I like how it shows Janeway. She is very openly athiest, but extremely open towards religions and belief systems. Except in THIS case, where it’s killing a member of her crew. And the religious members are excited to help her with this. No one ACTUALLY wants Kes to die. So if there’s a way out that satisfies both parties.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XXJ2zvC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>There’s some very fun like, ancient mystical monk rituals. Every so often we jump back to the ship where Chakotay is grumpy and wants to rescue Janeway and everyone like “Dude she went through this of her own volition, let the woman do her job”.</p>

<p>When she finally gets an audience with the spirits (the doctor, viewing her biometric levels, says she’s being given a psychative drug). The spirits in her dream tell her she has everything she needs to save Kes, that everything she went through was meaningless. Her guide says that too. And when she goes back, they try to use the info to save Kes, but it doesn’t work. And again the doctor repeats those words. Everything she did was meaningless. Her guide explains that yeah, all that was just cause that’s what she was expecting. The ritual isn’t even a real thing. She just has to believe in the spirits. She has to take Kes and walk into the “biogenic field”, aka the spirits, and trust them.</p>

<p>Chakotay is the voice of “this is stupid don’t do that” which is very weird? CHAKOTAY of all people like “HOW CAN YOU BELIEVE IN THESE FOOLISH BELIEFS”? Oochie Mama, we are far from the bones of our out of character. She takes her through anyway, and it saves Kes. The Doctor has a big scientific explanation for what happened, but Janeway is a bit… out of it. Her belief in science, what was a solid rock to her, is kind of broken.</p>

<p>While the concept was kinda cool and a few scenes were fun, it was a LITTLE boring sadly.</p>

<p><strong>Future’s End Part 1</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pVBz5PC.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back in the 60s, something slams into a mountain as a hippie watches. Far out.</p>

<p>Back in the present, y’know, the 2300s, Voyager meets a Federation ship from the 2900s. It attacks Voyager, explaining that Voyager is causing a major problem in their future, and must be blown up. In the fight, they’re both sent back in time to 1996. Now they’re stuck in the past and need to find that “timeship”. They have reading to go off of. Los Angeles.</p>

<p>It’s always funny to see modern times in Star Trek.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MGcLarr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And also fun to see how the Trek crew try to fit in.</p>

<p>A SETI girl at an observatory catches wind of them in orbit, specifically based on a reading that some rich guy told her to look out for. He calls her up and he’s like “Do NOT contact them” and uh, she does anyway. It’s a very silly “standard greeting” for aliens. Very funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wNIXst8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find Braxton, the guy who was in the timeship, the guy from the 2900th century. He explains that his ship causes the timebreak in the future, so yeah, it was all his fault, it’s a paradox they have to carefully untie. He’s also a homeless raving lunatic who is very VERY bad at being a timecop. He’s a timecop from the future trying to stop time crimes, and in the past he tried to tell everyone he’s from the future and he’s treated like a raving lunatic, cause he’s acting like one. God how can you be this bad? He also explains that his ship was found by that rich CEO I mentioned earlier. Holy shit, the rich CEO was the hippie. That’s very funny.</p>

<p>They split into a few parties. Tuvok and Paris go to wipe the hard-drive of the cute dorky lady at SETI. At the same time, Janeway and Chakotay are going to break into the CEO’s house to find the stuff he stole. The CEO ALSO sends a goon to take out the dorky lady for sending that message to Voyager, and tells him to take “the weapon”, AKA a future phaser to kill him and the Voyagers.</p>

<p>I love this nerdy girl, I wish she’d join the crew. Voyager coulda been so much cooler if they just kept adding characters that they find. This show’d be better with her and Airheart joining the Voyager crew.</p>

<p>The rich CEO captures Janeway and Chakotay fiddlign with his systems, and even after being told he’s gonna blow up the future, he doesn’t seem to care. Like… dude? He’s trying to be a laughing maniacal villain, but like…. look I know he’s a rich guy and is thus evil, but it’s kinda stupid to be told, by people you KNOW are from the future, “you’re gonna blow up everything”, and then go “lol nah I know what I’m doing”. He’s being a fucking idiot.</p>

<p>Kim flies Voyager down to save them, teleporting them out. This ALSO makes it so EVERYONE sees Voyager. How are all of them SO BAD AT THIS?! The episode ends with the CEO stealing a lot of data from Voyager, including the doctor, who is now physically in his office. How is the CEO defeating Voyager with a DOS PC? How is the Doctor physically in his room? Again, with a DOS PC??? I don’t fucking know. And it’s very annoying.</p>

<p>It’s fine, but some of the things about it really bugged me. I’ll have to see how they wrap it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 4 - Paint Chase</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/06/UFO50-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 4 - Paint Chase" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/06/UFO50#4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/06/UFO50-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N1c1zYS.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s nearing the end of 1983, and we’ve got a new game by LX Systems! This one is called Paint Chase, and it’s designed by Gerry Smolski. Up until this point it hasn’t been exactly apparent what Smolski or Chun brought to the table, but it’s made clear here. Smolski was not a game designer. He was the hardware specialist. LX Systems made the LX itself, as well, you see. And his job was to make sure everything worked on it. But he had an idea, and decided to branch out, and this was his first attempt. How did he do in his new role as game designer?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/K9p9TvI.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Paint Chase is a racing action arcade game, though really less racing and more just themed around it. It’s more like Rally-X than a more modern idea of a racing game. You play as a little car that’s leaving paint behind it, and you need to paint as much of the ground as you can. At the end, you’ll be judged by how much of the arena is blue. Get above a threshhold, and more opnto the next level. There’s like 25 or 35 levels, and they get increasingly complex and difficult as you progress, throwing in new enemies and things. The enemies move around painting things pink. Pink or not pink doesn’t really matter to you, though, your main goal is just making EVERYTHING blue.</p>

<p>The game has some delightful music by Petterson, and it even has more cute cutscenes! A bit more expressive than what we get in Ninpek, these cutscenes are between every 5 or 10 levels or so, and introduce new enemies. It’s a welcome change.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VRUToz5.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Unfortunately, it doesn’t fix the game for me. When I first played Paint Chase, it felt kind of mid to me, and it’s only worsened as I’ve played it more. The conceit and concept is fun enough, and it doesn’t play poorly. Your car can’t turn around, which can make for some “ah fuck” moments, but it’s fine. The main issue is the enemies. This game is way too long, and it’s an RNG nightmare. I managed to beat it, with a few pretty good levels. I got a score of 350. What do you need to win? 550. Jeezus. Basically at the end, for every percentage you’re over the required percentage, you get a point. Good enough concept, but the enemies are WAY too numerous. They can spawn right next to you and easily be taken out, which makes a good score easy. Or more likely, they will spawn on seperate sides of the arena.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KbSYnnx.png" alt="Paint Chase" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>People watching me complain were like “oh, focus the gernades”. I did, then the slugs on the other side of the screen overwhelmed me. “Oh no, you need to focus the slugs.” So I did. Then the planes got me. “No, you need to focus the planes.” I CAN’T FOCUS ALL OF THESE THINGS, especially when they’re on seperate sides of the god damn map, and no matter what, I have to leave some of them alive, and some are <strong>faster than me</strong>. It’s an exercise in frustration, and no, I don’t like it very much at all. It’s just not very fun to play to conteract the frustration. I almost never feel like deaths are my fault, and that should never be how it is.</p>

<p>I’m sorry, Smolski. Maybe you’ll do better next time?</p>

<p>4/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 17</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/06/OOCY17.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 17" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/06/OOCY17</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/06/OOCY17.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IDuVQGR.png" alt="&quot;If that keeps going, I worry that 'dying because my wife was too cute' might become reality...&quot; &quot;That's it! And at the funeral, 'they both died because we were too cute...' WON'T THAT HAPPEN?! THAT'S BAD! I NEED TO KEEP LIVING!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yurikon</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yurikon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 16</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/05/OOCY16.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 16" /><published>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/05/OOCY16</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/05/OOCY16.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UNf2ef8.png" alt="&quot;The hell?! Swimsuits are crazy!&quot; she says, staring at some tits" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Don’t Know Which One Is Love</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Don&apos;t Know Which One Is Love" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 3 - Ninpek</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/05/UFO50-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 3 - Ninpek" /><published>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/05/UFO50#3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/05/UFO50-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2TZ4O53.png" alt="Ninpek title screen" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Following Bug Hunter, the trio of Petters, Chun, and Smolski needed to make a new game. Their previous two games were a little… uncommercial, maybe? Bug Hunters was an interesting but kind of difficult to grok puzzle strategy game about mutant bugs, and Barbuta is… challenging. But there’s something big sweeping the nation in 1983… that’s right, NINJAMANIA! Ninjas are REAL in right now, let’s make a game about that! And so we get Ninpek. But is Ninpek just the trio selling out, or is it worth a look?</p>

<p>Ninpek starts off the bat with an extremely impressive innovation: scrolling. Scrolling to us today feels like a no brainer, like yeah, what about it? But in the early 80s, this shit was hard to get working. And ESPECIALLY on microPCs at the time. Smooth scrolling on DOS basically asn’t solidified and commonplace until the 90s, and the LX is no DOS. It wasn’t really commonplace in the home until… gee, Super Mario Brothers? And that’s after Ninpek. So Ninpek was MASSIVELY ahead of its time. It’s not choppy either, it’s smooth scrolling.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLp9426.png" alt="Ninpek" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Ninpek is a game where you play as a ninja, and your hoagie gets stolen. I call it a hoagie, it could be a burger. Anyways, you gotta get your hoagie back. That’s it. There’s a cute little intro, and then you’re off. The screen auto-scrolls to the right, and you run and shoot your way around. Very early arcadey platformer, the most obvious real life analogue might be SonSon, which in 1984 in arcades, was impressive. And this is 1983 in the home. I do feel this is a BIT of a temporal anomaly? Like, when I say it’s ahead of its time, it’s REALLY ahead of its time. It also for some reason reminds me of Chubby Cherub, but I have no idea why.</p>

<p>It’s not very complex. Run, jump, shoot. You move alongside the screen, so you constantly gotta fight against the screen in order to hit things in front of you and not run into them. It takes a little getting used to, but it’s mostly just weird to our modern sensibilities. For the time, it made sense. When enemies die, they drop little blobs that will give you points. You don’t get points until picking up the blob, incentivizing a bit of hectic and occasionally risky maneuvers to get your shiny points.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Muh7ETS.png" alt="Ninpek" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game ALSO has music for the first time! While no one is directly credited with anything in the game, Petters is credited in later games for sound and music, so assumedly it was his composition here. The music is pretty pleasant, IMO. It’s VERY Ninja-y. Which y’know, makes sense. This game feels very VERY Japanese, though it’s important to note I have no fucking idea what country this company is from. Parts of them feel British, American, and Japanese, all at the same time. And kinda nothing helps symbolize that more to me than a section in the game with little collectibles. They’re cherries, then you collect enough, and they become rice balls. Mmm, jelly donuts. Then collect enough of THOSE, and they turn into… coffee! Coffee is a pretty common sight in these games, these devs love their coffee.</p>

<p>Anyways Ninpek is nothing like, transcendent, but for an early 80s arcade platformer, it’s stunningly ahead of its time and quite enjoyable. I cherried it on my second ever attempt, which in this case means two loops through the game. Pretty challenging, but a good challenge.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 2 - Bug Hunter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/04/UFO50-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 2 - Bug Hunter" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/04/UFO50#2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/04/UFO50-2.html"><![CDATA[<p>The year is 1983, only a few months after Barbuta was unleashed onto the world. Thorson Petters, the artist, was nearly fired for making the game on company time, but that’s okay because he didn’t really seem to like working at Business Soft anyway. I mean, with a name like that, who would? So he and two of his coworkers and friends, Gerry Smolski and Benedikt Chun, break away Business Soft to form LX Systems, a fledgling game company making games for the LX. The LX, like most micro computers, was never really intended for video games, the industry was still so extremely new. But companies like this began to pop up all over the place, and while LX Systems was not the most creative name for a company focused on making games on the LX, it would soon prove itself with its next, and technically first, release: Bug Hunter.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6FJ8GMl.png" alt="&quot;Bug Hunter&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Bug Hunter, you play as a mercenary exterminator hired by a moon quarry to stop bugs that have been running rampant. Can you stop the bugs before they overrun the mine? To assist you, the owners of the quarry will drop energy blocks on you, which can be used to upgrade your weapons.</p>

<p>The game is an extremely interesting strategy puzzle game. You have slots for seven actions. You start with very simple actions, run, jump, shoot, and lob. As you collect energy, you can spend it to change out your actions for a new action. This also refreshes the action, so if you have the energy, you can keep cashing out to do more and more things in one turn. Each turn, bugs and energy will spawn, and your goal is very simple. Kill the bugs. If a bug is not killed in a turn, it will evolve into a new form of bug. These bugs all have different abilities, some way worse than others. You’ve got bugs that make holes when they die, bugs that turn energy into anti-energy near them, bugs that explode when they die, bugs that create fodder and can’t be killed unless you kill the fodder (the worst), bugs that take two hits (the OTHER worst). And after they evolve, then evolve again into scarier forms, they will become… take a guess… yep, that’s right.</p>

<p>An egg. Oh, Petters.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4a8p0OE.png" alt="&quot;A screen of Bug Hunter&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And then if you can’t kill the egg, it will hatch and you’ll IMMEDIATELY lose. Eggs also don’t count towards your kills, so it’s best to not even let them get to that point. On top of needing 30 bug kills to win a round, you also need to finish in ten days. So an average of 3 bugs a day. Not too bad, right? Well, it can get pretty hectic, and it feels very RNG heavy. Some bug types feel like straight up run killers. It’s probably easier in multiplayer, and it DOES have one of those though I haven’t tested it, but the game is a real brain tickler. It also helps to remember you can mario stomp enemies by walking on them from heights, I kept forgetting that. Also, you can shoot energy to make it explode and kill enemies around it. But it can ALSO kill you, so be careful. For being a 1983 brain tickling puzzler, it’s shockingly kind, because if you’re targetting things, it’ll show where an energy explosion will reach, including all the chain reactions. Very pleasant.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/A9TgS0z.png" alt="&quot;The bug threat has evolved!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Overall, Bug Hunters is an interesting game, but not one I’d go back to every much. I got my 6 runs in a row for the cherry, and that was probably good for me. It has no music, and the graphics are primative, but pleasant enough. It feels weirdly isolating and uncomfortable, which hey, that fits. It also introduces Benedikt Chun and Gerry Smolski into the story as the other two co-founders of the company. Though they don’t have a chance to really shine here, we’ll learn more about them later.</p>

<p>7/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The year is 1983, only a few months after Barbuta was unleashed onto the world. Thorson Petters, the artist, was nearly fired for making the game on company time, but that’s okay because he didn’t really seem to like working at Business Soft anyway. I mean, with a name like that, who would? So he and two of his coworkers and friends, Gerry Smolski and Benedikt Chun, break away Business Soft to form LX Systems, a fledgling game company making games for the LX. The LX, like most micro computers, was never really intended for video games, the industry was still so extremely new. But companies like this began to pop up all over the place, and while LX Systems was not the most creative name for a company focused on making games on the LX, it would soon prove itself with its next, and technically first, release: Bug Hunter.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 15</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/04/OOCY15.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 15" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/04/OOCY15</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/04/OOCY15.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UfClyBA.png" alt="&quot;Oooh... so this is that &quot;manga anime&quot; you speak of&quot;. &quot;That's just a manga.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Demon Lord of “Yashiro”</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Demon Lord of &quot;Yashiro&quot;" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dream Journal 10/4/24</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/04/Dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dream Journal 10/4/24" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/04/Dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/04/Dream.html"><![CDATA[<p>Had a dream last night that I had to fake my own death in order to get the One True President elected. It was basically a One True King plot, but with a president of the United States.</p>

<p>So in my dream, my brother was a member of some ancient order trying to bring balance and progression to the United States, and there’s a presidential candidate that they were trying to get elected. He basically looked like JFK, I’m not gonna lie. Anyways he was nearly assassinated and gravely injured, and we were nursing him back to health in my grandma’s house, for some reason, when we got the call of what we’d need to do.</p>

<p>While transporting the president elect to a small seedy town, we’d need to fake our own deaths, and the death of the president elect. Then, nursing him back to health, in two years, just before the election, he’d rise again, as if from the dead, and take his place as the rightful <del>king</del> ruler of this <del>realm</del> country. It’s a very Return of the King energy plot, but with America slapped hastily on it. And in hindsight, working for a shadowy organization trying to rig a presidential election is a little sus of me, dream brain.</p>

<p>So we made our way to this new town. My parents were driving us there, JFK in the back seat in a sick bed. And by driving us there, I mean we hitched our car to a train and were riding the train. We made our way to this new town, though my parents weren’t TOTALLY in on the story, they just thought my brother, JFK, and I were moving to this new town. As we got there, we went to the police station to ask for assistance, and my brother pulled out a fucking gun and pretended to rob the place. Shots were fired, he and JFK dipped, and I was left with a “WHAT THE FUCK AM I DOING” situation. I heard a deep voice bellowing in my mind, telling me to do the right thing, and I <strong>went with them</strong>, for some reason.</p>

<p>Now that I had faked my own death, I was stuck with my brother, lugging around this injured dude, in the seedy underbelly of this new town. We were assisted by two floating talking plushies, who had taken some of the bullets for us and wanted us to join their gang. They explained they couldn’t be injured cause of their plushie bodies, and my brother wisely went “Ah yes, but I’ve heard the plushification process can lead to some really bad backpain”</p>

<p>Anyways then I woke up.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="dreams" /><category term="dream journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Had a dream last night that I had to fake my own death in order to get the One True President elected. It was basically a One True King plot, but with a president of the United States.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Dream Journal over the past two years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/04/CohostDreams.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Dream Journal over the past two years" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/04/CohostDreams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/04/CohostDreams.html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past two years I’ve been on Cohost, I’ve posted a lot of my weirder more interesting dreams over on the site. As a push to move my stuff onto my new website, this is a GIANT post, showing all of those dreams. There’s some darker and weirder stuff in here, so uh, you’ve been warned I guess. My subconscious is weird.</p>

<hr />

<p>One time I had a dream about Scott the Woz. I don’t know Scott the Woz, and I do not watch him, but other people really like him, and any time I tell them about this dream they find it absolutely hysterical.</p>

<p>So, in my dream, Scott invites me to go on a road trip to the corners of North America. We head up north to visit the most northern point of the contiguous continent. We take my car, and he’s driving. He’s like “Okay let’s go!” and then IMMEDIATELY floors it through a beach where a bunch of sea lions are relaxing, causing them to scatter, and drives directly into the ocean.</p>

<p>We scramble out of the car as it sinks and he starts yelling at me and blaming me and my car. Then I woke up.</p>

<p>I have no idea why this dream happened but it’s hilarious, and also kinda feels like an introduction skit for one of his videos.</p>

<hr />

<p>So I was lounging in my room, listening to music (it was the FF4 ost, I remember) and playing some game. I’m laying on the floor, for some reason without a shirt on, but I’m in blankets? I heard my mom talking downstairs to the kids, my niece and nephew, and she came upstairs with a question</p>

<p>“Hey Liz, Toy Story 2 for Genesis,” she asks, “is that a two player game where you can play as some crooks?”</p>

<p>I’m a bit confused. I guess the kids wanted to play a Toy Story game and also play as some crooks? I dunno. But I go “no that’s single player and you play as woody”. Note that there is no TS2 game on Genesis. I guess my brain mixed up TS1 and TS2.</p>

<p>“Oh and also in some levels you play as Buzz-“ I start, as some guy I’ve never seen before walks up the stairs into my room and then slices my mother’s throat open right in front of me. I try to scream and scramble but can’t possibly get away fast enough, the guy is between me and the only exit. He just stares at me and shakes his head.</p>

<p>Then I woke up in a huff. What the fuck, dream brain?!</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night, I needed to take a flight to a convention. My brain never really decided what convention, or where it was, but I needed to go there. And for some reason, this is what happened</p>

<p>I got on the plane and loaded my bags, including my cat. Then I realized, I had forgotten to buy a ticket, I had kept putting it off and now it was too late. So they kicked my off the flight, and my cat traveled to the convention.</p>

<p>I made my way there in other ways. I honestly don’t know how, one moment in the dream I’m like “OH NO” the next I’m at the convention. Maybe I walked. So, I’m checking my Discord and people at the convention are hanging out with my cat and posing with her. I go in and try to find her and everyone is like “Oh, I can help with that, just not right now” and then they walk away. And I’m like “I JUST WANT MY BAGS AND MY CAT”</p>

<p>Then I woke up before finding Majora</p>

<hr />

<p>I always said if I was in Star Trek I’d be a Space Librarian. That was put to the test last night</p>

<p>I was in Starfleet and the Borg were attacking. Everyone was tasked with finding SOME way to stop the Borg… so I came up with one.</p>

<p>I took an old video format, what was essentially “Space Eight Track for Video” mixed with “Space Windows ME” and packaged it up as some secret new weapon. Just the shittiest hardware and software, that we had sunk so much time an energy into getting ti work, but was a buggy awful mess. That was our secret weapon. Then we sent off a fake defense force to protect it.</p>

<p>I woke up before the Borg took the bait, sadly.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream that there was a natural phenomenon where a poison was spreading through the world. It was causing everyone to slowly asphyxiate, and was killing all the plants</p>

<p>Turns out, however, there was a cure.</p>

<p>Mario Bros 2 US on NES produced a compound that would neutralize the poison.</p>

<p>So I plugged in an NES and watched out my window as all the plants in my yard died, and people died beyond that that I couldn’t see, as my NES played cheery Mario Bros tunes.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream that Covid evolved in a way that people who contracted Covid turned into Gibdo, life sucking mummy monsters that spread covid.</p>

<p>I took up magical powers and tried to protect my house from the zombie apocalypse but there were too many, and my parents died. Then Covid evolved further, and the gibdo turned into something I forgot what I named, but it was just floating Gibdo head that could drain your life from a far with laser beams. I then went “That’s it, the human race is going extinct, I give up” and wandered into a combination gamestop and bar, and just drank to the end of the world.</p>

<p>Then I woke up!</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream a Binturong of all things broke into my house and was very, VERY aggressive</p>

<p>I managed to trick it onto the screen in back porch and it just circled around staring at me through the glass door, like it was hunting me.</p>

<p>Which is funny cause the only thing the Binturong looks like it can hunt are naps and fresh fruit that’s fallen to the ground</p>

<hr />

<p>Had an extremely not good very bad dream where a giant group of people forced their way into my house at knife point and started ransacking the place</p>

<p>This is a nightmare I used to have all the time as a kid actually. It used to keep me up at night. The thought that a robber would just break into my house and fucking kill me. I was like “this is the last night I’m alive someone is going to shoot me in my sleep” cause I had been taught that there was an epidemic of robbers who wanted to kill you</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream I was a contestant on a game show that took place in the old church I used to go to, and as a prize for winning, I was given the chance to have surgery to give me a massive penis. They represented it via a baseball bat.</p>

<p>I accepted cause shit, why not, and they brought me to this magic machine and I got inside. Then they literally forgot about me and I was standing naked in this Dick Machine for like an hour.</p>

<hr />

<p>I dreamed of floppy disks last night</p>

<p>I dreamt someone gave me a DOS PC, and I was fucking around with it, and namely a bunch of the floppy disks it came with. I was feeling them in my hands, sliding them in and out of the floppy disk drive</p>

<p>Very nostalgic. I miss it.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream last night that I was visiting my friend Cariad, who lives in Vancouver. In my dream, she lived in a giant highrise with glass floors, that snaked in intricate patterns between carpet. I once laid down on the carpet and put my hand in it and got bit by a rat.</p>

<p>We were talking about what to do while I was visiting, when The Joker’s Minions showed up, saying I had pissed him off. I had to fend them off, terrified (I tried to reason with them but no dice, it IS the Joker) and I had to blow them up with a rocket launcher point blank.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a weird and stressful dream.</p>

<p>I was living with my boyfriend in what was apparently my grandmother’s house. There was some kind of traumatic event, I can’t remember what, and he was never quite the same. He devoted his entire lifes work to taking a giant collection of VHS tapes and turning them into like, nuclear bars, through some kind of process.</p>

<p>He’d then stack these bars in the garage, which was next to the room we were in. He carved holes in the walls for easy access into the garage, going back and forth, stacking the tapes in giant piles. I was concerned, but I didn’t want to make a fuss, so I just tried to comfort him while hanging out nearby in the room, playing games on my computer.</p>

<p>And then all the nuclear VHS tapes reached critical mass, and the house exploded.</p>

<p>We were both now extremely irradiated and only had a little time to live. My boyfriend became even more lethargic, as his life’s work was ruined, and I just kind of wandered the house. My transphobic and abusive aunt and uncle came over to berate me for how I was taking care of the house, but I ignored them, drinking Tang and wandering aimlessly.</p>

<p>And then I woke up!</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream that was all over the god damn place. It was like an IRL stream where I was in a game as my friend was streaming it, and as he beat the game I was standing there next to him. Then we watched a plane start to take off right next to us, a bunch of people running after it like “WAIT YOU FORGOT US”</p>

<p>Then as I was watching I realized I was ON another plane that was also taking off (right next to that first one, at the same time) and was like “wait I never checked out of my hotel WHAT DO I DO” and my girlfriend next to me is like “I TOLD you check out was at 6AM. Why didn’t you LISTEN?” as if I had gotten onto this plane without any of my bags. I was freaking out, then I woke up with a cat in my face.</p>

<hr />

<p>In today’s dream, I found out that my old friend group apparently made a fighting game. It was a minor success for a few years. The theme was SUPPOSED to be like, fairy tales, but it didn’t stick to the theme very well, because all of the people from that friend group were playable characters. Including me.</p>

<p>The characters were things like my old friends, Santa, a spooky scarecrow guy, a prince. I don’t remember too many of them tbh, except for the newest DLC character. Which was a licensed release of Master Shake, from Aqua Teen Hungerforce.</p>

<hr />

<p>In today’s dream, I was goofing around at GDQ, but was having kind of a bad time. I lost some arcade equipment and was kinda depressed by it. To make myself feel better, I got whipped up into working with this old rich woman, who was a Fallen Diety. She was trying to Regain Her Power, which was taken from her. To that end, I needed to invite several people into “the party”, and have them join my cult too. I managed to invite all my roommates, a few others, and the fallen god’s adopted daughter. Then we needed one more. I managed to befriend the fallen god’s biological kid she had had since falling, a trans man who just wanted to have fun and speedrun Pokemon. i convinced him it’d be a fun time and he seemed into it, he just wanted to make new friends at GDQ,</p>

<p>Then it turns out that in order for the Fallen God to “rise”, this kid would have to literally die, and become part of his mom. Everyone else seemed okay with this, but I was extremely disturbed by it. The dream ended and I woke up as the two of us were being surrounded by the cult for daring to defy them.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream that some kind of cult was sweeping the nation. They had this magical tome that that hurting people and brainwashing others. Half of the Dragon Ball Z cast got turned. I pretended to be interested then stole it and started to fucking shred it</p>

<p>Then the cult leader showed up to meet the new recruit, found me half done shredding the book, and ordered me killed. I began whispering something to her right before I died, and she walked over. Then it turned out I was Bomberman, and I exploded, killing her and releasing everyone else.</p>

<p>gg?</p>

<hr />

<p>taking a nap, had a dream Cohost introduced a new feature where a user could repost a thing, and instead of the usual epost it’d have a little box in the bottom right with the reposter’s avatar, and the sentence “This user is also gay”</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night I dreamt I visited a tourist trap that had a Homestar Runner branded store. But it wasn’t like, a HSR diner, or a HSR merch shop. Instead it was like a tiny bodega packed into the corner of a shopping center where Homestar worked as the cashier. You’d go in, buy some prepackaged bodega food from Homestar (not branded, normal food), then go home. And because Homestar was the cashier, he was fucking horrible at it, and you’d stand in line for like 30 minutes.</p>

<p>It was great, I got to say hello to Homestar and he got to be an idiot at me.</p>

<hr />

<p>What would you do if a Goblin burst into the room you’re in, holding a sword, and shouted out “YOU ARE IN DANGER, FUCKING RUN”?</p>

<p>Because in my dream last night, my family just stared at me like I was fucking nuts and continued what they were doing, so I couldnt protect them from the demon that was attacking us.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream last night that I was part of a leftist freedom fighting insurrectionist cell against the American government. I was still like, living here, in my house, and doing normal stuff, but also sometimes I went into a treehouse in my back yard and used an old DOS machine that had some kind of programming that was doing SOMETHING to hurt the government</p>

<p>In retaliation, the government sent HORDES of cops and agents who went door to door, and I had to scramble to delete any evidence of the files. I kept reloading a save but they always showed up at an inopportune time like “WE ARE ALWAYS WATCHING” and carted me off to jail</p>

<p>Gee I wonder why I had this dream. Hmm.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream I slept through GDQ. Like, I just missed it entirely, sleeping all the way through it, and was fired, even though sleeping for a week and a half is probably a medical issue.</p>

<p>And I was so, extremely fired.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream I was able to go back in time in my sleep, kinda by accident, and I went back in time and got Nixon impeached early.</p>

<p>When I got back to my current time, I woke up in the car with my dad who was like “You alright?” I started asking him questions and he was getting REALLY confused and worried. Stuff about who had been president. “Why would Ronald Reagan have been president???” “Yeah, Trump was president in the early 2000s”. And I was like “I wonder how different things are in this world”</p>

<p>And then my dad drove us directly into a flooded road, while cursing global warming, which had apparently gone out of control. I tried escaping the car and woke up holding my breath.</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night, I was trying to get home from an airport, probably from GDQ cause some of my GDQ friends were there. There was a giant backup at the elevator going up to the airport, and a lot of people were belligerent and shoving us out of the way. To spite them, I sent the elevator up without them and left.</p>

<p>I went to get some food, cause my flight wasn’t for hours. After eating, I decided to get back to the airport, but it was miles away now and no uber would reach it without costing hundreds upon hundreds of dollars. And the flight was now soon, so I had to hurry! I ran through a city I didn’t recognize or know, my luggage falling off and me needing to stop to collect it every now and then, and every time I checked my phone, the airport was further away.</p>

<hr />

<p>Last nights dream: I dreamt I was doing yardwork in the backyard, clearing some plants that were causing issues. I was doing this with a blowtorch. While setting fire to my lawn, I was listening to music, specifically Simon &amp; Garfunkel. In this universe, Simon was the one who faded into obscurity, and Garfunkel gained major cultural prominence. So what kind of music did he make with his newfound popularity?</p>

<p>I was listening to like, a folksy ode about The Legend of Zelda, from the perspective of Ganondorf. I thought it was pretty good.</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night, my coworkers and I went into the Matrix to steal some data or something. We entered a giant government complex in the Matrix and raided it, my coworkers shooting up everything and running through deeper into the building. I was in the back, and extremely uncomfortable with doing murder, so I didn’t shoot anyone, and I was QUICKLY surrounded by security, who was like “DON’T MOVE” and I was like “uh, no, as you can see, I’ve done nothing wrong, this is just my cosplay”</p>

<p>They didn’t trust me and kept me under scrutiny as I milled about on my phone, pretending to be anxious about the random attack, as my Slack blew up and all my coworkers were like “LIZ YOU’RE ABANDONING THE MISSION” and I had to try and explain to them that no, I was captured, and they were angry that I wasn’t like, getting myself killed for my job</p>

<p>And then I woke up</p>

<hr />

<p>Had two dreams last night. I only vaguely remember the first.</p>

<p>The first was a new Pokemon version, I remember that. I remember it being REAL interesting and when I woke up in the middle of the night after it I was like “wow I can’t wait to write that down” and now I don’t remember anything from it &gt;:(</p>

<p>The second dream was very explicitly another gameboy color-era RPG. Same kinda graphics and stuff. It took place on a train that was moving through a tunnel and never ending. There were like, seven clans on this train, and they each had some kind of thing that they did, but some kind of dark prophecy had come to pass and the train was going to be derailed, and everyone was going to be hurt…. but I was the Chosen One, and I had to go help every clan through their Turning Point.</p>

<p>I helped two clans, I remember that, but I only remember the second clan. They had big Malkavian vibes, each of them was possessed by a shadow that sometimes took over with a different personality. One of their members had disappeared deep below into the bowels of the train, and was going to like, set a freaking bomb, completely taken over by their shadow. I was going to go below to help, when another one of them shoved by down a hole to try and get rid of me, possessed by her shadow, and fell down with me. Suddenly, I had a party member! She was this cute genki girl character, who also had a murderous shadow that sometimes took her over.</p>

<p>The two of us traveled deeper into the train, and eventually we found the missing clan member, and disarmed the bomb and stopped him. I was able to use some kind of magical chosen one powers to bring him back to his sanity, and there I got some really interesting backstory/lore. His name was Isaac, and he was one of the only other members of the clans that I knew. Each of the clans was isolated, but I had heard of Isaac. Every year, during the festival, his clan took their chosen from that year and sacrificed them for Lord Baphomet, to keep the train running. The Shadow seemed to just be wanting to keep his friend alive.</p>

<p>After discovering this lore, I woke up. Feels like an actual RPG you could play from like, 1999 or 2000. Parts of it were really vivid, but other parts I just don’t remember at all. ):</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night I was attending some massive racing event, because my mom was there taking care of some cats and I was mostly there to be with my mom and play with cats. However, once the people in charge found out I was at the event, they pulled me aside and were like “PLEASE DO COMMENTARY FOR THE RACE”</p>

<p>And I had to tell them “No.” Because I don’t know jack shit about racing, and by that time there were only 3 people left in the race cause everyone else had exploded and a lot of people at the event were getting bored and going home.</p>

<hr />

<p>Driving and roads are a big part of my dreams. Mostly because I hate it and driving is a nightmare for me, but also because I live in the suburbs of America so I have to be in a car on roads a lot.</p>

<p>In my dreams, I’m usually driving around my home, but the roads are completely different. The layout of the roads and what connects to what is wrong, however, it is usually the same between all of my dreams. Yes, that interstate intersection that goes into the jungle doesn’t actually exist in real life near my house, but it CONSTANTLY appears in my dreams.</p>

<p>Does this happen to anyone else? Locations, specifically the roads that you drive on, not actually existing but reappearing in dreams constantly?</p>

<hr />

<p>My dream last night: I dreamt that I woke up and it was five years later. I had no memory of the past 5 years, and had to learn about this life I was now living.</p>

<p>I lived in a small townhouse with my boyfriend, and someone I had never heard of, who was apparently my wife. When I saw her I pulled the “damn, you’re my wife? I’m the luckiest girl in the world” routine, and I don’t think she was impressed.</p>

<p>Sam (my boyfriend) basically did his best to try and be my guide into this new world I found myself in. I still wore my hats, every day. We lived in a walkable city with lots of plant life which was really nice, and we went to this fast food joint nearby that I’d basically describe as Sonic, and ate while listening to some radio music, which I described as “the fast food equivalent of Boston”. My wife was like “You mean Boston Everett??” and I responded with “Nnnno I don’t know who that is” which made things more awkward lol</p>

<p>Googling it after waking up, Everett is a town near Boston I guess.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream I was browsing Youtube for the Napple Tale soundtrack, and I found a Youtube video by Yoko Kanno. It was like 50 minutes of her playing a meddly of random music, a lot of it from video games, with written commentary underneath of her thoughts on the songs. She was very goofy and moved like Ed from Cowboy Bebop. Alongside video game music she also played some ad jingles that never saw the light of day, some anime tunes, and a bunch of other stuff. The mix was extremely varied and VERY good, she even played some Ristar music. The medley wasn’t one single take, but I still enjoyed it greatly.</p>

<p>I also remember there was another guy in the video, some guy in the corner who instead of having a piano like her, had three keys. They were labeled “RISTAR” and just played samples from Ristar, like the “C’MAWN” sound effect lmfao</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a LOT of dreams last night, like, I was dreaming extremely vividly, then I’d wake up, then I’d fall back asleep and dream vividly again.</p>

<p>The main one I remember though is a weird one. I was investigating murders at GDQ. Several people I know and are friends with seemed to have done murders on OTHER people I know and am friends with, at GDQ. I was investigating all of these murders, trying to find out why there was a sudden outbreak of murder</p>

<p>Meanwhile, there was a serial murderer following me, who was locked away years ago but had recently managed to break out. Any attempts to apprehend him were met with a LOT of death. He kept following me, and he was highly dangerous and unstable, but he was NOT doing a murder on me. Instead, he was cryptically guiding me towards new evidence.</p>

<p>I imagine this story would have had an amazing twist about this individual (I don’t think he was based on anyone real, like everyone else in the dream) and his supposed serial murder streak, but sadly I woke up before I could determine anything.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream last night that transformed from fighting for my life in Silent Hill to a sex scene with a trans guy to us going out on a date to me being Alucard from Castlevania and honestly I have no idea what my subconscious was doing</p>

<hr />

<p>My dream last night was a kind of Fallout-esque game that took place in my old middle school. I was a wanderer who didn’t know who I was, and I was wandering the halls helping people. There was some kind of apocalypse that had happened in this labyrinth, and the rooms that once held people and small communities had been overrun by monsters. Lots of acid and poison themed stuff, specifically.</p>

<p>I started in my mom’s old class room (she taught at that school), and I remember talking to the people who lived in that town. One of them could see the future. I asked them to tell me what they saw about me, because it might shed some light on who I once was. The person, crying slightly, told me that what they saw was clear: I was going to die. I would side against humanity with the monsters, though not out of malice, and then I’d be eaten. So, please. Do not trust the monsters.</p>

<p>I wandered the halls and kept checking rooms for new exciting things but every room was locked or showed combat and I didn’t like the combat. Then I woke up.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream that I was playing a version of The Sims, but it had a character like Dark Urge in it. Dark Urge is a playable character in Baldur’s Gate 3 where it’s someone who’s kinda like… possessed by a demon, who makes them do horrible evil things? And they can give in to the urges, or try their best to fight them (and often fail)</p>

<p>Anyways so in the Sims I was playing as this fat middle aged black guy who was Dark Urge. He almost murdered his wife, and got divorced over it, which tbf seems like maybe it wasn’t going far enough. He was miserable and just wanted friends. He was very very bad at that though.</p>

<hr />

<p>I have NOT been sleeping well lately. I slept so poorly two nights ago that yesterday I was like, barely functioning</p>

<p>I slept worse today lol</p>

<p>Had some bad dreams involving driving through cities, cars breaking down, being hounded and attacked by random people. I called my mom, while on like 5% battery life, and begged her to come pick me up and she did so, but spent the entire call complaining about how much of a leach I am, and how useless I am. Why can’t I get a NORMAL job and do NORMAL things.</p>

<p>Nothing pleasant.</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night I kept waking up in my room feeling worse and worse with cuts and bite marks all over me and finally I looked up and the top of my wall behind my bed was covered with big holes that were FILLED with swarming bugs</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a bunch of dreams last night that kept transforming into different things. None were particularly pleasant.</p>

<p>In one of them, I was getting ready to fly to GDQ, but I left my luggage in my car, and ended up missing my flight trying to get it.</p>

<p>And in another one, I was very tired and kept waking up and falling asleep, and I kept waking up covered in cockroaches for some reason.</p>

<hr />

<p>Lots of dreams last night, I’ll write down what I remember</p>

<p>I was visiting Target to get a gift for my dad’s birthday, which is next week. We decided the thing he’d want is an old Gameboy, like the ORIGINAL Gameboy, which is weird cause my dad has never enjoyed video games ever but whatever. So I go into Target, and I find my highschool friends sitting at a table that looks like it belongs in a library, playing D&amp;D. I say hi but continue to the games section.</p>

<p>Their games section is robust and filled with lots of retro stuff. They have a lot of unique versions of the Gameboy, A LOT of them Pokemon-themed, and I also get distracted by other things. “Ooh, Kid Icarus for the Gameboy! Wait, that sticker says several hundred dollars. Nevermind, please put this back”. At some point the gift morphs from my dad to a family friend, who’s birthday was yesterday IRL, but even still I keep getting distracted by stuff in the store. They have binders, FILLED with printed out pages of the Sonic comics from the 90s! And they’re only like, 3 bucks! I get one and open it up to the page where Charmy Bee overdoses on LSD, and then I woke up.</p>

<p>But I was still eepy so I fell back asleep. I woke back up in the Target’s game section, and stepped out, going to the front of the store. But as I moved, something hit me, and I fell over, exhausted, collapsing on the ground. When I came too, I was in the store, but something had changed. It was now like, sunset, red light streaming through the windows, and the Target had decayed. It was like I went hundreds of years in the future. People in Roman-esque garb were sitting at the tills, cheering on a horse race that was going on on the road right outside. I spotted the emperor, and knew EXACTLY what to do, for…. some reason.</p>

<p>I grabbed some scissors from… somewhere, and waked up to the emperor, schmoozing him, “My emperor, which horse do you feel most suited for victory today?” And as the Emperor excitedly talked about horse prospects, I prepared the scissors, then slit his throat. Everyone around me was STUNNED that I just murdered their emperor, and then I threw the scissors to shatter the glass in the front of the store to make my escape. The scissors broke through the glass, but didn’t shatter it. All was silent for a bit more, before I just ran, throwing myself through the glass.</p>

<p>I fell in front of the horse race, dodging through them, as I made my way to the parking lot, which had collapsed into a giant lake of some kind. I dove into the lake and swam to the other side, finding myself in an overgrown and rusty version of my neighborhood. I walked around, then heard a CREEPY grinding robo voice behind me, as what looked like a walking car came towards me, grinding.</p>

<p>Then I woke up again.</p>

<hr />

<p>I had two different dreams last night, which were alternate universe Star Trek spinoffs. I was basically watching these two spinoffs in an alternate universe, and comparing them to the ones we got.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The first was DS9, but it launched a little different. There was no Sisko. Instead, it was Riker who left TNG and joined as Commander of DS9. It was kinda interesting. Not much else was different, same other characters. I’d say it wasn’t like, superior to our DS9. I do like Sisko, as mucch as I love Riker (also I can’t imagine how this would effect TNG). Also, I think Worf joins much, much earlier, too. …Maybe cause TNG got cancelled early with no Riker lmfao</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>And the second was another new series that was spun off of TNG even before DS9 would have, like season 2 of TNG. In this one, Worf left the TNG crew and joins this one, acting as commander. It was like… a space station, except it suffered the Voyager situation and is now on the Galactic Rim. The Gorn were a major threat, and my opinion was Worf wasn’t quite mature as a character enough to lead this station, his character growth hadn’t quite happened yet. I remember there were a lot of different factions on this space station as they found a way to survive in this new region of space and create a kind of outpost, while trying to contact home and explore nearby. I feel like this idea could be really cool, actually, though I would not transplant season 2 Worf here lmao. I also remember looking at this and going “if this show exists, we will never get what we got in my universe. ….I’m really going to miss the Cardassians ):” I dunno why I singled them out, out of all of the ideas, but I AM gonna miss the Cardassians.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night, I was watching a Todd in the Shadows video while wandering my house. The video was about some eccentric guy who was like, a billionaire who had been cancelled recently, but had released a lot of music this year. He ALSO owned a candy company, and Todd was eating the candy all video, so I was eating it too. It was “edible clay”, and as I took the first bite, I was like “oh this is pretty good” but as I kept eating it as the episode went on, I became increasingly worried about how edible it was, and if I was just eating clay with sugar in it.</p>

<p>The video was a “top 10 songs” this guy made that year. And most of them were bad, and he spent some time talking about this guy’s downfall. I woke up before song #1, but song #2 was apparently a sequel song to a 90s Disney Movie, I think it was supposed to be Inspector Gadget-esque, but with a big private-eye dog.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream I was hopping between dimensions, and I went to two different dimensions where the Ghostbusters were real</p>

<p>In one of them, they were uber socialist, and Ray sacrificed himself to save the world, and it ended in a bitter sweet ending with Venkman blasting off into space, never to be seen again.</p>

<p>…Then I went to the Uber Capitalism universe. This one ended with every single one of the Ghostbusters betraying each other and dying gruesomely.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream laat night where I was a Goblin gang leader in a gang of Goblins, most of them little kids. I was an old coot, and my gang lived on the cracks of society, doing petty things to survive. But I had a dream, a prophecy! I would take my people, and we’d go on a great pilgrimage to a far away place.</p>

<p>So me and my children set off on an adventure. We went like 2 miles down the road to a big department store. We were beset by monsters on the way, but I protected my flock. I had a secret weapon. It was this thick block of amber, which I stuck in my mouth like a cigar, and I could use it to cast spells. So I used it to stop monsters (humans harassing us), and turn off the stores security. After using it so much I was getting very tired, and the amber was getting a dent in it, from my mouf.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I woke up before I could find out why we were robbing some box store.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a weird dream that morphed a bunch of times. First, I dreamt about a region that had collapsed, and my dad was going there to like, reintigrate it into the US. Originally in my dream it was a European kingdom, but then it morphed into like, a place in Louisiana that used to be “the South Eastern Hollywood”, until some shit happened and it became like, a lawless wasteland for brigands. The brigand’s leader died and for some reason it was up to my dad to go integrate it. He went, but a power vacuum had happened, and a new guy seized control. He arrested my dad for trespassing, and deported him to fucking Portugal. My dad got back quick though, because one, he is not from portugal, and two, his dad had apparently set up a fund to immediately pay for bail if his son ever got arrested.</p>

<p>I woke up and fell back asleep, and the dream morphed. Now, a bit later, this region had integrated, and my brother was starting up a fast food burger joint, and I was the manager. I was helping to come up with food concepts, and perfect them, as well as cooking and serving customers. By the end I was also training new employees (apparently our wages were 6.50 an hour, which, what the fuck Jeff), while my brother was coming up with some Eccentric Burgers. The ones I remember involved crab, and one that had french fries on it.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream that shovel knight did not exist. Instead, he was Bucket Knight, and he was originally from a TV show named like “Dr. Cleopatra’s World of Bulgolgi” which was a tv show about bulgolgi and ran for one season</p>

<hr />

<p>I had multiple dreams last night about eating something tough and inedible.</p>

<p>First it was pieces of metal, which I ate by breaking it down with phazon then chewing very slowly. Then it was , I think, absolutely fucked up pieces of meat at a birthday party. EDIT: wait no I think it was super hard candies</p>

<hr />

<p>I had a dream last night that I was in my back yard with my niece and nephew, hunting for red coins. Like from Mario. It was basically an Easter egg hunt, we were trying to beat the level (aka my back yard). Couldnt find all 8 tho.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream that was straight up a yuri manga or show or something. And not one of the fluffy ones I really like, this one had its drama.</p>

<p>It took place in a high school in the 3000s. Some of the students were robots, who were very similar in every way to humans, but they processed emotions and things a bit different. Our main character was Human, it was in first person from her, and she was a shy awkward dork. Her love interest was a robot, the perfect kid in school, who everyone loved.</p>

<p>The robot seemed like she was interested in the MC, being really sweet and taking care of her, but the MC was like “but she doesnt process emotions like me, does she really??” and she also saw the robot girl and a guy flirting at one point so shes all unsure and I’m literally yelling at my screen like “POLYAMORY, ITS CALLED POLYAMORY”</p>

<hr />

<p>Had one of those dreams where I kept waking up from my dream into another dream, and everything was just slightly off so I couldn’t tell I wasn’t awake. But it kinda had a twist.</p>

<p>So I was dreaming I was coming home from school. I was on the bus, and was kind of zonked out, not paying any attention, so it took me a while to realize every single person had been dropped off instead of me. The driver was like “okay, you’re the last one”, and off we went. I looked at my phone and realized we were REALLY far away from my house. I brought it up but the driver shrugged it off. We were like, on the other side of Atlanta, prolly 2 hours away lol</p>

<p>As we started driving, I was chatting with the driver for a bit, then just kinda watched the road. It moved from a highway to a forest road, just a straight line forever. And it got dark. It was 3PM, I checked my phone, but it was getting darker, and darker in the forest. I tried talking to the driver, but he was starting to babble incoherently. Something was very, VERY wrong.</p>

<p>Eventually, I realized what it was and woke up. Everything was normal! Right? Well, no, not quite. I was informed telepathically that I had very VERY nearly succumbed to the darkness. So there would be…. lasting effects.</p>

<p>I looked at my phone, and found a shit ton of messages on my work slack. Turns out I had been spewing racist and phobic rhetoric and spamming the channel up, so I was kicked from the server as they tried to figure out if I got hacked or not.</p>

<p>I woke up again. This time, I was back in my room. But every single person I loved in my life had been turned into like, small totems. I could put a bit of energy into them to try and bring them back to normal, but I barely had enough for myself. And then I woke up for good I think.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream I was at my grandparent’s. I remember specifically looking at old photos of my grandfather and thinking “I wonder how often he’ll show up in my dreams the further I get from his death”</p>

<p>Anyways the real meat and bones was this old Japanese PC I was setting up in my grandma’s old computer room, in the spot she had a Windows 95 in like, the mid 90s back in the day. It was like, a mid 90s era Japanese PC, which ran a proprietary OS. I was setting it up, and I got it to run a game based on an alternate universe Star Trek TNG movie from that era. I remember, in the dream, thinking that the movie was not very good. The only thing I can say about the movie is that it had a scene like the “THERE ARE FOUR LIGHTS” scene, with Picard slumped and beaten.</p>

<p>I know this, because that was the icon on the desktop. As you clicked on the game, a little description and thing of it popped up on the left, and the icon was Picard slumped over, all bruised. And he was animated! He had different sprites based on where the mouse was pointing. I remember going “wow that’s super impressive, there’s so many frames of animation”</p>

<p>Then sadly I woke up lol</p>

<hr />

<p>Dreamt I was watching an episode of Voyager. In this Voyager, Janeway wasn’t captain. It was Archer, from Enterprise, who I barely know. He was kinda like a friendly gay Pike. Anyway, this episode was a big special episode. It had a lot of shipping. The Doctor had shown interest in Archer, but Archer and Neelix were flirting instead, and Archer was like “You know what, I DO love you, Neelix”. Neelix was also extremely touch averse, so when Archer went in for a kiss, it was rebuffed, which was awkward, but they were an item, kinda. There was a lot of drama and angst and sadness from the Doctor.</p>

<p>There was a big party of some kind to celebrate a one year anniversary of being in space. Everyone got drunk and passed out. When they awoke, they were all surrounded by big super friendly and flirty gelatinous alien women. Turns out they had hit some kind of temporal anomoly that had shunted them a bit further in space, and they had reached the very edge of the Alpha Quadrant. These aliens also offered to give Voyager an upgrade to their engines which would make it go a little faster. This upgrade was a sentient potato that sat in the engines.</p>

<p>I also read a review of the episode, which said it was a good episode because it launched them forward away from all the Kazon stuff so they never had to deal with any of that half baked stuff ever again.</p>

<p>Anyways, then I woke up</p>

<hr />

<p>In last night’s dream, I was going back to college and moving into the dorms. My girlfriend and her roomies, who IRL just moved, were also moving in, and I went to visit them. We hung out and had a good time, and some random people I’d never met also visited. I then tried to go back to my room but I completely forgot where it was. EVENTUALLY I found it, and while doing things around the room, people started… entering my room, not talking to me, wandering around, then leaving. That’s when I found out that the locks in the dorm did not work, at all, and anyone could enter any room.</p>

<p>While I was worrying about THAT, I was also worrying about what my classes were, because I realized I had not been told, at all, what I was taking that semester. So I tried to find someone who could help me with that, and I got lost again.</p>

<hr />

<p>In my dream last night my brain invented a song that was supposed to play following Kakyoin’s death in Jojo Part 3, which featured long very fast paced Japanese rap breakdowns, where Jotaro would be punching, with a chorus of the word “KAKYOIN” being shouted out to the tune of “I’m aliiiiive” from the Last Unicorn’s theme song, as Jotaro went super saiyan.</p>

<hr />

<p>Had a dream where people were making fun of Goku because they realized that in the many years of Super, he had invented one single new move himself, which was called “Backburner”, and it was called that because “it burns an opponent’s back”, and everyone just kept mocking Goku for being bad at naming things.</p>

<p>Note: I’ve never actually watched Super</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="dreams" /><category term="dream journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the past two years I’ve been on Cohost, I’ve posted a lot of my weirder more interesting dreams over on the site. As a push to move my stuff onto my new website, this is a GIANT post, showing all of those dreams. There’s some darker and weirder stuff in here, so uh, you’ve been warned I guess. My subconscious is weird.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 14</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/03/OOCY14.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 14" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/03/OOCY14</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/03/OOCY14.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8KHR0y0.png" alt="&quot;I want to do naughty things with another girl before I leave my 20s...!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Yo mood</p>

<p>source: Fake sweets</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Fake Sweets" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>