<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-18T14:52:41-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 38 - Rakshasa</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-38.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 38 - Rakshasa" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#38</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-38.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Np50uZ1.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>We are now entering into what I call UFOSoft’s “India Period”. This game takes place in India. The following game has a character who I’m PRETTY sure is supposed to be Indian. Game #41 is directly inspired by an Indian board game. I imagine someone on staff went to India and came back EXTREMELY inspired, which is such a fucking game dev thing, that shit happens ALL THE TIME, I kinda love it being represented here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/n3mxrWG.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Rakshasa you play as Jangi, this Karnov-ass mother fucker, a village chief who’s entire village is slaughtered by demons. Jangi fights back, but is brutally killed as well. However, he finds himself re-awakening as a spirit, clinging to life. He can regain control of his body and fight on, in revenge for his people.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Q6x5Lnr.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Y’all like Ghosts n’ Goblins? Cause that’s EXTREMELY what this game is. No other game is more inspired by something, I think. It’s got the same slow stiff movement, lack of air control, and hard as fuck difficulty. This game is BONKERS hard, top 5 hardest games in the pack, for sure. You can walk and jump, and aim your attack at an angle. You’ll WISH you can aim straight up and down, as things come from those angles and they will fuck your day up. You cAN aim down by jumping, but again, you don’t have much mobility in the air. You can get powerups for your attack, three different weapons: spread shot, a short shotgun burst. Homing, long range but slow homing rings. And fireball, long range, fast, and very damaging. It’s the best, IMO. Charged, it has really good range and width, and missing an enemy with an attack is DEVESTATING, so making sure things land with a charged fireball will save your life a LOT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iuyPtik.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game’s major gimmick is its unique life system. You don’t have lives. Instead, each time you die, you have a chance to return to the land of the living. Rings will spawn, and you float around the screen as a spirit. Grab all the rings, and you’re back! But with each death, more rings will spawn, and more nemies will too, flying around to hit you. And they get faster and more violent with each death. You only need to get hit once for game over. You start the game doing this actually, and it’s very funny that you can start the game and IMMEDIATELY game over if you fucking suck at dodging this purple blob, though you probably won’t.</p>

<p>Rakshasa’s music is sparse, it’s most ambiance and animal sounds. It’s art is good, but a you looking like Karnov is very distracting. Those purple fly enemies are appearing a LOT in recent games. A LOT of bug imagery has been appearing in recent games actually. Huh, I wonder what that’s about. But yeah I really love the Indian flavor here, but I’ve always really liked Indian culture, I had a lot of Indian friends as a kid. The game is hard as fucking nails, but it IS learnable, like any GNG game, and it’s very rewarding once you do.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 37 - Valbrace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-37.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 37 - Valbrace" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#37</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-37.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BkrRevH.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One of the more immediately interesting games at first glance, Valbrace draws players in as soon as they see it exists. How could it not? Valbrace is a hardcore dungeon crawler, a classic 80s design that some people are really REALLY into. I’m pretty into them, myself. Grimrock is wicked, and I love a good blobby. As I played more of this though, parts of it started to kinda fade away and I realized I didn’t like it NEARLY as much as I’d hoped from the outset.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OiI4lHJ.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The lore is EXTREMELY simplistic. Some high fantasy world, you’re a knight who’s going to an evil castle to stop an evil dude, you’re caught by him, stripped of your equipment, and thrown in the depths of the tower. Climb down, fighting enemies and getting equipment, to proceed. The game is a hardcore first person dungeon crawler, akin to something like Wizardry. You’ve got equipment, stats, magic spells, traps, hidden secrets, switches, all the goodies. The game is the same every time though, like those classic 80s crawlers, it is NOT some modern roguelike-esque crawler. It is hand crafted, which means if you get REALLY lost and stuck, a map will work, though honestly it’s not needed.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8FDIeD0.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Perhaps the most interesting thing about this game is its magic system. See, you don’t learn the spells. YOU learn the spells. That make sense? Of course it doesn’t, I needn’t elaborate, though I will anyway, because I love hearing myself talk. You can cast any spell at any time, as long as you have the MP. But YOU, the player, must first learn the glyph for it. By pressing B and then moving around, you draw out a glyph, a mirrored character, and if you correctly put in a spell, boom, you cast it. As you explore, you find glyphs written in walls, hidden in spots, and it makes for some classic, utterly fantastic excuses to pull out pen and paper and write notes, alongside the notes you’ll be taking for maps and things.</p>

<p>On top of that, you’ve got a few other mechanics, like the chairs you’ll find on each floor, which you can use to increase your stats at the cost of essence, basically EXP. And of course there’s the combat, which is over the shoulder and live, kind of like a punchout almost. You can block, weave, dodge, and hit back. This is maybe my biggest gripe with the game. The combat is fine. But the enemies are numerous, and keep spawning, and it gets to be a MASSIVE slog by the end, especially as it spawns groups of like 6 god damn enemies, that are all blocking constantly, hit you through block, and bounce between the front and back row, while also throwing projectiles. It’s fucking annoying, and slows the pace to a crawl. This along the fact that all the late game weapons kinda suck ass, and are slow and awkward to use. I was using the same fucking rapier from floor 1 until I HAD to get rid of it because it was barely doing anything anymore.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Gq9gglx.png" alt="Valbrace" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Valbrace is super interesting, and I do like it, but it really cooled on me as I was beating it, and I don’t think I ever have reason to go back to it, unlike so many other games here.</p>

<p>Also, from this point on, I probably won’t be elaborating on new members of staff. Why? Well, it’s now 1988, and over the next year, we will see eight total testers appear and disappear, and most of them are not very important, except for maaaybe two of them. One will become a full time tester, Delia Pace, and one will become the receptionist, Faiz Hanek. I’ll also talk about one of them, Sten Murzbach, MUCH later, but for now, no staff changes are particularly important…. except for one.</p>

<p>Valbrace is the final game made by long-time UFO Soft alumni Chiffon Bola. Was she fired? No. On February 29th, a month after her last game, Valbrace, was released, Chiffon Bola went missing. She is never found, and is presumed dead. I will go more into this later, as well, but it’s a pretty dark day for UFOsoft, which must continue on. But dark clouds are on the horizon, and the writing is starting to be seen on the wall by some of the people working there, who are getting uncomfortable with management, and a few… other things, which will become apparent soon.</p>

<p>7/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 36 - Hyper Contender</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-36.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 36 - Hyper Contender" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-36.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ouX6AOu.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Every company needs their fighting game, right? Taking place in the same universe as their other hits, Hyper Contender brings back the Pits of Phogon from Overbold, prolly worked on around the same time tbh.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ix2cdCV.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a platformer fighter, less a “traditional” 2D fighter and more something a little unique. And thus better. I’m sorry, I hate the traditional 2D format. Street Fighter 2 was a blight on the creativity of the genre. Thankfully in this universe, that doesn’t seem to have corrupted the industry so every single 2D fighting game doesn’t HAVE to just be a shitty clone of Street Fighter. Instead we get this, and it’s got a lot of creative ideas! Originally it was supposed to have a more traditional health system, actually, which is still in the game as a secret code, but the ring system works very well.</p>

<p>It’s simple. You choose your character, who has a movement ability and an attack ability, as well as a melee atack. Rings spawn throughout the arena every ten seconds or so, and your goal is to get five rings to win. You can beat the rings out of your opponents, and they go flying, bouncing around. It can get EXTREMELY hectic. You can also block, which helps dodge the ranged attacks and stun melee attackers.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2nHZxQO.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The characters are all nicely varied. I’m a big fan of Donkus, myself, because of fucking course I am, but the wolf angel is damn good too. I dunno if it’s BALANCED per-se, I struggled to win with some characters, but thankfully to cherry it you only need to win with half the cast. :3 And that’s it! While I really enjoyed Hyper Contender when I first played it, it seriously dimmed on me with subsequent plays and time away from it. It’s prolly really fun with friends though.</p>

<p>Also every character gets an ending! Here’s an ending from the 2P recolor of Donkus.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/is2qr1U.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Huh that’s some fun world building and certainly not commentary on anything else in particular :)</p>

<p>By the way, I haven’t brought him up yet, but there’s a new staff member at UFO Soft! His name is Winston Nemuru, and while his exact relation to new CEO Tao Nemuru isn’t stated, my guess is he’s his son. I’m sure he was hired for his skills and abilities and certianly not cause of his relation to the new CEO. He’s been sprinkled into the credits of other games, and is in the credits as this one, listed for having the idea for it, alongside KC Levin. Actually, above KC Levin. I’m sure he just came up with more of the concept :)</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 35 - Campanella 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-35.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 35 - Campanella 2" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50#35</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/18/UFO50-35.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fw3FFUE.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I have a theory I call “8-Bit 2nd Game Syndrome”. It’s that games from the 8-bit era that evolved into series would try something completely different and weird in the 2nd game, which would be completely ignored in future installations. Mario 2 USA. Zelda 2. Metroid 2. All the black sheep of the franchise. Does Campanella 2, UFO Soft’s flagship franchise, suffer the same fate? Well right off the bat, we don’t have Pilot! At Joy Akebi’s suggestion, he has been deplaced by Isabell, his sister, as the main character, because Pilot has been kidnapped and is being kept in a space station, and Isabell the bounty hunter has to go rescue him!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JwecRIO.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game uses the same engine as Campanella, the same fluid smooth UFO movement you know and love, but with a few twists. You can land your UFO and step out of it, very blaster-master style, and enter doors where you travel on foot. Either getting help from people (in rooms that REALLY remind me of Rygar), or a cave with items at the end. Because this isn’t your regular level-based game like Campanella 1, or even an adventure game where you explore. Campanella 2 is a roguelike.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SAnUeMn.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Look at this handsome man</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WgqKuii.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All of the levels are randomly generated. At the end of caves, one in each area, you get one of three powerups to choose from, stuff for your blaster, ship, or health/fuel. There are shops that also sell these upgrades. After two levels in the same world, you go through a cave, fight a boss, and move onto the next world. Each area has a bunch of stars floating in it, and once you get 10, the doors close and the exit opens, and you also summon The Bile Of Old. Stay too long, and more will spawn and fucking destroy you in one hit.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wxuFHcS.png" alt="UFO2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, in the 2nd area of every world, you have a Sage who will give you a scroll and tell you which world to go to next. Get to all three of them to get the good ending. This isn’t too hard, though exploring the big open areas in your UFO can be a little intimidating, because fuel is in VERY short supply. Stars replenish it, yes, but if you get too many of them, you can kiss seeing that sage goodbye. If you DO run out of fuel, you can burn coins, but only for a short time. It’s interesting.</p>

<p>When I first played this game, I thought it was the best of the three Campanella games. The most unique, the most creative, the best music. I still think that last bit, but it’s cooled on me a bit, and now it’s my least favorite. It’s still very good, I just like the other two more. It’s maybe not different enough in some ways, and sometimes it feels a little rude, like I’m fucked no matter what. But it’s still a good fun romp, just not as replayable as the other two, despite its roguelike roots.</p>

<p>8.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 28</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/18/OOCY28.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 28" /><published>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/18/OOCY28</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/18/OOCY28.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Eta5xbv.png" alt="&quot;Also, there's just one more thing I feel disappointed about. This magic refuses to give me any big doggos.&quot; BIG DOGGOS." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>BIG DOGGOS.</p>

<p>source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="NSFW" /><category term="Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 27</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/17/OOCY27.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 27" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/17/OOCY27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/17/OOCY27.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4l0vUGh.png" alt="&quot;I didn't even want to think about boobs!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="NSFW" /><category term="Sekai de Ichiban Oppai ga Suki!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 34 - Overbold</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-34.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 34 - Overbold" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#34</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-34.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ZwiiG4.png" alt="Overbold" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Three years and 27 games after her introduction, the Space Pirate Alpha returns! Remember, she’s the Samus-esque character from Velgress. After her struggles in Velgress, she’s broke with no ship. Her only hope of getting the money for a new ship is to fight in the Red Arena, a blood sport arena where the more you fight, the more you win.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sROd9bJ.png" alt="Overbold" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Overbold is a Smash TV-esque arena fighter, where you choose how many enemies you fight each round. The more you add on, the more you make, in quantities of 100. You can then use that money to upgrade yourself, with random upgrades costing more or less each round. After like 8 or so rounds, you’ll fight a round that’s INSTANTLY at max difficulty, with a boss. Beat that, and boom, you win. In each battle, you can run around, avoiding enemy fire and lava pits. You have a gun that travels the whole distance of the arena, and bombs, which can and WILL kill you, but instantly kill almost everything.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2UCAcvX.png" alt="Overbold" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>As you may be able to tell from the fact I just described the entire game in a paragraph, and not a particularly large one, this game isn’t very complex. Honestly, to its detriment. I know a lot of people who really like Overbold, and I have no fucking idea why. It’s fine, yeah, but it feels MASSIVELY undercooked, like it just has no ideas. There’s a SINGLE arena, runs will take you like 10 minutes, and while it’s got some challenge to it, that’s not really enough to carry the game for me.</p>

<p>Sorry :/</p>

<p>6/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 33 - Fist Hell</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-33.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 33 - Fist Hell" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#33</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-33.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GbnEbcU.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s been a little bit, we’ve got another game in the Partyverse! You can tell, because Amy is here. She’s the protagonist of Party House, and is in Hot Foot. You can also see the gym from Hot Foot, along with “GO GATORS!” signs. It’s cute. Anyways, on to the game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UnHHM02.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Fist Hell is a belt scrolling beat em up, most clearly influenced by Double Dragon and Kunio-kun, ESPECIALLY with the sprite art for the latter. In Fist Hell, a zombie outbreak is occuring! The zombies have kidnapped Jay’s mom, who was running for mayor. The current mayor is on the case, but he clearly can’t be trusted, so Jay calls his friends up and goes on a rampage to save his mom!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fl0YzMK.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got four characters, as I said, Amy is here, but the only real character to play single player is Jay, IMO. Everyone else is just too weak. This is a BRUTAL beat em up, and any advantage you can have to tide the swarm faster is one you should take.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bDynNyv.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a simple two button beltscroller. You’ve got your jump, you’ve got your punch. If you walk into someone while punching them, you’ll grab them, and then with a direction and a punch you can throw them. This will be required for at least one boss. You’ve also got a jump slam you can do with the grab, I never found it super useful. There’s also food pickups, of course burgers and pizza and fries, and money pickups. After each level, you can buy either a full heal, or a powerup. Yes, you don’t heal inbetween levels. There aren’t many levels, but this makes the game even harder than it already is, and it’s hard. I know it took me a long time to get good enough to even beat level 2, I just kept bleeding health getting to that point. Learning tricks and strategies helps, though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jJ7Pf0p.png" alt="FistHell" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You have VERY classic hit stunning in Fisthell, where if you don’t finish your combo, just punch thrice, wait for a second, then continue, you don’t kick them away, and can just stun lock them down. This, on top with taking advantage of how you have more vertical range up than enemies do down, means that you can hit enemies safely and lock them down. This does apply to you, though. I found the safest thing was to just hug the bottom of the screen, most of the time.</p>

<p>I don’t like beat em ups. I find them pretty boring, honestly. You punch a guy, wait for them to get up, and then punch them again. Do this for 2 hours. Fist Hell isn’t 2 hours, and the enemies go down fast enough that there’s not much waiting. It’s constant action. It’s okay for what it is, a perfectly fine beat em up. Even if that’s not entirely my thing.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 32 - Mortol II</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-32.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 32 - Mortol II" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#32</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-32.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/SBqyDyd.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The long awaited sequel to Mortol 2 is here! And while Chun came up with the original idea, it was kind of changed to make the game more fun and pleasant. But now HE’S in control, that ol fuddy duddy Smolski is gone, so now Chun can do whatever he wants. And he wants to go back to his original idea, with MORTOL II!</p>

<p>The government is bringing back the evil to gain more power. Wow, how unrealistic. The people, upset that their sacrifice was forgotten, stand up once more to save Mortolia. This time, you have 100 lives. And no way to gain them. It’s a much differently designed game, but that original idea is there, and while it is kind of anxiety inducing to watch your lives drain away, the game isn’t too long once you know what to do.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vN91B9F.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The correct play is to explore, not give a shit about your lives, then route out a path after you know what you even need to do. It’s one giant open map, which changes as you effect it. Enemies stay dead, your sacrifices stay there, allowing you to tame this wilderness. You’ve got 5 different units: The warrior, who has strong melee strikes and can turn into stone platforms like in the first game, the Gunner who has long range guns and can spawn an ammo pack, the Scout who can double jump, throw a few ninja stars, and can create a teleporter, the Engineer who throws arced wrenches and can build 5-tall pipes through the ground, very useful if you know how to use her, and the Bomber, who is TOTALLY not a girl in a kink outfit, who explodes. That’s what she does. She explodes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DuiZKUL.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Using these fives units, you must explore Nilpis (which is VERY fun to say) and tame it, reaching into the castle to defeat the ancient evil inside. Feeling your lives drain away is painful and anxiety inducing, but I managed to do it with 52 lives left… the cherry is to do it in under 50, for the record, so I was VERY close. But my route got me there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BeMpKtk.png" alt="Sac2" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Each of the units has their own music, and the vibe and aesthetics are dark and spooky and weird, in the same way Mortol 1 is. It’s a good weird time that is just as good, if not possibly even better, than Mortol 1.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 31 - Pingolf</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-31.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 31 - Pingolf" /><published>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50#31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/17/UFO50-31.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sZJYdkr.png" alt="Pingolf" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It is mid 1987, and UFO Soft has moved fully into its new offices! These new offices have a LOT of nice ammenities, including an indoor minigolf course, and a bunch of pinball machines. The new boss, Mr. Nemura, is really into collecting games it seems, so he has a bunch of old ones for the in-office arcade. Cool! Inspired by these, the team made Pingolf, a kind of combination of Pinball and Golf.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PPUgwXj.png" alt="Pingolf" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Pingolf is a cyber futuristic-esque golf game for a big tournament with a bunch of robo-people, but it’s also… a carnival? It’s weird, I don’t really like the vibe or aesthetic much. The music is fine though. It’s a side to side pinball game, just choose the angle and the power, and let her rip. You can also dunk the ball, which will SLAM the ball downwards, often at an angle if it’s moving forward. Do 18 holes and win the tournament!</p>

<p>It’s not very complex of a game. Compared to some of the recent games, in fact, it’s SHOCKINGLY simple. Very short, even, this can take you like, 10 minutes. Getting GOOD though, that will take you a while. The holes are the same every time, you learning a route, where and when to dunk, that’s gonna take you a bit longer. The cherry is to get under par. The AI is actually pretty damn bad at this, so like, just getting under par means you win handidly.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MQNta4a.png" alt="Pingolf" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s it! I didn’t like this game very much when I first played it tbh, but it’s… alright. I think it’s just okay. A little too simple for its own good, and a bit frustrating as you try and learn it, cause your ball bounces all over the mother fucking place, and dunking is hard to really grok. The best thing about this game is that using a code you can play as Waldorf. Hell yea, Waldorf.</p>

<p>6.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>