<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-10T08:17:06-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 20" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/10/OOCY21.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R0AaJwj.png" alt="&quot;A woman kabedoning another with her leg&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Black &amp; White</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Black &amp; White" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 9 - Attactics</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-9.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 9 - Attactics" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50#9</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-9.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EUTyCA2.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>We’ve got the core team for LX Systems, there won’t be too many changes for at least a little while, so there’s not much to say about this game other than to talk about the game itself.</p>

<p>Attactics is a strategy action game that’s pretty different from anything I’ve played. It’s a realtime turnbased game. You’ve got a 5x8 grid, and units will spawn randomly on each side of it. Those units will then move every single turn, depending on what kind of unit they are. Turns go automatically, every few seconds. However, you can grab and shift your units, moving them up and down, or back. You can shift and swap units this way, as well, for maximum strategy. When a unit kills another, it gets a promotion and deals extra damage. The goal is to just get enough units to the enemy’s side, to knock down all their flags, and you win!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/McWFLo1.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve got a bunch of unit types, each with different strengths and weaknesses. Grunts will be immune to melee damage if they’re in a column of 3 or more units. Archers will shoot from afar if a unit is in their sight, instead of moving. Shieldmen are tanky as fuck and can block arrows. Cavalry move twice, good for sneaking through weak spots and getting quick damage in. Spearmen attack two spaces instead of just 1, through units, good for hiding behind shieldmen. Assassins will throw daggers up and down as they walk. Sappers will explode when they die, which blows up the enemy, but can ALSO blow YOU up. Aaand then there’s heroes, unique units that happen every 5 promotions on certain stages, and they move twice as far, pierce two stages, and start promoted like, 5. They’re good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9TJpbvh.png" alt="Attactics" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And that’s it! Battles are tense and hectic. The AI can’t move at all, so it usually gets like, 70% more units to compensate. I imagine multiplayer is WILD. The description of the game explains that the game was delayed cause the devs just wouldn’t stop playing it, and the credits show that “Chiffon the Strong” was the office champion. It just shows how the vibe was in those days at the office. Their games aren’t selling… amazingly, but they’re loving what they’re doing.</p>

<p>This one was pretty alright, and then grew on me a bit more. It’s nothing amazing, but it’s fun for what it is. And not super long.</p>

<p>8/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 10 - Devilition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 10 - Devilition" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50#10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/10/UFO50-10.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tInZkFa.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Devilition has an interesting IRL story behind it. So I’ve been talking about the in-universe characters who supposedly made these games, and are credited as such, but there’s a REAL actual team of actual people who made them, and they kinda split up the work, each person creating a few different games. I’m not sure who created what, exactly, except for a few of them where it’s obvious (Hello Velgress/Upwell). In this case, it’s obvious, because in 1999 Derek Wu created a game called Diabolika. That game was repurposed for UFO 50, with some touch ups and changes. Apparently in the original, the little devils had big swinging dongs. They don’t got that here. There’s a few other changes, too, I’ll get into those.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EjakEoN.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Devilition is a puzzle game where you play an alchemist trying to keep a town of puritan-esque settlers alive from a horde of Demons. Each round, devils are placed randomly about the board, and then you can place your pieces anywhere on the grid. When these contraptions explode, they explode in different directions, signified by the colors emenating from them. So you’ve got ones that explode in a cross, an X shape, you’ve got ones that blast out further, ones that blast all around, ones that do 3 spaces in front of them, ones that only do side to side, aaaand the rocket, which will blast up then fall on a space, blasting all around. Your goal is to try to kill as many Devils as you can this way, while avoiding the settlers. At the end of a round, if the settlers outnumber the devils, you move on. If not, you lose, start over. If you get rid of ALL the demons, you get an extra settler. You can kill your settlers all you want, which is fucked up, all that matters is that they are equal or outnumber the demons. After ten rounds, you fight a boss, who’s actually extremely easy, and you’re given a score based on your time, pieces used, and settlers left.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a0Lz65u.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And that’s it! It’s not a very complex puzzle game, and while it seems okay at first, it falls a bit flat to me on repeat plays. I acknowledge I’m not very good at this game. It is not kind to those with ADHD. I get distracted and suddenly forget an entire third of the board is there, or think I planned out a way to deal with THAT ONE devil, and nope, I forgot about it again. But the real thing about this is that it’s a bit of an RNG fest. The game can absolutely give you unwinnable situations, especially if it clumps a bunch of the devils together that take two hits to kill, with no room to put anything near them. I had that once. It tends to spawn things away from your already set up contraptions, and I had one left over by accident, and whoops, giant clump in the corner :)</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dIyrft7.png" alt="Devilition" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s FINE, it’s a fine game, but the music, setting, idea of it, all of it just doesn’t really speak to me. It’s notable though that this setting of all settings will be re-used later, far, far down the line, and for MUCH better effect.</p>

<p>5.5/10</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 8 - Planet Zoldath</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 8 - Planet Zoldath" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50#8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-8.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dmAIsML.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’m gonna make more of these a day so this doesn’t take me literally 50 days.</p>

<p>This is one of the more important games in the canon of LX Systems, because it is the first appearance of Zoldath, a major setting for their games, the little red UFO that will become their trademark symbol down the way, and its pilot, named… Pilot. Neither the UFO nor Pilot are actually named here. Writing is credited to Gregory Milk, so we can assume he came up with Zoldath and this world, though I think it’s implied it’s also in the board game Smolski and Chun made years ago? Unsure. Anyways, what is Zoldath actually about?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zchLX5O.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game starts with you landing on Zoldath in your UFO. You are not given any goals. You are not given any information. All you immediately know is there’s three spaces for… papers? And four different resources of some kind, and you’re being timed. You can’t do anything but run around and explore screens that shift and move like Zelda 1.</p>

<p>Zoldath is incredibly confusing on your first play, but as you actually learn what it’s about and how it works, you’ll find that it’s actually… really shallow, and uninteresting. So basically, you need three pieces of an intergalactic map that are hidden in this world. They can be hidden in a number of ways, and you’ll need different items to obtain them. Often times these items are just lying around, and there’s like 5 of them. Once you discover what every item does and how it can be used to open up the map for more exploring, it all falls into place. Like, using the transmogrifier to turn crystals into meat so they can explode and NOT kill you, or using the transmogrifier to turn yourself small and go through holes, or using the boots to go over acid, or using the boomerand to grab things across pits, or using meat to lure out enemies so you can sneak past them. Lots of options, but none of them are super interesting past that initial “Oh that’s what the game wants me to do” moment.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z4jUCZq.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Each time the game starts, a world is generated. There are like 8 different alien species, and out of those, two are friendly. One needs a translator to talk to. They can give little fun lore tidbits, or trade you items for resources you can find lying around the map. One of the maps will ALWAYS be traded for, so you’ll need to find who trades for what, so you can get good amounts of what the map is traded for, cause they’ll want like 30 of them for it. Also, out of those aliens, a few are chosen to shoot bullets, and one is chosen to fucking EXPLODE when it dies, so you always gotta be careful until you know how every enemy acts.</p>

<p>There’s also a little dungeon, which has a map at the end. The third map piece is usually sitting somewhere in the world, either behind a big invincible enemy, or over a pit. And uh, that’s it. You get those three, blast off, and the game is over. Do it as fast as you can.</p>

<p>I find Zoldath kind of boring and unfun. It’s not BAD or HORRIBLE, I just never have any interest in playing it again. It’s kinda like a VERY mini Zelda, with less fun exploration and worse combat. This world, its characters, and even the ideas within it will be done much better down the way.</p>

<p>4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5sJvf5t.png" alt="Zoldath" class="center-block" /></p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 7 - Velgress</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 7 - Velgress" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50#7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/09/UFO50-7.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ODhzsfp.png" alt="Velgress" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’m gonna make more of these a day so this doesn’t take me literally 50 days.</p>

<p>Still in early 1984, we’ve got a game that’s pretty important for two reasons. One is that it introduces yet another staff member to LX Systems! Her name is Chiffon Bola, and while I don’t hear much talk about her from fans who discuss the meta narrative of UFO 50, she is EXTREMELY important. She’s notable for being y’know, another woman, and a programmer this time! She’s the lead programmer on this project, alongside Benedikt Chun, who directed it. Chiffon seems like a cool lady, she’s big into bikes and her effect on the company was a positive one, for sure. It’s absolutely possible that her suggestions are what truly made this game, as it is yet another game with a female lead, and one that would become a major part of the company’s character lineup: The Space Pirate Alpha. She’s a lady in green space armor with a rifle, and she’s got a LOT of Samus Energy going on.</p>

<p>Velgress is about Alpha, who is captured by the Demon Princess Chakras and thrown into a deep pit known as Velgress. It’s a deep pit filled with traps and monsters, and now Alpha has to escape alive! The best way I can describe this game is by calling it “Upwell”. Notably, the creator of Downwell IRL worked on this game, so like, makes sense? You can run, jump, double jump, and shoot, and your goal is to move up a shaft. As the camera moves, so does a spike pit at the bottom. All floors crumble and break underneath you as you land on them, so you have to CONSTANTLY be on the move. The only thing that actually kills you is the bottom of the pit, everything else wil lstun and throw you, and will PROBABLY end with you landing in the spike pit, but maybe not! You might be able to jump out of it. But you’ll probably die.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UkadO8i.png" alt="Velgress" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You die a lot in Velgress. But it’s built with that in mind, it’s VERY replayable. You die, press A, and with an animation of you being thrown into a pit, immediately jump back into the action. It slams you back to the first stage, which after the first time of getting to level 2 and dying being jarring in a “AGH DAMMIT, MY PROGRESS” kinda way, you get over it fast. The game is like 5 minutes long. It’s VERY short. Only the four levels, the last one being mostly a boss, and a shop inbetween.</p>

<p>Along the way, mini bosses will show up. They barely even try to attack you, but if you kill all three in each of the levels before they run away, you get the good ending. I never got the bad ending, they’re not hard to kill.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HTyvGZ9.png" alt="Velgress" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another cool thing about Velgress is that it uses random generation. That wasn’t unheard of back then, but it’s a cool addition, and fits this gameplay very well. Its is also notable for having more than one musical theme! The other games would have one track, and then maybe an ending theme, but Velgress has different music for each level. I like level 1’s theme a lot, the others are just okay.</p>

<p>I didn’t super love this the first time I played it, but after sitting down to beat it, it really grew on me. But I can’t deny the game is very, VERY short. Also, I dunno why, but it reminds me of Kid Icarus even though it’s nothing like it. Maybe it’s the music.</p>

<p>7.5/10</p>

<p>ALSO, important to note, I got the early lore of LX Systems completely wrong. I’ll edit my earlier posts and fix it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 20</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/09/OOCY20.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 20" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/09/OOCY20</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/09/OOCY20.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tMhmxgz.png" alt="&quot;Even if she ends up choosing someone else, I...&quot; &quot;You're thinking something stupid again, aren't you? &lt;3&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I wonder what it’s like to NOT have anxiety about relationships</p>

<p>source: Yurikon</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yurikon" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 19" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/08/OOCY19.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FsOSYUN.png" alt="&quot;Oh shut up!! If it comes down to that, then we can just have an orgy together! I want to celebrate, right this instant!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: come rain or shine</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="come rain or shine" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 6 - Mortol</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/08/UFO50-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 6 - Mortol" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/08/UFO50#6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/08/UFO50-6.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4tL6TaI.png" alt="Mortol" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Mortol has a lot of interesting things about it’s backstory, so bear with me. We’ll start with the concept.</p>

<p>Benedikt Chun came up with the original concept of this game, but is notably absent in its credits, except for graphics. There are few hints as to why. Mortol 2’s description, and a hidden code that changes the way the game plays, explains that Chun’s original vision for the game was that you had to sacrifice your characters to continue, which the game still has, but you couldn’t gain back lives. I imagine the others played the prototype, or even talked him out of it really early, cause that shit is pretty rough and unfun (as you can tell from the code), and he kind of sat out development because of it.</p>

<p>The credits also show something else important. We’ve got another new worker at LX Systems! The first person other than Chun, Smolski, or Thorson who was brought on for actual game development reasons. Credited for graphics and level design, he’d go on to do basically every single possible job position at the company in his long, long tenure there. He is the protagonist of our story, in fact. His name is Gregory Milk.</p>

<p>Gregory Milk’s most important contribution to our story is that he literally made UFO 50. In the contexts of the world, he made the program UFO 50, which was found years later by Mossmouth, and ported to PCs. His hands are all up in it, and while I WANT to call him a hero, he’s also an unreliable narrator. I’ll talk about that much, much later. But suffice to say, Milkdud is my man, and in my opinion a force of good in the company.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ha48kny.png" alt="Mortol" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Anyways, his first game he ever worked on, what was it?</p>

<p>An ancient evil has re-awakened and is laying waste to your country. How many men must lay down their lives to save Mortolia?</p>

<p>Mortol is a platformer. Kind of. One of the more traditional videogames in the company’s early catalogue, it of course has a weird twist that takes it in a different direction, the one that Chun original came up with. What if you had a game where, in order to progress further, you had to literally sacrifice people to get there? At the start, you have 20 men, and they each have three actions they can do, alongside running and jumping. Depending on what direction you press the D-pad as you press A, your character with either 1) Explode 2) Turn into a block or 3) fly directly forward and imbed your skull into any wall in front of you.</p>

<p>As you platform around, you’ll run into obstacles. Blocks you gotta blow up, enemies you gotta platform around, walls you gotta make a ladder of men with their skulls in the wall to proceed. Y’know, normal stuff. If you solve puzzles in the levels, like using a ritual explosion in juuust the right way, you can set up for picking up some of the lives that are scattered around each level. As your men give their lives for Mortolia, more will parachute out of the ship, which moves along as you make progress.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UqUVR28.png" alt="Mortol" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is certainly fun, and it’s pretty rewarding to retry a level and try to get through with as few deaths as you can. It’s like a puzzle, trying to figure out how to get all the life pickups, and get around obstacles with the fewest deaths. As I first played it I was a bity frustrated by the package, but after I beat it and went back to re-learn every stage and improve them, it got more and more fun. It was never BAD, but it did grow on me a little bit.</p>

<p>The music is also really nice, but unfortunately the last two levels completely remove the music. I guess for ambiance and vibes, but I’d prefer the music.</p>

<p>8/10</p>

<p>It’s worth noting that a lot of people REALLY like Mortol, so I’m a bit worried that people will be upset at my score. Remember that an 8/10 is still very good, people lol</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 18</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/07/OOCY18.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 18" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/07/OOCY18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/07/OOCY18.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3Bxcr2k.png" alt="&quot;CATS HAVE THE POWER! TO HEAL! JUST BY EXISTING!!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Demon Lord of “Yashiro”</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Demon Lord of &quot;Yashiro&quot;" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 5 - Magic Garden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/07/UFO50-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 5 - Magic Garden" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/07/UFO50#5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/07/UFO50-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ez864SS.png" alt="Magic Garden" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It is the turn of 1984, the LX is already a little long in the tooth. Technology was evolving considerably in the 80s, and yesterday’s top machine is today’s trash. Shit, not much has changed, but it was almost more pronounced back then. So in 1984, LX Systems released not only their next game, but an entirely new computer to go along with it, the LX2.</p>

<p>This wasn’t really anything new, and wouldn’t take all that much effort, all things considered. The MSX2 was something very similar to this. Same ol’ computer, but with some added ram, or a few added systems and boards, that kinda thing. I’m not a hardware specialists, I’m a Goblin who plays games on the internet. But anyways, the LX2 was created, and they hired a new specialist to help them develop it. Meesha Danry is our newest employee, and the first woman to work at LX Systems, which is cool. While she never will do a whole lot in the actual game development side, her effects are very pronounced on the company. She’s often considered a confidant and friend to those who work there.</p>

<p>So, what can the LX2 do? Well, it can display more sprites and colors per sprite, mostly. Typical upgrade stuff. And to show that off, we got our first game of 1984, Magic Garden.</p>

<p>And it’s one of the best games ever. This is my favorite game of the collection, hands down. I thought MAYBE Mini and Max would bop it, and it did for a bit, but after cherrying M&amp;M, I have to admit, Magic Garden is still better.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4iQuk6N.png" alt="Magic Garden" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Magic Garden, you play as a cute girl who’s tending to her garden, while the jealous witch Cloveranna tries to ruin your day. Magical slimes, named Oppies, grow and sprout out of the ground. You need to collect them then release them in the star squares, which move and shift around every 10 seconds or so. Meanwhile, angy Oppies are spawning, so avoid those. If you release oppies NOT on the star blocks, they’ll get angy. This can be useful, which I’ll explain later. Save 6 or more Oppies, and a potion will spawn, which will make all enemies vulnerable, except for the mushrooms. The mushrooms are only vulernable if you get a gold potion. You get gold potions by saving 10 Oppies at a time, OR by waiting, as potions will grow in strength if you leave them there. On top of the release button, there’s also a jump button, which should probably only be used as a last resort, cause it’s really hard to use. You gotta time it just right, and you can’t turn as easily after landing, so you gotta be careful, but it HAS saved my ass.</p>

<p>The goal of the game is to get 200 Oppies saved, after which the Gardener will tell the Witch that she’d be HAPPY to teach her how to garden, and then they walk off together. I assume to make out. THis game SCREAMS yuri, and I know I see yuri in everything, but no. This is yuri. Also I wanna note, early 1984, and a female protagonist? Ahead of the curve, LX Systems, good on you. Maybe Meesha made a suggestion. It’s certainly possible. Anyways, while saving those 200 Oppies, you can try to get a high score. Save more Oppies, or beat enemies in a row with the potion active to get more points. You can chain potions together to elongate the window of beating enemies, and ALSO to increase your score multiplier.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RmBsytE.png" alt="Magic Garden" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game is so charming. I love the sprites. I love the art. I love how it changes color palettes as you reach different levels of Oppies saved. I love the style and design. The little cat yawning, so cute. The little trees with eyes. The oppies are WONDERFUL. THE YURI, OF COURSE. Also the music is FANTASTIC, this is Petters’ best work yet. Everything about this game works. Like, to be reductive, it really is just… Snake. But with a few extra steps. But it’s so extremely addicting. You take a hit, start all over, and it doesn’t feel bad, you just go “AHHH, okay one more go!” and then it’s 2 hours later. I seriously cannot overstate how good this game feels and is to play.</p>

<p>The ONLY thing that’d make this game better is an endless mode, which sadly it doesn’t have. This means there’s a theoretical cap to the socre, probably, as you can only get 200/6 potions, with which to beat Oppies. That’s where releasing Oppies and making them angry works out, btw. Fills the field so you can get a HUGE combo, which feels so satisfying. This game could also be improved with a multiplayer variant, which I feel it’s built very well for. Clears could send over more Oppies to the enemy field. Could end up with some really long lasting battles, but hard fought.</p>

<p>So, hats off to Chun. This game is fucking fantastic, and I have no bad things to say about it whatsoever. I’d buy UFO 50 just to play this game. Not a joke. 25 dollars for this game. It’s a BIT pricy, cause it’s such a short experience, but I do love it that much. At 50 cents its a god damn steal.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><category term="yuri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>