<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-27T21:04:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 186</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/27/OOCY186.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 186" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/27/OOCY186</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/27/OOCY186.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Fi1O3J5.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Silent Hill f Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/27/SilentHilf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Silent Hill f Review" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/27/SilentHilf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2025/09/27/SilentHilf.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7yLJLIT.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Silent Hill is back. Apparently.</p>

<p>I wouldn’t call myself a Silent Hill superfan. Silent Hill 3 might be my favorite horror game of all time (though it might be SIGNALIS, I’d have to think on that), and 1 and 2 are fantastic as well. 4 is okay, and everything after that you can basically just leave. Though I did unironically like Shatmem, maybe even more than 4.</p>

<p>The series was re-awakened after a decade about two years ago now. Let’s ignore the pachinko, they do not count. Konami announced THREE new Silent Hill games at the exact same time. The first was one stupid AI thing or something that no one liked and everyone already forgot. The second was the Silent Hill 2 remake, which a lot of people liked. I didn’t enjoy what I saw, but I am a Bloober Team hater. And then they announced Silent Hill f.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y1ueDE4.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There were a lot of thoughts about the trailer. The most prevelant ones I heard was “how is this a Silent Hill game”. It DID look more like Siren to me, but there were a lot of other things that set Silent Hill f apart. It takes place in Japan, the first Silent Hill game NOT taking place in America. And it’s VERY Japanese. It’s so extremely culturally Japanese, it feels like Mega Man 6 where they made Wily’s castle extremely Japanese for some reason. It’s also the first Silent Hill game produced in Japan since…. fuck, The Room? Silent Hill 4? That was a long-ass time ago. According to interviews, the reason this game is so extremely Japanese is cause they were afraid the series has become too Americanized and lost its Japanese roots. Which again, is interesting, since the series ALWAYS took place in America.</p>

<p>There’s another important thing about this game that there was a lot of talking about before its release. It stars a woman, and is very, VERY explicitely about feminism and the way women are treated, specifically in 1960s Japan. A lot of people were angry about that, and I heard lots of the funniest shit I’ve EVER heard, like someone going “I hate that they’re shoving this woke shit in there. Why couldn’t it be like Silent Hill 3, where it’s feminist, but you can easily ignore it cause it doesn’t shove it in your face”. THE GAME WHERE YOU LITERALLY ABORT GOD? So yeah, THAT made me interested. As I said, Silent Hill 3 is an utter masterpiece to me, and anything TRYING to invoke the ideas and themes of that is something I will at least be slightly interested in.</p>

<p>So I played it. And it’s…</p>

<p>alright. It’s alright. Not bad. It’s the best Silent Hill game we’ve gotten in a while. And it IS a Silent Hill game. I saw a lot of people claiming it doesn’t feel like one, but it IS. It’s a different setting and got some different vibes, but it has a lot of nods to the original games. “This is just a Fatal Frame” game was the funniest thing I saw from people who stepped in and watched for two minutes. Yes, they are both very Japanese. Fatal Frame is ghosts and spiritualism. This game is VERY meaty. AND flowery!</p>

<p>The thing this game REALLY reminds me of is Higurashi. In many ways, it feels almost like a retread of Higurashi. But that makes sense, they’re both written by the same person. This game was written by Ryukishi07, a guy I don’t know a lot about, but I respect a lot because his name is a reference to Final Fantasy V, and like respects like.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WTnP6lG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Silent HILF you play as Hinako, a Japanese school girl in 1960s Japan. She has an argument with her family one day and goes to spend time with her friends, when suddenly Horrible Shit starts happening around town. One of her friends dies, monsters come, a fog monster is killing everything, Shits Bad. Hinako is an ordinary enough girl, though she’s always been a bit of a tomboy and prefers playing with boys. She always strained against her alcoholic father for being a failure of a woman, though her sister always protected her…. until she left to get married.</p>

<p>This game is not subtle about its themes. That’s not a bad thing. I will once again point to how we saw a character abort god earlier in this series. I have no problems with that. And the things its saying ARE good… but I dunno. It’s hard for me to explain, but I don’t think it hits as hard as it, or I, want it to hit. Yes, women are forced by incompetent and failed societies to place all the burden on themselves, that does suck. What’re we gonna do about it?</p>

<p>There is ONE thing about the story, though, that kinda floored me. So, I looked at a lot of reviews of this game before I got it, and they all said the same thing. 9/10, very good, and it also has a scene in it that’s possibly the most haunting, upsetting thing in any Silent Hill game, or even horror game, so heed the content warnings. I think it’s more a 7/10, but that warning? They uh, they were not kidding. That shit was upsetting. It’s not what I expected (I expected sexual assault, which thankfully is NOT a thing in this game, except for the one monster inspired by it), but it really blew my mind. I liked it, it was good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/YoJT6tn.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I do like the monster designs. Silent Hill has always had good monster design that fit in with the themes of the game, and this is no exception. You’ve got creepy dolls, women who are beaten and abused and lash out at those they CAN lash out at, horrifying sex predator monsters, big pregnant monsters who’s only job is to breed, school children scarecrows who watch and strike when you don’t expect it, it’s good.</p>

<p>The story, vibes, and themes are all fine, but didn’t blow me away. The gameplay, on the otherhand, was outright annoying. Silent Hill combat has never been good. Ever. And that’s fine. I don’t mind that. The issue is, uh, this game has the combat be MUCH more important. There’s no guns or anything, what the fuck do you expect, this is Japan, not America. Instead, Hinako uses exclusively melee weapons, and it IS cool to play this school girl beating the shit out of monsters with axes and naginata.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TMGei5z.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But the combat is very clunky and annoying, and filled with required counter attacks, and I never liked counter attack combat. The first 70% of the game was rather good, because I could fight when I felt I needed to, but avoid combat a lot of the time, like all the other Silent Hill games, and only really have to engage 25% of the time, or for bosses. But then uh… the last 30% of the game is Not like that. The last 30% of the game FORCES you into a lot of combat. You have a LOT of combat arenas in a row, and nothing else. No real exploration. No puzzle solving. JUST combat arenas. All the enemies are damage sponges, ESPECIALLY the fucking breeder enemies. AND the game has a weapon durability mechanic. Yes. That DOES suck, I agree!!!</p>

<p>It frankly ruined my enjoyment of the game. It doesn’t help the game runs like shit on my computer, and I have a new, strong computer. I was just happy for it to be over by the end, I could barely enjoy the ending. And then I learned another rough thing about the game. It has like, 5 endings. 1 bad, 2 neutral, 1 good, and a UFO ending. You can ONLY get the bad ending on your first playthrough. Then you need to get both neutrals on New Game plus, then fiiiinally you can get the good ending. So you need to play this game four times to get the best ending.</p>

<p>No thanks. It wasn’t long, or anything. It took me 11 hours. But I can’t be assed to play again.</p>

<p>Do I recommend Silent Hill f? I do. But not for 70 dollars, and ESPECIALLY not for the 80 dollars I paid for it for the special edition. Though the art book IS nice. For 40 dollars, this is a good deal. But I know what world we live in now, so like THAT’LL ever happen.</p>

<p>So, is it a return for Silent Hill? I’m not certain. It’s a step in the right direction, at the very least. But maybe if you’re looking for a modern Silent Hill game that’s as mindblowing as the classics in the series, just play SIGNALIS or Sorry, We’re Closed.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Horror" /><category term="Silent Hill" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 209 - Kwirk</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/27/RA209-Kwirk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 209 - Kwirk" /><published>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/27/RA209-Kwirk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/27/RA209-Kwirk.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z5Wq4HV.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing my random early Gameboy exploration, we got KWIRK! Kwirk is a rather classic gameboy game, though I don’t think it ever really hit that eschalon of anything above cult classic. But when I played this, I did have lots of people in chat go “oh man I played this a lot in the car back in the day”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VxylGws.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also known as Puzzle Boy, this is the second game I’ve played in this series. The first was on PCEngine, and it blew. It was a buggy broken mess and was missing a lot of cool mechanics. This is so much better, it’s not even funny. In the Puzzle Boy franchise, you play as a lot of different veggies and fruits. In this one, you’re a little tomato boy who doesn’t appear in any of the other games.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wpg5Xcy.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The goal is extremely simple. In normal mode, you’re dropped into a screen with an exit. Get to that exit. Between you and that exit are blocks and spinners. The spinners take a bit of getting used to how they work, it’s a bit hard to spatially grasp them, but those are really the only two mechanics. You’ve got blocks, which you can move around and push into holes to fill them, and spinners, which can be blocked depending on the shape of the spinner and whats around it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9z5ZE7K.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>There’s also a challenge mode, where it gives you a number of rooms and you have to go through them as fast as you can. You decide the number of rooms before it starts, and you get points on how fast you clear each room. There’s only so many rooms the game has in store for each difficulty, of course, but it likes to do mirrored rooms to keep things fresh, and you’d be surprised how much that works to remove the previous room from your brain.</p>

<p>Kwirk is a very simple puzzle game, but one that stands tall. If you were in 1989 and had a gameboy, you could do so much worse than this. Kwirky little puzzle games on the Gameboy you can pick up and do a few puzzles in were the bread and butter for this system, and this is really one of the greats. At least, until we get to the sequel~</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Platformer" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 185</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/25/OOCY185.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 185" /><published>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/25/OOCY185</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/25/OOCY185.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mvOsIFp.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Useless Princesses</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Useless Princesses" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 208 - Parasol Henbee</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/25/RA208-Henbee.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 208 - Parasol Henbee" /><published>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/25/RA208-Henbee</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/25/RA208-Henbee.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/w8jJK6q.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Continuing my desire to explore random early Gameboy games, here we have Parasol Henbee. This is based off of a manga from the late 80s by Fujijo Fujio. If you don’t know, that’s the group that made Doraemon. This is basically a Doraemon wanabee, about a magical creature who comes to Japan and hangs out with kids and they go on cute little adventures, it’s a thing. Henbee is a little gremlin mother fucker with a parasol. There’s not much more to know about him.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VxylGws.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is a game by Epoch, who were a console developer in the 80s, but after that flamed out, they’ve kept trucking along by being the only company with the rights to make games for Doraemon. And they’ve seriously just existed because of that, and that alone, for the past 35 years. And barely anything else. But they also had the rights to this, which makes sense, made by the same people.</p>

<p>In this game, you play as Henbee. It’s a kind of 2D platformer, but with some 3D elements. It’s almost like a 2D beat em up, with a Z axis. And yes, this DOES get very confusing in some levels. The cave levels especially, it’s like an Escher painting in there.</p>

<p>You can run, hop, glide using your umbrella. You pull the umbrella out in the air, and it carries you for a time. Depending on the level of your health, however, your powers increase. You can spin at higher health levels, and you can do more than just hover if your health is at the top. Using powers uses up your health, but it’s not hard to keep your health up, there’s powerups everywhere.</p>

<p>It’s also possible to hover almost indefinetely putting your umbrella away and back out over and over. This game isn’t very long, it’ll take you like 40 minutes, and it’s a very easy game for babies. But it’s not bad. Just… not super memorable. Just waht you’d expect from a forgotten manga/anime tie in.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Platformer" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 3 episode 6-8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/21/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 3 episode 6-8" /><published>2025-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/21/LizstartrekSNW3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/21/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nVITuMH.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Through the Lens of Time</strong> - SNW
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N8mQara.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This season is going really hard on the romance drama, which is starting to get mostly tiring for me. But it’s ALSO pushing this new nurse guy, Dana. He’s SO excited and happy to be here. This guy is SO fucking dead. He’s got the voice over and it’s really pushing him, he’s so fucked. It also seems like he was brought in secretly as a third wheel so that thigns aren’t TOO awkward between Spock and Korby as they do some kind of dig.</p>

<p>Ortegas’ brother is also here! He’s recording stuff for a documentary, it seems, and is also invited to this mission, which SEEMS to be an archaeological dig on a sacred site. He’s also getting romance vibes with Uhura. They’re really trying to hook EVERYONE up this season aren’t they? Though Pelia the Warpcore Witch also seems to be real into him. And I like that, cause it’s funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5JfYBa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They all enter some kind of temple, after Chapel does some kind of thing to gain entry. They IMMEDIATELY find corpses and Spock is like “okay, protocol tells is we need to leave now”. Korby gets pissy and refuses, and Chapel, who’s in charge of the mission, sides with him cause he’s her girlfriend. There’s also a lot of tension cause of the whole Spock x Chapel thing. See, this is why everyone shouldn’t just fuck. Use the holodeck to fuck- wait. We already had an episode about how that’s a bad idea at this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ypNSSmn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>New Kid, who’s name is Gamble, acts like a TOS red shirt and randomly touches shit. Anyways, woah, New Kid gets his fucking eyes exploded cause things are actually super dangerous in here! Looks like Spock was right, what a mother fucking shock! The native living with them sees something else, freaks the fuck out, and tries to run away, and is vaporized. But we have so many things we could learn here!!! Korby was ABSOLUTELY going to just fucking die because he wasn’t being careful enough if others didn’t die before him, frankly. Why was he SO SURE that he had to do this dig RIGHT THE FUCK NOW? “I’ve waited all my life for this!” Yeah dude, but you’re like, 33. This temple isn’t going anywhere. Put down that fucking idiot ball, right now, mister!</p>

<p>They get split up, as if it couldnt’ get any worse, and are in different rooms, but able to communicate. This now turns into a split room puzzle game escape room. Seems to be the same room but also not, seperate dimensions. They can still communicate though. Why? I dunno, bad writing?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x4jYCCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Eyeball Regenerator, which apparently exists, is not working. New Kid’s brain is also registering as braindead. New episode name: Gamble’s Brain. Gamble is also acting Kinda Sus now. Hmm.</p>

<p>Ten minutes ago, Gamble’s eyes exploded. Now, Spock is saying how Korby is not being safe enough and not taking any precautions, and then he TAKES A FUCKING VISOR OFF OF A DEAD ALIEN AND PUTS IT ON HIS EYEBALLS AND USES IT TO LOOK AT THINGS. WHAT THE FUCK, SPOCK? I’m starting to think this episode might just not be well written.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLyV7Ze.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel, who I remind you is now half Gorn, meets Gamble, and starts speaking in tongues. Gamble does the same, and they proceed to beat the shit out of each other. Gamble also murders someone in the scuffle. After he’s captured, he just breaks through the force fields and kills more red shirts. Damn, this episode has a body count.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hp0x8tF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Pelia shoots Gamble in the back, releasing the ancient dimensional alien inside of him. Scotty then captures it in a Pokeball and tosses it up into the transporter. He locks it in the transport buffer, until they can figure out what to do with it. There’s no WAY that’ll backfire!!!</p>

<p>Pelia has a big discussion about ancient evil, which turns out to be her mugging for the documentary. Okay, that was funny. I was like “wow that’s very on the nose- oh okay, that’s good”. I do like Pelia. As M’Benga calls Gamble’s parents to tell them about their son, the Enterprise computer screens flash alien text. Wow, I knew it’d backfire but THAT fast.</p>

<p>I think my judgement of this will depend on if and when it goes anywhere, but I feel it was poorly written. Something was off and the pacing was bad.</p>

<p><strong>The Sehlat Who Ate Its Tail</strong> - SNW
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iXkfagX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What a weird episode title.</p>

<p>Anyways, Kirk is on the Ferragut, and he’s bored as fuck. His captain, V’rel is a hot Vulcan bitch who does everything By The Book, and Kirk wants a shakeup. Be careful what you wish for, Kirk. They disturb a disturbance in the crust of a planet they’re observing, which turns out to be the planet fucking exploding. The captain and a lot of the crew is taken out. Comms are down, so there’s no way to communicate.</p>

<p>Enterprise comes to help out, a team beaming over to try and help. Kirk is in charge, V’Rel is alive but injured. Turns out there was some kind of gravitational beam that blew up the planet, though it’d take a ship so much larger than anything else on record. Uhura sets up comms with the Enterprise, who orders everyone to evacuate. Fair. La’an and some of the critically wounded beam over first. Before they can do anything else though, THIS happens!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nV2aKch.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A giant fucking thing comes and literally eats the Enterprise. La’an explains she thinks it’s the Eater of Worlds. A giant ancient scavenger ship. Ghost story. Interesting. You’d think something like this would be more than just a Legend, but whatever works. Kirk refuses to leave people on the ship, and demands Scotty make miracles. This is actually the first time Kirk and Scotty are even working together. Since Spock is here too, as acting 2nd in command, with Uhura too, it’s practically a TOS reunion party. Just like, a pre-union.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2J7mGnt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The things in charge of this giant Scavenger ship appear to have boarded the Enterprise, and are just fucking Big Daddies.</p>

<p>Kirk is making bad decisions. He ignores all his advisors, and the ship explodes. Not like, fully, it’s just dead in the water. He ignored Scotty, and he’s pushed it too far. He gets angry and refuses to listen to any other advices. He storms off. They decide he needs someone to help him through this, someone with a less emotional style to calm him. Time for the start of Spock x Kirk!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FJxOfv8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get to see Pelia’s quarters. It’s absolutely incredible. She digs in a box for some ancient junk. She pulls out a mother fucking Atari. Holy hell. I want to see her video game collection. Communications are being jammed, so her plan? Wire the enterprise with ancient cables and use old-ass phones. That’s honestly fantastic.</p>

<p>We learn what the title of this episode means. The Sehlat that Ate Its Tail is a Vulcan idiom, similar to “the dog that caught the car”. Someone hunting after a thing, then… now what? Kirk, going after leadership, now he’s stuck and frozen. It’s cute. Anyways, Spock and Kirk have a heart to heart, and it helps. He comes back with a new plan. Make their ship look REAL tasty to the scavengers so they’ll come biting, then make them regreat it.</p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, the Big Daddies refuse to kill Pike after it knocks his helmet off. Weird. Strange.</p>

<p>“I haven’t done this since I was a roadie for the dead!” “…Your species can communicate with dead people?” Holy shit, I LOVE Pelia. When they actually do things with her she’s so funny.</p>

<p>This episode is not doing a LOT with Pike, but it’s doing more than the rest of this season’s done. He’s the CAPTAIN, and he’s barely got any love this season. He’s the best character on this show. Very fun moments with him. “Take a step back, this might blow up.” “Captain, if it does, it’ll blow up the entire engineering section.” “…A very large step back, then?” I love you, Pike.</p>

<p>Spock manages to hit the aliens where they hurt and blow them upm just as the Enterprise escapes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lQm5m80.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out the Scavengers were Human. On the side of the ship, they find “XCV-100”, which is a reference to a classic Ship concept. Apparently many years ago, some Humans built a ship to escape an environmental collapse of Earth. But then the ship disappeared, never to be heard from again. But how did they go from THAT, to whatever they became? It’s not explained.</p>

<p>I’m not really sure I like the ending all that much? The big twist? But the lessons Pike imparts to Kirk in the end are good, at least, and the action and jokes are good. It’s like, a solid season 1 or 2 episode.</p>

<p><strong>What is Starfleet</strong> - SNW
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hb6jfUp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So for the past season, we’ve seen Beto, Ortegas’ brother, recording a documentary about Starfleet. And now this episode IS that documentary. We get to see this guy’s documentary he made about what Starfleet is. And you know what? It kinda sucks.</p>

<p>We’ll see if, by the end of this, it’s… intentional. But it feels like a first year film student trying to Do Something. To Say Something. But it’s honestly stunning how bad the editing is. That HAS to be the intention, but I don’t care if something is intentionally bad if it’s bad to watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ePXmjB1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It jumps between scenes with weird camera angles and bad shots. None of the scenes flow together, with the different members of the crew talking about random inane bullshit. Apparently we get a Spock Self Harm backstory. When he was a kid he tried to carve the human half out of him with a knife. Joy. Glad THAT’S canon now.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/J9er1s6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Whatever this thing is, it’s pretty.</p>

<p>We see them go do… something in some war. It’s not super well explained. Every character feels weirdly out of character. I THINK that’s the point? They’re being misrepresented for some kid’s school project. Pike is angry and lashing out about the cameras being around. M’Benga is represented as a violent shady war criminal. He tells Uhura her friend is dead, just so he can get her reaction on camera. Oh yeah, just ask your sister on camera, who’s knee deep in PTSD, how her hand is doing after 3/5ths of it was dissolved in Gorn Goo.</p>

<p>Neli, the friend I watch these with, describes it as “them trying to do ‘Faranheit 911’. A kind of shockcumentary that is so up its own ass and full of itself. Yeah.</p>

<p>Also the camera shakes around so much this is so extremely hard to follow and hurts to look at. Beto is… bad at being a documentarian. I’ve said that a lot, but his camera work is ass, as ass as his editing. Why was THIS GUY given full open access to record anything on the flagship of the Federation?? It’d be like giving Uwe Boll unlimited access to do whatever he wants.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sqdG641.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Is he RECORDING PEOPLE WITHOUT THEIR KNOWLEDGE for this documentary??? I doubt that’s legal in the Federation. At least it seems like everyone on this ship is kind of sick to death of Beto. Uhura tells him to fuck off after he asks her some self pretentious shit about colonizers. At least we know where THAT romance plot is going. I swear, if they STILL try to push a romance with them after this episode, it’ll be even worse than the Worf x Dax bullshit.</p>

<p>So there’s some kinda plot about a society at war with another society, and they’re doing some kind of project to make this giant space amoebas into beasts of war. The neural implant they’re using is torturing it, and it breaks so it can’t be controlled anymore, and it lashes out. They communicate with it telepathically, find out it can’t control itself, and they help it commit suicide. That’s the plot. Honestly, not terrible? I would have liked to watch a normal-ass Trek episode about it. Because the first half is whatever hte fuck was going on there, weird propaganda shit, and this second half is actually Trek-like and kinda okay, but it’s COMPLETELY ruined because I was so extremely checked out. Also the editing and camera work are still fucking ass.</p>

<p>And it just ends. Here’s some comments from a video that put the ending out there clearly:</p>

<p>“The space moth killed itself and that was sad. But is war bad? Well at the end of the day: it is what it is. But most importantly: we are a family. The End” - robstein1313</p>

<p>“Is Star Fleet a military colonizing force? I think the real Star Fleet is the friends we made along the way.” - CouncilofGeeks</p>

<p>All of this was done to give character development to a character that I didn’t really care about and thought was just a little annoying at best, and now I kind of hate him. And this episode.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 9 - 12</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/21/LizstartrekEnt1-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 9 - 12" /><published>2025-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/21/LizstartrekEnt1-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/21/LizstartrekEnt1-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ssVkiCl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>STARTING ENTERPRISE NOW! I know NOTHING about this, other than it takes place very early in the timeline, has a guy named ARcher and a guy named Phlox, people smother gel on each other naked a lot, and a lot of people get a lot of opinions.</p>

<p><strong>Civilization</strong> - ENT
4.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/h1wMp9A.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got some anomalies on scanners. Some cool stars and collapsing stellar phenomina. And everyone is like “Ughhh that’s so booooring”. My man. Voyager went out of its way to look at shit like this, and they were going to die. How are y’all THIS bad at being space explorers? You’ve been up here for THREE WEEKS, AND YOU’RE ALREADY BORED???</p>

<p>Anyways they find a planet nearby with a bunch of life signs. A pre-industrial society called The Akaali. So now, before this episode EVEN STARTS, we know where this is going to go. They’re gonna send people down there (and one of those people is going to be Trip even though WHY WOULD YOU SEND THE FUCKING CHIEF ENGINEER ON THIS MISSION, he just goes on ALL the fucking missions for some reason) and they’re going to fuck everything up, Trip is probably going to fuck some alien, and then after the dust settles and an entire culture is ruined for the rest of time, they’ll go “you know maybe we should create a Prime Directive so that this shit doesn’t happen again”.</p>

<p>I want to say this right now, if this wasn’t clear that this was my thoughts already, this is the most incompetent, poorly chosen crew. The worst possible choices were made hiring almost everyone here.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/adJxhpW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They get a reading that there’s some weird tech shit going on. They’re trying to find out if maybe another alien force is trying to fuck with things. They’re immediately caught by a native of the planet, who pulls a crossbow on them, but is shot in the back by T’Pol. “GIRL, YOU’RE A VULCAN. JUST NECK PINCH HER.” - Neli</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RTzX4ke.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The owner of this antique shop appeared, and then shortly afterwards, people started dying of disease. This woman is an apothecary, and is investigating the strange disease. After talking to her, they get her help. Archer pretends he’s from another city. He also kisses her weirdly, but it was a ploy to fix his translator. It did REALLY throw me off when it happened though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nipHmn4.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This animation of boxes being taken into space looks like an animation from Riven. Anyways he has to pull out a gun to save them from these aliens, who appear to be lizard people. And when she asks wtf, he just… tells her. Yeah, we’re space aliens. She takes it SHOCKINGLY well. The culture on this planet is not very well thought out. Compare this to TNG episodes about pre-industrial cultures. They have a well explained culture, and they react realistically when the structure of reality falls apart around them. Her? She immediately understands how to work with computers, happily takes a phaser and knows how to use it, and her first question when she finds things out is “why would you come HERE out of all the stars in the sky?” Like…. that’s not realistic.</p>

<p>Anyways the two of them storm the shop, and some shit happens, and they manage to win, blowing up the shop. Turns out they were mining for stuff that was irradiating the water supply. They tell the aliens to go away, and some Vulcans agree to check in from time to time to make sure they don’t come back. Archer makes out with her, probably spreading some kind of horrible venereal disease across her planet, and then it just ends like that.</p>

<p>Also apparently this episode was shot AS 9/11 happened, and the actors were kinda checked out. I didn’t notice, but god, we really are in the 2000s now, huh?</p>

<p><strong>Fortunate Son</strong> - ENT
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/In2zETd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THAT AIN’T ME</p>

<p>THAT AIN’T MEEEE</p>

<p>Anyways two people are playing Football and going “oh boy I sure do love being alive!” when they are suddenly attacked by some Nausicaans. Enterprise gets their distress beacon and comes to help, where they’re told “everything’s fine, go home :D” but they insist on sticking around how help them make fixes. This 2nd in command, currently acting captain afte rhis captain is injured, is CLEARLY hiding somethin, and we see it real fast. He has a Nausicaan held captive, and is torturing him for some codes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ggukF9G.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is here to set up some lore, and also to give Mayweather an actual episode! Yes, it’s a Mayweather episode! Mayweather has a single character trait, and that’s that he’s a “Space Boomer”. People who live in cargo freighters and freight cargo and not much else. He’s proud of his time on the Freighter, and talks about it a lot. Like I said, it’s his one real character trait. And since they’re helping freighters here, he helps them get acclimated to the crew and the Enterprise. And they kind of hate him, cause he “betrayed his family” by leaving the freighter. Space Boomers appear to basically be the Human equivelent of southerners from small towns.</p>

<p>They find out about the Nausicaan, confront the acting captain about it, who’s a pissy butt baby about the whole thing. He agrees to take them to the Nausicaan so they can free him and heal him though… and then pull a gun on them. Though it’s important to note, Reed actually shoots first. I guess that’s his character trait. He’s trigger happy. They manage to throw the Starfleet off, then fire on the Enterprise and blasts off.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PKZYJVK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This guy is going on a revenge rampage cause “they hurt his family” and is torturing this alien. He’s also like “THEY NEED TO BE TAUGHT THAT THEY’RE NOT TO MESS WITH US!” Is the moral of this episode that “when you stand up to bullies, they’ll just hit you harder, so keep quiet and just keep taking the punches”. Also yeah Archer is like “We shouldn’t fight and kill these Nausicaans…” when they are, in fact, pirates who are killing everyone and attacking willy nilly. That’s not really like, wanton violence. Sure, the TORTURE is bad, and I agree with that, it’s a He Who Fights Monsters type situation though, and he’s trying to OVER correct.</p>

<p>Shit of COURSE goes south, and wow, the prisoner they took gave them the wrong codes and lied to them, WHAT A SURPRISE.</p>

<p>This episode is, yet again, another fucking Moby Dick episode, and for some reason I NEVER like those. It’s literally one guy who’s just a pissy whiny butt baby about everything and refuses to listen to literally every single person around them who says “this is dumb” because they are so self absorbed. It really IS like a southern butthurt conservative southern town coal miner who’s blaming everyone else for changing times and problems happening to them and their family.</p>

<p>Anyways Mayweather solves things by talking to him. The end. Yay.</p>

<p><strong>Cold Front</strong> - ENT
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ssVkiCl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>At the start, we’re introduced to a crewman named Daniels, a pleasant enough guy. Enterprise runs across some alien ship filled with religious pilgrims, here to see an interstellar phenomena they consider holy. Archer invites them onto the Enterprise for cultural exchange, and it’s all ncie and pleasant. There’s even a good scene where, while THAT’S happening, the lower commands are sitting on the bridge like “well, we’re stuck here” and it’s kinda cute actually.</p>

<p>Things go well with the pilgrims on board, though there’s some signs there’s some weird tampering. Daniels comes and tells Archer he thinks the Suliban he fought in the first episode, Silik, is here to cause a problem, and he explains.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QwXv7G2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Daniels is from the future. 3050, basically. He’s a Future Time Space Cop, and is here to figure out who’s trying to fuck with the timeline. It seems Silik is here… apparently to save Enterprise. So now Archer is feeling a bit conflicted.</p>

<p>It becomes especially interesting once Silik shows up and goes “I’m actually the good guy here, Archer, this future cop is dangerous”. Of course, it’s obviously bullshit, because he’s threatening him with a gun and the music is dark and evil. So this fascinating line of though doesn’t really go anywhere. Silik just IMMEDIATELY shoots Archer and then kills Daniels.</p>

<p>There’s also a side plot of Phlox learning more of the pligrim’s religion and getting super into it.</p>

<p>Silik and Archer fight, it’s a pretty classic Trek fight scene, and actually has classic Trek fight music, but Silik managed to exist. They manage to still have The Egg, something that Daniels had. They lock it up, and that’s that.</p>

<p>This is trying to set up something but there are no real plans and it’s not very engaging. When DS9 set up the Dominion it was background lore that you wanted to learn more of. Why should I care about a temporal cold war???</p>

<p><strong>Silent Enemy</strong> - ENT
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tqxMY8L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is maybe the funniest description for an episode I’ve seen in a while. This is some TNG season 8 shit.</p>

<p>“Enterprise is attacked by an unknown alien starship, as Archer orders the crew to install experimental “phase cannons”. Meanwhile, Sato is ordered to find out what Reed’s favorite food is for a birthday dinner. “</p>

<p>There’s a scene where Trip is like “My girlfriend broke up with me cause of the long distance” and complains that he didn’t know they’d be this long distance. Dude. Did you know ANYTHING about the mission you were going on??</p>

<p>If I may say, Archer’s way he handles First Contact is really awkward and kinda bad. He’s like “Yo hi. I’m a Human. We’re here to meet people. Wanna meet us?” with a lot of stuttering and awkwardness. First the aliens just leave. Then they come back, still silent, shoot once, and leave.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4FJ2dNu.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So for the entire series so far has been Reed going “Captain can we install good weapons so I can do my job, now?” and captain Archer going “NOT NOW, REED, TRIP NEEDS MORE SCREEN TIME”. But FINALLY he’s allowed to DO something. They’re installing some new weapons onto the ship, at the same time Hoshi is trying to figure out his favorite food for a surprise party. As stupid as this premise is, it’s AMAZING for telling us what kind of character he is. Unfortunately, he’s actually kinda boring. He seems like a straight laced gay guy who keeps to himself and eats soylent green and that’s about it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m7CUaEl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They straight up look like the aliens from Metal Slug 3.</p>

<p>Also a good Archer moment. They’re dead in the water, the aliens might come back. He’s doubting if he should have pushed to make them come here, cause he did it MOSTLY to prove himself, a selfish reason, and he feels bad he might kill people for that. Trip helps him come around. Actually KINDA okay Trip scene, too.</p>

<p>They test the cannon and it overloads, almost blowing up the ship, but they use that to their advantage, blasting away the enemy by INTENTIONALLY overloading in a last minute gambit. It works and they run off with their tail between their legs. It’s a bit sad we get no info about these guys cause they are intentionally antagonistic and fascinating.</p>

<p>Also Reed’s favorite food is pineapple, which Hoshi learns cause of Phlox testing some kinda medical thing. It’s silly.</p>

<p>Honestly good episode? Good banter, good character moments.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 184</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/20/OOCY184.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 184" /><published>2025-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/20/OOCY184</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/20/OOCY184.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/d3CITjR.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Make It Real</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Make It Real" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 207 - Mr Chin’s Gourmet Paradise</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/20/RA207-MrChin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 207 - Mr Chin’s Gourmet Paradise" /><published>2025-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/20/RA207-MrChin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/20/RA207-MrChin.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/U52EPCd.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I was looking through some random early gameboy games one day, and I found this one. I’d never heard of it. Mr. Chin’s Gourmet Paradise by Romstar. It’s one of the absolute weirdest gameboy games I’ve played. Conceptually, gameplay wise, it’s not THAT weird. But… hmm.</p>

<p>In this game, you play as Mr. Chin. He lives in a world with these little creatures, Momos. They kinda look like the fires from Donkey Kong. You’re dropped into a single screen platformer (though it usually scrolls left to right), and can jump and place… what looks kind of like a mine. If you place two of these mines at the same layer, they will connect together with a laser. And any of those momos inbetween turn into peaches, his favorite food.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zBtXqKZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The manual makes it clear this is morally reprehensible. He’s turning these cute little critters into food, killing and eating them. It’s kinda fucked up.</p>

<p>Other than that, it’s a simple single screen platformer type deal. Eat all the monsters, move to the next stage. Your score is labeled as “kcal” which is kinda funny.</p>

<p>All in all, this is a fine game, though it is very so SLIGHTLY jank, and pretty simple. You’ve got some power ups, like one that lets you fly, but it’s really just like 10 stages and that’s it. They’re pretty easy to learn, cause the enemy patterns are the same every time. Committing warcrimes has never been this fun(?)</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Platformer" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 183</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/18/OOCY183.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 183" /><published>2025-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/18/OOCY183</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/18/OOCY183.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/818ZgL4.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Picked Up a Bunny Girl</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Picked Up a Bunny Girl" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>