<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-09T00:17:38-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 21 - 25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/08/LizstartrekDS96-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 6, Episodes 21 - 25" /><published>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/08/LizstartrekDS96-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/08/LizstartrekDS96-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zdayXgW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>So, there’s only one more episode left in DS9 season 6. We’re going to watch it next week, where I’ll repost this with the additional episode.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>The Reckoning</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fiK79p8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The war is going bad, though a BIT better with the Romulans entering. That’s good! Odo and Kira are cute and lovey dovey now which will take some getting used to.</p>

<p>Anyways, Sisko, Kira, and Jake go down to Bajor, cause apparently some monks found a thing that might be important for the Emissary. Jake is being a weird little bitch about it like “Why is my dad okay with being Jesus now, why are we here, isn’t there more important stuff to worry about”. Jake. You’re an adult now. You’re like, 20. You don’t need to tag along when your dad goes away. As they see some old door that says “Welcome Emissary”, Sisko gets a vision that tells him that THE RECKONING APPROACHES.</p>

<p>They bring the stone door up to the station and give it to Dax, who has one of my favorite lines. “Yep, I know what this was the moment I laid eyes on it. It’s a hunk of stone with some writing on it.”</p>

<p>Sisko: “The prophets are never clear in their messages”</p>

<p>Kai Winn: “Ah, I wouldn’t know. They’ve never spoken to me.”</p>

<p>WHY IS THIS WOMAN POPE?? Anyways Kai Winn is a bitch like she always is, and demands the stone tablet back, just cause she’s a weirdo xenophobe. And then they translate the tablet and it says, very clearly: “DS9 is going to blow up”. Uh oh. And then the wormhole gets unstable and it starts fucking up Bajor.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2ulIDbN.png" alt="trek" />
<img src="https://imgur.com/x5XQf56.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then Sisko gets fed up with it all and throws the fucking tablet against the wall. We then see Things release from it. I’m sure that’s fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yPjAwhq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We then find out what’s happening. Some Prophets and some Pah-Wraiths were released. The Prophet takes Kira, who it says is willing so that’s fine, and says that it is going to fight a Pah-Wraith here once it takes its own body to fight with. Kai Winn is like “FINALLY, A PROPHET” and begs it to give her something to do, she wants to help, and its basically like “who are you” by just, ignoring her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KBoEKlv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They call for an evacuation, and everyone leaves, except Winn who’s being annoying as always, and we see the Pah Wraith’s choice of body: Jake. There’s a lot of body horror in his face, it’s extremely upsetting to watch. There’s a fucking DBZ-ass battle, with energy beams, and it’s unsure who’s going to win, and who might die… Until Kai Wrinn uses a button that hurts Prophets, and knocks them out of their body. Why? We don’t know. She goes “Prophets forgive me…” but uh, I dunno if they will.</p>

<p>Keep in mind that everything that follows is probably her fault. The prophets said everything would be good if they win, which wasn’t guaranteed, but it looked like it was. So yeah, she just killed a LOT of people, and Space Satan is still out there. Kira calls her out on it, and blames it on her pride, which y’know, makes sense. It’s what the whole episode was about.</p>

<p>Interestng lore, just alright episode.</p>

<p><strong>Valiant</strong> - DS9
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JLpcQmR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>While Jake and Nog are going to Ferenginar to deliver a thing to the Grand Nagus, they’re attacked by some Jem’Hadar, oh no! They’re rescued by… the Defiant! Nope, not the Defiant, it’s a ship called The Valiant, which is clearled based on the Defiant. So they’re trying to mass produced the Defiant now. That’s… gonna go well I’m sure. The people on the ship are all cadets… kind of. Turns out they’re RED SQUADRON! You may not remember them. They were the Elite of the Elite cadets at the Acadamy. They ALSO tried to help set up a coup a season or two ago. They explain that they were supposed to just be on a training exercise (the same one they were sent on in that episode actually), and then all the senior crew died in an attack, and one of them, Shepard, took command and now they’re stuck behind enemy lines and basically doing run and hide tactics to hit at the Dominion.</p>

<p>They invite Nog in to join them, and Nog’s always looked up to Red Squad, so he’s on board, and they need an engineer. But Nog is a little suspicious… because this captain seems to be doing this under the radar, and all the missions are sent to the dead captain instead of him, and they don’t know he’s just assumed command. But everything is on the level so far. So far.</p>

<p>Jake befriends the doctor on board, and asks her about home. This gets her kinda emotional and missing home. Y’know, normal human stuff. But this is a WAR and we are a MILITARY. Please ignore the fact that Starfleet is not, in fact, military. They are a MILITARY. They bring her and Jake in and are like “You are not allowed to be friends because you’ll DISTRACT THEM”. Also, the captain appears to be addicted to pills, and is kinda wigging out in a very sussy way. Jake is side eying all of this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OOB1m6S.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re all just kids. They’re kids who are thrust into a situation they aren’t ready to handle, and they are kids who are basically being used to play out the captain’s Captain Fantasies.</p>

<p>Jake is thrown in the brig because he’s questioning this guy’s bullshit. Everyone else has kinda swallowed the poison. The captain has them go attack a destroyer. It’s basically like the Millenium Falcon trying to blow up a Star Destroyer. It does not go well. It predictably does not go well, and everyone starts dying as the Explodium goes off. It’s now just Nog and the girl Jake befriended, and then they rescue Jake from the brig and escape in a pod, barely making it out. The girl is like “the captain was a good man, and if he failed that means we failed him.” She’s STILL drinking the coolaid, but Nog makes the episode’s message clear: He may have been a good man. But he was a bad captain. And he killed a lot of innocent people with his arrogance.</p>

<p><strong>Profit And Lace</strong> - DS9
1.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zdayXgW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Here it is. One of the big ones. This is often considered the worst episode of DS9 of all time. And as a woman myself, I am sure I will have a LOT of opinions about it. But who knows? Maybe it’ll surprise us, and be good!</p>

<p>The episode starts with Quark sexually harassing one of his workers by demanding she sleep with him or he’ll fire her.</p>

<p>Well, that didn’t last long!</p>

<p>Anywayst the REAL episode starts when Grand Nagus Zek shows up on DS9 with Quark and Rom’s mom, Moogie. She’s wearing clothes! and in PUBLIC! Zek explains that he recently passed a law that allows women to wear clothes. And if they can wear clothes, they can go out in public. And if they do that, they can make profit. Yay! Unfortunately, this caused societal upheaval, and all the men in power banded together to depose Zek, and now Brunt is acting Grand Nagus, to be sworn in in only a few days. Zek drags the other main character Ferengi in trying to get people on his side. It doesn’t go well. Everyone is sexist. Fuck, even Zek is. He’s progressive… for a Ferengi. Anyways they get ONE person on their side, ready to see a female to prove females can interface with society</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gk5PrgF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Brunt continues to be the most punchable man in the galaxy.</p>

<p>Quark and Moogie get in an argument and she has a heart attack. That’s not good. They need a woman to show to this guy, but where are they going to get one?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AHWrcp5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Good thing Bashir does gender reassignment surgeries like every other day. It IS the 24th century.</p>

<p>Yes. That’s right. This is the transgender episode. Kind of. It’s actually the Gender Bender episode, but like, this hits a lot of trans energy. And not in a good way. Quark is now a woman, MEDICALLY, like he’s filled with estrogen. And it’s making her emotional. Ha ha, you know them women. ALWAYS emotional. They have a lot of things to grill Quark on, she has to be presentable in like, 12 hours. She needs to work on her walk. And her voice. And she needs to smile more! They don’t literally have that last one, but god, they might as well.</p>

<p>This is one of those feminist episodes that…. fails in almost every way, but god, is it insulting. I mean, I guess it’s trying. Kind of. The original concept was to make it a kind of comical farce, like a Shakespearean farce, but the director, Bashir’s actor, and Quark’s actor decided to play this DEAD serious. As such, the writing and the visual intent clash in a way that is very, VERY uncomfortable.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1Pgnw9l.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We literally get three straight minutes of this guy they invited chasing Quark around her room, trying to sexually assault her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cDnTSaX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Brunt bursts it and is like “THAT’S NOT WOMAN, THAT’S A MAN, BABY” but when Quark shows her tits to this guy, he doesn’t care. Well at least he’s a chaser, I guess. Anyway alls well that ends well, and he backs Zek to put him back in office. Quark’s experience with being a woman makes him more sympathetic, at least for a bit, and he apologizes to the woman he sexually assaulted, and she’s like “oh but I was looking forward to fucking you :(“. Ha ha, what… fun.</p>

<p>Yeah, this blows a lot. To be fair, Armin Shimmerman, Quark’s actor, also agrees. He thinks the half-serious half-joke idea failed horribly, I agree, and he actually toned down some of it, because the script wanted him to cry a lot, and he felt it was a bad stereotype, and went against the feminist angle of the episode. Yea, that’s true. It could have been even worse. Also, Quark really learns nothing by the end, and yeah. THey LITERALLY go “You’ll be back to your old self soon~”</p>

<p>And obviously, this episode wasn’t built with trans stuff in mind, but as trans stuff is VERY in the public conscious these days, it’s hard to ignore that reading. And that voice outing scene made me want to gag. I hated this episode, but I can’t give it a 1. It’s at least TRYING to be good, it’s trying, but fucking god.</p>

<p><strong>Time’s Orphan</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dVWHBeg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>O’Brien is back! We haven’t seen him in a few episodes. And KEIKO IS BACK! We haven’t seen her in AGES! They’re back from Bajor, and O’Brien doesn’t want them to ever part again. The bad news is, they are immediately parted. O’BRIEN MUST SUFFER! They’re playing on a Bajoran colony on vacation, and Molly finds a weird gate thing in a cave and falls into it, disappearing as the gate closes.</p>

<p>They find out it’s a TIME PORTAL that was just sitting around I guess, and it sent her hundreds of years in the past. She’s now somewhere in the past, when the planet was uninhabited. They reactivate the portal, and get her back… but 10 years too late. She’s now 18, and is a wild child. She bites O’Brien before she’s sedated. She’s VERY unga bunga. Now they need to re-integrate her into society, and good luck with that,.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the B-plot is that Worf needs to baby sit Yoshi, and he is VERY bad with kids. At least the A and B plots fit. It’s also a fun concept.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4fCwdwq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The episode then becomes Keiko and O’Brien trying to rehabilitate Molly, who seems to have repressed all her childhood memories and remembers nothing. It’s actually REALLY heartwarming and sweet to watch, tinged, with some sadness.</p>

<p>Eventually she becomes a little unstable. She’s improving, but she wants to go “home”. They take her home, but no, not THAT home. HOME. They can’t go back to the planet though, so they take her to the holosuite. But they can’t keep her there forever, and when other customers want it, Molly goes…. feral, and freaks out, and then runs through the bar and STABS A MAN IN THE STOMACH WITH A BROKEN BOTTLE. Oh. Oh that’s very bad. The man presses charges and wants her incacerated, because she’s dangerous. I mean, she kind of is… it’s a very unfortunate situation. She needs wide open spaces, but they can’t really give her that on the station. And they’re going to send her to a therapy center, which is PROBABLY not going to be good for her either. And imagine her being on a transport for a few days.</p>

<p>So what are they going to do? Time for O’Brien to do crimes.</p>

<p>They kidnap Molly and drag her, sedated, back to the planet. She’s not safe there, she’s not really safe anywhere… so they try to steal a runabout, and are caught. Odo’s like “Come on Chief, I thought if ANYONE could steal a runabout without getting caught, it’d be you. On your way”.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oABXZlr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They send Molly back through the portal, planning to destroy it after. It’s a tearful goodbye, but Molly goes through, to his home… and then finds out she’s been transported not to her time, but to the exact time she went through the first time, finding herself as a 7 year old. She sends her back through, and fades away due to temporal shenanigans.</p>

<p>Well, that KINDA negates the gut punch. That’s a real shame. Like, I liked everything about this episode, it was cute and heartrending, and then it meant nothing! Hmmrf. Good, but didn’t hit the landing.</p>

<p><strong>The Sound of Her Voice</strong> - DS9
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4HcpJvs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On the way home from a long tiring mission, the Defiant gets a distress call from a woman who’s apparently a star fleet officer asking for help. They head over to help her. They can’t get any messages back through the planet, and O’Brien is on the case. He leaves her SOS message on as she rambles, basically. She’s just rambling about her life, because she has no one to talk to and is scared she’s going to die. Everyone is like “why are you doing that”. And he’s like “I dunno, it just feels right, like someone HAS to listen, otherwise she’s falling on deaf ears, and that’s sad”</p>

<p>Also the B-plot is Quark is distracting Odo by reminding him of his love for Kira in order to do illegal stuff, and Jake is researching him. It doesn’t fit.</p>

<p>Anyways they connect and can communicate with her now. She’s a captain who was returning to the Alpha Quadrant after an 8 year exploration of the Beta Quadrant. She’s the only one in her squad left, and she’s dying on an L-Class planet, so they’d better get there fast, but they keep her company. Most of the crew find her boring as fuck. Especially Bashir. She tortures him for ignoring him by pretending that something got her and ate her. It wakes him up and makes him realize he was being shitty. She’s his patient.</p>

<p>It’s kinda interesting seeing this. Everyone talks to her in a different way. O’Brien practically uses her as a friend and therapist. She tries to give advise to Sisko. And she and Bashir jab at each other. But things take a bad turn; the medicine she’s using runs out faster than expected, as her last dose was tainted. She’ll die in two days of CO2 poisoning. And they’re still 3 days away.</p>

<p>The b-plot ends in a cute way. Quark gets outplayed by Odo, who hears Quark like “and after I helped him with with Kira, tsk tsk”, and Odo decides to… let him have one. JUST this one. It’s cute. Odo’s been pretty good these episodes, he’s really grown as a person.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HvaIkGS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Tried taking a picture and caught this picture instead that looks like Sisko just heard someone on the bridge make a racist joke</p>

<p>They have to risk their lives in a few ways to make it in time, but they do it, to save her life.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lxajUtY.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways they go, and find out she’s been dead for years. The anomaly that they had to get through caused her SOS to go forward in time. They couldn’t have EVER made it in time. She had no chance ):</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sW6ycOK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They couldn’t save her, but they have a funeral for her, because over those six days, she had become a friend. And not only that, but she taught them all that they needed to talk, that they were holding things inside. It’s really touching. A very good scene. And a good episode! The Quark B plot was alright but mostly unrelated and didn’t fit in, but it ended quite nicely.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 68</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/08/OOCY68.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 68" /><published>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/08/OOCY68</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/08/OOCY68.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UHndcCZ.png" alt="A girl sending a text to the girl she's holding hands with that says &quot;I love you&quot;, which causes the other girl to explode into steam" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Unforgettable Flowers and Rainbows</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Unforgettable Flowers and Rainbows" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 67</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/05/OOCY67.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 67" /><published>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/05/OOCY67</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/05/OOCY67.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hisVuNe.png" alt="&quot;Hello! Right now I am playing basketball. Basketball is a sport where you try to put a hard ball that hurts when it hits you into a net.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Subtraction Tautology</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Subtraction Tautology" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 127 - Final Fantasy 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/05/RA127-FF5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 127 - Final Fantasy 5" /><published>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/05/RA127-FF5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/05/RA127-FF5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P7X5pt9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I played all the NES FF games recently, and decided to keep it going with some SNES, but after playing FF3, I decided I wanted to play FF5 next. This game is basically the sequel to FF3 in many ways, and also, I’d played it once before, but never beaten it. And I remember ABSOLUTELY loving it. I had played the GBA version though, and this is the original SNES version. Which isn’t too different, tbh, it just has a few less bonus features. But how does it hold up? Is it as good as I remember it?</p>

<p>Final Fantasy 3 is, in my opinion, the best Final Fantasy game. In terms of its mechanics, that is. FF6 still wins out over all, though if you told me FF5 is your favorite, I’d go “that is 100% fair”. FF5 builds on what FF3 does in such a way that ESSENTIALLY perfects it. I have a single problem with the game and it’s not even really a problem. I’ll get into it.</p>

<p>Let’s start with one of the things people tends to complain about with this game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nZIElFz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, the story. FF5 is nestled between FF4 and FF6, which have large complex stories with lots of characters. FF5 has four characters, and then you swap one of those out for another later down the way. That’s it. And the story isn’t some major political intrigue with FF6 or a game with major twists about the characters like FF4. Like I said in FF3, it seems that even FF games are story-based, and odd ones are mechanics based. And yeah, this story is simple. An evil force is trying to break the four crystals to free himself. But I think people who say the story is simple and boring are frankly, wrong. This story DOES have twists, and it has a LOT of fantastic moments. A FF game that suddenly has a surprise second world map isn’t anything new, but this has THREE.</p>

<p>And of course, the Galuf Fighting Exdeath scene is, frankly, one of the best scenes in all of Final Fantasy. I felt EXTREMELY invested watching that scene, which is more than you’d expect from a “childish” story, as people say. It’s not FF6 or Chrono Trigger, sure, but all the characters are likable and interesting (Lenna is maybe the least, but hey, it’s fun to make fun of the fact that she poisons herself like four times), the plot is good enough, and the writing is goofy and fun. FF2, 4, and 6 are kinda serious games. FF1, 3, and 5 are a little goofy. And it’s goofy in a GOOD way. That’s not to say EVERYTHING lands, but I like the story. It also has a lot of themes about old generations and new generations coming along to fix the pasts’ mistakes, and that’s a theme that I like.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ypGDh71.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Now for the best part of the game: The mechanics. FF5, like FF3, is a job system. You have characters, who are Freelancers to start, who can swap to different jobs, after unlocking those jobs from the crystals you find. These jobs have their own levels you can gain and their own EXP, on top of your normal levels and EXP. This unlocks new abilities you can slot into your ability slot, but notably, you can ALSO slot those abilities in for OTHER jobs too. So for example, get enough levels in Thief, you gain the steal ability. Now when you swap over to Dragoon, you can also slot in Steal, so your Dragoon can steal as well!</p>

<p>The jobs are balanced by the fact that most of them are fucking busted. A lot of them have VERY strong abilities you can use. Time magic, for example, has a spell that just lets you use two actions in a turn. Nuts. And dual wield + X-Factor is SO powerful that they literally made it Bartz’s super finisher in the Final Fantasy fighting series. So yeah, a lot of things are busted. But not everything is busted, sadly, and some jobs, like Dragoon or Berserker fall by the wayside. At least Red Mage KINDA has a chance to shine… kinda. Red Mage sucks-ass, but if you get 999 job points, you get dual cast, which you immediately put on someone OTHER than Red Mage, because by that point not having tier 3 magic bloooows.</p>

<p>I essentially cannot sing the praises of FF5 enough, but if there was one thing that bugged me…. So, in FF2, when characters died, they were put in the back. That was a fiddly thing I kept forgetting. In FF3, when back attacks happened and I had to swap rows, it didn’t automatically swap them back, so that was a thing I kept forgetting. The tradition continues here, too. This game’s Fiddly Nonsense I Kept Forgetting was the auto-equip system. In FF3, you had to manually unequip everything to change jobs. That was annoying. Luckily this game has an auto-equip feature that chooses the best equipment! Good! Unfortunately, it only cares about stats. So if you say, have the Bone Mail, which has KILLER stats but turns you undead, and then forget to take it off… Oh hey, Faris is low on health, let’s cast cure and- oh she’s dead.</p>

<p>This gets worse if and when you have cursed equipment. I ended up getting so fed up I ritualistically killed the equipment (and by that I mean, sold it)</p>

<p>But other than that, I seriously have no complaints. This is one of the best RPGs I’ve ever played, extremely fun, and highly worth your time if you haven’t played it. Unfortunately it’s pretty forgotten these days, and never got its due here in the west, since it took until the GBA era to come out here.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 126 - Dragon Quest 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/04/RA126-DQ2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 126 - Dragon Quest 2" /><published>2024-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/04/RA126-DQ2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/04/RA126-DQ2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xdEO1Ed.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So Dragon Warrior 1 was the first game I ever emulated, back in the very early days of emulation. But obviously, I wasn’t going to stop there. And if I was enjoying Dragon Warrior 1, why not try out its sequels as well? While DW1 devoured me, and I did beat it back then, I did not beat Dragon Warrior 2 until just now. And on further reflection, I know why.</p>

<p>This game is kinda fucked up</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZByAS5F.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Dragon Warrior 2, or Dragon Quest 2 if you’re not an old head like me, is the perfect example of a sequel to an RPG. It continues the story, many generations later, in a distant land. You can go back to the previous game’s region and explore it. It takes the original graphics and gameplay and straight up adds to them, in every way.</p>

<p>In DQ1, you have one on one battles with a character I can only describe as “Ness from Earthbound”. Strong and kinda good at everything, though not as much at damage spells. In DQ2, you get a party of three characters, each with their own spell list and stat growths, so they each excell in different ways. Your main hero, the Prince of Midenhall, has no magic to speak of but is built like a brick shithouse and hits like a dozen trucks. Your cousin, the princess of Moonbrooke, is squishy and weak, but has a lot of good damaging spells, and supporting spells too. And your other cousin, the prince of Cannock, is very good at dying! He uh, is weaker than you in every way, and has less spells than the princess. He’s kind of trying to be a redmage, master of none, but he’s certainly a master of none, to a kind of meme-worthy degree.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hF6pbWP.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>And since you get more than one party member this time, so does your enemy! Enemies come in groups, and if there’s more than one type, you need to specify which enemy type you’re fighting. You can’t focus down one enemy if there’s multiple of that type, it’s random who hits which, and if you try to hit an enemy that’s no longer there, you waste your turn. It’s VERY classic RPG bullshit, and they didn’t fix that for aaaages.</p>

<p>So yeah, it’s typical early Dragon Quest stuff. Wander around, kill slimes, go into caves and towers to get items to progress further in your quest. The thing about Dragon Quest 2 though is that once you get past the more linear early part of the game, getting your three party members together, you reach a town and get a boat, and now the entire game is wide open to you. And that means that you will prolly wander to a place you can’t survive in yet, cause there’s no guidance, and get your shit beat in. This is… not very fun, honestly.</p>

<p>Dragon Quest has a LOT of very cryptic hidden shit, and it’s all mentioned as rumors by towns folk, but you need to do a LOT of note taking and exploration to know what the fuck any of it means. And this game is not kind to that exploration. DQ1 had a bunch of cryptic shit too, I mean getting that item in that swamp? But DQ2 has a lot MORE of that, and in DQ1 it’s pretty easy to know where new enemy groups begin, and slowly progress further into new areas, but it’s not here. This is, IMO, to the game’s detriment. This is a game you’ll probably want to use a guide to complete, which tells you exactly where you can go without becoming paste with Vegeta’s face ironed into it.</p>

<p>The end game is also pretty mean. DQ1 was a huge grind fest, and this game is also, indeed, a huge grind fest. You NEED to be at a high enough level to even stand a chance of the boss gauntlet and huge-ass dungeon in front of you. But once you finish your grind, it is in fact a relatively fun game. Prolly better than DQ1, though I think I do prefer DQ1 more still.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Dragon Warrior" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 66</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/04/OOCY66.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 66" /><published>2024-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/04/OOCY66</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/04/OOCY66.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/riPCwhP.png" alt="&quot;Whether I think of her as a friend or my wife, I love her. I love her more than anything else...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Trying Out Marriage With My Female Friend" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 65</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/03/OOCY65.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 65" /><published>2024-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/03/OOCY65</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/03/OOCY65.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WV6mQT4.png" alt="&quot;It's always been a dream of mine to kidnap the princess and hold her hostage!&quot; &quot;No, thank YOU! It's also been my fantasy to be kidnapped and be the damsel in distress!!&quot; &quot;YOU'RE BOTH SO WEIRD.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Mage &amp; Demon Queen</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Mage &amp; Demon Queen" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 64</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/02/OOCY64.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 64" /><published>2024-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/02/OOCY64</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/02/OOCY64.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kpeENhL.png" alt="&quot;I told you right at the start, didn't I? That I wanted to go out with you!&quot;&quot; &quot;That's... a different matter... *her hand is so fluffly...*&quot; &quot;Go on. Give it a feel.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Love Allergy Syndrome</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Love Allergy Syndrome" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 20-25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/01/LizstartrekVOY3-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 20-25" /><published>2024-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/01/LizstartrekVOY3-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/12/01/LizstartrekVOY3-4.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LfhWsO6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Rise</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W02qh83.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is helping some friendly aliens who’s planet is being harassed by a bunch of asteroids. They can’t blow them apart though, no matter what, the asteroids are reacting weirdly. If they can’t stop them, many might die. They get a call from a scientist from the surface who says the asteroids are “Not what they seem” before he’s cut off, so it’s time to visit him. On the way down, however, their shuttle crashes, which is the only thing I ever see these fucking shuttles do.</p>

<p>It’s now Neelix, Tuvok, an alien they brought with them, and the scientist and his friend who go and meet them at the crash site. They need to get back up to Voyager with the scientist, but how? The shuttle is fried. Luckily there’s an orbital tether nearby they can use to get up, though it’s damaged. Neelix offers to take control of the mission, basically, and takes responsibility for fixing the tether. He wants to prove to Neelix that he has what it takes to be on this team. They find a squatter who’s been hiding in the tether, who threatens Neelix with a knife, but he’s a pleasant guy so he convinces her to stand down and join them instead.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RmVZTPA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile on Voyager, they determine that the asteroids have some kind of guidance system in them. Someone is TRYING to attack the planet.</p>

<p>Back in the tether, the scientist they picked up is being a dick. He tries to leave without them. He gets in a fight with others. One of them tries to throw him out of the thing, and Tuvok needs to stop him. So when he’s killed, seemingly by poison, there’s no immediate idea of who it could be. (Though it’s kinda obviously just from vibes) It’s a good setup and concept for a murder mystery… though the pacing, and as I said, vibes, are a biiit off. It’s not as good as it could be, I feel. The scientist gives a warning about something on the roof before dying, and Neelix decides that they have to go up to see what that is. Tuvok, being a condescending dickhead, disagrees, and Neelix RIPS into him in a scene I kinda love, about how yes, he has no feelings about Neelix, as he says, but that’s the problem. NO respect, at all, for the past three years.</p>

<p>Anyways Tuvok goes on the roof and gets thrown off by the traitor, who’s the guy they came down with, who was working with some aliens who are trying to genocide the planet and claim it for themselves. Neelix is injured, but manages to sneak Tuvok back into the shuttle, who beats the shit out of the traitor and throws him out in a HILARIOUS scene that looks like shit in a way I appreciate. He and Neelix have a heart to heart, and they make it back, using the scientist’s information to take out the aliens and save the day. Yay!</p>

<p>The actual episode part of the episode was just okay, though I did really like the Neelix and Tuvok parts</p>

<p><strong>Favorite Son</strong> - VOY
4/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LfhWsO6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>As they fly around space, Kim is having some deja vu moments… including a moment where they meet a new alien species, he goes “I REMEMBER THIS, THEY’RE GOING TO FIRE”, then reroutes weapons to ops and opens fire on the random aliens. Well that’s fucked. Belanna gets second degree burns on her lungs in the ensuing battle. That’s VERY fucked. Harry feels bad cause oopsies he did a warcrime and almost did murder ):</p>

<p>He then has nightmares about it, and about being sick with chicken pox, and then wakes up with a weird-ass rash. The doctor can’t find anything wrong with him, he’s just… turning red in parts of his body.\</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Txsd0r8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>After some study, they find out yes, those aliens WERE about to shoot on them. So uh, turns out Harry’s hunches are a GOOD thing, in a way? Especially as they’re now being chased by more aliens. Harry leads them to a star system, where they are saved by people calling themselves Taresian, who explain that Harry is a Taresian, who’s finally made it back home.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lYhrmFs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Taresians are almost all sexy women who are rubbing all over Harry, and it grosses me out. Thats intentional, for the record. The purpose of this episode was, quote, “a male fantasy piece with a dark twist”. Well, we’ll see the dark twist eventually. The Taresians explain that they go around to other planets and impregnate women with their babies, which is fucked beyond belief, and then those babies will try to find their way back to Taresian space. Hey cool, can you help get us back to Earth then??????? No? Okay.</p>

<p>The vibes here are rancid. They’ve got a lot of weird rituals that are… off, and they seem to be isolating Voyager from Kim. But it’s fine cause he’s about to be married to a bunch of hot women, that’s GREAT! Voyager finds out they implanted a virus that’s turning him into a Taresian. But for what reason? :o</p>

<p>This episode keeps trying to be sexy, but Kim has this permanent virginity energy about him that makes it uncomfortable, nad not in the way they’re TRYING to make it uncomfortable. He always has the energy that he’s trying to get away from these hot babes and get to the nearest D&amp;D table.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/z0J6siN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Harry looks for the only other dude who has were, and find him, a dried husk. Oh my god they <strong>SUCKED HIM DRY</strong>. Yeah, they turn aliens into them, lead them there with implanted genetic memories, and then eat their genetic code. Voyager rescues him, and they leave. Eh.</p>

<p><strong>Before and After</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ckwWkCq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Fascinating cold open here. We see the Doctor, with hair, operating on people worried about their family member. He then tells the person that they were “the best friend they ever had”, and then used a “temporal bio-chanber” something or other on her, and then she wakes up and a boy is like “hello, Grandma Kes”. Ooh, some intrigue!</p>

<p>Kes is apparently 9 years old, so this is six years in the future. We see some interesting things, I always love seeing what Trek assumes it could be like in an alternate future. Kes has a kid with Paris, and their kid has another kid with… Kim. Kim, the fuck you doin’??? Janeway appears to be gone, and we’ve got Captain Choky, as we’re calling him. Kes appears to have no memories of anything, except for that first scene, and then she gets cold and wakes up in her room.</p>

<p>It appears to be that she’s living life in reverse. Everyone is thinking she might be delusional, but eventually she knows something she SHOULDN’T know, after going back in time again, so they’re like “okay, sOMETHING is up”</p>

<p>Apparently, B’Ellana and Janeway died in <strong>“THE YEAR OF HELL”</strong>. I’m sure that won’t be important. Paris rebounded with Kes, apparently.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sl5MSvl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The aliens they fought during <strong>THE YEAR OF HELL</strong> used temporal weapons, and they has caused chroniton radiation. And this, alongside the bio temporal chamber thingy are causing her to live life backwards, her first memories from her death. And eventually she might just… go back to her birth, or even before.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/V8xEZlW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We have to watch Kes give birth. Whoof. This is DURING the <strong>YEAR OF HELL</strong>, and then we go back even further, to just the start of the <strong>YAR OF HELL</strong>. Okay I’m getting tired of writing it like that. It’s the <strong>YELL</strong> now. So at the start of <strong>YELL</strong>, Kes gets to meet Torres, who’s in a relationship with Paris, and then we watch her and Janeway die. Dammit. Kes is trying to use her future knowledge to help people, now not caring as much about fixing her problem, and worrying more about helping others. After she finds out she’s infected, though, she goes and finds out what the torpedo’s… variance was, so she can stop her backwards movement. She goes back one more time, 11 years before <strong>YELL</strong>, and they uh… throw some anti-chronitons at her. Did you know there’s <em>anti-time</em>??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rm9BxTF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It does work. She goes back to the start of Voyager, then to her childhood. This is horrifying. Her parent, or whoever it is, is kinda like “ohhh you’ve been on a starship, of course you have!” and she has NO way of fixing this issue. She goes back to being born… Then to being an embryo… then egg cells, and finally nothing. It’s black.</p>

<p>They maybe should have just stopped there, that would have been fucking NUTS, but no, now time is moving forward normally. She’s brought back, the anti-chronitons worked perfectly! She’s now back as a healthy 3 year and two month old. Kes now has all her memories, AND the future memories. And she’s keeping a lot of those secret… but she will warn them on the Krenim. I’m sure that won’t be important.</p>

<p>I actually really liked this episode. Really fun concept, done well, rather horrifying in a way</p>

<p><strong>Real Life</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KBdd0QU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with a Jetsons-ass 50s-ass family ready to see their husband/father off to work, as the Doctor comes back, and then transfers to Sickbay. Turns out he made a new Holodeck family, to see what its like to have a family. It’s kinda like something Data would do. In fact, he DID kinda do that once, though uh, hopefully this time it will end without me sobbing into my tea. He invited his friends over to meet his family, sounds cute.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, they are exploring space and find that some aliens blew up a scientific space station, and they need to find out who did it. These two concepts aren’t going to mesh well are they?</p>

<p>The holo-family keeps talking about how great the doctor is, and how he’s the best person and best doctor in the whoooole wide world. Torres, who has had a very, VERY not good family life, is EXTREMELY offended. This COULD be interesting! A plot that tries to show that the perfect neuclear family we are TAUGHT is the goal isn’t true or real, showsn through Torres’ fucked up familial history, sounds almost more MODERN than something from the 90s. I’m worried they’ll fuck it up though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qBWZ9bq.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Torres “fixes” the problem by apparently adding randomness. Now one of the children is a brat who is very very needy, the mom is exhausted and belligerent, and the son is trans-Klingon. Torres programmed his life into a wacky sitcom. TOTALLY on purpose, too.</p>

<p>There’s a scene where Torres and Paris flirt with each other. I… WEIRDLY don’t hate it. So there’s a thing this episode is doing. Torres is kinda… a character. Not just an angry woman who does her job. She’s snarking back, reasonably annoyed but putting her frustrations to positive things…. she’s reading porn. In the mess hall.</p>

<p>“Doc, you’re acting like you’re trying to cure a disease. You can’t… CURE a family” - Paris. That line is…. very good.</p>

<p>“Dad! what are you doing here???” “I live here, Jeffery, in case you’ve forgotten.” That line is. Also good.</p>

<p>Jeffery gets in with some Bad Boys (Klingons), and we see a knife they call their dak’tag. I was like “that’s no Dak’tag. I’m guessing they fucked up?” Nope. It’s a Kut’luch knife, used in ritual violence to hurt someone innocent to become a warrior. That’s a… very dumb ritual. Why would they do that and then call it honorable? Anyways, it’s a good twist for Trek Nerds like me to go “WAIT NO.” Also, the Doctor’s daughter is injured playing Parese Squares and is probably going to die. Remember that sentence I said earlier about hopefully this won’t end with me crying in my tea? That might be ironic. The Ensign ends the problem, because holy SHIT, he cannot handle this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ar0BBxs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Amazing scene with Paris and the Doctor. You can’t have the good times and ignore and throw away the bad. The good things that can grow from adversity. The whole point of having a family is being there for each other.</p>

<p>Yep. I teared up. It’s pretty fucking harsh. And we watch this girl die, on screen. Fuck you, me. Fuck you and your ironic joke about crying. WHY DO WE EVEN HAVE PARESE SQUARES? THAT SHIT SHOULD BE OUTLAWED.</p>

<p>This episode’s A plot was basically perfect and hit very, VERY hard. The B-plot was uninteresting and barely there. It really holds the episode back.</p>

<p><strong>Distant Origin</strong> - VOY
9.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nXtBN9q.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got two scientists, Voth, a reptilian race. We’ve got Veer, and Gegen, who find a Voyager crewman who died a season ago, and determine that his DNA is actually shockingly similar to their’s, which supports Gegen’s theory: The Voth did not evolve here, but are from the Alpha Quadrant. Now they need to hunt down this ship and find out what they can about these people. When they go to get funding, however, the People In Charge are bothered, because this could upset the balance (namely, the fact that they claim they are the most superior people here, and disrupt their power, y’know how it is). They charge Gegen, so Gegen and Veer go to chase after this dead person’s vessel. They have a thing in his tech that says they’re chasing after something called… Voyager.</p>

<p>This is a VERY good and interesting setup.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IANmL5L.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They make it to Voyager, and sneak on board, cloaking to examing. It’s basically two nerds walking around and making biological commentary about humans. They’re not harmful or evil at all, just weird. And then they’re discovered. The Federation, understandably, think they might be dangerous. And they run away like “maaaybe we should explain outselves”, but when they’re shot at, and the younger one, Veer, shoots back, stunning Chakotay. Gegen kidnaps Chakotay, while Veer goes into hibernation out of fear.</p>

<p>Chakotay and Gegen kinda bond, because Gegen is a pleasant dude who just wants to learn about Humans, and Chakotay is white bread who can’t stay mad even when he’s kidnapped. Voyager discovers the connection between their species, that the Voth evolve from Dinosaurs… and then a Voth ship shows up. It’s huge. Like, HUGE. VERY, VERY BIG. Thousands of times bigger than Voyager. Voyager is literally beamed inside of the ship, and then the Voth invade, and COMPLETELY obliterates them. They can’t do SHIT.</p>

<p>Now Gegen gets a message. They have Voyager and will kill everyone if he doesn’t come to stand trial for heresy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qvtCi9Q.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The last part of the episode is a trail. Gegen is on trial in a kangaroo court, Veer denounces him publicly, probably cause he was threatened. Gegen and Chakotay defend themselves, and science, against conservative ignorance. It’s very well written, though regretably it IS held back by Chakotay reading his lines with all the temerity of a guy reading the TV Guide out loud. The bigoted, conservative minister is going to lock EVERYONE in a detention colony unless Gegen publicly denounces his scientific claims. It’s PAINFUL watching him denounce it.</p>

<p>Gegen hopes that someday the truth comes out, but he wasn’t strong enough to stand up to the powers that be. Chakotay gives him a globe of Earth. He hopes, one day, he can see it, eyes open.</p>

<p>This episode was FANTASTIC. Almost perfect. I wish Chakotay and Janeway’s roles had been reversed, but like, it’s so well written in every other way.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 125 - Dharma Doujo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/01/RA125-Dharma.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 125 - Dharma Doujo" /><published>2024-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/01/RA125-Dharma</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/01/RA125-Dharma.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/blJnQct.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’ve already talked about this one before, but hey, I mastered the set, so time to talk about it again.</p>

<p>This is a game set that I myself made! The RAM for this game is fucked, as the RAM for a lot of the sets I try to dev are.</p>

<p>Dharma Doujo is a SNES game made by Metro, based on their Arcade puzzler. It’s a very unique puzzler unlike anything I’ve played, except its spiritual sequel made by the same people, and a bootleg of it called Mang-chi. But other than THAT, it is very unique. You’ve got a stack of blocks, and you can hit anywhere on this stack vertically, grabbing the furthest left block. If you get all of the same block, it’s cleared. Otherwise, the blocks you grabbed will slide back up into the stack. Organize your grabs to clear all blocks and beat the stage, before the yokai climbs all the way to the top!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/caFDIXx.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a hard as hell game, mostly based on it being unlike anything you’ve ever played. You gotta basically learn a new language with this game. And it gets HECTIC. If you’re playing as the monk in this, the yokai is time based, but if you’re the shrine maiden, you can take your time, the yokai will only climb with misses. This can be good for learning the game, though there’s a lot to be said for lighting a fire under your ass.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/k0KqDT2.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You’ve also got two unique modes for this game, which aren’t in the arcade! You’ve got Endless Mode, where a Tengu will knock blocks down periodically. He’ll show up when there are only two matches left to make, or if you take a long-ass time. It’s really kinda easy, at least it is to me, as I’m really good at this game. Maybe for noobs he’s hard as hell, who knows. The harder difficulties make it so that some junk blocks show up too, it’s not all clearable, which is fascinating.</p>

<p>There’s also a multiplayer mode, which is fantastic, but I didn’t have to do for the set</p>

<p>The other unique mode is Puzzle Mode, where a judge shows you a finished stack, and you have a stack on the left. Organize it in a way to mimic the stack on the right. This is very, VERY hard to me. My brain just boggles at this, and it gets really, REALLY complex by the end. It takes genius level brainpower. 50 levels, and a challenge for sure jsut after the first 10.</p>

<p>Over all, I do prefer the arcade version, but that’s just cause of the mild graphical changes. This version IS prolly much better, all things considered. And as a game is very, VERY worth your time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Dharma Doujo" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>