<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-27T14:41:51-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Dream Journal 10/27/24</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/27/Dream.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dream Journal 10/27/24" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/27/Dream</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/dreams/2024/10/27/Dream.html"><![CDATA[<p>Had a dream last night that Games Done Quick was taking place in my Elementary School’s cafeteria this year</p>

<p>They had a giant pool installed in the ground, and one of the most anticipated runs of the year was a real life run where my friend Dowolf was going to swim, with no gear, in the pool, and the walls and floors would rise up and move out and try to squish him, and he had to dodge them.</p>

<p>This seemed COMPLETELY normal to me.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="dreams" /><category term="dream journal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Had a dream last night that Games Done Quick was taking place in my Elementary School’s cafeteria this year]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 117 - Earthbound/Mother 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 117 - Earthbound/Mother 2" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/27/RA117-Earthbound.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m40cwUj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>A month ago, September 20th in fact, I mastered Mother 1, and made a post about it. I should go back and change that post. I feel like I was focusing a bit too hard on Mother 1 and comparing it to Mother 2, and didn’t talk enough about what I liked about it. I’ll try to do a little less of that this time, though some of that will probably come out anyway. These two games are VERY comparable, because they’re very similar, at least in how they present themselves.</p>

<p>Earthbound, or Mother 2 in Japan, is often considered one of the best RPGs of all time. It is HIGHLY influential. And it booooombed. It did NOT do well over here, though giving credit to it, it DID actually come out here, unlike its NES prequel, Mother 1, which got translated but was never released. When I was a kid, I played Mother 1 thinking it was this game, and didn’t learn that I was wrong for like, months. When I DID finally play this game, I got into it, and stopped playing prooolly around after Threed. And that’s about the way it was, for years. This is the best RPG ever, you HAVE to beat it, I’d pick it up, play until around Fourside, and then stop.</p>

<p>This year though, I FINALLY beat it. And yeah. It’s good. Pretty good! I do see why people like it. But some parts of it fall…. flatter than I’d hope.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/y1CHXvR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Earthbound is about a young boy named Ness, who lives in the town of Onett in Eagleland. One day, he’s woken up in the middle of the night by a meteorite falling onto the hill near his house. After some shenanigans with his bratty neighbor Porky, a fly named Buzz Buzz comes out, claiming he’s a hero from the future who is here to warn Ness, the Chosen one, that evil is on the rise. An evil named Giygas has come to destroy the world, and Ness must gather three friends and stop him. And then Buzz Buzz is swatted like a fly and dies.</p>

<p>That’s kind of how I’d describe this game. It’s got a big plot about friendship and banding together to overcoming terrifying odds and circumstances, and then its also filled with very goofy funny moments. It’s maybe a little jarring? You’ve got funny goofy moments that are nonsensical, like oh hey, you need to move forward but there’s a big metallic pencil in your way. Well don’t worry, just get your handy dandy pencil eraser, which will erase any pencils! And then you have scenes like the one where Poo is meditating and a spirit comes to rip off his arms, legs, eyes, ears, and brain, violently, and horrifyingly.</p>

<p>It’s got a little bit of a tone problem.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q62vZen.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>That’s not to say that either of these moments are bad. They’re both good. And this game is really quite funny. I love the little inconsequential dialogue, I went around speaking to everyone, cause it’s just funny and enjoyable. Everyone’s got something weird to say.</p>

<p>Let’s talk about gameplay for a bit. There’s no run button, which IS pretty painful. The first game didn’t have one either… except for the American Beta, which added a run button. So this is kind of a step back, actually. It’s slow and plodding, which is a little painful tbh. IMO the pacing of this game is off, and it’s not jsut with how slow it runs, the game REALLY drags in the middle, and then it doesn’t pick up for a while. But anyways, the gameplay is still a Dragon Quest-ish JRPG, though this time you can have up to four characters. The backgrounds aren’t all black now, you’ve got some really frekaing cool effects back there, I’m a big fan. Also a big fan of the new rolling health system. As you take damage, your health ticks down. If you win before it ticks to zero, you live, and your health stops falling! You can also do a quick heal as it’s ticking down to save yourself. IMO this is an ingenius invention, and GREATLY improves things. As you panic and quickly mash through menus to heal Paula for the millionth time, it keeps turn based combat exciting and fun!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Y7AeldK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One of the things that feels a bit downgraded over the NES version is actually the world itself. The NES game takes place on one giant contiguous map. You go out, you explore the world. You see how places connect and move together. This doesn’t quite have that. It’s more like, a few dozen maps stitched together with doors to and from. I don’t think it’s a big deal for most, but for me, it feels like a downgrade. You know what’s also a biiiit of a downgrade? The music. I know, I know, I KNOW you’re booing, but look, Mother 1’s soundtrack is fucking fantastic, and while Earthbound’s is very, very good, and I like it a lot, it doesn’t have a Pollyanna, or a Paradise Line, or a Bein’ Friends, or an All That I Needed, and definetely not an And Fallin’ Love or a Mother Earth. Sometimes I heard tracks from Mother put in this game as a remix and I got VERY excited, but they’re few and far inbetween. You hear a relaxing heartwarming rendition of Polyanna in Ness’s house, and a great remix of Youngtown in Paula’s house, but that’s about it. again, this is not to say the soundtrack is bad. It’s very good. And it’s got a LOT of really interesting things about it, and a lot of references.</p>

<p>Okay, let’s talk theming. Mother 2 has, in my opinion, a bit of a theming problem. Like I said, it’s a game about friendship and banding together to overcome powerful odds, constantly pushing through even if it’s scary, because that’s what you have to do. That second part, I think the game handles quite well. The final area is really intimidating and scary, and it and the final boss emphasise this part of the theme very well, in my eyes. It’s the friendship part where IMO the game falls flat… I don’t think I can imagine these people as being the best of friends. Poo shows up randomly and says “I am your friend now” and then leaves with the exact same energy. Jeff leaves the game with a “Well, call me if you need some appliances fixed”. All of the characters talk about have a bit more character than their counterparts in Mother 1…. maybe. Honestly it’s about the same. There’s not a lot of character here, and because of that, I can’t really feel like they’re best friends who are banding together. They’re just random characters being shuffled together as fate decides, because a psychic child had a dream that said they’d be best friends.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hIMnDYG.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This also leads me to one of my other major problems with Earthbound. It’s a big retread of the previous game, and yet it also has NOTHING to do with it. The only thing that links these two stories together is the main villain, Giygas, who might as well be a completely different character. The game does nothing to actually explain the connecting bridge between the two games, and if you didn’t even know Mother 1 existed, like kids didn’t in the early 90s, you wouldn’t expect anything is out of line. Ninten, Ana, Lloyd, and Teddy might as well not even exist. They’ve been replaced. Now we have Ness, who is just Ninten again, Paula, who is just Ana again, and Jeff, who is just Lloyd again. Teddy has been replaced ENTIRELY with Poo, who’s his own thing, at least. But there’s a LOT of retreat ideas. Area under attack by zombies? Yep. A desert filled with a monkey cave? Yep. Collecting 8 parts of a musical piece? Yep. Musical act scene? Yep. Gotta do a thing so that the pubic transit works and you can go through the tunnel? Yep. Like, the thing is, most of these would feel like references to JP kids who played both, or at least I think it was intended to feel that way, but it feels more to me like they were just trying to make Mother 1 again. There are plenty of unique ideas, and they’re all quite good, but a lot of the retreating feels like it doesn’t fit the themes and is just… there. And yeah, there’s no connection to Mother 1 despite all this. I know a lot of fan theories, like Giygas erased Ninten and his family from the timeline, which broke him because he also erased his mother. Or Ninten is Buzz Buzz. I’ve heard all these theories. But that’s all they are, theories.</p>

<p>This doesn’t actually make the game bad in any way. I’d give this game an 8/10, it is a very good game, and I totally get why parts of it are very influential. But people kinda ignore the most obnoxious forgettable moments, and especially the pudgy middle section, as they just re-do the same really interesting parts over and over, like the final Giygas battle, which is VERY influential, and yes, quite good.</p>

<p>Well, there’s Mother 2 done. I really only have one more thing to do…</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="SNES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="RPGs" /><category term="Mother" /><category term="Earthbound" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 36</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 36" /><published>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/27/OOCY36.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/B7NVOLu.png" alt="&quot;Hey Aya, when we kissed and did that lewd stuff, what exactly were you thinking?&quot; &quot;This rocks. I'm so glad I'm alive right now. Thank God my parents made me take aikido classes.&quot; &quot;Noooo don't think about your parents while we're doing it, dammit!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Yuri Story About a Girl Who Insists “It’s Impossible for Two Girls to Get Together” Completely Falling Within 100 Days</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Yuri Story About a Girl Who Insists &quot;It&apos;s Impossible for Two Girls to Get Together&quot; Completely Falling Within 100 Days" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 35</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/26/OOCY35.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 35" /><published>2024-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/26/OOCY35</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/26/OOCY35.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3cEuRpR.png" alt="&quot;That's what I... love about you&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mTshXK4.png" alt="Oh shit I said it face" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Hana Ni Arashi</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Hana Ni Arashi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 116 - Ultraman - Hikari no Kyojin Densetsu</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/25/RA116-Ultraman.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 116 - Ultraman - Hikari no Kyojin Densetsu" /><published>2024-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/25/RA116-Ultraman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/10/25/RA116-Ultraman.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VnYI0nj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I know jack shit about Ultraman. But I do know kusoge fighting games, and this is one of em!</p>

<p>Based on several years of Ultraman, Ultraman: Legendary Giant of Light, how it’s translated here, is a fighting game on the Saturn by SIMS. If you don’t know them, they’re VERY prolific. SIMS, or “Soft development Innovation Multi Success”, though no one calls them that, is a joint venture company between Sega and Sanritsu. They made a LOT of Sega games, their output is stunning. But the thing about them is while they made a LOT of games, it’s nothing I’d really say is… worth caring a lot about. Oh boy, Wimbleton II for the Master System. Oh joy, Outrun 2019 on the Mega Drive. So yeah, they’re the perfect group to make a tie in videogame for Ultraman.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Be1CHyL.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Ultraman is a big deal, as far as I’m aware, in Japan, but again I know jack shit about it. I know that it is A) a show where a giant dude fights kaiju. B) Very cheesy in like a 50s way, and C) Made by a catholic. And I only know THAT because there’s a stage in this game where the background is filled with Ultramen who have been crucified on giant crosses, and it was SO FUCKING WEIRD WHEN I FIRST SAW IT.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7zn3Dsq.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This game, for what it’s worth, seems like a huge love letter to Ultraman. It’s got a bunch of the music, which does NOT fit this combat usually, lots of lovingly rendered monsters and ultramen from the series, and lots of locales to destroy as you throw monsters into em. It’s a bit jank and goofy, but I’ll be real, pretty charming.</p>

<p>I only did this set because I needed one more game mastered to become the top Saturn person on Retro Achievements, and this looked easy. And it was. It was pretty simple. You just jump kick then stand kick over and over again and it defeats the AI. But it kinda surprised me. This is considered kusoge, but is pretty enjoyable. Much better than a lot of fighting games I’ve played. And it’s got a bunch of cool kaiju in it! Sick! They seem HORRIBLY balanced, but y’know, cool!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lTpW8oD.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It won’t blow anyone away, but if you were a Japanese kid in the late 90s who really liked Ultraman, you could totally do worse than this. There are some SHIT Ultraman games out there.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="obscure games" /><category term="kusoge" /><category term="Ultraman" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 34</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/25/OOCY34.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 34" /><published>2024-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/25/OOCY34</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/25/OOCY34.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/a4IYZ4c.png" alt="A delinquent reading a dictionary definition of love: &quot;Intense feelings of romantic attachment for a member of the opposite sex&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FC5v71Y.png" alt="&quot;...Dumbass dictionary. All I've learned is that you ain't worth shit.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Delinquent, A Transfer Student, and Their Silly Little Game</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Delinquent A Transfer Student and Their Silly Little Game" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 33</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/24/OOCY33.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 33" /><published>2024-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/24/OOCY33</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/24/OOCY33.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IgIhlFe.png" alt="Anime girl trying to forget about tits, and then she's shown some springy, bouncy mochi" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NtBe1N8.png" alt="Anime girl having a tit-based PTSD episode." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Tits so good they give you PTSD</p>

<p>Also yesterday was the first day since I started my blog that I didn’t post yuri. I went out to the park early to hang with friends then I felt like shit for the rest of the day so I didn’t post yuri lol please forgive me.</p>

<p>source: Hana Ni Arashi</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Hana Ni Arashi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 32</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/22/OOCY32.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 32" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/22/OOCY32</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/10/22/OOCY32.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lvBrKMe.png" alt="&quot;Sh-she's not straight...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3RYhH5C.png" alt="&quot;Sh-she's not straight...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Same</p>

<p>source: Hana Ni Arashi</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Hana Ni Arashi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 52 - Conclusion</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-52.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 52 - Conclusion" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50#52</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-52.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WNpJ4yk.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO50 was a collection of 50 games made over the course of seven years by LX Systems, later UFOSoft. It was made in celebration of their 50th game, and while it seems like it might never have been released, it was found 30 years later by some nerds in an old warehouse, as seen in the cracktro intro for the game.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KjLr1JU.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, what’s the purpose of all this? UFO 50 is just a collection of 50 games with a fake backstory. Why go through all the trouble to make a fake backstory, with fake characters, a fake murder coverup, and a fake CEO who hordes games instead of releasing them for people to play and use, cultivating a collection for himself and no one else? What is the point of UFO 50?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0N91bUn.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO 50 is about preservation.</p>

<p>As we get further into the future, more and more games are lost to time. People made these. These aren’t just products to make a profit, and they aren’t just code with no purpose. People put hours, days, years into creating them. They are the culmination of creative people who care about the thing they love. Games. And it’s easy to forget that, especially as these people and their work is swept under the rug. As the game are forgotten, lost to time, locked away behind CEO’s vaults in case they might possibly sell them in the future, or locked in personal collections and never shown to the public, those people are forgotten as well. All their work, their love, their passion, it’s lost.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RHsIeEW.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO 50 is about preservation. Greg Milk’s entire goal, from creating UFO 50, under Nemuru’s leadership, to hiding hints and messages and an entire game that shows him, his coworkers, and the world they had to live in, it’s a bright, blinding message that they were there. They were the people, the love, and the passion behind those games. And while someone like Nemuru might try to seal away play for himself, some might leak out, and be preserved, by those who love it. It might be played, and enjoyed, for years to come. It might, some 30 years in the future, be the topic of 33.8k words of reviews written by a dork in her basement. It might even be her game of the year.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nMQoRA2.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO 50 is about love. And I hope we don’t ever forget that. May it shine on, forever.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">UFO 50 Retrospective Part 51 - The Terminal &amp;amp; Miasma Tower - SPOILERS AHEAD</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-51.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="UFO 50 Retrospective Part 51 - The Terminal &amp;amp; Miasma Tower - SPOILERS AHEAD" /><published>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50#51</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/2024/10/22/UFO50-51.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LcKO9Uj.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>UFO50 has a built in terminal. It’s not a secret thing, it’s right there, in the menu. This is implied to be the terminal of the computer itself, which you can use to access files and execute commands directly, rather than use the GUI of the game itself. There are a lot of more obvious uses for this terminal. Several games will tell you codes that can activate hidden modes and cheats, like the WOLF-PACK code that lets you play as four dogs in Grimstone, which I mentioned. But there’s also more to the terminal. A secret. A very, very in depth secret, which will blow the story of UFO 50 wide open.</p>

<p>The story of Miasma Tower is a very deep and interesting thing, and I am going to go very in depth. If you want to experience it for yourself, do not read ahead, as I am going to go FULL on with spoilers. Everything will be laid bare. Ready? Okay, let’s go.</p>

<p>There is a secret 51st game in UFO 50. Even before I started playing the game, I guessed there might be. This is the kinda game that screams meta secrets. But how do you find this hidden game? The most obvious, and correct answer, is the terminal. It’s gotta be chock full of secrets. But how do you get at them? There are a few ways to discover Miasma Tower, the hidden 51st game. I discovered it by noodling around in the menus. The terminal is like an old computer terminal. It has commands, and once you have a general idea of those commands, you can do a lot. A common command from back then was HELP. And sure enough, it works here. Each game has a four letter name, like UFO1 for Campanella, SAC1 for Mortol. But they are also numbered. So 0001 is the first game, Barbuta. You can do HELP-0001 to learn all the commands you could use with Barbuta. It’s very simple stuff, basically stuff you can find in the GUI already. The history, the name, etc etc. But if you put in HELP-0051, you get shown a different game. And it’ll helpfully tell you its name. MIAS. Input EXEC-MIAS to start the game…</p>

<p>That’s the way I found it. But there’s another way. A more complex way, and the way most people found it. When you look at the terminal, you notice something. It’s two words, each four letters, seperated by a hyphen. Where have we seen that before?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ssoYojM.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Our boy, Greg Milk. Milkdud here gave us a clue. Remember, Gregory Milk is the person who MADE UFO50. And he also made Miasma Tower, and he wants it to be seen. But it’s hidden away. Why? Miasma Tower was never meant to exist, and it was not meant to be in UFO 50. But it had to be, for reasons we’ll get into, so Greg hid it, deep in the terminal. And your first clue is by typing in GREG-MILK, which will give you a cryptic message.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VgPY6ct.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’m not going to go in depth with these messages. They are a hidden meta puzzle that will take you into many of the 50 games in the pack. You need a knowledge of all 50 games to proceed, and as you follow Greg’s trail of bread crumbs, you’ll eventually come to a message that says “EXEC-MIAS”. So there you go. The other way to find Miasma Tower. But what IS Miasma Tower?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OHQb5rt.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Let’s hop in and find out…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sGniQ2S.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Miasma Tower, you play as Gregory Milk. This is an autobiographical adventure game, not quite a game as much as a visual novel, showing you what life is like at UFO Soft. The game is explicitely from the point of view of Mr. Milk, who’s opinions, views, and thoughts are on full display. As you interact with things inside the UFOSoft office, you’ll see what Greg thinks of them, and how they effect the world, and the people around them.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/BwzGKx0.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game takes place inside the current UFOSoft HQ, and has all the workers and coworkers there. They’re all represented by weird little critters, but it’s not actually that hard to put a name to a character. This wasn’t really meant to be seen by outside forces. It was a game made by Greg, basically for Greg. He knows who they are. We have to do a bit more sleuthing, but based on where people are, what they say, and what their job is, we can make a guess. This is Meesha! The characters are all represented by little weird critters, and I like how Greg represents himself. He’s a brown lumpy… thing, with a permanent frown. If you read Greg’s inner thoughts, the man is clearly depressed and anxious. The years have not been kind to him, and the recent events at UFOSoft have left him with serious scars.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/VqDT6h9.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3FNqXWv.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/amfRxi5.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DOvoUgb.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Greg isn’t the only one. A lot of the people around the office are overworked, and exhausted. They’re being put on jobs that aren’t really what they’re good at, and being milked, and it’s pretty obvious they know. The corporate culture of the office ia also quite toxic. There’s references to a kind of hazing ritual that poor Shayn had to go through recently, which Greg is HORRIFIED at the idea of ever happening to him. Thorson Petter is hard at work in his office, as it lights on fire around him, as he overworks himself to death to add more games to Campanella 3. Why? It’s never explained.</p>

<p>And that last one there, that’s Benedikt Chun, the only founder left. He’s getting neurotic himself. He sold the company over to the devil a few years ago, for just the safety of being able to make the games he loves, and now he’s asking if Greg thinks anyone will ever play their games. What does he mean by that? I’ll get into that in a moment…</p>

<p>First, you should know the structure. This game is split into a few parts. You start in a closed space, and then find a disk and play it. It’s an old beta demo disk. After beating that, you get more puzzles which lead you to a new execute command, and now more of the offices are open. You then find another disk, beat THAT demo, and get more puzzles, and then even MORE of the offices are open. It’s an interesting progression mechanic, as you go through the past to reach the present.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6Ez95fA.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x86uYkS.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fTBCpLN.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6mqVmbZ.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All throughout the offices, you’ll find references to the fact that the games that the company has been making for the last year do not seem to actually be released. The workers seem to know this too, as is hinted from that message in Diskonia I mentioned: “HOW FAR IN THE FUTURE ARE YOU READING THIS?”. What kind of company can continue running when it’s not even releasing its games? For what purpose? There are so many expenses, but no income. And yet, the HR accountant tells you flatly that the boss has allowed her to give out raises. They’re spending a LOT. The offices are filled with things that aren’t neccessary to make games. A barely used gym. A dormitory which Greg feels weird about using. A whole arcade and game room, filled with Nemuru’s personal collection. How can they justify this?</p>

<p>Becuase the point isn’t to sell games.</p>

<p>Tao Nemuru has connections to a company that’s hinted at in Miasma Tower in a few places: &lt;MPI. Or the Murtzbach Preservation Institute. There was a tester called Sten Murzbach, who’s name also leads to a code that shows a bunch of time capsules. What does this mean? What is the purpose? It’s never said, but we can make some inferences. And to reach that conclusion, let’s talk about the people in charge.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xpqwsvd.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P0it4OC.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CYsPBd1.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AAp49kk.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/GXjNsBq.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eNFmHWm.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>All of Greg’s coworkers and friends are represented by weird critters, but the people Greg doesn’t like are represented in two ways. The boss’s minions and enforcement, HR and the middle manager Ian Spinzer, are represented by giant groteqsue dinosaur like monsters. And the boss, his child, and their psychophant tester, are all represented by bugs. Nemuru is shown as having a kind of… cultist energy to him. He has a book of philosophy he pushes on others, the psychophant following it heavily. And that book is this one:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLZ5X1s.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The Grasshopper: Games, Life, and Utopia. I have not read this book. But it’s clearly at the root of the grasshopper and ant imagery, especially seen in Combatants, Nemuru’s baby. It’s based on the classic kids story of the grasshopper and the ant. Y’know, the grasshopper plays all summer while the ant works, then winter comes and the grasshopper starves like the ant plays. The book itself takes this further and turns it on its head a bit. It’s a book of philosphy that consists of rumination on the nature of games, told through reconsideration of the fable in ways that parallel the game, ranging from both the concept of saving games in preparation for a future utopia where we will play forever, and the framing of games as an obstacle.</p>

<p>That first part is the thing that really hits at key here. Nemuru is a games collector. He is shown to have a vast collection, and he’s gathering more. He’s very, very into preservation, but in a… bit of a twisted way. More of a collection for a collections’ sake. What it took to make that collection, and what it contains, doesn’t quite matter, so much that he has it. Murzbach Industries seems to be some kind of group, almost cult like, which collects and is locking away games in a kind of time vault. That’s why Nemuru is so interested in pumping out more games, and in UFO 50 as a culimation, a grand testemant to what they’ve made. That’s why there’s a paper showing multiple game companies, and next to UFO Soft, it shows the words “Almost done?”. They’re almost done using up UFO Soft, and then these games will be locked away, forever. For some idyllic future where the billionares will play and play.</p>

<p>I have a lot of thoughts on this, and I’ll talk about them in a conclusion to this entire story. For now, there’s a few other things hinted at in the backstory of UFO 50 through Miasma Tower that are extremely interesting, and should be shown.</p>

<p>I’ve seen people going “this game feels like it could hold a creepypasta meta secret, I sure hope it doesn’t”. I have bad news for you. We’ve got to talk about Chiffon Bola.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/feDbrKy.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/qwB17sA.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chiffon Bola was one of the first people to join the company. She was a game designer, a developer, a bit of a jock. She likes bikes. She thanked bike clubs in the special thanks of her games. Some time in 1988, she went missing, and was presumed dead.</p>

<p>https://imgur.com/MMvWEoK</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/MMvWEoK.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/mIe5mCg.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p0REdQZ.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Hints of her are still in the company, and any time you come across them, Greg averts his gaze. When he enters her old cubicle, he spells out I’m Sorry on the wall, and doesn’t elaborte or comment further. He doesn’t even say who’s cubicle it was, you just have to theorize. When he gets to her name in the company’s registry, he stops reading. He’s HAUNTED by Chiffon Bola. Later on, near the end, you run into a ghost of a floating bike helmet…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/f6YacfY.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The ghost blames Greg for what happened to her. Or Greg blames himself, more accurately. What happened? What happened to Chiffon Bola? Well, Greg has some theories…</p>

<p>Chiffon Bola very obviously chaffed against the new leadership as soon as they showed up. Everyone kind of did, but Chiffon seems to have been a rather independant woman, and would make her opinions known. In one of her games, Vainger, she shows the space station has being taken over by a malignant, insect-like force, who only wanted to save themselves, the universe be damned. In her cancelled game that you can find in her old cubicle, the cyberpunk RPG I mentioned, she deliberately calls the evil supervirus calling all the problems the Spinz/net.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0mZRZI8.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Chiffon Bola clearly chaffed against leadership, especially Spinzer, who is a raging meathead dinosaur, according to Greg. And Greg has some ideas as to what happened to her…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/O1xgJBS.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gPy0fhq.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jl5fb22.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W5qkxzQ.png" alt="Secrets" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>You can find several hints that her disappearance is foul play. A detective is snooping around. There are stains near the bike rack, now empty. There’s a shattered bike hidden in the vents. The only way into the vents is a ladder, which is in Spinzer’s office. One of Spinzer’s coats is missing a button, which can be found in the stairwell. You find photos being thrown away, and you quickly avert your gaze, as if you don’t want to see them. It’s never directly said or explained, but I think the implication is clear.</p>

<p>However, I should specify that all of this is MY interpretation. Someone else could easily have their own interpretations about the things going on here.</p>

<p>In the end, Greg has had enough. Everything that’s going on here is too much. He cannot be a party to this. After he finished Miasma Tower and UFO50, no matter what happens, he’s done. You end the game by taking the Nemuru’s chopper and flying away into the sunset. I don’t think Greg LITERALLY stole their chopper, I think it’s just a metaphor. He’s moving on to different pastures.</p>

<p>And that’s Miasma Tower.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="Reviews" /><category term="UFO50" /><category term="Reviews" /><category term="Modern Games" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>