<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-25T13:05:50-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 80</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/25/OOCY80.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 80" /><published>2024-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/25/OOCY80</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/25/OOCY80.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UKBk9bm.png" alt="&quot;It's Christmas! I bet you got a present or two for your girlfriend!&quot; &quot;You sound like you're shaking me down. Here. Were you not expecting something for a loser like you?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Murry Chrystler, happy Hondadays, and happy Life Day.</p>

<p>May you have a very yuri chrimmus.</p>

<p>source: Yuri Christmas</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuri Christmas" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 135 - Dragon Quest 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/25/RA135-DQ3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 135 - Dragon Quest 3" /><published>2024-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/25/RA135-DQ3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/25/RA135-DQ3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Yq1guQ7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So I’ve played Dragon Quest 1 many, many times. I DID pick up and look at DQ2, 3, and 4 a few times, but I never got super into them. That finally changed recently, with me finishing Dragon Quest 2, and now 3. And of all of them, DQ3 was the one that interested me the most, for all these years, for several reasons.</p>

<p>First, this game is a HUGE upgrade from DQ1 and 2 in so many ways. DQ1 was a large game for its time, with a giant sprawling world you had to explore, with many towns and dungeons and caves. This was compounded in the sequel, which practically doubles the size of the world, gives you a ship, and allows you to explore around, INCLUDING on the old game’s world map. How can they match that for Dragon Quest 3? By doing it again. DQ3 is fucking HUGE. And its one of the first RPGs I can think of that does the bait and switch “Whoop, here’s a second world map!” twist at what you THINK is the end. Final Fantasy 3 KINDA did it, but it feels a bit less large than it does here. And in FF3, it’s like “oh we’re already out of places to explore, and we’re not even that far in the game. Oh snap, it’s a floating island!” In DQ3, you’re told to fight Satan, you go on a LOT of adventures through this GIANT map, kill Satan, then learn OH SHIT THERE’S SATAN 2, THE BOSS OF SATAN, GO TO HIS WORLD, ANOTHER GIANT WORLD MAP, TO STOP HIM. That’s nuts. For this era, that is NUTS.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/XwxJpPc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The second thing that interested me as a kid, and still today, is the game’s party system. In DQ1, you had one character. In 2, you had three characters who were all like, characters. In this one, you name your hero, and then get to build a party out of randos at the local bar. They each have their own classes, so you can build a team of 3 randos that you name and concept, from about 6 classes. That’s pretty rad, and creates cool replayability value. And especially when you get reclassing later, so you can make soldiers with spells and stuff, if you wanted to. This game ALSO allows you to choose the GENDER of your characters. Which is absolutely stunningly ahead of its time. Confusingly though, the dialogue does NOT change if you make your main character a girl.</p>

<p>If you’re female, every character refers to you as a man. Except for two. There’s a kid who’s like “Hey, you’re the legendary hero! Wait, you’re a girl!” and then your dad who finds you in the final dungeon, and doesn’t recognize you, telling you to go to his daughter in your hometown, and let her know of his passing. This implies to me that your main character is, in fact, cross dressing. Which is fucking hilarious. Only your mom, dad, and some random kid notice. Mulana the RPG. It’s never really explained though, so it feels confusing when you first pick it up, like “But I chose girl though…”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aOUr9mq.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Other than that, it is Dragon Quest, though it feels a lot more concise and… dare I say, pleasant this time around. Yes, there’s still grinding, but all of the puzzles and dungeons and things you do feel better telegraphed than hearing one dude in a random town go “Oh there’s one tile in a swamp you need to check, good luck”. And like I said, it’s huge. Hyuuuuuuggggeee. This game blew me away, honestly.</p>

<p>The story is also exciting and fun for an NES RPG, especially as a fan of DQ1 and 2. It looks like it’s disconnected at first, with a completely new world map. But then with that plot twist you find out this is a PREQUEL, as you go to Alefgard, the location of the first game, and see how different it was hundreds of years prior.</p>

<p>One other fun thing about the game though, is that I played this not long after the Switch remake, and I was finding it difficult to find good information online about the original. Also, what the hell is with new Dragon Quest’s magic translation? The ice spells are Crack now? WTF does Kazam and Kafrizzle do?? Or how about Swooshmurta? Yeah, I know people shit post about the NES DQ translations, but I actually kinda prefer it. ESPECIALLY because, in your world, the first world map, everyone talks… normally. It’s only in the fantasy Alefgard world that they speaketh liketh thiseth. It’s also really kinda neat, cause in Dragon Quest 1, when you find the tablet from Erdrick, it DOESN’T speak like that. There’s a reason. Erdrick was from a world where they just… don’t speak like that. That’s a cute detail.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jl1IzRw.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>DQ3 is by far the stand out of the Erdrick trilogy, and a shining jewel of an RPG on the console. It can be mean, very mean, with some of its bosses, and I DID need to grind to stand a chance at the end, but I didn’t really mind much. A very fun time I’d recommend.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Dragon Quest" /><category term="RPG" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 79</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/24/OOCY79.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 79" /><published>2024-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/24/OOCY79</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/24/OOCY79.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LK8LZVQ.png" alt="&quot;All of this, it really is just some game to you.&quot; While kabadoning a girl who looks like she is having a LOT of fun." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>She is VERY into this game, it looks like</p>

<p>source: Nevermore</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Nevermore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 78</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/23/OOCY78.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 78" /><published>2024-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/23/OOCY78</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/23/OOCY78.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ki1Utoe.png" alt="&quot;What about you? What color is your tongue? Hey, if we combine them, what color do you think it'll make...?&quot; leans in for a kiss." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Purple</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Purple" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 77</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 77" /><published>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q9BSf8s.png" alt="&quot;I ... I like... you...&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IMvfNDG.png" alt="&quot;You finally did it.&quot; &quot;I- I like you...&quot; &quot;I like you too.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sunday 13.00</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sunday 13.00" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 134 - Zelda 2 The Adventure of Link</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 134 - Zelda 2 The Adventure of Link" /><published>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gumj4Aj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When I was really young, we had two Zelda games. We had Link’s Awakening, and we had this, Zelda 2. So a lot of my love of this is nostalgia. I’ve been playing this game since I was 2. But I think even if I played it today, I’d love it. Zelda 2 is a very controversial title, but is in my opinion one of the absolute best Zeldas, and it gets a bad wrap. I’ve lived my life on the internet, and the common pervailing idea around this game for YEARS was that it blows. These same people suck the dick of Dark Souls, but Zelda 2 is bad. Because it’s hard. They are very, VERY wrong. Zelda 2 whips. It whips so hard I mastered it, which involved me playing this game FOUR FUCKING TIMES. And I had a great time doing it!!</p>

<p>Zelda 2 is maybe the POSTER CHILD for my “NES Sequel Syndrome”. Games from that era that were sequels to a popular game that’d continue on with an amazing series, but the second game is different and weird compared to the others. I’m talking games like SMB2, Final Fantasy 2, Metroid 2 I guess, and this. The absolute poster child. Conceptually, if I explain what this game is out loud, it sounds very similar to Zelda 1. You play a little elf boy who travels around an over world fighting monsters. You explore this overworld and find dungeons, which contain an item that will help you progress further. Go through all the dungeons, go to the final dungeon, beat a boss. That’s just Zelda 1, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1V131xK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Well no, obviously. There’s a lot I didn’t mention. Zelda 2 has towns you can explore to heal up, cause there’s no health drops. Zelda 2 has magic spells you get from these towns, which can be used to do things like shield you or heal you. Zelda 2 has no money or shops. Zelda 2 has EXP, which upgrades one of your three stats, Health, Magic, or Attack. And most notably, Zelda 2 is not a top down action RPG, it is a side scrolling action RPG. You walk back and forth, jumping and ducking and stabbing with your dinky little sword. This has some VERY deep combat in places, frankly, I like it more than the Zelda 1 combat, by a large, large margin. Combat in Zelda 1 is a little… hokey and awkward at times. Fighting randomly moving enemies like Darknuts or the Wizzrobes blooooows. Here, the enemies have patterns you learn, and it’s like a beautiful dance with each one, that’s so rewarding. It feelS SO good once you can take on darknuts flawlessly. Or hell, the Dairas. GOD the Dairas.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/l8DUKvc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The world of Zelda 2 is pretty expansive, with a big-ass overworld to explore. Lots of little caves to go into and get EXP or heart containers, or items to unlock magic spells. And while some people might claim this game is bad because it’s so obtuse, this game isn’t Castlevania 2. All the people in towns give good hints. And nothing is SO obscure that you’ll get lost. Shit, it’s WAY less obtuse than fucking Zelda 1, which people still love to death. That god damn 8th dungeon bush? Burning EVERY BUSH to find entrances??? Zelda 2 has none of that. The most obscure thing here is the forest town you gotta find by breaking down trees with your hammer, but there ARE hints for that.</p>

<p>The other reason people hate this is cause of its difficulty. And yes, it’s hard. It’s a hard mother fucker. Like, I can practically play this game blindfolded now, but its HARD. Death Mountain is a cakewalk to me, but to your average joe, it is a WALL, a brick wall you must beat down with your face. I acknowledge this. I realize that I am biased. But that feeling of satisfaction when you beat it! Also, it never feels UNFAIR hard. Like, you’ve gotta learn the patterns, you’ve gotta perservere. You never need to grind, you can push through and make it. Though the option IS there if you want it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cmo3ltz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Frankly, Zelda 2 is a masterpiece, and I cannot praise it enough. It saddens me that Nintendo decided to never return to this style again, though to be fair, so many other games picked up the slack and did their hand at it quite well. Shout outs to Monster World 4. While they’ve never returned to this style, they certainly don’t seem ashamed of Zelda 2, and they haven’t forgotten it. Ocarina of Time brings some enemies back and re-uses the names of the towns for the sages. And of course you can play it in any Nintendo online service from the past 17 years.</p>

<p>So if I love this game so much, why did it take me this long to play it for Retro Achievements? It didn’t. I beat this game a year ago, securing the beat. …But not the mastery. This is a series on the MASTERIES of a game, where I 100% the achievement set for it. And the achievement set for this game required me to play it multiple times. Technically I COULD have mastered it in maybe two playthroughs, but I wasn’t going to do a candleless 1cc with no heal or shield spell on a 1st quest, so I had to split everything up into four playthroughs.</p>

<p>So yeah, I played this game MULTIPLE times this year. And you’ll find out soon, even more than that. It’s not too long, I can breeze through it in two hours, and it’s a fun two hours the entire time. Absolutely fantastic game. If you’ve never checked it out due to its reputation, give it a chance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Zelda" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 76</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 76" /><published>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WuMHUBp.png" alt="&quot;What does it mean to love someone romantically?&quot; &quot;You're interested in even the smallest things about them... in finding a side you haven't seen yet... if you realize this, it means you like them more than a friend!&quot; &quot;NOPE!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tnznnB7.png" alt="&quot;The very first thing you like about your romantic love is their face, right?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: In a Home Where Lilies Bloom</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="In a Home Where Lilies Bloom" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 75</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 75" /><published>2024-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zjk0wG1.png" alt="&quot;I bumped into the tank today because I was thinking about you...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, since this is a repost, there’s also a very funny reaction and response I now need to share about this post…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/d194RA3.png" alt="&quot;Wow what a cute and sweet panel, I wonder what happens next in this manga.&quot; &quot;HARDCORE GAY LESBIAN SEX.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Higher the Breakwater, the Quicker it is to Crumble</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Higher the Breakwater the Quicker it is to Crumble" /><category term="NSFW source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 74</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 74" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RelCIYl.png" alt="&quot;Look at me as much as you like. Like me more and more. And if you blush, use that blush to dye me red too.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Fall for me and dye me red</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Fall for me and dye me red" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 133 - Fire n’ Ice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 133 - Fire n’ Ice" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZgfxJ8B.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I love how god awful this cover is. What the hell is this. This is supposed to make me buy your game? No wonder this sold poorly here.</p>

<p>So I was watching a friend, Mister Radon, play some games, and someone made him play this for a bit. I was like “WOAH. THIS LOOKS LIKE IT’S EXACTLY MY JAM WHY HAVE I NEVER SEEN THIS”? So I played it the following day and DEVOURED it.</p>

<p>Fire n’ Ice is the sequel to classic Tecmo title “Solomon’s Key”. Known in Japan specifically as Solomon’s Key 2, it’s actually a prequel, showing the first adventure of the great wizard DANA! An evil fire wizard is attacking the peaceful ice island, and Dana has been chosen by the fairies who rule the island to stop him!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wdEBJiR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a single screen puzzle game. You get into a level, and then your goal is simple. Push ice onto the fire. Once all the fire is gone, you move onto the next level! Complete all 100 levels and you’re good! You can push ice, or climb up on it if it’s already up against something else. You can also create ice, but ONLY down and diagonal from you. So it can be pretty difficult to go upwards, you need to prepare ahead of time if you want to climb back up. But using these tools, you can get through all the puzzles, creating ice blocks, then clearing the way so you can push them onto the fires.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zkVpAS7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s really rewarding, and honestly, AMAZING for the NES? It’s a late NES game, but honestly it feels more like an itch.io puzzle game, or a modern NES homebrew. The animations are fantastic. Dana has a lot of personality, like his little shimmy when he’s up under a ceiling (or ice block). The fire is constantly wiggin’ out, and the music is really chill and fun. And every now and then you get a BOSS LEVEL, which is a screen that’s constantly scrolling and looping, which makes for some interesting gameplay, cause you often need to build a way up, but without blocking yourself on the second loop.</p>

<p>After you beat the 100 levels and the final boss, you can sit through the credits and get a code to unlock 50 more bonus levels. This game has SO MUCH CONTENT. It is CHOCK FULL of puzzles, and there’s really no stinkers in here! There were no puzzles I played and went “wow that fucking blew?” They can be challenging, but very rewarding to push through.</p>

<p>All in all, this is a FANTASTIC NES game, that frankly more people should know about. I HIGHLY recommend it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Fire n Ice" /><category term="Solomon&apos;s Key" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>