<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-05T12:32:03-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 132</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 132" /><published>2025-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/05/OOCY132.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DkqsVPA.png" alt="'Know what you wanna be after you graduate?' 'Yep. Your wife.' 'Huh?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Misread It as Love!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Misread It as Love!" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 131</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 131" /><published>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/04/OOCY131.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9hmh7Vy.png" alt="'I love my failures the same as my successes. And I'll love your failures as well'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Curtain Call for You</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Curtain Call for You" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Blazing Dragons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 167 - Blazing Dragons" /><published>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/04/RA167-BDragons.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9M9Rq3m.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is Blazing Dragons, a point and click adventure developed by Illusions Gaming Company, who mostly made point and click games you might vaguely remember based on prior properties like the Genesis Scooby Doo game, or the windows Beevis and Butthead games. It was published by Crystal Dynamics, who actually still exists, and is pretty well known for Tomb Raider. Not so much this game. This is one of the more obscure games in their repitoire, another point and click adventure game based on a prior property. This time, it’s based on the TV show Blazing Dragons… kind of.</p>

<p>Blazing Dragons was a late 90s British cartoon made Terry Jones, of Monty Python fame. My THEORY is that this game was something entirely different, and then they connected it to the cartoon because they had Terry Jones on the project. It has some of the same characters, but the designs are COMPLETELY different and a lot of the characters are changed or missing. The most interesting change is the different designs. In the cartoon, they’re very bipedal dragons, typical cartoony dragon design. In the game, they’re all taurs, which is VERY interesting. I kinda like taurs. I just think they’re neat.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wVjoiyH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In the game, you play as Flicker, who starts the game as the royal inventor, I think. He’s a smartypants kinda socially unaware dork, but he has a romance thing with the princess of the realm, Princess Flame. Unfortunately, she’s set to be wed to the winner of the Knight Tournament, and Flicker isn’t a knight, much to her chagrin. So the goal of the game is to become a knight by helping the Knights of the Square table, as bumbling as they are. At the same time, the kingdom’s sworn enemy, King Geoffry the Human, is trying to take over the land with the help of his wizard Merl. They also have an evil dragon on the inside, the king’s advisor, who is not in the show. So you’ve gotta stop that too. Simple enough premise, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xtJI4GL.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The game is a rather traditional point and click of the time. You’ve got a cursor that changes actions, things like look, talk, grab, use. You wander around, interract with people, solve puzzles, and collect a bunch of items that you rub on other items. The game is, for the MOST part, filled with good puzzles, but there are a couple that completely confounded me with their leaps of logic. But, in clal, it was actually a rather well crafted game, puzzle wise.</p>

<p>The big thing about the game is its writing and star cast, though. First of all, the cast is wild. Terry Kones, Cheech Marin, Jim Cummings, Rob Paulsen, Jess Harnel, it’s an all star cast, and they all do a good job. There’s ONE problem I’ll talk about later with the voice acting, though. The other thing is its writing. It’s very, VERY Monty Python. Makes sense, with Terry Jones being there. It’s a comedy that does not take itself seriously, with outrageous goofy setups and even goofier characters. It’s also very, VERY British in that way. If you can’t stand British comedy, maybe stay away. I DO like British comedy, except for oooone thing that this game is very bad at.</p>

<p>British Comedy does this thing where if there’s a female character, there’s like a 90% chance it’ll be played by a guy doing the most awful shrill cockney voice you’ve ever heard in your fucking life. British comedians playing women have ONE voice, and they really, REALLY love to whip it out at any god damn opportunity, and I HATE that voice, it’s AWFUL on my ears. This game is lousy with that voice. They got Jess Harnel to play like, one character, and then every other woman in the game is like “ELLO ELLO OIM A GOIYL”, clipping the fucking mic.</p>

<p>OTHER THAN THAT, THOUGH, the game is actually very good. Not too long or difficult, it’s well worth the time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Blazing Dragons" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Point and Click Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is Blazing Dragons, a point and click adventure developed by Illusions Gaming Company, who mostly made point and click games you might vaguely remember based on prior properties like the Genesis Scooby Doo game, or the windows Beevis and Butthead games. It was published by Crystal Dynamics, who actually still exists, and is pretty well known for Tomb Raider. Not so much this game. This is one of the more obscure games in their repitoire, another point and click adventure game based on a prior property. This time, it’s based on the TV show Blazing Dragons… kind of.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 130</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 130" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/02/OOCY130.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I6BjMEl.png" alt="'Well, can't be all bad, if it means I get to flirt with you...' *slides in for a kiss* suddenly in a crowd 'LOOK AROUND YOU.' 'Yep.'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Itazura Privacy</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Itazura Privacy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 166 - Tryrush Deppy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA166-Tryrush.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 166 - Tryrush Deppy" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA166-Tryrush</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA166-Tryrush.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/sBKoZTA.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is another set that I personally made, which also means it’s a set of a game I really care about, and have also already reviewed for my obscure games series I did. So I don’t need to go over it again. But there’s a few things I can add! I had to do a BIG deep dive into Deppy to figure stuff out about it. It has a lot of hidden stuff in it I never really tackled until making this set. BTW this set’s RAM is fucked. This was an AGONIZING experience to code for.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dCWvwsX.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So, Tryrush Deppy is a platformer where you play as a cute taxi cab racing across America. The thing about Deppy is that it has a lot of hidden stuff to find in each level, but the game doesn’t make it very easy or rewarding to explore a level. Usually when I play, I just try and play fast and clean to get through each level. But there are three collectables: Dramas, Stars, and Extra Stages. Each level has a Drama, some specific levels have Dramas, and each world has an Extra Stage. Stars are special mini stages where you need to get through a small puzzle room cleanly while getting all the purple stars in them. Dramas are saving different characters in a level, which can also change future level layouts and stuff. And finally, extra stages are bullshit.</p>

<p>Extra stages are hidden fake walls you can jump into by pressing up. These are USUALLY in like, billboards and things, but there’s no indication you can do this. You then get an extra bonus stage to run through, with weird-ass dog cars that bark and bite at you, and usually a mini gimmick. And if you clear the stage, nothing happens. Instead, you need to find the fake wall in the middle of the fucking level, break it, and then destroy the enemy that pops out.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jLtfWDi.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Getting different combinations of collectables gives you different endings. No one knows how to get one of the endings, namely this one with the weird omake cutscenes by the author. Once you beat the game with all the extra modes, you ALSO get a time attack mode with the extra stages, getting through them as fast as possible. The times o</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Saturn" /><category term="Tryrush Deppy" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is another set that I personally made, which also means it’s a set of a game I really care about, and have also already reviewed for my obscure games series I did. So I don’t need to go over it again. But there’s a few things I can add! I had to do a BIG deep dive into Deppy to figure stuff out about it. It has a lot of hidden stuff in it I never really tackled until making this set. BTW this set’s RAM is fucked. This was an AGONIZING experience to code for.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 165 - Shining Force Gaiden</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA165-SFGaiden1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 165 - Shining Force Gaiden" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA165-SFGaiden1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/04/01/RA165-SFGaiden1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JxxIbas.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>My goal this year is to play all the main, early Shining games. I finished Shining in the Darkness, now it’s time for the Shining Force games! Though for some reason I started with this one.</p>

<p>This is Shining Force Gaiden, the side story game for the Sega Game Gear, Sega’s handheld console of the time. It’s made by the same team as the Genesis one, and came out exclusively in Japan about 8 months after Shining Force did. And it is an EXTREMELY impressive attempt, to me, to translate Shining Force to a Game Gear.</p>

<p>This is also the only Shining game I can think of that’s NEVER been translated. Kind of. This game, and Shining Force Gaiden 2, it’s sequel, would later be repackaged on the Sega CD, which DID come out over here. And Gaiden 2 came out over here, but Gaiden 1? Well, fan translators decided it didn’t need to be translated, I guess, cause we already have Shining Force CD.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vkAEmux.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>SFG is a sequel to Shining Force, very directly. Taking place about 20 years after the first game, you play as the forces of Guardiana, many of which are the children of the heroes from the first game. Queen Anri is attacked by an evil wizard claiming dark powers over some evil God, and you all need to go defeat him so she wakes from her magical slumber. Or something. Look, it’s in Japanese, and it’s been a long time since I played SFCD. I didn’t follow the plot very well.</p>

<p>This game translated nearly everything from SF1 perfectly. Well, in terms of the main game bones. All the exploration of towns, hidden secrets you can find exploring maps after defeating them, and conversing with people? That’s pretty much stripped out. It’s a LOT more Fire Emblem now, with you going from one battle to another, strung together by cutscenes. And that’s perfectly fine! I didn’t dislike the exploration in SF1, of course, but it’s still a fun strategy RPG without it, IMO.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2hFJznU.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>One thing I need to compliment Gaiden for is its fantastic graphics. This game looks amazing. It’s a very, VERY solid recreation of what the Genesis had for Shining Force 1, on an 8-bit handheld.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zybtYWa.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I think a lot of it is just that I really, really love the early Shining Force art style? It looks fantastic, and is translated amazingly here. Take the Narrator Girl for this game. Look at her! She’s so cute! And that usual Shining Force Character Design is here all the way through. Yes, your character of Prince Nick is pretty generic SF hero energy, but you’ve got all the centaurs, bird people, and of course Gyan/Teddy, who’s like a big tiger bear with a badass eyepatch.</p>

<p>Anyways yes, all this boiled down, it’s more Shining Force. It’s actually quite easy, though, IMO. I had some troubles with Shining Force 1 when I played it years ago, and Shining Force Gaiden 2 legitimately kicked my ass, I’ll get to that, but Gaiden 1 was easy. I didn’t use any stat boosting items or rings I found, cause it’s entirely in Japanese, and even WITH that I had absolutely no trouble whatsoever with this game, your characters are just in general very strong.</p>

<p>Even with all this, I’d prolly just recommend Shining Force CD, though note that SFCD is TWO games in one, and it feels like it. It’s long. It’s a trek. SFG is a bit more short and pleasant. It’d be great for car rides, tbh.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Game Gear" /><category term="Shining" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My goal this year is to play all the main, early Shining games. I finished Shining in the Darkness, now it’s time for the Shining Force games! Though for some reason I started with this one.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 129</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/01/OOCY129.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 129" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/01/OOCY129</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/04/01/OOCY129.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/idnMc3u.png" alt="'So this is what it feels like when dreams come true' says a woman on a bed, as she's surrounded by all the symbols of homosexuality" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Childhood Sweetheart Liaoliao" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 20-25</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekDS97-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - DS9 Season 7, Episodes 20-25" /><published>2025-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekDS97-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekDS97-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Vf2hKzS.gif" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>When It Rains…</strong> - DS9
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1jTJeuz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things are rough. It’s pouring, pretty hard. The Breen have an energy dampening weapon that fucks up ALL the allied Fleets. They do have one plan, though. ONE Klingon ship was able to defend against it, cause the engineer had just done some Tech Babbelry with his engines. Unfortunately, ONLY Klingon ships can do this, so the rest of the fleet is fucked. This means the Klingons are rushing to stop an advancement, all by themselves. Meanwhile, Damar’s rebellion is already going poorly. Their first push failed, and they’re in hiding. They need help, an expert at murdering occupiers. Luckily, we got one of those!</p>

<p>This just in, worst person you know has a point. Kai Winn is working with Dukat, sure, but it’s mostly out of neccesity and to keep power, NOT because she likes her. Yes, they fucked, but holy HELL that was before she knew who he was, GET YOUR HANDS OFF ME. Their alliance is currently very strenuous.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DVG5u23.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Cardassians do need the help, but the idea of a Bajoran helping them disgusts them. They’re a proud people. Damar doesn’t give a shit. He literally said “I did hate her, but that’s a luxary I can no longer afford”. He’s come a LONG way. His people though, they’re not quite there yet. So they do what they can to make her less threatening and not remind them that they’re being helped by Bajor: They give her a commission and make her official part of Star Fleet. Odo, Kira, and Garak head off to help.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Bashir is working on a passion project where he wants to make replicatable stem-cell-ish organs. To do that, he borrows some of Odo’s goo. He literally says “I need to borrow some Goo”. He also has a lot of weird shit with Dax. Bashir is really regressing, IMO. He’s not season 1 bad, that was very VERY bad. Like, AWFUL, I HATED Season 1 Bashir more than any other character in Star Trek, but he’s pretty rough. He’s smiling weirdly, like when he’s telling Odo that he’s infected with the disease that’s killing his people, he’s smiling so weirdly. And he’s all super horny about Dax and it’s so uncomfortable.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PbHL3zR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Gowron is visiting the station. This episode has a lot of plot points. This is like, the D Plot. He’s here to award a big honor to Martok, and puts all that shit with Worf under the bridge. Looks like he’s FINALLY coming to. Unfortunately, he ALSO takes Martok’s power and station away from him, putting himself in the position as leading the war forces. Ahhh, he’s a glory hound.</p>

<p>Bashir tries to get some of Odo’s medical records to cure him of the disease he has. Starfleet refuses to give them over, and when Bashir calls up to ask why, they basically accuse him of colluding with the enemy and working to cure them. I can smell what’s happening here a mile away. Luckily, Sisko has clearance for the file, so he gets it. Aaaand then Bashir can tell, immediately. It’s a fake. It’s not Odo’s real file. They immediately come to an assumption. It’s the work of Section 31, they’re trying to stop Bashir from curing them, even if it means Odo’s death.</p>

<p>Oh btw, Gul Dukat tries to read The Necronomicon and gets his sight taken from him because he’s not Satan Pope. I’m actually surprised, the Pah Wraiths are ACTUALLY treating Kai Winn like she matters. And now that Gul Dukat is blind, AND not in the good graces of the Pah Wraiths, she’s throwing him out on the streets as a blind beggar. Maybe eventually they’ll find pity on him and restore his sight. God, if you can’t trust THE ANTI-POPE.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6doNaRn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Gowron has a strategy to win this war. He’ll surprise the Dominion with an astonishingly bad strategy. He’s going to throw all of the reserves at them, while the Federation and Romulans are out for the count. THey can barely hold the line NOW, but a full on attack? That’s GENIUS!</p>

<p>Bashir uses some shenanigans to find out when Odo was infected, and finds out it was three years ago, far before he joined with the Female Shapeshifter, and was in fact the day Odo was tested by Starfleet Medical. Section 31 infected Odo to use him as a carrier to infect the Changelings and genocide their entire race. Fucking Christ.</p>

<p>And it ends like that. This episode is fine, but it has its hands in too many pies. It’s trying to wrap up every plot line, and it’s a bit disjointed.</p>

<p><strong>Tacking into the Wind</strong> - DS9
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/adIsR6z.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Cardassians are very bad at terrorism. They’re good at being a military. But this is not a military. They’re bad at whatever THIS is supposed to be. Even when they succeed, they fail, basically.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jd4e1xx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile Odo is falling apart. He’s deteriorating VERY fast now. Garak finds him like this, and it’s heart wrenching, but he doesn’t want anyone to know about it, and he wants no pity. He ESPECIALLY doesn’t want Kira to know about it, and he fully intends to keep doing his job as long as he can. He won’t just sit there and die.</p>

<p>Gowron’s stupid-ass plans were stupid. Martok was nearly killed. Worf is certain it was a plan by Gowron to get Martok either killed, or dishonored. Martok is VERY popular, and Gowron is trying to politik basically. Worf wants Martok to challenge Gowron to become the Chancellor. Martok is like “What the fuck no. I’m a soldier. I don’t want to do that.”</p>

<p>Damar’s family is killed. He’s floored by it. They were innocents. They weren’t in the rebellion, and the Dominion knew that. What kind of government would murder innocents just to break the hearts of its people? What kind of person could GIVE that order?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/i5cO3t8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is one of the best lines in DS9. Fucking Christ. Her delivery of this is FANTASTIC. It’s soft, it’s sad.</p>

<p>They go on a mission. Kira pretends to be a prisoner. Odo was the handcuffs, take a drink. The Female changeling then comes in and grabs one of their guns to inspect it, and hands it to Garak to “inspect it”. He immediatley starts blasting. God, I love Garak. Also, Odo was the uh, Changeling, take a drink.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TewgNr2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We finally get the culmination of TEN YEARS of Star Trek plot. Gowron is still being a politiking dufus. Worf calls him out, and then Gowron challenges him to murderizing. It uh, doesn’t go well for Gowron. He is, in fact, just a politician, not much of a warrior. And thus, Worf is now the leader… for ten seconds.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Z2HS4YW.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Martok doesn’t want to lead. That’s why he should.</p>

<p>Damar’s friend, and second in command of the rebellion, turns on Kira cause he’s a racist who hates her. It becomes a standoff. “Garak, you wouldn’t shoot me, a Cardassian, for a Bajoran woman?!” “Oh how little you understand me.” Damar then joins the standoff, telling them BOTH to stand the fuck down. Notably, Damar this episode? Been doing his best. He’s swallowed his pride. He’s swallowed his sadness. He’s here to do one thing. And that’s help his people. He’s done doing anything else. Even when Kira snapped back at him, he didn’t raise his voice. And now? When his long time friend tells him to kill both Garak, AND Kira, so that they can bring the Empire back to the glory it once was?</p>

<p>He shoots him. That Empire is gone. And it isn’t coming back.</p>

<p>The Damar Stans are WINNING, y’all.</p>

<p>Fun episode, lots of good scenes.</p>

<p><strong>Extreme Measures</strong> - DS9
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TrRBrav.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Odo’s lookin’ like shit. He’s taking this WAY worse than the Female Changeling. He looks GROSS. Bashir gives him one week to live, maybe two, if we’re lucky. Odo isn’t giving up, but he’s practically given up. Kira wants to stay by him, but he tells her to get the hell out. He’s being a bit selfish. They have a heart to heart and kiss and tell each other they love each other. It’s cute, and sad.</p>

<p>Sisko is FINALLY brought into the loop about all of this stuff. So you see, they plan to lure an operative here by lying about a cure being found. Bashir didn’t want to tell Sisko, cause Sisko would tell Starfleet, cause that’s his job, and then Section 31 would get win of it and go deeper into hiding. Plus, Bashir is using an illegal Romulan mind scanner. So uh, fighting illegal with illegal here. Hey, we do what we can.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5qv7Fzx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Sloan does his thing he does, sitting in Bashir’s room as Bashir sleeps, like a dickhead. This time Bashir is ready for him. He traps him in a forcefield, and then shoots him. When he wakes up, he finds himself on a table with O’Brien and Bashir looking down on him. He tries to reason with them, but no, they have him dead to rights, and with that scanner, he’s fucked. Soooo he chews a tablet and kills himself. It scrambles his brain too, so they can’t just scan it.</p>

<p>Also that quote is SO deliciously ironic.</p>

<p>Bashir keeps him alive, just barely. He’ll die in an hour, but they can’t just scan his brain, it’s jumbled. So Bashir rigs up a scientific thingamajig, and allows him to dive into his dreams so that they can MAYBE find the cure before he dies. Yep, it’s a DREAM DIVE EPISODE! O’Brien comes too. It’s nice to see him having something to do.</p>

<p>While in Sloan’s Brain Meats, they meet Sloan. He’s friendly, and very helpful. Well, he WANTS to be, but he can’t. When he tries to tell them the cure, it comes out all jumbled. And then he’s shot by Evil Sloan, who runs off. Yep, one of those. O’Brien and Bashir then get shot by a part of his psyche, who’s “protecting the Federation”, and we get one of the WEIRDEST scenes I’ve ever seen in all of Star Trek, where Bashir basically just tells O’Brien he loves him, cause they both think they’re going to die. It’s really weird.</p>

<p>And then they’re woken up by Sisko and Worf and some doctors. And then they watch Sloan die. And with him, any hopes of a cure. As Bashir lies down, depressed, ready to read his evening book, he finds that his copy of A Tale of Two Cities is… weird. He’s still in the dream.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HYB05tT.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Bashir and O’Brien makes their way to the depths of Sloan’s mind, and find him, and all his files on Section 31. They find the cure, but also so, SO many other things. Sloan says that if they want to take down Section 31, there’s no better time than now, to gather data.. But… that’s what he wants. If he can keep Bashir in his mind, he’ll die and he’ll win. But O’Brien is there. And he realizes it. So he convinces Bashir, and they leave, and save Odo.</p>

<p>This episode was alright. Trying to be a sendoff to O’Brien and Bashir’s Bromance, but it’s just so weird.</p>

<p><strong>The Dogs of War</strong> - DS9
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/uzZ5IDf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Ezri and Bashir being awkward. If they DO get together, it’ll last like two years at most. And then they get a new ship. The Sao Paolo, a Defiant-class. But as they take it off the Admiral’s hands, he tells them they’re allowed to change the name, so they did. To “The Defiant”. Yep. The real IRL reason was so they could re-use Defiant footage, and that footage had The Defiant written on it. Very funny.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kira, Damar, and Garak go to Cardassia to try and get some high ranking Cardassian military to join their side. Unfortunately, one of the ones who was going to help them immediately betrays them, and they’re stranded on the planet. They only have ONE place they can hide. Garak’s old home, with his old nanny. The LAST person on Cardassia he can trust.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NJwxec1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Meanwhile, Quark gets a message from the Grand Nagus. God, I’ve been thinking we need more Quark this season. The transmision is coming in spotty, though, and the Grand Nagus can barely hear Quark, though he tells him that he’s retiring, and coming to DS9 to announce his successor. Why, it’ll be HIM! Congratulations… Then the message garbeled. Though the astute who have listened to a LOT of garbled messages, like me, might realize… he doesn’t say “Quark” at the end, but something else…</p>

<p>Quark immediately starts researching what happened in Ferenginar lately. And by that I mean, his new advisor, Brunt, kisses up to him and tells him what’s going on. He’s basically spouting right wing republican bullshit and saying “IT’S A DISEASE. CAN YOU BELIEVE THEY MADE MONOPOLIES ILLEGAL?! AND MADE IT SO I CAN’T DUMP TOXINS? I HAVE TO CARE ABOUT ANIMALS NOW?” Then he sells the bar to Rom for “only” 5000. He’s gone SOFT. He’s going to REFUSE the Nagus position, unless he can stop this POISON.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oaTbeU1.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Dominion announces Damar is dead, but he’s obviously not, AND he’s become a Town Hero. So they take it over the edge. He bombs a military installation, and announces to the world he’s still alive, and calls for revolution. Open, bound revolution.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/OjuZ5NI.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, this happens.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9s8P642.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Plot twist, it was never going to be Quark. Obviously. Who the hell wants him to be Nagus??? Rom is going to be the new Nagus. Quark throws a hissy fit, but eventually comes to it. And yep. Rom deserves this. A great conclusion to one of the unsung best characters in all of DS9</p>

<p>Oh hey, Sisko’s wife is gregnant. We never DID find out what the Prophets were warning about with that. I dunno what’s funnier, that the prophets couldn’t judge the severity of a situation, or that it really was the pepper plant.</p>

<p><strong>What You Leave Behind</strong> - DS9
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ozEwD1X.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We have everyone’s reactions to having to Battle of the Bulge the Dominion. Ezri and Bashir make out, to all of our collective groans. O’Brien is talking about retiring to teach at a university after the war ends. He’s ALSO not talked about it to Bashir, his Husband, which is Bad. I love that they tried to make Bashir less gay by seperating him from Garak and getting him a girlfriend, but then just made him MORE gay with all the subtext with Bashir and O’Brien.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, on Cardassia, everyone is awaiting the fleet patiently, but nervously. We have Cardassian Quisling, who’s Damar’s replacement to work with the Dominion. He’s doing his best. He has no respect. Just like a Quisling. Unfortunately, they are NOT happy cause of all the citizens rising up and attacking Dominion installations. Sooooo they retaliated. First they strangled the Quisling a bit, and theeen.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yDHrCyc.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone is ENRAGED. It’s time to strike back, and hard. As Garak says, “Chop of a snake’s head and the body will die.” Unfortunately, the Jem’Hadar find them, kill Garak’s nanny, and fucking THROW HER CORPSE AT THEM with a GERNADE ALONGSIDE IT. Poor Garak is NOT doing well. They’re all captured and to be IMMEDIATELY executed. Unfortunately for THEM, they’re IMMEDIATLEY shot in the back by their Cardassian allies, who go “THat’s for the city you blew up”. WOW. I CAN’T BELIEVE THAT TACTIC FAILED!! And then the Cardassian ships turn traitor and start attacking the Dominion ships, turning tides of battle.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/PkLKCDV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Female Changeling calls for a Cardassian genocide. Starting with their Quisling. Wow, what a fucking surprise.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Kai Winn and Ducat reawaken the Fire Caves. Oh yeah that plot is happening! That feels a little out of context for everything ELSE thats happening, but it’s fine.</p>

<p>In the attack on the Dominion HQ, Damar is killed. His last order… Keep. Don’t give in. NEVER give in. Rest in peace, Damar. Genuinely NEVER seen a better turn around for a character than Damar. A nameless extra in the background of a villain, to a horrible hated villain, to a funny comedic villain drunkard, to someone you GENUINELY FEEL FOR. He wasn’t perfect, at all. He was awful. But he could have been better, and he was genuinely trying to be by the end.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tfGSfpz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Wow we’re killin people left and right! That was the last Weyoun clone. He’s gone for good. Odo comes down and links with the Female changeling, and she IMMEDIATELY surrenders. The war is over. The war is done. She’ll stay and stand on trial, though. So who’s going to go cure the Great Link? Odo. It’s Odo. Odo is the going away, take a drink ):</p>

<p>We get a VERY good scene with Garak and Bashir, and a sendoff to our boy. The last time we see him. Ohh, Garak. “Spare me your Federation optimism. Yes, Cardassia will surive. But not the Cardassia I knew.” But it WILL become better.</p>

<p>We get the final story threads closing. Worf leaves to become an ambassador to Kronos. Goodbye, Worf. So, I kinda hated DS9 Worf?  But he’s been pretty good for the past 6 episodes. Much better as the sassy friend. Obrien is leaving Odo is leaving, Worf is leaving. We even get one last Vic Fontaine song! It’s a cute little sendoff to all of the main cast members. And that’s the end, a great send-off to-</p>

<p>Oh, yeah. We have one more thing. Sisko is suddenly like “Oh yeah, I now know what I need to do. But I WILL be back” and then he goes to the Fire Caves.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/L8ExRUU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kai Winn thinks she’s been chosen as the Emissary of the Pah Wraiths, but no, it’s Gul Dukat. Wow what a surprise, if you can’t trust something called THE PAH WRAITHS. Now Dukat is a super powered evil satan. Sisko is doing his best to act in this, but it’s a bit silly. And doesn’t feel very Trekky to me.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lIFkWO7.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kai Winn is burned by the Pah Wraiths, and then Sisko throws himself into the fire, pushing Dukat into it, who’s burned away like fucking Gollum, with his book. This seals the Pah Wraiths away again, but also “kills” Sisko. He’s still here, of course. He’s in a white void, and is told that he’s with them now.</p>

<p>THIS is what they built up for the past seven seasons, since episode 1. The Prophet storyline hasn’t been super interesting, tbh, all together. And here it doesn’t make the story BETTER, IMO. But it’s not THAT bad.</p>

<p>Sisko Prophet Warps into Casidy’s mind and tells her he WILL be back. Maybe in a year. Maybe yesterday. He still has things to do, but he WILL be back. This is one of the major things in the ending, Sisko was going to just Die, but his actor was like “Fuck that, I’m not gonna be a disappeared dad”. So he WILL be back.</p>

<p>Then we get a weird-ass clip show with Bashir and O’Brien? I do NOT get it. And then we get clip shows with EVERYONE. I…. I don’t like this. It’s weird clip shows of all the characters and their relationships over the past 7 seasons, with cheesy 60s violin music behind it. If you were gonna do this, do it during Vic’s song. The thing is, this is the LAST WE’LL SEE OF MOST OF THESE CHARACTERS. THEY WON’T COME BACK IN ANY FUTURE TREK SHOWS.</p>

<p>At least after this we get Quark and Odo being sassy at each other. Quark LITERALLY says “That man loves me”. MY SHIP IS CANON. Odo returns to the link, with one last kiss for Kira. She says she’ll never forget him. I think the implication is she won’t date after him, but I like to imagine that right now in the current canon, 20 years in the future, she has like 4 girlfriend. Her story ends with her looking at Sisko’s baseball on her new desk with a smile. And our entire story ends with Quark going “the more things change, the more they stay the same”, as Jake watches the Wormhole with Kira.</p>

<p>The first half of this episode, with the battles and the action was very good. The second half kinda flubbed it. It’s hard to end a series like this, but I think all of this stuff actually worked, FOR THE MOST PART. By this stuff I mean the past 9 episodes, which all move into each other and tie up the loose threads. But this ending with them breaking up the band, just for dramatic tension? Not a fan.</p>

<p>….And that’s DS9.</p>

<p><strong>Thoughts</strong></p>

<p>It’s my favorite Trek, other than SNW. Too many good episodes to name, and honestly? I don’t think I had a single 1/10 here? The closest was that fucking Worf Terrorist episode I gave a 1.5/10. I stand by that. ONLY because it gave us nearly naked Jadzia. Oh man, Jadzia. Look, this show had some of the best Trek characters, and not all of them were handled well. But when they hit, they hiiiiittttt.</p>

<p>A lot of people say DS9 is the best because it “shows a dark mirror to the Federation” or whatever the fuck. That it’s darker, edgier, more willing to show the wicked evils at the heart of Socialist Utopia Future. That’s not why I like it. I like it because it shows that stuff but also the optimism at the heart of it. I like DS9 because it’s designed SPECIFICALLY to show the underdogs, the citizens, the regular shmoes. You’d never get a Rom on TNG. You’d never see a Garak on TNG. DS9 also introduced a lot of good recurring villains! TNG had like… Lore? I think that’s it? But here, Gul Dukat is MOSTLY really good! I didn’t like how his story ended very much, but he was very good for like 90% of the show. Kai Winn was AWFUL, I love hating her. Damar. DAMAR. FUCKING DAMAR. NONE of these characters could be on TNG, and they certainly couldn’t be on Voyager. But they’re here, and the show is all the better for it.</p>

<p>Goodbye, DS9. I’ll miss you.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="DS9" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 20-27</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekVOY4-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 4 episodes 20-27" /><published>2025-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekVOY4-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/03/30/LizstartrekVOY4-5.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lEMFojx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Vis a Vis</strong> - VOY
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/pZiSY9u.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Paris is playing around in the Holodeck with his favorite past-time, muscle cars. It’s honestly pretty cute. I like a 24th century guy being a gearhead, it’s a fun hobby. The Doctor gets on his case about how he’s not putting enough effort into being the backup doctor, and he’s like “I didn’t even WANT to do that, I was assigned to it”. But it’s his job now, so, buh. The further we get in this show the more I like Paris. Anyways, Paris is then called to his station, so he has to arrive all covered in grease and shit which is funny, and he finds out why. There’s a weird-ass ship that’s zorping around. Paris guesses it’s a Coaxial Warp Drive, which literally folds space time around itself in order to travel real far real fast. That could be useful.</p>

<p>Too bad the warp core is exploding. Paris does some shenanigans to keep the ship from exploding, and all’s good. The alien needs some help getting his ship from exploding, so Paris volunteers, cause he’s interested in the ship’s drive. When he asks, Chokey is like “Well, you’ve had bad reports from the doctor about shirking your duties, are you okay?” and he’s like “Yes? I just don’t care about being a doctor”, and Chokey rides his ass for a minute before assigning him to work on the ship. But then he has to dip from THAT cause he had a date with Belanna. He’s late to it and she’s all pissy and angry at him, saying he’s hiding shit. Lady, he was ASSIGNED TO WORK ON THIS. What was he going to do, tell his superior officer no??</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LSHXfdm.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I can’t believe this show made me like Paris. I’m genuinely offended. And not only that, but it’s swapped how things were. At the start, Paris got away with a lot of bullshit, and we kept yelling at him, cause he was awful. Now, people are riding his ass and acting like he’s being awful and he’s genuinely not doing anything, just doing his job and living with his hobbies.</p>

<p>Now to be fair, Paris IS feeling that Wanderlust. He’s comfortable here, but that’s making him uneasy. He’s not USED to feeling comfortable, to being happy. So he’s kinda self sabotaging, slightly. That honestly makes a lot of sense. It doesn’t help that Steth, the alien, offers him an escape on his ship. I mean, they can go fly around and explore, and then can meet up with Voyager later! Unfortunately for Paris, Steth here has some Weird Shit going on with morphing and DNA forms and he keeps turning into a she and it’s weird. Either way, Paris gets caught up in it and gets his form stolen by this clearly fae creature, who then shoots him and takes his place on Yovager. His ship then speeds off, presumably with Paris’ corpse.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/I7wCo0V.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, Steth is very bad at being Tom. You’d think they’d like, actually REALLY research a person before trying to subsume their life. That seems weird.  Everyone is IMMEDIATELY sus of him because like, duh. He doesn’t even know where the fuck the Medbay is. It’s really awkward to watch. You’d think someone who’s entire life is this would be better at it. He ends up making out with Torres and then choking her out while drunk. It’s weird.</p>

<p>No, obviously, Real Paris isn’t dead. His drive has just been shut down, and he’s thrown at the people who ACTUALLY owned it, who are about to blow him up for stealing the drive. But before they can, another ship comes and scares them away, and the REAL Steth is here. Paris hastily explains whats going on.</p>

<p>Janeway confronts “Tom”, and the next thing we know, security is barging in and stuns Tom. Phew, the Doctor is safe. Real Tom and Real Steth come, and the captain is like “Okay, he’s probably the cause of all this. Hold him in a Hold on, I need to do a thing real quick”, and then dips the fuck out in a shuttle. Welp, he swapped with Janeway. But Tom convinces Chokie to let him go with a heart to heart, and he catches the DNA Swapper.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1gbfTJ2.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It ends with Tom trying to open up to Torres and they make out in his Camaro. He’s all “It’s a MINT CONDITION 1960 COMARO”. Tom, it’s a hologram. Come on man.</p>

<p><strong>The Omega Directive</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KoYnbib.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with Seven waking up and talking about what she’s going to do today. She’s gonna read The Christmas Carol, as suggested by the Doctor. That’s cute. Suddenly everything is interrupted by the ship dropping out of warp, and everyone is confused as an Omega symbol appears on all screens and they get locked out. Janeway is like “Hey, don’t worry. I’ll take care of it. but don’t tell ANYONE about this”. Sussy.</p>

<p>Turns out it’s sonething called The Omega Directive. Something called an Omega Particle has been detected. If that’s detected, the goal is to destroy it, at all costs. It’s very, VERY dangerous. Only Captains and above even know about it. All of the crew is curious, but not allowed to know… except one. Seven was Borg, and so she knows all the Borg knew. That includes what they learned from assimilated Starfleet captains. So she’s in on it. But she’s not interested in helping destroy the Omega Particle. She wants to harness it. The Borg think it’s possible, and ALMOST got it, but not quite. Sure it destroyed 23 Borg vessels in the attempt, but it’s worth attempting again! Oh Seven.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/M8erMDx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everyone has theories and fan theories. Everyone is reacting to it differently. Even Tuvok admits to being curious. That means he’s very, very, VERY curious.</p>

<p>Janeway explains to Chokie what’s going to happen. She and Seven are gonna go out in a specially reinforced shuttle with a giant bomb. Either they return happy and alive, or Voyager senses an explosion and has 10 seconds to get out or it’ll be vaporized. Chokie convinces her that this is a very special case, so she should explain to the crew what’s up. So she does. A single molecule of this stuff, when it was synthesized, existed for a second, before collapsing. The explosion killed all the scientists, but MORe important, destroyed Subspace. Warp travel is not possible in that sector anymore. Any more of this stuff could wipe out sub space in an entire quadrant, and that would be very, VERY bad.</p>

<p>Imagine that. The Federation not being able to use FTL travel. God, how horrible that’d be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nXIXBqs.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They make it to the source. A planet with a horribly damaged science facility. Subspace isn’t here, so they slowly get to it and find some survivors, who explain that they lost containment, but some of their experiment survived.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vd0eOS6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven speaks to the head scientist, who explains that this experiment is his people’s salvation. He’s disgusted by them wanting to blow it up.</p>

<p>Down on the planet, they find the Omega molecules. She’s ready to destroy it, and doesn’t even want to study it at all, even when it’s stable right now. Even as a woman as science, she feels like science has limits, and she knows when to quit. It’s just too dangeorous. That amount of Omega would straight up destroy half the quadrant. That is a LOT of space. It’s even enough to throw the Prime Directive out the window.</p>

<p>Seven tells Chokie she thinks she can stabalize the particles and save them. She BEGS Chakotay to let her. She still has some Borg Programming left, and the Borg basically worship Omega as a God. It’s a perfect molecule, a million parts working together as one. Like the Borg collective. It’s interesting that the Borg basically have a religion. When Chokie can’t convince Janeway, Seven tries ONE MORE time on Janeway. She could probably beat her in combat and do it if she wanted, but she won’t. She does understand why Janeway is doing this. THIS is a good Seven and Janeway clash!!! It makes WAY more sense that that shit last time. They both have a clash of personality and opinion where neither of them come off as a complete asshole! It’s great!</p>

<p>Seven manages to see a stabalized Omega for a few seconds, before they manage to throw it out and explode it. The episode ends with Janeway and Seven discussing religious experiences. This was a nice one.</p>

<p><strong>The Omega Directive</strong> - VOY
3.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dfh17AB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is caught between two cloaked ships fighting. It looks like one explodes, before they get an audio message that simple says “Chakotay, please, I need your help”. Fascinating start. Too bad it will CLEARLY involve Chakotay.</p>

<p>Her ship is falling apart, and for some reason they can’t beam her over, and so they beam over to help her. Chakotay saves her from some rubble, and she’s like “Ohhh Chakotay, I knew you’d come for me~” and he’s like “who the hell are you”? When they get her over to the ship, I guess they could beam her once Chakotay was with her, the Doctor’s scanners won’t work on her either. Her name is Kellin. She begs the captain to give her Asylum, because “they” are chasing her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/xCT1pAA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She explains to Chokie that her biology makes it so people forget her the next day. That’s just how her people are, the Ramurans. Some pheramone shenanigans. Apparently this also won’t let technology talk about her. Why they couldn’t just… write about her or talk about her on a log, I dunno. She claims it’s a virus that erased all data of her from the logs. And now her reason for being here is she fell in love with Chokie and gave up her life on her planet, which is VERY taboo on her planet. Honestly I believe the shit with the pheremones more than I believe someone falling in love with Chakotay after 2 weeks of being near him. Chakotay trusts her, for some reason. After all, he’s a VERY good judge of character. He doesn’t have any actual desire to continue any relationship with her. To him, it didn’t happen, he has no feelings.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/juW9Bzh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Some of her people come to take Kellin away, and she helps them detect the ships, so they can actually fight back. CHakotay keeps being flaky about whether he trusts her or not. At first he does, then he’s like “No, I don’t”, then he begs her not to go when she’s like “You’ll be in danger if I’m here and clearly you’re not into me”. God. I DO get Chakotay not trusting her, after all the Seska shit, but buh. Wait until the end when we find out she’s actually a Romulan spy.</p>

<p>We also learn what her previous job was. She was the person who hunted people who ran from the Homeworld, and used a memory wiper on them to make them forget the outside world so that they want to stay home. That’s fucking horrifying.</p>

<p>Eventually things get into a nice comfort. They all start to like the idea of her become a member of the crew. Oh boy, I can’t wait for that to happen! No, obviously not.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5WeqjpV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>One of the agents from her planet gets aboard and wipes her memory. It wipes slowly, which is ESPECIALLY horrifying. She’s like “Please, if I forget you, please make me fall in love with you like you fell in love with me this time”. Chakotay almost beats the shit out of this guy, but he’s so smug about it. He’s like “Of course I’m right for doing this. This is the wya of our world, our laws”. Fucking gross behavior, to wipe someones mind like this, but eh.</p>

<p>Of course, her memory is gone. She doesn’t remember him or why she’d want to be here, so she just… leave. He can’t convince her to stay. Chakotay, who’s going to lose all his memories again, writes the log down on paper. Neelix has a nice scene about love before the episode ends. So, I don’t think this episode is bad in concept, or even mostly in practice. Most of it is good. It’s basically a retread of that one episode with Riker loving the agender alien. The problem with this episode, and there’s only really one, is that Chakotay is a sucking black void of charisma. Chakotay is the Omega Particle of boring. He is perfect.</p>

<p><strong>Living Witness</strong> - VOY
8.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CpZdykM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with a scene between Janeway and an evil smarmy guy, a Vaskan. He brings JAneway and Voyager into a war. She is OVERLY evil, with Tasha Yar hair and black gloves. She agrees, if he helps them get home. There’s also a Kazon soldier who walksbuy. She then uses Biogenic weapons on the planet, despite the original evil smarmy guy’s statement that he didn’t want to kill that many people, just win the war and defeat his one enemy. The Doctor makes a biogenic weapon, and then they release it on the planet, killing millions.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lEMFojx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out this was a simulation and a video being shown many years in the future on the planet, which is owned by the Kyrians, to explain The Voyager Incident, when Biogenic weapons were put on their planet. This is an AMAZING cold open. VERY entertaining, and you IMMEDIATLEY know what’s happening (it’s propaganda). It’s mostly just fun to watch everyone over act as super evil people. And to see all the things they got wrong. They’re from Mars. Tuvok SMILES. We all recoiled in horror at it. They have multiple Borg drones on board they use as weapons. Fucking NEELIX is at Ops. Of course, Chakotay’stattoo is all over his face.</p>

<p>The Voyager Conflict ends with the leader of the Kyrians being killed brutally in a firing squad, as the Kyrian watches in terror. It’s shown this is a museum in the future. The Kyrians lost the war and are now under the control of the Vaskans, and are basically second class citizens. A Vaskan is annoyed by this, and claims they made up this just to make the Vaskans out to the villains. But the Kyrian museum curator and historian has some new evidence that should help cement the historical record. It’s some data, maybe some records!</p>

<p>He researches it and finds out it’s code… for a hologram. SURPRISE. IT WAS A DOCTOR EPISODE THE ENTIRE TIME! The Doctor finds out he’s 700 years in the future, and is horrified at the idea he’ll be a museum piece. Although probably not. On their planet, AI are responsible for their own crimes. And he DID make the Biogenic weapon.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HaMNMB8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Everything in the diagram made about the incident astounds the Doctor. They’re making him out to be a murderer, and the entire crew maniacs. “Halfway across the galaxy, I hope, Janeway is spinning in her grave”. He explains that they were just doing a trade agreement with the Vaskans, and then the Kyrians started a war with them suddenly, and Voyager was caught in the middle. The museum curator is stunned, and disgusted. No way, he’s a second class citizen, how could HIS people be the aggressors? He shuts down the Doctor, but it also confused why a medical hologram would be willing to lie so much. So he eventually comes back and apologizes. He’s ready to learn the truth, no matter how uncomfortable it might be.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/47C99rK.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>When he shows his recreation of events, one of the other Kyrians in the Museum is disgusted by it. There’s a lot of political and racial disagreements here. I’m not 100% sure how I feel about it portraying the clearly second class citizens as willing to throw people under the bus and hurt them just to make themselves feel better. He might have a way to prove himself innocent, though. He has a medical tricorder that can prove it was Kyrian weapons that started the conflict, and help his side of events. Unfortunately he loses it in the fucking RACE RIOT that occurs over this, as Kyrians storm the museum and smash it up. The Doctor makes a decision.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QeZa3Bh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He should be erased. Him EXISTING and trying to find the truth is making more people die. Two people died already. Who cares about the truth, what matters is lives. But the museum director disagrees. They’ve been abusing history, and all its done is worsen relations. They need to try and learn the truth so they can move past it, and live together. It’s a nice moment. And then, abruptly, we find out THIS was a simulation, some further point in the future, just like it was at the start of the episode. It’s like poetry, it rhymes. The world is at peace, and all is good. The Doctor stayed with them for a while and worked as their chief medical director for years before taking a small vessel and flying back to the Alpha Quadrant… hoping to reach home.</p>

<p>So, I think some parts of this episode were maybe clumsily handled, and you could easily twist its narrative to imply it’s saying heinous shit. I could argue right now it’s a holocaust denial episode. But it’s not, it’s trying to have a more positive message, and even if it’s not perfect about that, it’s fine. I liked most of it.</p>

<p><strong>Demon</strong> - VOY
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/o5CvEIR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Voyager is out of Deuterium. They’re running on empty and people need to vacate the living spaces and sleep in one room to conserve power. But before Astrometrics is shut down, Seven finds a planet nearby with lots of Deuterium. They just need to go grab it. Unfortunately, the ship is Class Y. There’s no worse planet for supporting Human life. Worse than zero atmosphere? Worse than a GAS GIANT? Wow. Harry volunteers himself to go down and mine it, cause teleporters aren’t working. He also volunteers Paris to come with him. I’m sure this will go VERY well.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4ZXnWRv.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Harry IMMEDIATELY falls in some goop, and a seal breaks on his suit. He runs out of oxygen. Paris fishes him out, and then a seal breaks on his suit too. They both run out of oxygen and die, on screen. We hear the beep and everything.</p>

<p>There’s also a B-plot about Neelix trying to turn the Medbay into a barracks. That happens. The Doctor is a shitty dickhead about it. It doesn’t fit.</p>

<p>They’re about to run out of energy, and the Deuterium is down there. They can’t contact Harry or Paris. Hey, do you remember that Voyager can land? They won’t be able to go back up if they do, but they CAN land. Well, they do. And Chakotay and Seven go out to find our Dead Boys. They find out Dead Boys, shockingly alive. Not only that, but outside of their fucking suits. Paris is outside his suit and SUPER thrilled about it, he’s like “it was exhilerating! You should take off your helmets too :D Join us :D”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FxBXvbS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s creepy.</p>

<p>They take Harry and Paris back, and they IMMEDIATELY start suffocating. The doctor checks them out (not before being a dick to Neelix again) and finds some weird silver goo in their blood, which he determines bioformmed them. Like terraformation. They can only breath the atmosphere here, so either they fix it, or they leave them behind. Janeway and Torres determine it has “Memetic” properties, and can mimic things it touches.  But as they go out and explore more… they find Harry and Paris’ corpses. Well, not corpses, they are BARELY alive, even though they’ve had no oxygen for ages. The Non-Dead Kim freaks out about this, and runs off declaring that he “belongs here”, as the others teleport back.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/QXh3ObB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway is weirdly aggressive, as the ship is being held down by this silver goop. She has a beam thing that can hurt it, and help them escape, and Fake Kim BEGS her to stop. She’s still aggressive, and like “okay I will blow you all away if you don’t let us go”. Kim literally says “WE DESERVE LIFE”. We’ve had arguments about this in episodes before, but we’ve not really had a Starfleet Captain willing to throw away sentient life like this.</p>

<p>So, to explain, this goop, it’s called “The Silver Blood” by Janeway. It gained sentience by finding Kim and Harry. And it doesn’t want to be alone, so it wants to use the rest to make it a family. Janeway lets people give it their DNA so it can literally create a second race of changelings to take over the Delta Quadrant, and then blast off with more Deuterium than they could ever want. This episode was alright.</p>

<p><strong>One</strong> - VOY
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dOgHjQ6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our episode starts with Seven practicing getting to know people better. She does this by interrogating them, then the Doctor stops the holoprogram and is like “Okay tell me what you did wrong” “Nothing.” “…Okay then.”</p>

<p>You know it’s bad when the DOCTOR is having to give Not Be A Dick lessons</p>

<p>Anyways the crew enters a nebula with some radiation and everyone is suddenly being burned like, from the inside out. They’re too hurt to even get out of the nebula, Tuvok has to Vulcan his way to the console. One person straight up dies. Yet another one gone. The Nebula is in their way, and it’ll take a month to get through it. A whole YEAR to go around it. The Doctor can put everyone in suspended animation pods, but uh, that’s a WHOLE MONTH of just the Doctor. Well, not just the Doctor.</p>

<p>Seven is immune to the radiation, it seems. Oh, Borg Shenanigans. She’ll also stay awake. Janeway is a bit worried, cause it’s bad enough that as a Borg she’s now on a ship with 150 people, but total isolation is very rough on Humans. She thinks she can handle it, though. Everyone is A Little Concerned.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Xq8TtqD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Things go well at the start. Sort of. I mean, things are GOING, at least. Paris is claustrophobic and does not like being in the coffin, so he sleep walks out of it. That’s weird. But at least he’s not horribly burned. But over all, Seven is being a little irritable. So is the Doctor, mind you, but that’s mostly cause he has to put up with her. So it’s more Holodeck How To Be Personable time. And you know what? She does it. HOW does she do it? By getting Neelix and Janeway into her hyper fixation so they can all gush about warp fields and shit. Everyone’s big into it, but the Doctor is like “No you’re failing”. Bitch, she did good, how dare you. You’re just jelly.</p>

<p>This is all interrupted by the warp core breaching. That’s not good. Turns out it’s not actually though, they’re fine. The Neuropacks are having problems and freaking out. And not just that, but also the Doctor’s holo emitter. He has to stay in sickbay for the rest of the two weeks. She’ll now REALLY be alone. Yes, they were just bickering and being rude to each other, but this is… a bit more. Things are already going bad. She’s having dreams. The ship is breaking down more and more. She’s hearing things, people calling out for her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7rjnPEe.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But then, someone shows up. Someone else trying to get through the nebula, asking to trade some parts. Seven does so, though he’s… creepy, and uncooperative. It eventually turns to her escorting him out of the ship, but he gets away from her.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/g3RiuEE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She hunts down this guy, as he mocks her. She sees and hears more fucked up shit as she goes. But this guy is impossible to defeat. Impossible because… he’s not real. The Doctor manages to fix himself in time to find her waving a gun at the air. He also thinks the radiation is effecting her. Unfortunately, before he can try and help, he’s deactivated by the ship breaking down even more. Now it’s LITERALLY just her. And she’s not taking it well.</p>

<p>What follows is her being nuts and doing what she can to survive. She barely does. In the end, she cuts life support to reroute it to the engines so they could make it through. She nearly doesn’t make it, but she does. She gets them through. And she realizes what it truly means to be alone, and to want companionship. In the end, she goes to spend time with her crewmates in the mess hall. It’s sweet. Everyone is mean to Neelix for some reason.</p>

<p><strong>Hope and Fear</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rwN3reQ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Seven and Janeway are butting heads. Seven is very competitive right now. There’s a hot scene where they’re playing Sportball. It’s good. Anyways, Janeway’s big project these days is trying to decode the message Starfleet sent them. It’s very degraded and encrypted. Luckily, there’s a guy here to help! His name is Arturis, he met Neelix while trading and is VERY good at languages. Janeway asks for his help, and he manages to fix it easily. It’s a bunch of messages, including a star chart nearby!</p>

<p>There, in the area they were pointed to, is a Federation starship! A new class they’ve never heard of, and it has a weird-ass drive called a “Warp Slipstream” drive. No one is on board, just them. The Slipstream drive should help them speed along home in only 3 months!! Wow, I can’t believe Voyager is about to end.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eywgWnz.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The message from the admiral explains to them that they’ve been developing this technology, and sent it along to rescue them. Oh how nice!! It’s perfect! …Too perfect. Tuvok, Seven, and Janeway are all suspicious. They all WANT it to be true, but Janeway immediately thinks “I think this Arturis guy is sus”. Well, MOST of them want it to be true.</p>

<p>Seven decides to stay behind. When Kim tells her “it won’t be the same without you”, she smiles. ACTUALLY smiles. But she’s unhappy. Scared, about going with them. But then they make a breakthrough on the last bit of the message that Arturis said “was unrecoverable”. THey recover it. It it is an Admiral apologizing that he can’t send them any better way to return them home. Well then.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/NdFyM2d.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They confront Arturis. He’s like ‘oh it was a setup by Seven! She’s been against you getting home this entire time!” And even with all the antagonistic Seven stuff this episode… no one turns on her. And it call comes out. He captures Janeway and Seven and speeds along in his slipstream ship, and explains. His species had been eluding the Borg for centuries, but finally they overwhelmed them and most of his species are gone now. He doesn’t blame THEM, they’re basically a force of nature. He DOES blame Voyager. They made a deal with the Borg and stopped them from being obliterated by Species 6969. So in his grief, he set this up to capture them all and take them to his homeworld so they’ll be assimilated.</p>

<p>Seven and Janeway have a nice moment where they basically make peace, after an entire season of butting heads. If I was in charge of his show we know EXACTLY how it would end. With sloppy makeouts. Sadly, I am not God. Anyways, they manage to get close to stopping Arturis, but he blows up his controls and makes it so now the ship can NOT be stopped before it reaches Borg Space. Buuuuut, then VOYAGER SHOWS UP! They made their OWN slipstream drive and chased after them! They save Seven and JAneway, and Arturis is off to be assimilated, I guess.</p>

<p>They don’t think they can risk using hte Slipstream again, it’s too dangerous. But now Seven is WITH them. She’s been there for a year now, but now, she’s with them. She’s working on a way to get the Slipstream drive to work again.</p>

<p>Good episode, great Seven and Janeway moments. And a great end to a surprisingly good season.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 164 - Blue Mint</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/28/RA164-BlueMint.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 164 - Blue Mint" /><published>2025-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/28/RA164-BlueMint</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/03/28/RA164-BlueMint.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bSxojgA.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is gonna be a short one.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LkuBCAw.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Blue Mint is a Doujin game on the PC88 by Caramel Ribbon. It’s a program for the PC88 that shows you 80s anime styled art, and then you need to unjumble it in a sliding puzzle. That’s it! There are six puzzles and then you’re done.</p>

<p>The puzzles get progressively larger. They start as like, 3x3s, until they get to about 8x6s or so. A sliding puzzle is the ssame no matter the size, if you know what you’re doing. Honestly, I played this cause it was 1AM I wasn’t tired, and I needed something chill to play through a high anxiety night. This was chill. There’s not much more to it than that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="Blue Mint" /><category term="Obscure games" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is gonna be a short one.]]></summary></entry></feed>