<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-15T11:34:31-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 5 - 8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/14/LizstartrekEnt1-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 5 - 8" /><published>2025-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/14/LizstartrekEnt1-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/14/LizstartrekEnt1-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Eky6oSo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>STARTING ENTERPRISE NOW! I know NOTHING about this, other than it takes place very early in the timeline, has a guy named ARcher and a guy named Phlox, people smother gel on each other naked a lot, and a lot of people get a lot of opinions.</p>

<p><strong>Unexpected</strong> - ENT
2.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/AjfXSIi.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is it. One of the most important episodes. The person I watch Trek with, Neligahn, remembers this specifically. Why? You’ll find out.</p>

<p>The episode starts with some general malfunctions all over the ship. They determine that the problems are cause there’s an alien ship sitting within their warp field, squatting. They communicate with them, and they seem friendly enough, and are just using it cause their systems are malfunctioning. They offer to fix it up, and send Trip over. “Mind your manners”. Trip? Minding his manners? That’ll be the day. He immediately shows his ass by getting impatient with a 3 hour decompression, which he knew was coming. Trip is the worst character in this so far.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/W5ubYXU.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hey look, it’s the BEST character in this show! :D Porthos is the best boy.</p>

<p>The Xyrillians, the aliens they’re helping, live in a very different pressure and atmosphere, and it’s causing some serious problems for Trip. This is conveyed with weird drug filters and flashing lights, which are VERY bad on the eyes. He’s helped by this hot lizard babe, who helps him adjust.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/eLbChJN.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The two of them work on fixing the engine, and on the off time, hang out and relax. She shows him a kind of holodeck, and plays a game with him where they kinda share minds and thoughts for a minute. He finds out she finds him very attractive. So, I usually don’t like romance in Trek. I feel like it doesn’t work very well, usually? Feels stilted and off. But here it… WEIRDLY works? It helps that she’s instigating, but gently and not too far, and Trip’s wet blanket “Huh, what?” energy kinda works with that.  Nothing ACTUALLY happens though.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Eky6oSo.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But it doesn’t matter. He goes home, they all leave, and it’s fine.  But then, Trip has a weird growth. What is it? Phlox looks into him, and we find out… he’s pregnant. Everyone assumes he just fucked around, but no, he actually didn’t.</p>

<p>This is handled very, shockingly bad. This is funny to someone who like badly written things. Like, if you’re really into “Take my wife, please” jokes, this is the episode for you. He’s PMSy and it’s awful. Very poorly written.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/bQNhwva.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They find the Xyrillians, who are hiding in some Klingon’s wake now. The Klingons do not take happily to this, and are going to kill all of them. Archer and T’Pal manage to convince them to let them go, in exchange for holographic technology. The Klingons are… very unpleasant. The Klingons in this show are a little worse than Klingons in the 90s-era. Trip goes back on the ship, and they manage to get the alien out of him. T’Pal tells him that he’s the first Human Male to ever get pregnant. I guess trans men do not exist in the future.</p>

<p>Anyways this sucked, obviously. But it wasn’t as horrible as it could have been. THEY DIDN’T EVEN LET HIM COME TO TERM. Cowards.</p>

<p><strong>Terra Nova</strong> - ENT
6.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5J0WJS8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Enterprise is heading towards Terra Nova. Years ago, trying to colonize the universe, some Humans left Earth to get to an earth-like planet 20 light years away. No one knows what happened to them, because Enterprise is the first ship that’s really gone out this far.</p>

<p>When they get to the colony, it appears abandoned. There’s some kind of background radiation, 70 years ago it would have been lethal and they wouldn’t have been able to head back into space cause the ship was designed to BECOME the colony. So where are they? They find a guy, who runs away and leads them to a network of tunnels. Some weird people capture Reed, and then run away back into the tunnels. Now they need to do a rescue mission.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hRhDkUg.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer lets himself get captured and communicates with these people, who are Human, actually. Not even really majorly mutated, just… the culture has kinda fallen apart. They need to try and get these people to trust them. They think Humans hurt them, the Novans, some time in the past with poison rain. Archer tells them no, they ARE Human, and they can work together to learn what happened. They offer to take some of them up to the ship to cure diseases.</p>

<p>They keep trying to convince them they’re Human, but they’re not making much progress. And on top of that, the tunnels they live in aren’t totally safe from the radiation. Eventually they take them back, not much progress made, but begging them to just move to a safer location. Archer WANTED to take them back to Earth, but T’Pol was like “you’d be erasing their culture. That’s a Bad Thing, by the way.”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/my6Aq1E.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Back on the planet, the landing causes quakes that collapse some tunnels. Archer risks himself to save some Novan lives. This endears them to them, and they agree to move, which is done off screen, and the episode just ends.</p>

<p>This one was alright. Pacing was a bit off, but it wasn’t bad.</p>

<p><strong>The Andorian Incident</strong> - ENT
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nWavyVS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This is one of the episodes I’ve been looking forward to. Andorians are a very, VERY important peoples. They are historically important but have barely been expanded upon. This is where that changes. Not only that, but He returns.</p>

<p>We see Andorians attack some Vulcans. Then we get the Enterprise going to go visit a Vulcan temple on a far away planet. They aren’t GREAT with outsiders, but the Humans wanna learn more, so we’ll learn more.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/m6WYDUM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>It’s him! They discover the temple is under attack by… someone! This is Jeffrey Combs. You may remember him as a bunch of different, very good DS9 characters. They are VERY unhappy to see them. Once they’re captured, T’Pol explaisn they are Andorians. They are very anxious and suspicious of the Vulcans. And now that the Humans are here, they’re even MORE suspicious. They think the Vulcans have some sensor arrays here, and demand to know where they are.</p>

<p>The Vulcans deny anything of the sort. But they also say they MIGHT have an old one in The Catacombs. There’s no way these Vulcans aren’t actually doing shady shit down here.</p>

<p>There’s also a cute scene between Archer and T’Pol. Is it just me, or do they have some actually good chemistry?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/E1qDNdh.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Humans plan out a strategy. They use the old radio to contact Enterprise. Dunno how the Andorians don’t notice it. They sneak some Humans down using transporters for a surprise attack. Reed gets to do something! Holy shit! They also conscript one of the Vulcan monks, a younger one, to join them in the fight.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/oxCItqR.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Wow what a fucking surprise, I was right. Called it. Now that Archer finds out about it, he is EXTREMELY unhappy about it. He’s like “Give them all the info about this, now. The Vulcans violated the treaty and the Andorians have a right to know about it.” The young Vulcan monk tries to hold them hostage, but Archer beats the shit out of him. The Andorian leader is actually appreciative of this, and does leave. And then it just ends.</p>

<p>Interesting, sets up future plot lines. Curious where this goes.</p>

<p><strong>Breaking the Ice</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Jb87HmB.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>If this episode doesn’t IMMEDIATELY follow the plot of the last one, I’ll be confounded. How did that NOT cause them to pause everything?</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>The Enterprise follows a comet and scans it, while T’Pol gets some kind of message. She does not look happy. They scan the comet some more, and a Vulcan ship shows up. They’re like "We’re here to watch you :</td>
      <td>". Everyone sees EXACTLY what’s going on. The Vulcans in this show have been pretty unpleasant and unmoral so far. I imagine they’re going "The Humans will be just as unpleasant and unmoral, we cannot trust them, time to watch them as they do bad stuff". So the Humans, knowing this? What do they decide to do? Just… keep being normal.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>There’s a scene where Archer and the crew answer questions sent to them from kids, knowing the Vulcans are listening in. That’s so fucking funny to me. This is, unironically, the best scene in the entire show so far. Archer forces Trip to answer a poop question. He is NOT happy. I am VERY happy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/aFJyM7N.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>On the Comet, while doign scans, Merriweather and Reed make a Snow Vulcan. It’s cute. The most character Reed’s got. They then blow it the fuck up while they’re drilling deeper into the comet.</p>

<p>At the same time, there’s that letter T’Pol got. It was encrypted. Trip is SURE it’s something suspicious, so he has it unencrypted and reads it. It’s VERY personal, very private, not at all suspicious mail. Well, shit. He feels genuinely awful about it, and goes to tell T’Pol, who continues to be VERY unhappy.</p>

<p>They have a dinner with the Vulcan captain. He is, like every single one of the Vulcans on this show, a fucking bitch. I hate it. I really don’t like it? I don’t like how Vulcans are shown and represented in this show, at all. Vulcans have always been standoffish, and a little bitchy, but this is like, INTENTIONALLY being kind of cruel and rude.</p>

<p>T’Pol talks to Trip about her problem, since he already knows. What’s the issue? Her arranged marriage is about to be called off because she decided to work on Enterprise instead. This is, IMO, stupid, but I have opinions on arranged marriage kinda shit. Trip doesn’t have very good advice, because he’s Trip.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gTwQJ52.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Merriweather and Reed get in a snafu on the surface of the Comet, and nearly get killed. The Vulcans offer to assist, and Archer WANTS to resist, but T’pol is like “They think you’ll reject the offer, because they think of you as arrogant. You can prove them wrong.”</p>

<p>He accepts the help graceously, and wishes them a safe journey on their way. T’Pol decides to stay on the Enterprise, and it all ends. This one was alright. I liked a few parts of it a lot, but the rest was shitty, jerkish Vulcans.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episode 6</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/14/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Strange New Worlds Season 7 episode 6" /><published>2025-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/14/LizstartrekSNW3-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/14/LizstartrekSNW3-2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IVV1wHl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>This is the third season of SNW, finally coming out. We’re gonna watch an episode of this once a week until we finish, alongside Voyager, cause it’s coming out y’know, one a week. Yay! I love SNW!</p>

<p><strong>Through the Lens of Time</strong> - SNW
5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N8mQara.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This season is going really hard on the romance drama, which is starting to get mostly tiring for me. But it’s ALSO pushing this new nurse guy, Dana. He’s SO excited and happy to be here. This guy is SO fucking dead. He’s got the voice over and it’s really pushing him, he’s so fucked. It also seems like he was brought in secretly as a third wheel so that thigns aren’t TOO awkward between Spock and Korby as they do some kind of dig.</p>

<p>Ortegas’ brother is also here! He’s recording stuff for a documentary, it seems, and is also invited to this mission, which SEEMS to be an archaeological dig on a sacred site. He’s also getting romance vibes with Uhura. They’re really trying to hook EVERYONE up this season aren’t they? Though Pelia the Warpcore Witch also seems to be real into him. And I like that, cause it’s funny.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/p5JfYBa.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They all enter some kind of temple, after Chapel does some kind of thing to gain entry. They IMMEDIATELY find corpses and Spock is like “okay, protocol tells is we need to leave now”. Korby gets pissy and refuses, and Chapel, who’s in charge of the mission, sides with him cause he’s her girlfriend. There’s also a lot of tension cause of the whole Spock x Chapel thing. See, this is why everyone shouldn’t just fuck. Use the holodeck to fuck- wait. We already had an episode about how that’s a bad idea at this time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ypNSSmn.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>New Kid, who’s name is Gamble, acts like a TOS red shirt and randomly touches shit. Anyways, woah, New Kid gets his fucking eyes exploded cause things are actually super dangerous in here! Looks like Spock was right, what a mother fucking shock! The native living with them sees something else, freaks the fuck out, and tries to run away, and is vaporized. But we have so many things we could learn here!!! Korby was ABSOLUTELY going to just fucking die because he wasn’t being careful enough if others didn’t die before him, frankly. Why was he SO SURE that he had to do this dig RIGHT THE FUCK NOW? “I’ve waited all my life for this!” Yeah dude, but you’re like, 33. This temple isn’t going anywhere. Put down that fucking idiot ball, right now, mister!</p>

<p>They get split up, as if it couldnt’ get any worse, and are in different rooms, but able to communicate. This now turns into a split room puzzle game escape room. Seems to be the same room but also not, seperate dimensions. They can still communicate though. Why? I dunno, bad writing?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/x4jYCCp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The Eyeball Regenerator, which apparently exists, is not working. New Kid’s brain is also registering as braindead. New episode name: Gamble’s Brain. Gamble is also acting Kinda Sus now. Hmm.</p>

<p>Ten minutes ago, Gamble’s eyes exploded. Now, Spock is saying how Korby is not being safe enough and not taking any precautions, and then he TAKES A FUCKING VISOR OFF OF A DEAD ALIEN AND PUTS IT ON HIS EYEBALLS AND USES IT TO LOOK AT THINGS. WHAT THE FUCK, SPOCK? I’m starting to think this episode might just not be well written.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HLyV7Ze.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Patel, who I remind you is now half Gorn, meets Gamble, and starts speaking in tongues. Gamble does the same, and they proceed to beat the shit out of each other. Gamble also murders someone in the scuffle. After he’s captured, he just breaks through the force fields and kills more red shirts. Damn, this episode has a body count.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hp0x8tF.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Pelia shoots Gamble in the back, releasing the ancient dimensional alien inside of him. Scotty then captures it in a Pokeball and tosses it up into the transporter. He locks it in the transport buffer, until they can figure out what to do with it. There’s no WAY that’ll backfire!!!</p>

<p>Pelia has a big discussion about ancient evil, which turns out to be her mugging for the documentary. Okay, that was funny. I was like “wow that’s very on the nose- oh okay, that’s good”. I do like Pelia. As M’Benga calls Gamble’s parents to tell them about their son, the Enterprise computer screens flash alien text. Wow, I knew it’d backfire but THAT fast.</p>

<p>I think my judgement of this will depend on if and when it goes anywhere, but I feel it was poorly written. Something was off and the pacing was bad.</p>

<p><strong>The Sehlat Who Ate Its Tail</strong> - SNW
8/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/iXkfagX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>What a weird episode title.</p>

<p>Anyways, Kirk is on the Ferragut, and he’s bored as fuck. His captain, V’rel is a hot Vulcan bitch who does everything By The Book, and Kirk wants a shakeup. Be careful what you wish for, Kirk. They disturb a disturbance in the crust of a planet they’re observing, which turns out to be the planet fucking exploding. The captain and a lot of the crew is taken out. Comms are down, so there’s no way to communicate.</p>

<p>Enterprise comes to help out, a team beaming over to try and help. Kirk is in charge, V’Rel is alive but injured. Turns out there was some kind of gravitational beam that blew up the planet, though it’d take a ship so much larger than anything else on record. Uhura sets up comms with the Enterprise, who orders everyone to evacuate. Fair. La’an and some of the critically wounded beam over first. Before they can do anything else though, THIS happens!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nV2aKch.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>A giant fucking thing comes and literally eats the Enterprise. La’an explains she thinks it’s the Eater of Worlds. A giant ancient scavenger ship. Ghost story. Interesting. You’d think something like this would be more than just a Legend, but whatever works. Kirk refuses to leave people on the ship, and demands Scotty make miracles. This is actually the first time Kirk and Scotty are even working together. Since Spock is here too, as acting 2nd in command, with Uhura too, it’s practically a TOS reunion party. Just like, a pre-union.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2J7mGnt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>The things in charge of this giant Scavenger ship appear to have boarded the Enterprise, and are just fucking Big Daddies.</p>

<p>Kirk is making bad decisions. He ignores all his advisors, and the ship explodes. Not like, fully, it’s just dead in the water. He ignored Scotty, and he’s pushed it too far. He gets angry and refuses to listen to any other advices. He storms off. They decide he needs someone to help him through this, someone with a less emotional style to calm him. Time for the start of Spock x Kirk!!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FJxOfv8.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We get to see Pelia’s quarters. It’s absolutely incredible. She digs in a box for some ancient junk. She pulls out a mother fucking Atari. Holy hell. I want to see her video game collection. Communications are being jammed, so her plan? Wire the enterprise with ancient cables and use old-ass phones. That’s honestly fantastic.</p>

<p>We learn what the title of this episode means. The Sehlat that Ate Its Tail is a Vulcan idiom, similar to “the dog that caught the car”. Someone hunting after a thing, then… now what? Kirk, going after leadership, now he’s stuck and frozen. It’s cute. Anyways, Spock and Kirk have a heart to heart, and it helps. He comes back with a new plan. Make their ship look REAL tasty to the scavengers so they’ll come biting, then make them regreat it.</p>

<p>Back on the Enterprise, the Big Daddies refuse to kill Pike after it knocks his helmet off. Weird. Strange.</p>

<p>“I haven’t done this since I was a roadie for the dead!” “…Your species can communicate with dead people?” Holy shit, I LOVE Pelia. When they actually do things with her she’s so funny.</p>

<p>This episode is not doing a LOT with Pike, but it’s doing more than the rest of this season’s done. He’s the CAPTAIN, and he’s barely got any love this season. He’s the best character on this show. Very fun moments with him. “Take a step back, this might blow up.” “Captain, if it does, it’ll blow up the entire engineering section.” “…A very large step back, then?” I love you, Pike.</p>

<p>Spock manages to hit the aliens where they hurt and blow them upm just as the Enterprise escapes.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lQm5m80.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We find out the Scavengers were Human. On the side of the ship, they find “XCV-100”, which is a reference to a classic Ship concept. Apparently many years ago, some Humans built a ship to escape an environmental collapse of Earth. But then the ship disappeared, never to be heard from again. But how did they go from THAT, to whatever they became? It’s not explained.</p>

<p>I’m not really sure I like the ending all that much? The big twist? But the lessons Pike imparts to Kirk in the end are good, at least, and the action and jokes are good. It’s like, a solid season 1 or 2 episode.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Strange New Worlds" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 182</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/10/OOCY182.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 182" /><published>2025-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/10/OOCY182</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/10/OOCY182.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WJePbPg.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>New reaction image just dropped</p>

<p>source: A Pitiable Boss And A Pathetic Liason</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Pitiable Boss And A Pathetic Liason" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 204 - Amazing Penguin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/10/RA205-AmazingPenguin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 204 - Amazing Penguin" /><published>2025-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/10/RA205-AmazingPenguin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/10/RA205-AmazingPenguin.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2cxRMAK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Amazing Penguin is one of those Gameboy games that I feel left zero impact. No one remembers this game, and no one goes out of their way to play it, but it’s there, and it’s certainly not bad. Some people prolly had it as a kid or rented it, and think rather positively of it. But it’ll always be a like, low B or C tier Gameboy game. Just another part of the collection, never a standout.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/R27ndhu.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Amazing Penguin is a Maze Chase game, rather similar to something like Pepper II for arcades. You play as a Penguin moving through an area made up of lines. There’s orbs on those lines, and if you pick up all the orbs surrounding a square/filled in area between the lines, it’ll clear and become an image. You can also kick the orbs. Black orbs are just pickups that can be kicked, and the negative orbs make enemies swap direction. Enemies move around entirely in a clockwise/counter clockwise motion, and don’t chase you at all, which can be used to try and dodge/read their movements. Of course, there’s usually a LOT of enemies.</p>

<p>Later levels in this game get pretty hard. One path through, and lots of enemies. But it’s still a simple and cute little game, only about an hour or two in length if you sit down and power through it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Maze Chase" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 181</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/08/OOCY181.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 181" /><published>2025-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/08/OOCY181</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/08/OOCY181.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/jCt0MJj.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: A Pitiable Boss And A Pathetic Liason</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="A Pitiable Boss And A Pathetic Liason" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 204 - Star Wars Chess</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/08/RA204-SWChess.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 204 - Star Wars Chess" /><published>2025-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/08/RA204-SWChess</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/08/RA204-SWChess.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/nTXtZnO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>So way back in the 90s, as computers and consoles were getting better with Chess AI, there was a game called Battle Chess. It was basically just Chess, but any time a piece was taken, there was a little animation between the pieces where they fought. It was a cute little thing, though its pacing was a little off. Sometimes you just wanna play Chess, honestly, and watching a little animation with EVERY piece being taken takes a lot of time.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FCZPyg9.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But it was still a popular idea, so they took that and brought it to Star Wars! Star Wars was always really, really big, and it sure was in the early 90s. Enter Star Wars Chess, or “The Software Toolworks Star Wars Chess” which rolls right off the fuckin’ tongue. It’s literally just what I said earlier.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEH6kGiBo-c?si=GszcJ5DAQJ8fooxI" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>You’ve got some fun animations here. My favorite is Yoda, the light side rook, being killed by Boba Fett, the dark side bishops, because boba fett melts Yoda and Yoda kinda becomes one of those green blobs Calvin would eat in Calvin and Hobbes. But yeah, it’s chess other than that. And I DO like chess. The AI here is fine. Can only think a few moves ahead, not too hard to beat, even on the hardest difficulties. Don’t got much more to say than that. If you ever wanted to watch Chewie get brutally murdered, this is the game for you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Sega CD" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Chess" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 1 - 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekEnt1-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Enterprise Season 1 episodes 1 - 4" /><published>2025-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekEnt1-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2025/09/07/LizstartrekEnt1-1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/LleEO6i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p>STARTING ENTERPRISE NOW! I know NOTHING about this, other than it takes place very early in the timeline, has a guy named ARcher and a guy named Phlox, people smother gel on each other naked a lot, and a lot of people get a lot of opinions.</p>

<p><strong>Broken Bow</strong> - ENT
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/vgoPgE9.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We start with a kid being racist towards Vulcans, complaining that if the Vulcans were actually helping them, they’d be going at Warp 5 by now. We then jump cut 30 years later, and it’s now the opening of Star Trek. Some aliens drop down, a Klingon blows them up, and then a farmer blows him away with a blaster shotgun.</p>

<p>Then we get the opening theme song. If you were wondering, this is was my watch club’s reaction to it:</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6ZMdhOd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>So apparently the plan for Enterprise was that Voyager’s rating were falling by the end, so they’re trying to make a new kind of Star Trek. Something Modern. By modern, we mean dated as fuck, and kind of boring, I guess? Also the CGI is very, VERY dated too.</p>

<p>Anyways, the Vulcans are here. The Klingons are upset a Klingon got shot. He’s still alive, but the Vulcans are ready to just kill him. Their logic is nonsense. Then we’re introducd to our ‘hero’.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/c9gbUUj.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Captain Archer’s ship is ready to be launched, but the Vulcans are like “Don’t launch yet and go out and meet other people in space, you’re not ready”. They’re all kind of dicks about it. Whoever wrote this doesn’t know how to write Vulcans. A Vulcan woman tries telling him to wait until he’s ready, and he threatens to beat her. Captain “Would beat a woman” Archer. The Earth Admiral is like “alright fuck these guys, we’re launching after all”.</p>

<p>We then get scenes of all the crew. It’s kinda hard to tell who is and is not important in these scnees, but I’ll try and explain them all. We’ve got Archer, he’s kinda smug and I’m not sure how much I like him so far. Then Phlox, the doctor working on the Klingon who seems like a friendly guy, Reed, the Armory Officer. I can’t tell what his deal is. Mayweather, the resident Black Guy. We’ll see how he is. So far he seems young and friendly. He’s also really horny for aliens. Sato, a Linguist who’s really excited to learn Klingon, she’s kinda cool so far, but she has a character trait of being anxious about being on spaceships and it’s slightly annoying. “Trip” Tucker, the Engineer, who’s kinda belligerent and rude. He yells a lot. I cannot tell Tucker or Reed apart.</p>

<p>And then we meet T’Pol.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/0rhsVB0.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She’s assigned to the ship, the Enterprise, by their Vulcan superiors. No one is happy about this. When she entered in, I was like “is Archer gonna be racist in this?” and then he opened his fucking mouth, and yes, he is. AND Sexist! I think the idea is that he’s annoyed at the Vulcans cause of history and personal things, and the idea is that we’ll eventually grow as people and our cultures and civilizations will grow closer. That’s the idea. But it’s not pleasant to watch the start of that!!</p>

<p>We also get a scene where an alien talks to the Emperor from Star Wars about the Klingon being takne by the Humans. This guy’s alien species then comes and steals the Klingon away. The alien’s species is the… Suliban. Which is inspired by the Taliban. Yeah. <em>sigh</em>. The Suliban is genetically enhanced, which is strange for their species. T’Pol tries to tell them to go back home. She’s told to shut up. They go to the last known place the Klingon, Klaang, was known to be. A planet called Rigel. Everyone is pretty much immediately kidnapped. T’Pol gives a “told you so” look. Alright.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ia1Bkar.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We learn that this girl, Sarin, was who Klaang met before hand. She kisses Archer because apparently though kisses she can gauge how truthful someone is being. It feels like Berman was just horny, and also thought kisses would sell more. It’s dumb. She agrees to help them, then gets killed and tells them to find Klaang. Okay, sure. She tells them about The Cabal, and something called The Temporal Cold war. Whatever that is. On the escape, Archer is shot in the leg and T’Pol decides to take command of the Enterprise. Dude, he just got shot in the leg, it’s fine.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/r4V61Td.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We then get the most infamous thing in Enterprise, at least to me. T’Pol and Trip get into the decontamination room and rub gell on each other. It’s extremely over sexual and the smell of Berman is thick all over it, and I hate it. They exposit over this sexualization, or sexposit I guess, and T’Pol ends up actually not taking advantage of this situation to make them go back to Earth, but instead do what Archer would have wanted and go after the aliens. It’s a VERY sudden turn around, there was no… anything there. Maybe that’s just what sex gel does to a woman.</p>

<p>They’re attacked by the aliens but are hiding from them. They steal one of their ships, and go down in it, Trip and Archer. Why is he bringing the chief engineer for this mission? Instead of the guy who can actually fly the ship, Merriweather? I dunno. They enter the alien vessel and rescue Klaang, but leave Archer behind. I have no idea why they left Archer behind. So the story can happen? I dunno, it makes no sense to me. Archer tells Tucker tells Trip not to come back for him, but then lies and is like “How DARE you all not go back for him! IT’S AN ORDER OF HIS!” and I think Trip is supposed to be the good guy in this situation.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6LFsTXX.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer talks to The Bad Guy, some dude named Silik, and they fight in a temporal anomoly room, and then in a flashing room. It’s… a little rough.</p>

<p>He’s teleported out just as before he was about to be shot at. The telporter btw is only used for like, supplies and food. It’s SUPPOSED to be safe for Humans but this was the first test of THAT. Yay!</p>

<p>We take Klaang to the Klingons, and find out that apparently Klaang was carrying some data in his DNA. Oh boy. This is technically Klingon First Contact, and it seems to go… kinda well.</p>

<p>Archer then openly admits he’s been a racist and is looking to move past that, and wants T’Pol to stay on board. She offers to contact High Command and ask them herself. Again, the pacing of this character development feels slightly off but it’s not a bad payoff.</p>

<p>Over all, the episode is fine. It’s fine for setting up over arching plot. But as for the character setup, I dunno. I have NO clue what Reed’s deal is, he has no personality so far except he’s English, and there.</p>

<p><strong>Broken Bow</strong> - ENT
7/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/EWAxYTt.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Hoshi Sato starts our episode off by being sad her pet slug they found on an alien planet is dying. Oh this’ll be good. They apparently haven’t had very much luck meeting aliens out here yet.</p>

<p>Reed is grumpy that they left stardock without testing their weapons, which is the closest we’ve gotten to a character trait for him. The tests go poorly. A lot of this early episode is just… people talking about how nothing is happening, and very little happening. Though we do get to see more Phlox. He’s fun. He’s also VERY horny. He and T’Pol are the only two non-Humans on this ship, and he’s here cause he wants to learn as much as he can about other Cultures and peoples. Even, and possibly especially, their mating habits.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/dpvnXDZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>THey find a spaceship floating around out in space, and venting air. It seems to be damaged. They decide to try and find out what’s wrong, going over to it. Trip is pissy and like “I should go on the mission with you! I came here to explore, not sit in Engineering and Engineer!” Then why the fuck did you sign up to be an Engineer? Meanwhile, Hoshi is like “I don’t want to go over there sir, I’m claustrophobic”. Then <strong>why did you sign up to be on a spaceship???</strong> These people don’t seem to know what they’re doing here.</p>

<p>They find some corpses on the ship  being drained of something. T’Pol now suggests they leave. Archer is like “we should stay and find out who did this so we can stop them!” It’s an interesting argument in this case actually. And the first time T’Pol is written for giving an argument and it actually being any kind of reasonable.</p>

<p>Hoshi screamed at the corpses, and she’s talking with Phlox about it. He’s VERY chill. “It’s honestly a good thing you’re not used to rooms full of corpses?” and basically politely suggests she should take care of herself, and not be here if it’s not what she wants.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/hFXHNHM.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Archer decides fuck this and goes back to try and find out who the corpses are. Apparently the attackers are harvesting their blood, which has a special compound in it. As the aliens come back, surprise surprise, Archer blows up the harvesting pump and heads back to the Enterprise.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/09UM9sZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>They’re tractored in by the murderers, and then another ship shows up, this one one of the murdered aliens. He thinks they did it, and is angry at them. They need Hoshi to talk to him, but she’s all in her head about it. And you know how they take her out of it? “We need you to do this”. That’s all it takes to make someone no longer self conscious and afraid. She talks to him directly, not through her translation app, and it works out and they blow up the attacking aliens. Yay, more examples of why we need more fucking translators on ships.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UVov5Kb.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>And then while making a metaphor about Hoshi finding her place on the ship, they brought an invasive species to an alien planet. The end!</p>

<p>This one was okay too.</p>

<p><strong>Strange New World</strong> - ENT
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3X4o0xS.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>But we already watched SNW this week!!</p>

<p>While flying around, they find an Earth-like M-class planet. They decide to go down and check it out, cause it seems nice. T’Pol thinks they should spend a week scanning it instead. They refuse, put on these dumb hats, and go down with an away team. They also brung the fucking dog. Archer’s DOG is on this away mission. Do they have any idea how dangerous space is?!?! Like, yes, T’Pol is kinda a bitch at this point, but when she’s like “We were scheduled to rendevous 15 minutes ago, where are you?” and they’re like “Gosh get off my ass mom, we’re just enjoying our time here”, we’re not supposed to… empathize with her??? Also why are the people sent on the survey mission the engineer and the pilot???</p>

<p>They camp out on the planet. Is that why they’re out exploring? To go camping?  These people are too lax. Merriweather tells a ghost story, which is cute. Very suddenly, there’s a storm that rolls across the planet. They hide out in a cave, and now it’s a fucking ghost story. Merriweather goes back out and sees some forces walking around outside. Oh boy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/b4yRYtw.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Scans still show nothing. One of the redshirts they took with them freaks out and runs out into the storm. These people are not prepared to be in space. They’re not prepared to be on a HIKE, let alone in space. They choose the wrongest, dumbest things to do, and then get pissy when their babysitter (T’Pal) tries to help them in any small way.</p>

<p>One of the other redshirts sees T’Pal talking to aliens, then later when she asks her about them, T’Pal is like “…what are you talking about? I’ve seen no one else here.” The first Redshirt tells Archer to “go to hell” when Archer is like “We’re landing to take you out”. They’re struggling to land the shuttle though. Gosh, if only they had their fucking pilot up there instead of ON THE SURVEY MISSION. Archer crashes the shuttle like he’s Captain Olimar and has to fly out.</p>

<p>Trip gets all up in T’Pal’s face and is racist and assumes she’s evil and trying to hurt them. He pulsl a fucking gun on her when she’s like “Let’s go get some water”. I think they’re trying to make him a Bones kinda thing but he’s like… very, VERY aggressive and irrational and frankly, awful. I kind of hate him? I hope there’s SOMETHING on here that’s making him go nuts, but this isn’t really THAT far from what we’ve seen before.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ld0HHkV.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Our first teleporter incident! He lives, though. THis is the first redshirt who ran off and told Archer to go to hell. According to Phlox, he’s filled with a psychotropic compound. Okay, that explains it. It’s the LSD Bad Trip Planet. Archer calls Trip, tells him to stop being violent, and explains what’s going on. “You trained for this, y’all?” but the training means jack squat.</p>

<p>Trip: “Hey aliens, we’ll teach you that she lied to you about Humans! We’re actually wonderful, pleasant people!” as he waves his fucking gun around and shoots at the wall. Also there’s poison now so they need to act MUCH more quickly. But Trip is too far gone. They first try to explain it to him, but he’s too paranoid. They then trick him into letting them talk to her in Vulcan, and basically tell her “fucking shoot him”. It works.</p>

<p>It all works out in the end. I didn’t like this episode very much. It was mostly stupid and unpleasant to watch.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Enterprise" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 180</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/04/OOCY180.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 180" /><published>2025-09-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/04/OOCY180</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/04/OOCY180.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FdKvpAg.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/KkfHLOf.png" alt="'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class’s Green Tea Bitch</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="That Time I Was Blackmailed By the Class&apos;s Green Tea Bitch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 179</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 179" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2025/09/01/OOCY179.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UYb48Ag.png" alt="Out of context yuri, panels are from 'Keeping a Jewel' by Sachi Miyabe. Two women are on a bed, looking at each other, with a soft filter effect going on. Their hands are almost touching. One thinks, as she looks longingly into the other, 'I'm sure the reason my heart races even though she's a girl is because I have social anxiety...'" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Sorry for no yuri in a bit, got distracted</p>

<p>source: Keeping a Jewel</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Keeping a Jewel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 203 - Link’s Awakening DX</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 203 - Link’s Awakening DX" /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2025/09/01/RA203-LOZLADX.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/TMF9nVH.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I apparently never moved my Link’s Awakening review over here. God, what do I say about Link’s Awakening? Well, it’s my all time favorite  Zelda game, which means it’s one of my favorite games ever. I replay it once every few years. I own like six copies for some reason. It’s utter Zelda perfection.</p>

<p>Coming out in the middle of the Gameboy’s life-cycle, it got a port to the Gameboy Color six years later. It’s pretty similar, with only a few minor changes, and is more of the same. I mastered the original last year, and put this one off cause some of the challenges annoyed me.</p>

<p>This set has a lot of missables. No hit challenges, don’t do this in this order, etc etc. I actually had to play this game through twice to do this because it glitched out. If you kill like 80 enemies in a row or something (I was trying to farm for acorns, forgetting how that worked) it will change your tunic color, and might glitch out other things. It gave me a photograph and I couldn’t get the achievement for getting that photograph later. Oops!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8hZucB7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Link’s Awakening started as a remake of LTTP, but I’m so glad it became this in the end. It’s a weird, unique Zelda game. Lots of things that are just… It. And the story! Oh man. I think it’s fitting that my two favorite  Zeldas are Majora’s Mask and this, the two games with the most melancholy and sad stories.</p>

<p>I don’t think I need to go into a full deep dive of Link’s Awakening. All I need to tell you is that it’s fantastic, and this is a good version. Not DEFINITIVE. It adds an additional dungeon, which is an okay dungeon, and the photos system, which is cute.</p>

<p>If you’ve never played Link’s Awakening, I highly recommend it. It’s not too long compared to other Zelda games, but it’s a solid thing for a Gameboy title. Do yourself a favor and check it out.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="Retro Games" /><category term="Zelda" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>