<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-23T12:42:03-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 77</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 77" /><published>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY77.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/q9BSf8s.png" alt="&quot;I ... I like... you...&quot;&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/IMvfNDG.png" alt="&quot;You finally did it.&quot; &quot;I- I like you...&quot; &quot;I like you too.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Sunday 13.00</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Sunday 13.00" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 78</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY78.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 78" /><published>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY78</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/21/OOCY78.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Ki1Utoe.png" alt="&quot;What about you? What color is your tongue? Hey, if we combine them, what color do you think it'll make...?&quot; leans in for a kiss." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Purple</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Purple" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 76</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 76" /><published>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/20/OOCY76.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WuMHUBp.png" alt="&quot;What does it mean to love someone romantically?&quot; &quot;You're interested in even the smallest things about them... in finding a side you haven't seen yet... if you realize this, it means you like them more than a friend!&quot; &quot;NOPE!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tnznnB7.png" alt="&quot;The very first thing you like about your romantic love is their face, right?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: In a Home Where Lilies Bloom</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="In a Home Where Lilies Bloom" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 134 - Zelda 2 The Adventure of Link</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 134 - Zelda 2 The Adventure of Link" /><published>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/20/RA134-Zelda2.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/gumj4Aj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>When I was really young, we had two Zelda games. We had Link’s Awakening, and we had this, Zelda 2. So a lot of my love of this is nostalgia. I’ve been playing this game since I was 2. But I think even if I played it today, I’d love it. Zelda 2 is a very controversial title, but is in my opinion one of the absolute best Zeldas, and it gets a bad wrap. I’ve lived my life on the internet, and the common pervailing idea around this game for YEARS was that it blows. These same people suck the dick of Dark Souls, but Zelda 2 is bad. Because it’s hard. They are very, VERY wrong. Zelda 2 whips. It whips so hard I mastered it, which involved me playing this game FOUR FUCKING TIMES. And I had a great time doing it!!</p>

<p>Zelda 2 is maybe the POSTER CHILD for my “NES Sequel Syndrome”. Games from that era that were sequels to a popular game that’d continue on with an amazing series, but the second game is different and weird compared to the others. I’m talking games like SMB2, Final Fantasy 2, Metroid 2 I guess, and this. The absolute poster child. Conceptually, if I explain what this game is out loud, it sounds very similar to Zelda 1. You play a little elf boy who travels around an over world fighting monsters. You explore this overworld and find dungeons, which contain an item that will help you progress further. Go through all the dungeons, go to the final dungeon, beat a boss. That’s just Zelda 1, right?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/1V131xK.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Well no, obviously. There’s a lot I didn’t mention. Zelda 2 has towns you can explore to heal up, cause there’s no health drops. Zelda 2 has magic spells you get from these towns, which can be used to do things like shield you or heal you. Zelda 2 has no money or shops. Zelda 2 has EXP, which upgrades one of your three stats, Health, Magic, or Attack. And most notably, Zelda 2 is not a top down action RPG, it is a side scrolling action RPG. You walk back and forth, jumping and ducking and stabbing with your dinky little sword. This has some VERY deep combat in places, frankly, I like it more than the Zelda 1 combat, by a large, large margin. Combat in Zelda 1 is a little… hokey and awkward at times. Fighting randomly moving enemies like Darknuts or the Wizzrobes blooooows. Here, the enemies have patterns you learn, and it’s like a beautiful dance with each one, that’s so rewarding. It feelS SO good once you can take on darknuts flawlessly. Or hell, the Dairas. GOD the Dairas.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/l8DUKvc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>The world of Zelda 2 is pretty expansive, with a big-ass overworld to explore. Lots of little caves to go into and get EXP or heart containers, or items to unlock magic spells. And while some people might claim this game is bad because it’s so obtuse, this game isn’t Castlevania 2. All the people in towns give good hints. And nothing is SO obscure that you’ll get lost. Shit, it’s WAY less obtuse than fucking Zelda 1, which people still love to death. That god damn 8th dungeon bush? Burning EVERY BUSH to find entrances??? Zelda 2 has none of that. The most obscure thing here is the forest town you gotta find by breaking down trees with your hammer, but there ARE hints for that.</p>

<p>The other reason people hate this is cause of its difficulty. And yes, it’s hard. It’s a hard mother fucker. Like, I can practically play this game blindfolded now, but its HARD. Death Mountain is a cakewalk to me, but to your average joe, it is a WALL, a brick wall you must beat down with your face. I acknowledge this. I realize that I am biased. But that feeling of satisfaction when you beat it! Also, it never feels UNFAIR hard. Like, you’ve gotta learn the patterns, you’ve gotta perservere. You never need to grind, you can push through and make it. Though the option IS there if you want it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cmo3ltz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Frankly, Zelda 2 is a masterpiece, and I cannot praise it enough. It saddens me that Nintendo decided to never return to this style again, though to be fair, so many other games picked up the slack and did their hand at it quite well. Shout outs to Monster World 4. While they’ve never returned to this style, they certainly don’t seem ashamed of Zelda 2, and they haven’t forgotten it. Ocarina of Time brings some enemies back and re-uses the names of the towns for the sages. And of course you can play it in any Nintendo online service from the past 17 years.</p>

<p>So if I love this game so much, why did it take me this long to play it for Retro Achievements? It didn’t. I beat this game a year ago, securing the beat. …But not the mastery. This is a series on the MASTERIES of a game, where I 100% the achievement set for it. And the achievement set for this game required me to play it multiple times. Technically I COULD have mastered it in maybe two playthroughs, but I wasn’t going to do a candleless 1cc with no heal or shield spell on a 1st quest, so I had to split everything up into four playthroughs.</p>

<p>So yeah, I played this game MULTIPLE times this year. And you’ll find out soon, even more than that. It’s not too long, I can breeze through it in two hours, and it’s a fun two hours the entire time. Absolutely fantastic game. If you’ve never checked it out due to its reputation, give it a chance.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Zelda" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 75</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 75" /><published>2024-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/19/OOCY75.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Zjk0wG1.png" alt="&quot;I bumped into the tank today because I was thinking about you...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, since this is a repost, there’s also a very funny reaction and response I now need to share about this post…</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/d194RA3.png" alt="&quot;Wow what a cute and sweet panel, I wonder what happens next in this manga.&quot; &quot;HARDCORE GAY LESBIAN SEX.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: The Higher the Breakwater, the Quicker it is to Crumble</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="The Higher the Breakwater the Quicker it is to Crumble" /><category term="NSFW source" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 74</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 74" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/12/18/OOCY74.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RelCIYl.png" alt="&quot;Look at me as much as you like. Like me more and more. And if you blush, use that blush to dye me red too.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Fall for me and dye me red</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Fall for me and dye me red" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 133 - Fire n’ Ice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 133 - Fire n’ Ice" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA133-FirenIce.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/ZgfxJ8B.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I love how god awful this cover is. What the hell is this. This is supposed to make me buy your game? No wonder this sold poorly here.</p>

<p>So I was watching a friend, Mister Radon, play some games, and someone made him play this for a bit. I was like “WOAH. THIS LOOKS LIKE IT’S EXACTLY MY JAM WHY HAVE I NEVER SEEN THIS”? So I played it the following day and DEVOURED it.</p>

<p>Fire n’ Ice is the sequel to classic Tecmo title “Solomon’s Key”. Known in Japan specifically as Solomon’s Key 2, it’s actually a prequel, showing the first adventure of the great wizard DANA! An evil fire wizard is attacking the peaceful ice island, and Dana has been chosen by the fairies who rule the island to stop him!</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/wdEBJiR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s a single screen puzzle game. You get into a level, and then your goal is simple. Push ice onto the fire. Once all the fire is gone, you move onto the next level! Complete all 100 levels and you’re good! You can push ice, or climb up on it if it’s already up against something else. You can also create ice, but ONLY down and diagonal from you. So it can be pretty difficult to go upwards, you need to prepare ahead of time if you want to climb back up. But using these tools, you can get through all the puzzles, creating ice blocks, then clearing the way so you can push them onto the fires.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zkVpAS7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>It’s really rewarding, and honestly, AMAZING for the NES? It’s a late NES game, but honestly it feels more like an itch.io puzzle game, or a modern NES homebrew. The animations are fantastic. Dana has a lot of personality, like his little shimmy when he’s up under a ceiling (or ice block). The fire is constantly wiggin’ out, and the music is really chill and fun. And every now and then you get a BOSS LEVEL, which is a screen that’s constantly scrolling and looping, which makes for some interesting gameplay, cause you often need to build a way up, but without blocking yourself on the second loop.</p>

<p>After you beat the 100 levels and the final boss, you can sit through the credits and get a code to unlock 50 more bonus levels. This game has SO MUCH CONTENT. It is CHOCK FULL of puzzles, and there’s really no stinkers in here! There were no puzzles I played and went “wow that fucking blew?” They can be challenging, but very rewarding to push through.</p>

<p>All in all, this is a FANTASTIC NES game, that frankly more people should know about. I HIGHLY recommend it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Fire n Ice" /><category term="Solomon&apos;s Key" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 132 - New Rally-X</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA132-RallyX.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 132 - New Rally-X" /><published>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA132-RallyX</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/18/RA132-RallyX.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/P649Xo7.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Last PC88 game for a bit, this is New Rally-X, a classic arcade maze chaser from the very early 80s made by Namco. It’s basically just a lightly tweaked version of Rally X, which was a little bulshit. Some new graphics, easier gameplay, new music, and the iconic Lucky Flag you can pickup that gives you bonus points. And of course, like so many early 80s arcade games, this was ported to the PC88.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JDSVDcz.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’ll be real, I don’t think I like Rally-X very much. It feels… empty. Flat. To explain it very simply, you take Pacman, make the maze like 12x bigger, with scrolling, and place only a few dots all around at random. You also have a fuel meter, if that runs out you’re dead, and you can release smoke behind you to confuse the ghosts (cars in this case). Also some spaces are wider than the 1 tile you occupy, so enemies can juke you a bit easier.</p>

<p>I don’t really like it much. Like I said, it feels too big and empty, and the mini-map combined with the larger map on the left just feels confusing in a way I don’t think I appreciate. After a few levels you get a “Challenging Stage”, where the enemies don’t chase you, but instead you have shit laying around you can run into, and it’s way easier than the other stages. Another reason I don’t like it much is the AI of the enemy cars makes no god damn sense. Sometimes they’re like, ALL Inky from Pacman, good at jukes and chasing you down/doing pincer attacks. And at other times they’re all Clyde, ignoring you completely and just wandering randomly, sometimes going in the opposite direction when chasing you. It makes no sense and it makes me anxious.</p>

<p>This set was EXTREMELY easy though. It’s not a very hard maze game, all things considered.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Rally-X" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 130 - Puzzle Kana?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA130-PuzzleKana.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 130 - Puzzle Kana?" /><published>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA130-PuzzleKana</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA130-PuzzleKana.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/6lR1EZO.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>More PC88! So the PC-88 was NOT made for games, but it has quite a few really famous and popular ones. And they all kinda have a… vibe about them. After having played a lot of PC88, my opinions are that most of them are rough and awkward, held back by the hardware its on. I haven’t played all the most popular PC88 games, of course, I haven’t touched Ys yet. But of all the everything I’ve played? This my favorite. This is my favorite PC88 game. And it’s a random fucking doujin game from 1990.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/19meAxc.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Made by “Studio 4989”, Puzzle Kana is a very simple puzzle game. It’s a sokoban-style game where you push blocks into the “in” goal. In this game, blocks will slide forever until they hit a wall or another object, so it’s like ice-block puzzles. The first example I can think of with stuff like that is the ice cave in Pokemon Silver and Gold. So think that, but a bit more complex. You can’t push balls into each other, they’ll shatter, and some blocks can be pushed, but others can’t. There are a few other kinds of blocks, like redirection arrows, but its a very simple rules set up.</p>

<p>And yes, this is maybe my favorite game I’ve played on the PC88. It looks good. It SOUNDS fantastic. Every 5 levels you get a cute little cutscene or mini game. You can easily go specific levels using password systems. The little anime girl, Kana I suppose, is cute as hell. This is just a really well made doujin game. It is a tad short, and not very hard as far as sokoban goes, but that’s honestly a good thing, because a lot of PC88 games are fucking impossible.</p>

<p>I’m sure I’ll find SOMETHING I like more than this, but what do I have to compare it to? Super Mario Bros Special? Hydlide??? The Scheme maybe comes close, though I’d rather play Puzzle Kana again than play The Scheme again.</p>

<p>Anyways it’s fun.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Puzzle Kana" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 131 - Bomb Jack</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA131-Bombjack.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 131 - Bomb Jack" /><published>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA131-Bombjack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/12/16/RA131-Bombjack.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/va5mk98.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Another PC88 game here, this one is Bomb Jack, a port of the classic arcade game. Bomb Jack is one of those Tecmo games that’s more of like, a b-tier. People who play it like it but it’s not even CLOSE to the top when people name Tecmo properties. He got a few more games after this, including the sick NES game “Mighty Bomb Jack”, but is mostly remembered TODAY because of the game “Mighty Jill Off” which pays homage to it, and I had a LOT of people going “oh shit is this Mighty Jill Off” in the chat as I played it.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/N7fwy3O.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>In Bomb Jack you play as the titular Bomb Jack, who is attempting to collect all the bombs on the screen. Get them all, move to the next level. Once you get a bomb, a bomb on screen becomes lit, based on which bomb you picked up. There’s a pattern and order to the bombs, but you never know what it is until you pick up a bomb (or look it up). If you get enough lit bombs you can get bonuses and things, including an item that makes you super and lets you defeat enemies. SPEAKING of enemies, there are a few kinds. A bird is always slowly chasing you through the air, but skeletons spawn near the top and fall to the bottom off platforms. Once they reach the bottom they transform into a new flying enemy, and a new skeleton spawns.</p>

<p>As Bomb Jack, you can jump and hover. You can do a super jump by holding up, and hover my tapping the jump button in the air. It’s pretty intuitive in the arcade, but a little jank here. and that, sadly is how I’d describe this port. It’s very, very jank. A good game hampered by the hardware its on, which honestly describes MOST PC88 games I’ve played. Everything is on a kind of grid, which y’know, makes sense, but it also means hit detection is FUCKED. I’ve gone right through pwoer up coins and died hitting enemies I thought I’d be invulnerable to. And I STILL have no idea how to get an extra life, I guess I just got lucky for the achievement.</p>

<p>Bomb Jack is a good arcade game, but is sadly let down by the PC88. Just play the PC88 version. Or the NES version, which is completely different.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="PC88" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Obscure Games" /><category term="Puzzle Kana" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>