<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-21T11:52:21-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lizstar’s Trashcan</title><subtitle>A place where Lizstar writes about the stupid junk she wants to write about. Special interests include yuri, video games, writing, yuri, obscure video games, and a lot of yuri.</subtitle><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 56</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/21/OOCY56.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 56" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/21/OOCY56</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/21/OOCY56.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/irFkr4T.png" alt="&quot;Wel... is it me that you want? Because if so, you'll have to let me have you, too. Your beautiful, pale fingers, your cute, reddened cheeks. Your shining eyes, your beautiful, soft hair...&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5SXJUxX.png" alt="&quot;and your heart, unsullied by this cruel world. But if I take those from you, even once, I may never, ever be able to give them back. Even so, would you give me all that you are?&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yuki and the Authoress</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuki and the Authoress" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 122 - Pokemon Blue Prof Oak Challenge</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/21/RA122-BlueProfOak.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 122 - Pokemon Blue Prof Oak Challenge" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/21/RA122-BlueProfOak</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/21/RA122-BlueProfOak.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JI80GSp.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>This is one of the first “Subsets” I’ve done in ages, or at least mastered. A subset is a bonus challenge set for a game, usually. So in this instance, I did not do the set for Pokemon Blue. Instead, I did a Professor Oak’s challenge. What’s Prof Oak’s Challenge? It’s simple. You need to get a maxed out Pokedex at every single instance you can, with gym badges as cutoffs.</p>

<p>So like, in Blue, you can’t go past Pewter without defeating Brock, right? So you need to get every single Pokemon in the Pokedex logged before beating Brock. This means grinding your starter (in my case Bulbasaur) on Kakuna and Metapod for hours upon hours. And that’s just the one Pokemon. A lot of them are way, way worse than that. Being able to split it up is nice though, and you’re always working towards it and making progress.</p>

<p>I had Blue as a kid, and LOVED it. But I certainly never finished the Pokedex. This was my first time doing that, or at least, as complete as I can get it without trading. I didn’t get all Eeveelutions or Gengar or the Red exclusives. Blue is the best one to do this in btw, specifically because Porygon is like 7500 coins in the game center, while in Red it’s 9999. Which is agonizing. I just sold all my calciums and shit I found (cause I was grinding way above level anyway) to buy coins directly. I funded SO much Team Rocket shenanigans.</p>

<p>This is not very interesting. At all. Like, it’s not meant to be. It’s a grind. There’s a LOT of grind subsets out there on RA. Things like “get all the rare 1/128 items in Earthbound”, or “FF1 Solo Runs”. A lot of RPGS make for good grinding achievements, but there’s also stuff like the Shadow the Hedgehog all endings subset, which is a nightmare. I like grinds. It allows me to turn my brain off. It’s a thing to work on without caring too much, always making some progress and relaxing as I watch something on Youtube or someone on Twitch.</p>

<p>This took me 25 hours and 33 minutes. According to the game, it took me 82 in-game hours. I was fast fowarding through most of it. Most people’s least favorite part is from Misty to Koga, cause there’s a LOT of Pokemon to catch and a lot of grinds. But honestly, it wasn’t that bad? Like, most of those Pokemon can be grinded up as you do all the required stuff with Team Tocket, and/or caught as their evolved form. I had to grind evolve like, 8 Pokemon, which weren’t THAT bad, and there’s good spots for it. The worst part, IMO, was Brock to Misty, which required grinding on Diglett in Diglett Cave to get things up to like level 42. Even the Dragonite grind wasn’t too bad. I think I just planned it well.</p>

<p>Would I recommend this? No, not really. But I’d consider doing another one lol</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="challenge runs" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 55</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/20/OOCY55.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 55" /><published>2024-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/20/OOCY55</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/20/OOCY55.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/tRs37aL.png" alt="&quot;I want to have sex so bad I can't stand it!!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: I Don’t Know Why but I Suddenly Wanted to Have Sex with My Coworker Who Sits Next to Me</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="I Don&apos;t Know Why but I Suddenly Wanted to Have Sex with My Coworker Who Sits Next to Me" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 54</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/19/OOCY54.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 54" /><published>2024-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/19/OOCY54</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/19/OOCY54.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/RhA0Qb5.png" alt="&quot;What does she have that I don't?! Is it the voluptuous bod?? Those mommy milkers?? I can't compete with those, my back hurts enough as it is!!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Mage &amp; Demon Queen</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Mage &amp; Demon Queen" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 121 - Final Fantasy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/19/RA121-FF1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 121 - Final Fantasy" /><published>2024-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/19/RA121-FF1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/19/RA121-FF1.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/4rrSSlR.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I had recently played UFO 50, and that game has a game inside it called Grimstone, which is basically an attempt to make a FF1 clone. After playing it and loving it, I decided I wanted to play FF1 again. So I did. I’d never actually beaten it before, though I do own a copy on my NES. I got to the Volcano and then it got too hard. Well, no better time than now, right? And I have a LOT of thoughts on Final Fantasy, and a lot to get to. So let’s get started.</p>

<p>Usually every review of Final Fantasy 1 on the NES starts with talking about how Square was going bankrupt and this was their Final Fantasy, in a way, but that’s a myth and is probably not true, so we won’t be talking about that. Instead, I want to touch on the story of someone very important to Final Fantasy who doesn’t get enough credit today. Nasir Gebelli is an Iranian-American programmer, who was basically the first video game programming superstar. Later superstars like John Romero put together Apple II conventions just in the hopes of getting this guy to show up so he could meet him. He was HUGE in the Apple II scene, but after the game crash, he had basically retired… until a friend of his, Doug Carlston, the owner of Broderbund, told him about this hot new thing coming out of Japan called the Nintendo Entertainment System, and suggested he should try making games for it. Nasir was interested, so Doug flew to Japan with him and introduced him to contacts at Square, who basically immediately hired him off of name recognition alone. Nasir single handedly programmed this game, and the other NES Final Fantasy games. That is extremely impressive. I’ll be talking about a few programming bugs later, but seriously, this is a VERY complex game and I cannot overstate how cool this guy is. He also made 3D World Runner, Rad Racer, and Secret of Mana, for the record.</p>

<p>Final Fantasy is the Least Final Fantasy game, in a few ways. First obviously, it is the least final, because it’s the first. Secondly… it doesn’t really feel like a Final Fantasy game. Some series staples were introduced here. You’ve got crystals being important, musical motifs, and the different classes, and a few enemy types, but that’s about it. It also doesn’t have the same energy as future games, the overarching plot is there, but it’s mostly connected by interconnected vignets you explore in each town as you move around the world map. There’s another myth that’s surrounded the story of Final Fantasy 1 for years, which I feel holds a lot more water, and I want to talk about it. Final Fantasy isn’t a Final Fantasy game, kind of. It’s a Dungeons and Dragons game. A very early Japanese version of D&amp;D, specifically.</p>

<p>Signs that this game was heavily, HEAVILY inspired by D&amp;D are everywhere. First, its structure kinda feels like that of a D&amp;D game. You have a posse of nameless player characters you ascribe your own characters onto, who are chosen from different classes. You have a big arching plot hanging over your head, namely that the world is dying and you’re chosen ones brought together to reignite these orbs, or whatever. Then you explore the world, visiting towns to get new equipment and items, while also picking up quests. Go save our princess. Hey, we’re attacked by pirates, save us. Hey, our prince was put to sleep by an evil wizard, go stop him. Then after a few of those, the plot expands and gets more serious, as now you have to take on the four Prime Evils basically, and finally it culminates on taking on an ultimate evil, and boom it ends. It’s a D&amp;D campaign.</p>

<p>If that was all the evidence I had though, it’d be just a goofy fan theory. No, there’s a lot more than that. The classes you’ve got in this game are clear analogues to D&amp;D classes. Fighter is Warrior, Black Belt is Monk, Red Mage is Bard. Even the White Mage is more of a cleric than a traditional white mage we see in later games. They use hammers and are a BIT beefier than they will be later on. And the magic system is CLEARLY inspired by D&amp;D. It’s often the first thing people point to. It’s a vancian system, where you have different levels of spells, and you have a certain number of casts per day, but after a long rest, your spell slots return.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7PvkLdC.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>But the most damning evidence are the enemies and races you come across. Dwarves and Elves and Goblins? Sure, that’s fantasy stuff, that’s no evidence, though elves will rarely reappear in later games… dwarves do show up occasionally. Lali-hi! But then you get things that feel a bit more specific. The Wizards are Illithids. Couerls are Displacer Beasts. Sahags are Sahuagin. Kary is just straight up a Marilith. The Big Purple Worm is uh… the Big Purple Worm. But the biggest proof is the Eye creature. Which, y’know, looks like a big ol’ Eye. But in the Japanese version?</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Cre1E06.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Yep. That’s just a fucking Beholder. And Beholders are like, ACTUALLY copyright, so they changed this thing to a different design in the American version out of fear of copyright. And presumably, a lot of the future identity of the series is an attempt to move away from all this blatant D&amp;D stuff and create something new and unique, which I feel ended up working very well. But it’s still very interesting to view FF1 as more of a D&amp;D game than anything else.</p>

<p>Sorry I rambled about that for so long, it’s just very interesting to me. Anyways, onto the ACTUAL review.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rDngP7w.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Final Fantasy is an RPG for the NES by Square. The plot is that hundreds of years ago, the Four Fiends corrupted the crystals of earth, fire, water, and wind, and the planet is dying. But prophecy states that four chosen ones will appear and purify the crystals. That’s you. Go out and do that!</p>

<p>The most interesting thing to me about FF1 is the class system, and I really, really like it, on paper. You’ve got four slots, but six different options, so you’ll be leaving two classes behind. You could ALSO double up on classes, a totally realistic possibility. There’s lots of party loadout possibilities. Like, 126 to be specific. You could even be four white mages! Not that that’d ever work. But anyways, your six classes are as follows: The Fighter, who hits pretty good and has good health and defense, and can use a lot of equipment, which makes him expensive to maintain. The Rogue, who hits less and is a bit faster and uses less items, but is pretty much just a worse fighter. The Blackbelt, who uses no equipment at all, pretty much, and hits pretty good, but is a bit squimshy. The White Mage, your healing cleric. Black mage, your damage spell slinger. And my personal favorite, Red Mage, who can use both classes of spells, and can hold their own in combat, but just aren’t quite as good as everyone else. Jack of all trades. They’re also maybe the 2nd worst class. Rogue is the worst.</p>

<p>Yeah, I said I like it on paper. The balance isn’t QUITE there, you could do a bit more with this idea, and they have, and other games have, down the way. But on this one, the rule is pretty simple: Magic is just not as useful. Almost all classes get access to it, after class changes (only Blackbelt doesn’t), and you might think the mages are better at spells. And I mean, they do get access to MORE spells, and can cast more before resting. But, and this is rarely talked about <em>anywhere</em>, but uh, did you know FF1 is FULL of bugs and glitches? And those include the stats. Though, in this case, I dunno if it’s a bug or a glitch, because the Wisdom stat, which you’d assume connects to spell casting, doesn’t only not work… it doesn’t appear to be intended to work? Like, looking in the code, the number in the wisdom stat isn’t connected to ANYTHING else, in the entire game. It just wasn’t coded to do anything. It’s a number on your stat screen. So every character casts spells at the same efficiency.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/yUqWBSs.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Also, several spells flat out don’t work. Every character has three slots, and each level has 4 spells for each color of spell. So you might think that it’d be hard to choose which spell to cut out each level, but it very much isn’t. Half the levels have one spell that doesn’t work. Lock and Lok2 are supposed to reduce enemy evasion. They do nothing. Tempr and Sabr are supposed to increase your attack damage? Do not. And it’s not like a lot of the spells that DO work are useful. This game is a balancing nightmare. Oh good, AMUT. Now I can gain resistance against Mute casts. …Which only four monsters cast in the entire game.</p>

<p>Even cure and such aren’t very useful. It’s essentially just some extra potion storage, and you already get 99 potions. Just use the potions tbh, I’m glad I didn’t go White Mage, I was tempted to.</p>

<p>So yeah, beating the shit out of things is the way to go most of the time, though sometimes a good fire2 cast can be nice, especially on the PENINSULA OF POWER, an infamous part of the game where for two spots on an early game area, enemies from the end game show up, with all the EXP and gold that entails. Great grinding spot, especially for solo runs.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/66xtaQ8.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>As this IS a Retro Achievements Mastery post, I should talk about the challenge run I did. There are achievements for beating the game without class change, and for beating the game without opening any chests. Conceptually I didn’t hate this THAT much at first, except that there are ALSO achievements for opening every chest so I’d need to run back through the whole game again. But uh, in practice, it was annoying. All the best equipment is in chests, and you can use them to cast spells, and while I DID shit on the spell casting system, some spells are legit useful. That Defender sword WHIPS, but I wasn’t allowed to get it. Instead I had to rely on a Silver Sword for literally the entire game, and you can buy it in the third town, about 20 minutes in. Eventually I DID get through, though I couldn’t beat the final dungeon with both these challenges up, it was too hard. So I split my save and ranked up, then reloaded the save after winning and opened all the chests and stomped Chaos’ teeth in with my super weapons lol</p>

<p>So yeah, FF1 is a bit of a mess in every way, but I like it a lot. It’s very charming, and very replayable. Sure it’s outclassed by pretty much every game that comes past it, but we can’t forget where Final Fantasy came from, can we?</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="NES" /><category term="retro games" /><category term="Final Fantasy" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 53 - Lightly NSFW</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/18/OOCY53.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 53 - Lightly NSFW" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/18/OOCY53</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/18/OOCY53.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/G0V26PK.png" alt="&quot;How about I go take you for a walk? Oh, but you'll havbe to make me cum first, got it?&quot; &quot;If that's what my master wants, then I'll send you to heaven &lt;3&quot; *time skip* &quot;You sure talk big for someone who can't even handle that much&quot; &quot;...I apologize for my existence.&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Cynical Dog</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Cynical Dog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 14 - 19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/18/LizstartrekVOY3-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LizstarTrek - Voyager Season 3 episodes 14 - 19" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/18/LizstartrekVOY3-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lizstartrek/2024/11/18/LizstartrekVOY3-3.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2jhMYsD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Every Sunday my Twitch subs and I watch Star Trek in my Discord. Here are my reviews and thoughts on each of the episodes as I see it. If you’re curious about a nerd’s views on Star Trek episodes, please read on, I go quite in depth with some of these episodes! I’ve watched some Star Trek before but not all of it!</p>

<p><strong>Alter Ego</strong> - VOY
2/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/7F6VuNE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This episode is directed by the Doctor. Gee, it’s like they’re running a directing school here.</p>

<p>Voyager is looking at an “inversion nebula”, whatever that is, and Harry Kim goes to Tuvok like “Hey, can you help me remove my emotions” and Tuvok is like “it’s kind of not that easy, why?” and Kim is like “cause I’m in love with a Holodeck program” and Tuvok is like “lol you’re in love with A PROGRAM SUBROUTINE??? YOU NERD” and Kim is like “aww”</p>

<p>I wonder if Kim’s girlfriend just doesn’t matter anymore. I wonder if we’re even gonna bring it up.</p>

<p>Tuvok: “Vulcans don’t have friends. We have fellowships and the like.” Tuvok. My man. I know that’s wrong, because they made <strong><em>THREE MOVIES ABOUT THE TOPIC</em></strong></p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/fOPxHIk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>This holodeck character, Malayna, is very very lifelike. Like, all holodeck characters are lifelike. But she’s very perceptive, going beyond her coding as a beachside instructor. She’s very logical, calcualting, but also friendly and inviting. This comes to a head as Tuvok also becomes interested in the woman, who is putting the moves on, something fierce</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/rxO46nr.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>I don’t like this. Stop. This man is married. He has several kids and has been married for like 80 years. You can ship anyone else on this ship, have them all be in one big fuck pile if you want, but leave Tuvok out of this. Like, cheating and things don’t sit well with me, and Harry is TECHNICALLY dating someone, but like, after two years, I’ll accept that. It feels weirder for Tuvok, who is long lived, and WILL be alive and fine in 80 years when they get back home, everything can return as normal.</p>

<p>Anyways Kim and Tuvok get in a bit of a jealousy spat, and Tuvok deletes her from the Holodeck, but she just puts herself in Tuvok’s room instead, and is like “Hey, you’re move~” putting the hots back on him. THANKFULLY, Tuvok is immediately like “nope, all my hots are gone, this is clearly bad and this woman is a threat to Voyager” and calls security. Okay good. I was checking out SO HARD from this, but this helps. Anyways, Malayna has control over the ship’s functions, and she stops the alarms and zoops out of there.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/JGNmmEd.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Ten minutes earlier “I would NEVER be a threat to you or your ship!” Ten minutes later, she’s strangling B’elanna, and going “GIVE ME VULCAN DICK OR I WILL LITERALLY DESTROY VOYAGER”. Lady. He’s just not that into you, and you are going WAY too far for this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/3IZECG5.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways she’s actual an alien on a nearby station that looks over the nebula, and she’s alone. And very lonely. She hacks nearby ships that pass by to look into them and see what they’re about. Have you every considered like… saying hi??? I mean she technically did here, but then it went too far, she fell in love with Tuvok, and now she wants him so much she’ll do murder. I cannot relate to her in any way lol. She literally says “I chose a life of isolation here and I want to be here, alone”. So why would I feel bad about this?? Anyways he destroys her with Facts and Logic, and she sadly lets him go. He tells her to go back to her own kind, if this assignment is fucking with her THIS badly and she’s like “woah I didn’t think of that, huh”. THIS LADY THOUGHT SHE WAS LOGICAL ENOUGH FOR A VULCAN?? The episode ends with Tuvok apologizing to Kim, which fair, he did treat him kinda like shit, and teaches him a Vulcan board game.</p>

<p>Neli gave a good analogy. A ranger is alone in the forest and sees a group of hikers. He talks to one of them, likes them, and then kidnaps them and says “I will kill the others if you don’t fuck me”, and then when suggested to just… not be a ranger, cause clearly it’s damaging their psyche, they go “huh I hadn’t thought of that”.</p>

<p>This episode blows.</p>

<p><strong>Koda</strong> - VOY
6/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cM0TJ9H.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Janeway and Chakotay go on a shuttle, and it goes down and crashes onto a planet. Why the fuck would they put the two highest ranking officers on the same shuttle? Aren’t there rules for this? Anyways, Janeway dies in the crash. Pretty bold of the show to kill off the main character. Chakotay manages to revive her. They’re REALLY trying to make the thing between them a thing. I don’t want it. I hate it. Please.</p>

<p>Anyways turns out they were shot down by Vidiians, who come in and kill Chakotay and strangle Janeway to death. Then they wake back up on their shuttle. They appear to be in some kind of time loop. The Vidiians kill them AGAIN, but the third time they manage to disrupt the loop and escape the ships, making it back to Voyager. When they get back, suddenly Chakotay doesn’t remember the timeloop. And when the doctor examines her, apparently she’s infected by the phage. No idea HOW, but one of the phage’s side effects is that it can cause hallucinations, apparently, so that explains that.</p>

<p>When she awakes 40 hours later, Doctor goes “Nope, can’t find a cure. Guess I’ll have to kill you :(“ and poisons her with a neurotoxin, and we see her painfully dying. What the fuck??</p>

<p>Back to the anomaly. They can see it physically, and then Janeway sees Chakotay trying to revive her body, from that first time. She’s suddenly in a It’s A Wonderful Life situation, watching everyone react to her death.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/X94IKoE.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Kes seems to feel that she’s there, cause psychic, y’know. The rest of them take any chance to save Janeway, and Janeway stands there watching, as her dad shows up like “Hey honey, you’re dead, like me! Come join me in the afterlife :D” Janeway keeps holding on, until she sees everyone give up on her, and hold a eulogy.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/WL0cEP6.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>…But even after, no, she has to stand by them. She’ll just watch, it’s fine. She’ll be with them in spirit, and a captain never abandons ship (Incorrect, you’ve abandoned ship a few times already, but thats okay)</p>

<p>She starts seeing flashes of the Doctor trying to resuscitate her, and determines THIS isn’t real, and her dad is trying really, REALLY hard to convince her to just give up and die, which is not at all what her father would do. She asks him if he’s an alien, and yes, okay, he is, but he’s here to make people crossing over into the next life easier. Uh, no, clearly not. He’s basically a vulture, feasting on dying people. But she makes it back, and everythings okay.</p>

<p>I found this episode pretty interesting… at least, the second half. The first half was uh… what does that have to do with anything???? It feels like they wrote an episode, didn’t know how to end it, and just wrote a completely different episode.</p>

<p><strong>Blood Fever</strong> - VOY
3/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/kA1fReZ.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Y’all remember PON FAR?! One of the Vulcans on board is undergoing it, and asks Torres to be his mate. It’s a very “I assure you, I am quite fertile” moment. Anyways when he gets… handsy, Torres fucking decks him. Go Torres. The Doctor tries helping him, but the pon far isn’t a thing people talk about. It’s a private matter. The Doctor is annoyed by how Victorian Vulcans are about the whole sex thing. I agree. The only thing they CAN do here is just let him meditate, which doesn’t seem to be helping.</p>

<p>Torres, Neelix, and Paris go into a cave and do some climbing to find some minerals they need. Torres is very… harsh, fast paced, high energy. When their climbing equipment fails, Neelix is injured, she’d lightly hurt, and gets VERY angry at him. When Paris tries to stop her, she bites him, and is like “what the fuck?!”</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/cuty6Am.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Turns out Vorik, the Vulcan, mind melded with Torres briefly and now SHE’S experiencing Pon Far. They go after her, and some aliens come out of the rocks, and consider her hostile… because she is. An earthquake happens, and her and Paris are seperated. She refuses to accept something is wrong with her, and no one wnats to explain Pon Far to her. Just say its Vulcan Mind Meld Fuckery, seriously.</p>

<p>The Doctor develops an alternative for Vorik. He makes a Vulcan blow-up doll on the holodeck. No joke. It’s VERY funny. He’s basically teaching Vulcans how to masturbate.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/Pwo78lf.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Anyways, because it’s a Love Pollen episode and Torres and Paris are alone, Torres wants to fuck Paris. At least, benefits to Paris, he’s not IMMEDIATELY getting it on. Even HE realizes the ethical fuckery of this, but it is indeed, fucky, and VERY uncomfortable to watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/UGgU2vl.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>She tells him she’s ALWAYS been interested in him like he has in her, but like, no, you’re clearly saying that for sex,. and even after a kiss, he’s not comfortable with fucking her. God bless, thank you Paris. Thank GOD. But after Chakotay and Tuvok rescue them, they determine that they MUST fuck, or she’ll die. Vorik sneaks down to the surface, the masturbation not helping, and declares ritual combat. Y’know, the thing that Spock did to Kirk. Torres tells him to go fuck himself and declares herself as her OWN defender, and beats the shit out of him. The Blood Fever is over.</p>

<p>Torres tries to avoid the subject later on with Paris, who tells her she’s being ridiculous and he didn’t mind it THAT much. What a TERRIBLE start to their relationship. And then they find Borg corpses on the surface, which means this episode is kind of important. Oh no.</p>

<p>This episode made me feel gross.</p>

<p><strong>Unity</strong> - VOY
7.5/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/2jhMYsD.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay and an Ensign who’s prolly gonna die later are lost in space, and Will Robinson is nowhere to be found. They get the lead of a Federation beacon and head to it, but it’s a planet, not Voyager, and the people on the planet recognize them as Federation. They’re still pretty far out, so that’s intriguing. When they land, there are people there to meet them, who just start blasting for some reason. The Ensign is killed, of course, but Chakotay is saved after being injured. He’s saved by a Human who explains that she, and the others on this planet, were kidnapped by aliens and stranded here. There are some Klingons, Cardassians, and all kinds of other things on this planet. She demands he rest for a bit.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Voyager is floating through a large expanse of nothing, bored, and then find… A BORG CUBE! It’s powered down and seems dead, so they send an away team to scavenge it and see if they can find anything that could help against future Borg attacks that will TOTALLY happen if we’ve seen hints of the Borg two episodes in a row.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/lGdP8xA.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay thinks the human he met, Riley, is kinda sussy, so he follows her outside and finds… BORG! They’re all Borg! She explains that yes, they WERE Borg. She was from Wolf 359. But after their Cube broke down, they escaped and regained their personal selves. They just want to make a society on here, and live happy lives. Chakotay is weirded out but hey, they can’t help having originally been Borg. Anyways Chakotay is dying and some Borg technology can help him, and the post-Borg can help him basically, temporarily putting him into the collective. Chakotay is a Borg Racist though and is like “NO FUCK THAT SHIT”, but eventually y’know, he’s about to die, so they welcome him into the collective briefly with a simple thing placed on his head, and easily removed after. It shows an interesting representation of what the Borg is, what it’s like being Borg, in a way that’s less threatening. Borg that wants to help and protect each other… but even then, the violence they’ve committed still bleeds through. They can’t escape it. I like that, it’s interesting.</p>

<p>Voyager shows up and saves Chakotay. Riley goes up to explain a plan they have. They’ll reactivate the Borg cube, for a minute, which will allow them to start a new collective, reconnecting their minds for good, and allowing them to peacefully assimilate all the raiders who are attacking them. While that isn’t bad, and she doesn’t think these people are bad, that forceful assimilation is still…. forceful, which is fucked, and also it might attract other Borg to the area, which is VERY bad, so Janeway says no. They accept her decision, and they go about their way.</p>

<p>Ha ha, no, they use the link they had established with Chakotay to force him to go into the Borg Cube and activate it. Like, they’re under attack by Raiders and about to die. They feel threatened and they have no other choice, I get it, but it’s still… unfortunate it had to come to this.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/zuRotSx.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Chakotay reactivates the Cube, which allows them to assimilate the violent raiders, but also activates the Borg, who immediately get ready to fire on Voyager, but the New Cooperative, as they call themselves, blow up the Cube, sever the link, and say goodbye. Chakotay and Janeway wonder if they WILL be better than the actual Borg, because they DID force their will as soon as it suited their needs… and hoped that it would go better this time.</p>

<p>Pretty interesting episode, especially for a Chakotay episode!</p>

<p><strong>Unity</strong> - VOY
9/10</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/5dKL38i.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>We’ve got a Kes episode! Voyager meets some aliens, the Travelers, who explore space willy nilly. They look like Bajorans but their nose ridge is white, they CLEARLY are re-using makeup lol. They’re friendly enough, but often just go by their own whims. They’re willing to trade medical stuff and information to Voyager, to help them out, and Kes is working with one in particular, one named Zahir. He’s a bit different, very friendly and helpful. The Doctor, meanwhile, doesn’t like them and tells Kes to keep away.</p>

<p>At the same time, the Doctor is researching ancient people, and trying to implement their personalities into his own. This is… obviously a bad idea, and Torres calls it out as such, especially after the Doctor flirts with her and places his fucking hand on her thigh and she is like “I WILL find a way to break you, Doctor”. Changing your personality is DRASTIC, and dangerous. He just wants to improve his bedside manner and be more friendly, which makes sense. But this is noooot the way.</p>

<p>Kes and Zahir start a relationship, of course, and Kes is thinking of leaving Voyager to join him in his journeys.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/8ETNIsk.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>Late at night, Zahir is attacked and thrown in a ravine, and his friend is attacked and burned… by the Doctor! Who’s acting all evil and fucked up. They get the Doctor to help him, and he’s… perfectly pleasant, but Torres notices a problem in his personality subroutines. Something fucked up with it and he’s degrading, so she tries to work on him… and is attacked by his Evil Version. It’s a Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Hyde situation. He’s unhinged, they do something with his eyes, and it’s PERFECT at making him seem unstable and evil as shit. His actor is FLEXING, and is SO good.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/FLJ2vkp.png" alt="trek" /></p>

<p>He kidnaps Kes and tries to escape to the planet, booking a ship to flee, with Kes as his… slave? I dunno. She eventually surmises that actually it’s the good parts inside of him trying to protect her. They chase them to the planet, and he threatens to throw them off a fucking cliff. But they catch them with the teleporter, and fix the Doctor, and all is well.</p>

<p>This episode is very entertaining, I didn’t wanna really type to distract myself. Good damn episode, let the Doctor flex more please. It ends with him reciting the Hippocratic oath… good episode.</p>

<p>…And thank God we ended on this episode, or this would be a very rough night.</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="LizstarTrek" /><category term="Star Trek" /><category term="Voyager" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 52</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/17/OOCY52.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 52" /><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/17/OOCY52</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/17/OOCY52.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/DAT71SU.png" alt="&quot;Ehh?! I... I'm becoming yuri?! I'm gonna end up being yuri?!&quot;" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Yuri is Taboo to a Yuri Otaku</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Yuri is Taboo to a Yuri Otaku" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Retro Achievement Mastery 120 - Pokemon TCG Neo</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/17/RA120-PTCGNeo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Retro Achievement Mastery 120 - Pokemon TCG Neo" /><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/17/RA120-PTCGNeo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ramastery/2024/11/17/RA120-PTCGNeo.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/CBvhtIZ.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>Early on in this year, I played Pokemon TCG, and Pokemon TCG 2. These are both RPGs on the Gameboy where the battle gameplay is the Pokemon TCG, using cards from the early sets. I had the first as a kid, and the second never came out here, but I played it and loved it, it might be even better than the first. And then… that was it. Nintendo never made another one of these. No clue why, they were genuinely fantastic. But what if they HAD?</p>

<p>This is a romhack of the original Pokemon TCG, which adds in Gen 2 cards. Cards from Neo Genesis all the way to Skyridge have been swapped in. Nothing else is changed, mind you. It’s the same adventure through the 8 clubs to get the 8 medals. It’s just… re-experience the game you already love, but this time you can use a Totodile. Which, frankly, improves it for sure.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/r4BSprj.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I know how to make utterly busted decks in TCG 1 and 2, but for this one I had a bit more trouble. In TCG 1 you can always go Haymaker, prolly your best bet. And in TCG 2, I made this stupid fucking Zapdos deck with only 2 copies of Zapdos, to take advantage of the lack of a mulligan rule. For this game, I made my own deck concept, a Slowking + Typhlosion combo. Typhlosion deals a LOT of damage, but it’s lowered by the damage counters on it, and Slowking can move damage counters off other Pokemon and onto it, or another benched Pokemon. It was a good deck, though I eventually swapped to a deck similar to my Zapdos one, but using a Celebi. Not nearly as effective, that Zapdos is busted as hell, but still good.</p>

<p>The cards aren’t exactly correct, and not every card is here. It prolly has to do with ease of programming. We don’t have the stupid Slowking that dominated that format, for example, which makes opponents flip coins when they try to use a trainer. That card sucked, so it’s not here. And I think some other cards are changed, but I don’t know the format nearly as well as I do the earlier formats. I wasn’t playing during this era.</p>

<p><img src="https://imgur.com/9K3HrMg.png" alt="Game" class="center-block" /></p>

<p>I’d also be remiss if I didn’t talk about the art. The art in the original TCG game was fantastic, honestly kind of mind blowing. It’s really damn good here, too. This game takes the art from the cards and translates it VERY faithfully onto a system that can usually only show four colors in a square of space. That’s EXTREMELY impressive, I cannot understate it. Also, because it’s the TCG, a lot of the art is utterly fantastic. Here’s this.</p>

<iframe src="https://clips.twitch.tv/embed?clip=PoisedStupidRaisinNinjaGrumpy-OsAfk5Zd-I0NI2Tn&amp;parent=www.example.com" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="true" scrolling="no" height="378" width="620"></iframe>

<p>Pokemon TCG Neo is a pretty sick romhack, honestly. It’s just a fun way to re-experience the TCG if you haven’t played it in a while, and I recommend it! Here’s a link to it:</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="RAMastery" /><category term="Retro Achievements" /><category term="Gameboy" /><category term="romhacks" /><category term="Pokemon" /><category term="Reviews" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Out of Context Yuri 51</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Out of Context Yuri 51" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/oocy/2024/11/15/OOCY51.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://imgur.com/HdbAXcG.png" alt="&quot;Whether I'm a guy or a girl... nothing changes." class="center-block" /></p>

<p>source: Boyfriend Sometimes Girlfriend</p>]]></content><author><name>Lizstar</name></author><category term="oocy" /><category term="yuri" /><category term="Boyfriend Sometimes Girlfriend" /><category term="genderbender" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>